Ah-shue, where are your parents?
They left this morning.
Dad usually comes home late, drunk.
He staggers and vomits all over the house.
When did your father's club close?
In March.
It was chaotic for a while.
Many people died,
...and the neighborhood was wrecked.
Dad's friend, Mr. Ko, was arrested.
Ah-shue!
Aunt Hinomi, uncle has returned.
We waited a long time, but he knew...
...which station exit to take.
Ah-shue,
...look for your brothers.
Take your time and write.
Uncle, you cannot eat that.
It's food for the altar.
You can't eat it.
You are thinner.
Are you OK?
My brother disappeared.
He was hiding in Lai-liao.
One day soldiers came.
Since then, we have had no news.
Wen-ching!
Here comes Mr. Huang.
Mr. Huang, this is
my good friend Wen-ching.
He was in prison with your brother...
... before he was executed.
He has come especially to see you.
Sit down.
"In life, far from the motherland.
"In death, returning to the motherland.
"Both life and death
are governed by destiny."
Hinoe got married and
lives in the mountains.
I can't tell you where.
She doesn't want her family to know.
She said, "Consider me dead.
My life belongs to the motherland.
"In prison, I swore to live, for the sake of
friends who had died."
I cannot live like before.
I want to stay here.
I know I can do whatever you ask me.
This is no place for you.
What's important are your beliefs,
not where you live or what you do.
They suggested marriage to Hinomi,
but it's you she loves.
Let me introduce my best friend,
Wen-ching.
Are you going to reopen for business or not?
Enough!
Go and play outside
Wen-leung, this is for the altar.
Eat after the prayers.
You decided to close.
Now you won't say
when you'll reopen.
Can't you make up your mind?
Shut up!
Don't argue with me!
Don't drink from the teapot!
You're setting a bad example to the children!
You're too big for such things.
Are you thirsty?
Drink properly or not at all.
Don't be ridiculous.
Look!
You were gone for days,
God knows where!
You either lock yourself in your room
or hide out where...
...nobody can find you.
I wanted you to visit mother's grave
with me. Where were you?
That's why I have such bad luck!
I am the only one of the four children...
...who visits mum's grave.
She asks me why,
...and I don't lack for words.
As for you,
...how long do you think you can go
without working?
I planned to open a photographic studio
on the side so you could run it.
We discussed it enough.
When will you give me an answer?
How can he reply? He can't hear.
Shut up!
The only thing you know
is to tell people off.
Ah-shue, you tell him.
When a young woman visits us,
...without thinking of her dignity,
...it's obvious what's going on.
Don't you understand?
What are you waiting for?
What's all the row?
Stop singing!
Damn it!
Shut up!
What's all this howling?
You are like bad spirits.
What's all the noise?
Why are you shouting?
Can't you talk normally?
What's going on?
It's useless. He seems incapable
of acting normally.
I'm sorry.
Please, carry on singing.
No, thank you.
Take no notice of him.
You sing very well.
Please, carry on.
He's as stubborn as a mule!
People like him
can't be taught anything.
Damn you!
How come you're not dead?
You really made Wen-leung
suffer.
Shame on you!
So?
What's up?
You know what you did.
Shut up or you'll be sorry.
What will you do about it?
What?
Calm down.
You don't scare me.
Pig!
You'll come to a bad end
one of these days.
Older brother!
Ah-ga.
Call a doctor!
What happened?
Kim-tsua, take that knife.
Call a doctor.
Wen-heung!
Here comes the bride.
Let's ask our ancestors...
...for children and wealth.
Bow to the ancestors.
Kneel down.
Pray.
First reverence.
Two.
Three.
Pray.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Pray.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Stand up.
Bow to each other.
Kneel.
Bride and groom, bow
to each other three times.
One.
Two.
Three.
Stand up.
It's late.
I heard the first thunder
of spring.
One clap after another,
...as if waking the hillsides
and the sea.
Someone came from the mountains.
He said my brother
needed money.
He needed it...
...to print pamphlets
to educate people.
The man said they didn't want
to be always asking...
...for help from Weng-ching.
But only when they come
to ask for money,
...do we know that they're safe
and that the struggle continues.
Only then are we satisfied.
Ah-chien can already make sounds.
Last night I thought
he was saying "mummy."
I was so happy.
I hurried to find Wen-ching...
...so he could hear too.
It was only when I saw him I realized
my stupidity. How could he hear?
Prices are rising.
The neighbors say
times will be hard.
Maybe I'm a fool.
But while I have Wen-ching
and Ah-chien...
...I think I'll be happy.
Don't run!
Still running! Shit!
Why are you shouting?
On your knees.
Heads down.
What are you looking at?
Ah-shue, your uncle Wen-ching
has been arrested.
We still don't know where he is.
At first we considered running away,
...but there was nowhere to go
I am writing this long after,
...because only now do I feel
calmer.
This photo was taken three days
before Wen-ching's arrest.
When they came for him,
...he was taking someone's portrait.
He insisted on finishing the job...
...before they took him away.
I searched and asked all over
Taipei but have no news.
Ah-chien has his first teeth.
He has a lovely smile...
and your uncle's eyes.
Please, come and see us soon.
It's fresh in Chiu-fen.
The autumn flowers
are in bloom.
The mountains are all white,
like snow.
It's time to eat.
OK. Just a moment.
Ah-chi,
...you shouldn't be watching
adults gambling.
Bring your uncle.
Uncle, it's time to eat.
Where is Uncle Wan?
He said he'd be back soon.
Wash your hands.
Help yourselves.
December 1949.
Mainland China is lost.
The Nationalist government
moves to Taiwan.
Taipei becomes
provisional capital.
Translated by Wu Ming
Spanish version by kairocure y Silien
Corrected by kairocure
English version by mexicanray
WWW.ALLZINE.COM