After pondering the situation in the world
and in our empire,
...we have decided to resort to
an extraordinary measure.
Loyal subjects, we have ordered
our government...
...to communicate to
the USA, Great Britain,
...China and the USSR,
...our acceptance of
the provisions...
...of their Joint Declaration.
To strive for the security and
well-being of our subjects...
...and for the prosperity and happiness
of all nations, is a....
...solemn obligation handed down by
our imperial ancestors.
We declared war on
the USA and Britain...
...out of a desire to ensure
the self-preservation of Japan...
...and the stability of
East Asia.
To violate the sovereignty of others...
...or to embark on
territorial aggrandizement,
...was far from our
thoughts.
Relax.
Gently. Or it will be
more difficult.
Open your mouth when I tell you.
Keep it closed now.
You are doing fine, just fine.
The pain is coming back?
Close your mouth.
Do you feel the need
for a bowel movement?
Do you?
Is that what it feels like?
Well, squeeze tightly then.
Prepare the water!
Hurry!
The light has come on again. At last.
It's a boy...
Congratulations.
On August 15 1945. Japan announced
its unconditional surrender.
Taiwan was liberated following
51 years of Japanese occupation.
The wife of older brother,
Lin Wen-heung, gave birth to a son.
They named him Kang-ming,
which means Light.
CITY OF SADNESS
Directed by Hou Hsiao-hsien
Going already?
Sorry for the mess.
We didn't give you a proper welcome.
Come again.
- Ah, hello.
- A small gift for you.
Go and play over there.
Behave or grandfather will
take a stick to you.
Yes, it's me.
Thank you, thank you.
I don't want to inconvenience you.
I am sorry to trouble you.
Thanks.
Until this evening then.
I'll be waiting for you.
Wen-heung,
...did you tell your brother
you were coming?
I wrote to Wen-ching.
He is too busy to come.
He can't come?
So who will take
the photos?
Don't worry, father.
I've arranged everything.
Who did you ask?
A photographer friend
of old Gao-kun.
He's a top-notch photographer.
The best in the district.
Not as good as Wen-ching.
Mr. Xu is here.
Show him in.
To business and to our
future prosperity.
To prosperity!
LITTLE SHANGHAI
Stay still, don't move.
Don't move.
Smile, please.
Ready?
Thanks!
20 years and 11 months of
the Showa Emperor.
Good weather, with clouds.
I took the letter of recommendation
from my father...
...to look for work at the
Kimguishiu Miners Hospital.
My brother was giving classes and...
...sent his friend Wen-ching
to pick me up.
It was cool in the mountains...
...and the view was lovely.
From now on, I will see it
every day
I feel so happy.
A photograph.
Beautiful.
Photographs of two of my older
brothers before the war.
They have still not returned. Someone in
Shanghai saw my third brother.
But we have had no news of the second,
who was sent to the Philippines.
This is the studio of Wen-ching.
Hinoe says that this is the
studio of Wen-ching.
Why isn't he here?
Where is Wen-ching?
At the back, taking photos.
Come in, please.
- After you.
- No, after you.
Are all these books yours?
Mine and Wen-ching's.
We are real
book worms.
Are you reading Marx?
Very progressive, eh?
They are all interesting, and so
we are studying them.
Mr. Lin, do you remember Wen-ching?
The deaf man.
Wen-ching.
Let me introduce...
...Mr. Lin.
Pleased to meet you.
My mentor.
We've heard a lot about you.
It's a pleasure.
Mr. Ho, a journalist.
From the mainland.
Please sit down.
Are you familiar with China?
There's a lot for me to learn.
China is in a mess
at present.
Ever since Chen Yi became
governor of Taiwan,
...things have changed.
He thinks differently from the Japanese.
In what way?
He manages things differently
from the Japanese.
Our Japanese director had an
attack this morning...
...but he insisted on going out
after he'd had an injection.
His daughter Shizuko is very sad.
During the past 3 days,
dad has been...
...threatening to go to the south of Taiwan.
He said that Mr. Chen would take him.
But he died years ago.
Dad was at his funeral.
The other day, the Japanese
Repatriation Office told us...
...that a boat would be coming to
Keelung to pick us up.
They told us not to go
too far away.
But this morning dad packed
his bags and left.
We are all very worried.
A pain... in the head.
A pain... in the stomach.
Where does it hurt?
Don't worry.
I don't think it's serious.
Thank goodness he came back.
He can recover here.
Perhaps my mother's grave is
in an unlucky location.
She died leaving four children.
My younger brother
disappeared in the Philippines.
The youngest is deaf.
The third came back from the war but
is mad.
Wen-leung, what are you doing?
Wen-leung, quiet!
Let me be!
Wen-leung, you're mad!
Wen-leung, calm down!
Quiet! Quiet!
It's OK.
He'll be fine now.
When Taiwan was returned
to China,
...they told us we'd change flags.
The Japanese flag is white
with a red circle in the middle.
You can hang it in a way that's...
...different from the Chinese flag.
The people held discussions. Should the sun
be on the top or the bottom?
But the mayor was adamant.
It had to be on the bottom.
At daybreak, the sky is red and so
the sun had to be at the bottom.
Everyone had to have it
as he said.
But he sent someone to check.
The first people he checked had
hung it correctly,
...but not in the mountains.
Most people put the sun
on the bottom.
And so the mayor felt
vindicated.
But during the day,
a man arrived from the city...
...and said he was wrong,
...and that they'd shoot him for it.
The mayor landed and gave new orders,
...but it was already sunset.
The sky was completely red.
It's extraordinary. Suddenly Japanese flags...
...were no use any more.
Only as underpants for children.
They all have red bums.
Like monkeys.
Wu too has one.
Mind what you say.
This man
is a reporter from the mainland.
Can your wife do something
with my flag?
I'll write that all the teachers...
...in Taiwan have red backsides.
Let's stop talking
and drink.
Cheers.
Let's change the subject.
Now that the war is over,
how are things in Taiwan?
Everything's fine.
We are under the Chinese flag
once more.
Reunited with the motherland.
It's a good feeling.
But to tell the truth,
...Governor Chen Yi
is a bandit...
...and I don't trust
the Nationalist government.
Enough politics!
Let's drink!
Let's drink.
Raise your glasses.
They are singing
"The Song of the Exiles".
Yes, that's right.
We mainlanders
have heard it on the radio.
Let's join in.
Yes, let's.
September 18...
Ever since that tragic day...
...I have been far from my home.
I abandoned a wealth of treasure...
...and began my wanderings...
...began my wanderings.
Far from home...
...I began my wanderings...
...began my wanderings.
In what year...
...or in what month...
...will I commence my return
to my beloved home?
In what year...
...or in what month...
...will I commence my return
to my beloved home?
Good day, Miss Shizuko.
Good day.
Is Hinomi here?
She's on duty.
I'm sorry.
- Hello, can I help you?
- I'd like to speak to Hinomi.
She's in the surgery.
Maybe she's finished.
Shall I find out for you?
Wait a moment, please.
This sword was the most precious
possession of my dead brother.
It's no use to him now.
Please, give it to Hinoe.
I know my brother
will treasure it.
This is a poem my brother wrote.
Hinoe was there
when he wrote it.
Please give it to him with the sword
as a memento.
Thank you.
This is for you, Hinomi.
For me?
A kimono?
It's lovely,
...but I can't accept it.
It's your most precious possession.
Please accept it.
When I am back in Japan,
...you'll think of you whenever you use it.
Shizuko...
Hinoe has been so nice
to us all these years.
We must never forget
each other.
The dragonfly, red in
the sunset.
Did I see you the other day?
When I was picking
mulberries in the fields,
...did I see you or was
it only a dream?
I'll always remember you.
The flowers are blown hither
and thither.
I'll soon follow them.
The same will come to pass for us all.
The Japanese love the sight
of cherry trees.
First, in bloom...
...and then, when the flowers fall
to earth.
They believe life
too is like that.
In the Meiji Era...
...a woman killed herself
by flinging herself into a waterfall.
In the Meiji Era...
...a woman killed herself
by flinging herself into a waterfall.
She wasn't tired of life. She hadn't
lost the will to live.
She just couldn't face the loss
of her youth.
Once lost, nothing
means anything.
Why not imitate
the cherry blossom...
...and fall when in the fullness
of our beauty?
Carried by the wind.
The note she left
was an inspiration...
...to all young people...
...during the Meiji Era.
A time of idealism
and heroic spirit.
The flowers fly hither
and thither.
And I'll soon follow them.
The same will come to pass for us all.
In which ward is Wen-leung?
I see him now.
Wen-leung, business is what men
are for, isn't it?
Men can do any kind
of work.
Now that you have recovered,
you can do anything.
You have six boats in your family,
...laden with rice and sugar...
...and ready to set sail to make a lot
of money in China.
Those boats are ideal
for smuggling.
We'd make a lot of money
with a single round trip.
What do you say?
I'll have to ask
my brother.
Ask what?
Do you consult him on everything?
Let's keep this between ourselves.
We Shanghai people are well
organized. Don't worry.
We'll take care of everything.
The rice and the sugar
are not a problem.
Come on, be shrewd.
When opportunity knocks,
it's foolish not to open the door.
Cheers!
To you, Wen-leung.
Ah-ga, enjoying the company
of the ladies, I see.
Ah-tao, look to table eight.
Excuse me.
May I present Tsun-chu
and Yen-hung.
Be nice to these mainlanders,
and see they have a good time.
What's this?
We are talking business!
What are all these women
doing here?
Come sit here.
Come.
Forget those mainlanders.
I was waiting for you.
I have a business proposal for you.
Take a good look.
Can you tell the difference?
Red Monkey, introduce me.
It's Ah-ga.
This is my girl, Ah-tsun.
Hello.
You're very beautiful.
And you're very nice.
Have a cigarette.
Let me light it for you.
Mr. Ah-ga, we were hoping
to see you more often.
You will.
Thanks.
I'm going in, Red Monkey.
These are real Japanese
banknotes.
We'll put a stamp on them
and then they can be cashed.
Is it Kimguichiu's share?
How many do you have?
A full valise.
Have you had an idea?
No problem.
Not now, Red Monkey.
I want to sleep.
Let me rest.
I don't want to do it now.
Later.
Let me sleep a while.
Who is it?
Hinomi, are you busy?
A bit.
Here.
When I was here, everyone
was so nice to me.
Take these fruits as
thanks.
My thanks to you all.
Thank you.
The mainland police killed a
cigarette vendor, did you know that?
Yes, I heard.
- You too?
- Yes.
The local people were furious.
The whole street was very tense.
Really furious.
Things were quite explosive.
The cigarettes were brought in as
contraband...
...by a senior official.
Bribery is rife.
They pursue the little fish but
leave the big fish alone.
- We don't have to smoke.
- I do.
I can't go without cigarettes.
Cigarettes are not as
important as rice.
Prices are controlled by
Shanghai...
...to keep up their profits.
The civil servants don't only deal
in contraband cigarettes.
They don't care if we have
rice and sugar,
...only money.
Under the Japanese, times were hard
but we always had rice.
In less than a year,
rice has gone up 52%.
But have salaries gone up?
You are right.
Let's face it, this is not a government;
it's a private company.
Governor Chen Yi is filling...
...his own pockets,
...not yours.
Please, eat a little of the
rice dumpling.
Hinomi made it.
Thank you.
To tell the truth, that's not
the real problem.
The real problem
is unemployment.
You're right.
Since our return to China,
...many Taiwanese have lost
their jobs.
Many of them were
intellectuals...
...who weren't easily
pacified.
With no work,
...sooner or later
there's bound to be chaos.
And not only the intellectuals.
Soldiers too.
Yes, the soldiers conscripted by
Japan can't find work now.
Someone from the mainland took over
the court...
...throwing out the locals
and replacing them with...
...his own wife, uncle and nephew.
The court has been taken over
completely...
...by his family.
They follow his orders.
The Japanese gave you...
...a slave mentality.
You have to change.
We don't even know
how to speak Mandarin.
Slaves? Dammit.
Have we sunk so low as
to want to become slaves again?
The Ching Dynasty sold us out.
Who asked us if we wanted
to be ceded to Japan?
Drink up.
If the Nationalist Government...
...doesn't change its ways,
...even though we have won the war,
...our suffering will continue.
How long before we can lift up our
heads with pride?
Who knows?
We mustn't give up hope.
That would be a waste.
If we want a future,
...the suffering masses
have to resist.
If the Nationalists carry on letting
Chen Yi do what he wants,
...there'll be problems in Taiwan.
Lao He.
There certainly will, as soon as...
...Mr. Ho makes ready his pen
to tell the tale.
You are our witness
from the mainland.
It's a folksong called Lorelei,
based on a German legend.
It's about a beautiful siren
seated on a rock in the Rhine.
Sailors are so enchanted by
her singing,
...that they crash their boats into
the rock and die.
I first heard it when I was eight.
I remember the goats bleating and
the voice of an actress in the Opera.
I used to mimic her.
My teacher said I'd become an actor.
I fell from a tree, hurt my head
and caught a fever.
I couldn't walk and didn't
know I was deaf...
...until my father wrote me.
I was too young to
be upset by it.
What's the matter?
He has a fever.
Daddy loves you.
Wait for me downstairs.
Give him something for it.
And?
Here it is.
Hello, Wen-heung.
Give.
Give it me!
What's this?
What is it?
How they fuck you!
Tell your boss to come!
How they fuck you! Put it out.
Why are you smoking?
Put it out.
Are you blind? Can't you read!
Shit!
You want to die young.
How could you do that?
What do you think you're doing?
Bring your boss here!
Go and find your boss.
Don't I give you enough money
for your expenses?
If this gets out,
...a lot of people could be hurt.
And I could die!
I'll take responsibility.
You'll take responsibility?
How can you do that?
It says here that Lin Wen-heung
is in charge of the goods.
You can't take responsibility.
Don't make me sick.
And you dress like those types
from Shanghai.
The latest fashion!
Lay about!
Where's Wen-leung?
I don't know.
You're together all day...
...and you say you don't know?
Speak up.
I really don't know.
Go and call Mr. Ko.
Give me Taipei 24.