出品人：候孝賢 黃文英 Executive Producer Hou Hsiao Hsien and Hwarng Wern-Ying
監製：廖慶鬆 Editor: Liao Ching-Sun
主演：舒淇 張震 Starring Shu Qi and Chang Chen
導演：候孝賢 Directed by Hou Hsiao Hsien
-=THE LAST FANTASY=- 字幕OCR : 劉晗 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業途徑
最好的時光 THREE TIMES
1966高雄 KAOHSIUNG, 1966
戀愛夢 A TIME FOR LOVE
老闆娘 Ma'am...
秀美喔 You're here!
新營來的秀美？ You came from Xinying?
來， 裏面坐 Go on in
我金紙燒完就進去 I'll be right there when I've made this offering
好啊 Okay
要幫忙嗎？ Need a hand?
不用！不用！ No, thanks
你有看嗎？ Did you look around?
看一看我帶你去樓上 I'll show you the upstairs
好 Good
秀美 May
等一會上來吃午餐 Come upstairs for lunch!
好 Coming...
春子小姐 "Dear Miss Haruko..."
很冒昧寫這封信給你 "I'm being bold enough to write to you"
我要去當兵了 "I'm about to do my military service"
昨天收到家裏寄來的信 "My folks wrote to me yesterday"
說我的兵役通知單來了 "They said my call-up notice has arrived"
要我儘快回家 "They're asking me to come home as soon as I can"
時光飛逝 "Time flies..."
想想自己這兩年大學沒考上 "I failed the university entrance exam two years running"
母親去世 "My mother has passed away"
未來的日子茫茫不可知 "I've no idea what the future holds"
跟你說這些，是想謝謝你 "I just want to thank you"
這段在旗後的日子 "The days I've spent around here..."
是我最快樂的時光 "...have been my happiest days"
衷心盼望能收到你的迴音 "Hope to hear back from you"
敬祝安康 "Take care"
P.S.，有一首 "P S. You know that song called 'In Love'?"
歌詞是這樣的 "The lyrics go..."
思戀你，思戀你呀 "I think of you, I think of you"
你我離別三年啦 "It's been three years..."
昨晚的夢原來也是你的夢 "But you're always in my dreams"
港邊的海鳥爲何打醒我眠夢 "Why do seabirds wake me from my dream?"
啼哭聲音悲哀 "It's because their sad cries..."
會令人心內憂悶 "...pierce my heart"
春子在嗎？ Is Haruko here?
她去臺中了 She's gone to Taichung
臺中 Taichung?
臺中哪裏？ Do you know where?
車站那裏 By the railway station
你叫什麼名字？ What's your name?
你的名字？ Your name?
我叫秀美 My name is May
秀美 May
有進嗎？ You sank it?
漂亮！ Great!
認真一點好不好 You need to concentrate!
我想打這邊碰那邊 I thought I could get this ball over there...
看會不會滑進去 ...and sink it that way
那也差太多了 No way!
你很久沒進了 You haven't sunk a ball for ages!
我還是輸啊 So I still lose
對啊 Right
算了 Never mind
我要走了 I have to go
要去哪 Go where?
等一下要去臺北當兵 I'm starting military service, in Taipei
不用找了 Keep the change
寫信給你 I'll write to you
我寄到這裏 I'll send it here
秀美小姐 "Dear Miss May
還記得我嗎？ Do you remember me?"
入伍前跟你撞球的那個人 "We played one round before I left to do military service"
時間過得飛快 "Time flies"
轉眼已經三個月了 "That was three months ago!"
春雨綿綿 "We have non-stop spring rain"
此刻，營區正放着披、頭四的歌 "In our base, they keep playing that song"
"Rain and Tears"
就像我的心情 "It sums up my feelings...
期待能再見到你 Hope to see you soon"
祝福，永遠美麗 "Stay beautiful!"
先坐一坐 Have a seat
老闆娘 Ma'am...
我先走了 I should be going
你不吃飽再走？ Won't you have lunch with us first?
不用，我要趕車 I'll miss the train
你住不慣再回來喔！ You're welcome to come back here anytime
好 Thank you
你是不是在嘉義中正路做過 Have you worked in Jiayi before?
是啊 Yes
我好像看過你 I thought so, I saw you there
我先走了 I have to go
你好 Hello
秀美在不在 Is May here?
秀美已經不在這裏啦 She doesn't work here any more
她去嘉義羅 She's gone to Jiayi
嘉義？ Jiayi?
嘉義哪裏？ Where exactly?
嘉義的桌球室 A pool-hall there
你要找她嗎？ Are you looking for her?
我去幫你問一下老闆娘 I can ask our boss
老闆娘 Ma'am!
有人要找秀美 There's a man here looking for May
喔，好 Okay
你要找秀美？ You're looking for May?
對啊 Yes
她現在嘉義中正路685號 She's in Jiayi, at 685, Zhongcheng Road
中正路 Zhongcheng Road?
是，中正路 That's right
岡山 GANGSHAN
臺南 TAINAN
嘉義 JIAYI
請問一下 Excuse me...
秀美有在這嗎？ Is there a girl called May here?
秀美十幾天前就沒在這做了 She left days ago
知道她現在去了哪嗎？ Do you know where she is now?
沒聽她說過 Sorry, I don't
謝謝 Thanks anyway
加一分 One bonus point
水上 SHUISHANG
新營 XINYING
請問一下 Excuse me...
你們這裏11號3號在哪？ This is Number 11, so where's Number 3?
30號？ Number 30
3號 Number 3
這邊6號，醫生那間是1號 That's No. 6... The doctor lives in No. 1
3號不知道，你去那邊問問 You can ask there
有人在嗎？ Anyone in?
誰啊？ Who is it?
你要找誰？ Who are you looking for?
我要找秀美 I'm looking for May
要找秀美 May?
她不在家，她去了虎尾 She's not here, she's in Huwei
虎尾 Huwei
你是誰？ Who are you?
你怎麼會找到這裏？ How do you know this address?
我是她高雄的朋友 I'm a friend of hers from Kaohsiung
她有寫信給我 She wrote to me
這樣 Oh, I see
你知道她現在在哪嗎？ You know where she is?
有啦，她有寫信回來 Yes, she wrote to me the other day
我去拿給你看 I'll fetch her letter
謝謝 Thank you
不會，有空再來坐啦！ See you again!
大林 DALIN
斗南 DOUNAN
“虎尾” HUWEl
不要讓我啦！ You don't have to let me win!
很久不見 Long time no see!
你怎麼會跑來這？ How did you find me here?
問你媽媽，她跟我說的你在這 Your mother told me
真難找 It was hard to track you down
你吃飯沒有？ Have you eaten yet?
幾點下班？ What time do you get off?
還要2個多小時 Two hours from now
你什麼時候要回去？ When are you due back in base?
明天一早9點要回部隊 At 9 tomorrow morning
喝茶？ Have some tea?
好啊 Sure
謝謝 Thank you
坐啊 Sit down
要抽菸嗎？ Cigarette?
好啊 Okay
你有煙嗎？    煙… Hey, spare me a cigarette? Cigarette
9：50分…沒車了 There are no more trains
你幾點要回部隊？ What time you have to be there?
9點 Nine in the morning
不然我們到外面等叫客車 Then we'd better wait at the car-share place
1911大稻埕 DADAOCHENG, 1911
幾時上來的 When did you arrive?
昨日，去基隆港接樑先生 Yesterday... I met Mr Liang on the docks at Keelung
今日設宴東薈芳 There was a meeting today at the
酒樓擠滿人 Eastern Restaurant, and it was packed
你是說戊戌年維新失敗 You mean the Mr Liang who fled to Japan...
逃到日本的樑先生 ...when the Reform Movement collapsed?
樑先生演講一小時，亦手書四首詩 Mr Liang spoke for one hour and wrote out four poems
吾人感動非常 and we found them deeply moving
詩云 One poem read...
破碎山河誰料得 "Our homeland is torn asunder
艱難兄弟自相親 Our brotherly bond is ever tighter"
自由夢 A TIME FOR FREEDOM
這次北上待幾日 How long will you stay?
五日 Five days
隨後陪樑先生下臺中，屆時一起北返 I will go with Mr Liang to Taichung, and then come back north
年前你小孩發寒熱，可痊癒了 Before the new year, your son had a fever... has he recovered?
已痊癒， 折磨兩個月 He is well now, but it took two whole months
翌日 NEXT DAY
贖身的事，我們有誠意解決 We sincerely wish to resolve the matter of redeeming Ah Mei's contract
三百兩不是小數目 300 silver dollars is a large sum
可否再參詳 Is it possible to discuss some more?
阿妹有身孕，是茶莊小開姓蘇 Ah Mei is pregnant by the heir to the Su Tea Plantation
願娶阿妹爲妾 He is willing to take her as his concubine
結果如何 What have they decided?
蘇家出兩百兩 The Su family offers 200 silver dollars
阿婆要三百，談不成 But Madame asks for 300, so they couldn't agree
不足之數，我可以負擔 I will make up the difference for them
你多次在報紙撰文，反對儲妾 In your articles you have always criticize the keeping of concubines
如今可好違背 Aren't you acting against your own principles?
我反對儲妾 I do disapprove of keeping concubines...
然木已成舟 ...but in this case, I must assent
爲妹妹終身有托只能成全 Ah Mei's future must come first
承蒙張老爺照顧 Mr. Chang, your generosity is overwhelming
這次來去匆忙，不及謝謝張老爺 Your stay is too short to allow us to show our full gratitude
路上好走 Travel safely
月底返來叫阿妹夫婦，給張老爺嗑頭 I will have Ah Mei and her husband thank you in person when you return
六日後 SIX DAYS LATER
我看蘇公子老實人 I can see that Mr Su is honorable
蘇老闆亦明理，是你有福氣 His father is also very understanding, you are blessed.
你明日嫁人，不比在家 You will be married tomorrow, and your life will be very different
須早起送水奉茶侍奉公婆 Rise early to serve your in-laws
與夫人相待要知禮 Always defer to the first wife
不可任性 Never behave willfully.
一個月後 ONE MONTH LATER
此行陪樑先生 During my travels with Mr Liang
會晤多人 I met many people.
深深受到啓發 It has been very inspiring.
樑先生說三十年內 Mr Liang says China will not be ready...
中國絕無能力援救 ...to help our people secede from Japan...
吾民脫離日人統治 ...for another 3 decades.
這是贖金一百 This is 100 silver dollars.
謝謝，妹妹有福氣嫁的好人家 Many thanks! Ah Mei is truly fortunate to have found such a good family.
媽媽近日在找養女 Madame is seeking a new girl to adopt
求我多留些時日 Meanwhile, she asks me to stay here longer
原先媽媽答應，待阿妹當家 She always promised to release me for marriage...
即放我贖身嫁人 ...once Ah Mei became a top courtesan herself.
翌日 THE NEXT DAY
多大了  How old are you?
十歲  I am ten.
骨骼長得好 Good bone structure...
就瘦了些 A little skinny.
有身孕 You are pregnant.
不能太勞累 Don't overtire yourself.
阿妹今日回門 Today Ah Mei returns
特爲來謝謝張大爺 to express her gratitude to you, sir.
不是張大爺相助，哪來得有今日 Without your kind intervention, this would not have happened.
明日返家，你何時再來 You leave tomorrow, when will you come again?
爲樑先生辦報事 I will assist Mr Liang with his plan for a newspaper.
隨時會來 I may turn up here at any time.
我有話問你 I have something to ask you...
前次你說 Last time you said that you assented in Ah Mei's case...
爲妹妹終身有托， 只能成全 ...for the sake of her future.
如今媽媽求我，多留些時日 Now Madame is asking me to stay here longer.
我想問你，可曾想過我的終身 Have you gave a thought about my future?
三個月後，武昌起義 THREE MONTHS LATER THE WUCHANG UPRISING
我日前抵東京，已晤樑公 "I reached Tokyo a day ago to join Mr Liang"
明將赴滬 "We leave for Shanghai tomorrow"
此行遊馬關春帆樓 "I visited the hall where the treaty ceding Taiwan to Japan was signed"
思及樑公詩，悵然淚下 "Thinking of Mr Liang's poem, I couldn't help shedding tears"
明知此是傷心地，亦到維舟首重回 "Although this place has torn my heart, it is wrenching to leave it.
十七年中多少事 "With all that has passed in these 17 years
春帆樓下晚濤哀 the tears of the oppressed are not assuaged."
2005 年臺北 TAIPEI,2005
你還好吧 Are you okay?
青春夢 A TIME FOR YOUTH
媽，你找我？ Mother, did you just call me?
我知道了 I see
你沒事吧？ Are you okay?
早產兒 "Born premature"
太早破出的自我 "Showed up too early..."
代價是昂貴的 "High price to pay"
多處骨折， 心臟破洞 "Fractured bones, a hole in the heart"
癲癇，右眼漸盲 "Epilepsy, almost blind in my right eye"
“胸口烙”￥ "A yen sign branded on my neck"
開個價吧！我要賣靈魂 "Name your price! I want to sell my soul..."
沒有過去，將來， 只有飢餓的現在… "No past, no future, just a hungry present"
請睜開你的雙眼 Please open your eyes
打開你的耳朵 Open your ears
敲敲你的腦袋 Check you brain
瞭解你想要什麼 To realize what you want
瞭解你是誰 To realize who you are
沒有人能決定你怎麼想 No one can decide how you feel
不要怕 Don't be afraid to
解放你內心深處 Liberate deep inside your mind
你所見過的顏色 The color which you've seen
你所在的形狀 The shape which you're in
可能透露了祕密 May reveal the secret
你以前從不知道 You've never known before
所以慶祝吧，當你誠實面對自己 So celebrate when you're honest to yourself
所以慶祝吧 當你不需要忽略你的感覺 So celebrate when you no need to disregard how you feel
所以慶祝吧 當你的感受和我不同的時候 So celebrate when you feel different from mine
讓我們慶祝吧 當我們不需要說謊和隱藏 Let's celebrate when we no need to tell lie and hide
“我是癲癇症患者” "I suffer from epilepsy"
“請不要叫救護車” "Please do not call an ambulance"
“請把我移到安全溫暖的角落” "Please move me to a safe, warm place"
“ 臺北醫學院附設大學” "Taipei Medical University Hospital"
走 Piss off!
回去啦 Come home
幹麻啦！ Don't bug me!
我要紙巾 I need napkins
給我紙巾 Pass me some napkins
謝謝 Thanks
你怎麼都不接電話？ Why didn't you take my calls?
我打電話給你都不接 I kept ringing, you never picked up
你在睡覺你也可以打給我啊 Even if you were sleeping, you could have called back
在睡覺啊 I was sleeping
可是你可以打電話跟我說 Why didn't you call me to say so?
跟你說我很累 I told you I was tired
爲什麼我打你電話     之後你就關機？ Then why did you switch off your phone after my call?
我跟你講我放完電了 I told you, I had a fit
可是你傳完訊息給我 But right after you texted me
我打給你就是關機 you switched off your phone
之後我就睡了 I went to sleep right away
可是你可以打電話給我 You could still have called me
而且我打給你你沒有聽到嗎？ Couldn't you hear your phone?
你都沒有聽到嗎？ Couldn't you?
我開震動 I left it in vibration mode
不要生氣了好不好？ Don't be angry
可是如果今天是你會怎想？ If you were me, what would you think?
我等你收工回家好不好？ I'll wait for you when you finish, okay?
收到文字訊息 TEXT MESSAGE
“睡不着，想你，你的癲癇卡掉在我家” "Can't sleep, miss you, you left your epilepsy card at my place"
“照片洗好了，明天交給你” "Developed the photos, will show you tomorrow"
每次用這打火機點蠟燭，都燙到手 I burn my hand every time I light a candle with this lighter.
大拇指好痛 My thumb hurts.
如果再燒應該不能用了 It's almost run out.
根本沒辦法點 I can hardly light this one.
幫我拿一下那個 Pass that one to me.
謝啦 Thanks.
那個等一下再放 We'll light this one later.
還有那個 And that one.
那邊的都要點 That one too.
這些幹麻，泡到水是不是 Has water gone inside?
你聽到啪差啪差的聲音嗎 You hear that funny sound?
水跑進去了 The wick is wet.
明天在買些新的 Let's buy some new ones tomorrow.
還有另外兩個 There are two left.
這水都髒了 The water is dirty.
等一下你去換一下 Can you change it later?
是因爲那個蠟油嗎？ Is it because of the candle wax?
根本點不着 I can't even light them
泡澡用伊蘭跟鼠尾草好嗎？ Shall I put some fragrant oils in the bath?
好 Okay
那一起洗喔 Let's bathe together.
你不回答我就當你答應我 I'll take silence as a 'Yes'
好 Okay
那我去拿衣服 I'll go get clothes
以前拍的照片 "The pictures taken before
灰色眼睛的微笑 "With smiling gray eyes
也許停止，如此殘酷的聲音 "May rest, such cruel sound
靖，好啦！快點 Jing! It's ready, hurry up!
仍栩栩如生，好像一隻鳥一樣 "It's still vivid, like a bird"
靖！ Jing...
你還沒睡？ You're still awake?
阿婆有燉雞湯 Grandma made some chicken soup
我端上來給你喝？ I'll get some for you?
靖！ Jing!
阿婆有燉雞湯 Grandma made some chicken soup
我端上來給你喝？ I'll get some for you?
好 Okay
對不起來晚了 Sorry, I'm late
我剛打過你電話 I called you just now
但你沒有接 But you didn't answer
相片 The photos.
去你家 Go to your place.
靖？ Jing?
未接來電 "One missed call"
連結中 "Connecting..."
你應該在12：45以前出門的 You must have gone out before 12:45.
你留下了手機 You left your cell phone here.
我想你是故意的吧 I think you did it on purpose.
故意讓我知道你只在附近 To make me think you had...
只出去一下 just stepped out for a minute.
你手機最後未接電話是12：45 Your last missed call was at 12.45.
我想你應該是在那之前出門的 So you'd have gone by then.
現在已經3：33 Now it's 3:33.
你出去超過3個小時 You've been out for over 3 hours.
你知道我4點會醒 You knew I'd wake up at 4.
我不想再聽你的謊言 I don't want to hear any more of your lies.
不想再等你了 I'm fed up with waiting for you.
你都這樣逼我 You keep pushing me.
你知道我愛你比你愛我多 You know that I love you more than you love me.
你會後悔的 You'll regret this
我會死的，就像織香 I will kill myself just like Olika.
我想你是故意的吧 "I think you did it on purpose"
未接電話是12：45 "Your last missed call was at 12:45"
你出去超過3個小時 "You've been out for over 3 hours"
我不想再聽你的謊言 "I don't want to hear anymore of your lies"
不想再等你了 "I'm fed up with waiting for you"
你都這樣逼我 "You keep pushing me"
你知道我愛你比你愛我多 "You know that I love you more than you love me"
你會後悔的 "You'll regret this"
“我會死的，就像織香” "I will kill myself just like Olika"