3E帝國傾情奉獻 中英字幕合併:算妮狠
抱歉 Excuse us.
借過 Get out of the way
阿信 Ashin
哥，你有沒有怎樣？ Brother, are you alright?
怎麼這麼嚴重啦 How can itbe so serious?
小心點 Be careful
阿信啊 Ashin,
抱歉， 借過啊 Excuse us.
呵！ 這個猴囝子 What? This kid
真厲害喔！ He is good!
好像猴子喔！ Like a monkey!
什麼好像猴子 Nonsense,
那可是我孫子勒！ He's my grandson.
怎麼蹲的啊 Don't you know how to squat?
屁股坐下去 Lower your butt.
再下去 Lower.
再下去一點 Lower, much lower.
手擡高 Arms higher.
喂 Hey!
你是誰 Who are you?
你又不是體操隊的 You're not in the gymnastic team.
進來幹嘛 Why are you here?
出去 Get out!
走開啦 Don't get in the way.
現在開始倒立 Ready for handstand.
聽口令 Attention!
一拍手 One, clap hands.
二把腳踏出來 Two, step out your feet.
三手放下去 Three, put down your hands.
後腳擡高高 Lift your legs high.
就像小狗撒尿 Just like a puppy peeping.
撐住 Hang in there.
你已經胖到腳都擡不起來羅 You're too fat to lift your leg.
擡高 Lift your legs.
腳擡起來 Lift your legs.
誒你香蕉腰喔 Your waist is as weak as a banana.
媽不是跟你說過 What have I told you?
上課要專心要認真聽 You need to pay attention in school.
你怎麼偷吃便當啊 How could you eat the lunchbox during class?
媽,  因爲你滷的雞腿實在太香了 Mom, the braised chicken thigh you made smelled so good.
還有理由喔 What an excuse.
要是我雞腿用炸的 If I made fried chicken, then you'd
你不就上課走到半路就偷吃完了 finish iton the way to school.
媽 Mom,
我想要練體操好嗎 can I practice gymnastics?
要交錢嗎 Do we need to pay for that?
教練說不用 The coach said no.
不用錢就去啊 Then go for la.
手伸直 Straighten your arm,
不要撐 don't push.
很痛 It hurts.
好了啦 You may go.
下一位 Next.
看什麼看 What are you looking at?
換你啦 It's your turn.
伸直伸直 Make itstraight.
伸直啦 Straight.
小樹，不錯喔 Shu, nice.
腳伸直 Straighten your legs.
挺胸 Thrust out your chest.
看前面 Look forward.
新來的喔 You're the new kid, right?
要加油喔 You need to work hard.
來，腳伸直 Come on. Straighten your legs.
挺胸，看前面 Thrust out your chest. Look forward.
你以爲在拿方向盤開車啊 This is not a steering wheel.
回去重來 Go back and do itagain.
你是敢不敢跳啊 Are you going to jump or not?
今天要測驗鞍馬 Today is Pommel Horse skill test.
五圈加下馬 5 circular motions then dismount.
來，誰先來 Come on. Who wants to go first?
誰先來啦 Any one?
伊冠鈞 Champ Yi,
你先來 you go first.
預備姿勢這麼漂亮 Nice preparation posture but
一個都轉不起來喔 can't even do one circular motion?
你就一個一個來嘛 Fine, you can do one at a time.
連下馬都要分段喔 Even dismount is in sections.
回去回去回去 You can go back now.
維持好喔 Keep itthere.
高度維持好 Keep the height.
That's 30
停十秒 Hold itthere for 10 sec.
小樹啊 Shu,
比賽就快到了 listen, the game is coming,
你就保持現在的狀態 and you'll be fine if you keep
就沒問題了 your current condition.
阿信啊，來 Ashin, come here.
你的彈跳力很好 You have great jumping power.
在空中的動作也很漂亮 Also have good moves in the air.
你爲什麼就是不會落地呢 But, why can't you land?
好，加油 Okay, try harder.
小樹啊 Shu, Ashin's movements
阿信的動作越來越像你咧 are getting like yours.
大會報告大會報告 Attention please,
國小高年級組個人跳馬決賽選手 Senior Student Group players in Individual Vault Event,
現在開始報到 please do the registry now.
大會報告 Attention please,
現在場地開放跳馬項目 Three minutes practice time
決賽選手練習三分鐘 for vault players.
爲什麼會這樣 Why It Happened?
來來來，我來我來 Let me see.
怎麼樣 How do you feel?
腳扭到喔 Sprained your ankle?
腳先伸直 Straighten your legs first.
阿信啊 Ashin,
雖然你是個候補選手 as you're a substitute,
你就當這一次啊 just think this one
是一個練習 as a practice.
輕鬆一點 Take iteasy,
好不好 okay?
喔！還有 And, one more thing
只要你不摔個狗吃屎 As long as you don't fall on your face,
都行 la will be good enough.
加油 Go for la.
林育信 Lin Yu-Shin.
有 Here.
哥哥好棒喔！耶 Brother, you are great!
還在玩喔 Still playing?
吃飯了啦 Time for dinner.
媽 Mom,
你怎麼沒有來看我比賽 why didn't you come to my game?
我得到金牌勒 See, I won the gold medal!
靠那塊金牌就會飽嗎 Can you feed on the gold medal?
吃飯啦 Eat your dinner.
哥,金牌送我 Brother, give me your gold medal.
要金牌不會自己去拿喔 Go win your own.
媽,人家也要像哥哥一樣 Mom, I want to be like brother.
練體操得金牌 Be a gymnast and win a gold medal.
什麼金牌啦 Quit the medal thing.
你哥要吃屎你也要跟去吃屎嗎 If he eats shit then you'll eat, too?
啊,不要啦 No.
我要跟哥哥一樣啦 I wanna be like him
還要繼續吵嗎 You want to keep whining?
那我要拿藤條了喔！ Then I'll get my rattan.
不要不要 No, no, no.
會怕就好 Good.
唉喲！媽 Yuck! Mom,
那是什麼 what's that?
唉喲什麼 Yuck?
這我燉很久勒 I'd braised this for hours.
人家說“吃腦補腦” "Eating brain enhances brain."
看你吃完會不會變得比較聰明 After eating this, maybe you can
比較會念書 be smarter and get higher grades.
呃     媽 Yuck! Mom,
這是什麼腦啊 whose brain is la?
豬腦啊 Pig's brain.
我特地叫你阿嬌姨幫我留的勒 I asked aunt Jiao to save this one for me.
一隻豬隻有一個 One pig has only one brain.
哈哈哈，吃完豬腦變豬頭 Ha, you'll become a pig head.
你不要在那邊笑 Don't you laugh at him.
你也要吃 You have to eat, too.
啊 No
啊   話不要那麼多 No? No more moaning.
吃飯啦 Just eat.
活該 You deserve la.
林育信 Lin Yu-Shin.
有 Here.
阿信 Ashin,
你的直體笠鬆很直 your Kasamatsu Stretch is perfect.
動作也很漂亮 Your movements are great.
但是落地的時候 不管怎麼樣你都要站好嘛 But you need good landings.
小樹 Shu
你動作都很好 your movements are great.
我可不可以拜託你 But,
臉不要這麼臭 please don't wear this long face.
好不好 Okay?
觀衆跟裁判沒人欠你錢耶 No one owes you money.
喔 Oh.
媽 Mom,
怎麼這麼久 what took you so long?
我肚子很餓勒 I'm starving.
哥，你腳怎麼了 Brother, what's wrong with your foot?
那你下個月全國賽怎麼辦 What about your national game next month?
比什麼賽 What game?
你也學一下你弟 Why can't you be like your little brother?
人家讀書有在認真讀 He studies hard and helps me
放學回家又會幫我顧水果攤 at the fruit stand after school.
那你呢 And you?
一天到晚就只會練體操練體操 All you know is gymnastics.
有本事你就不要受傷 If you're really good,
還要去給醫生看 you'd better never get hurt.
要花多少錢你知道嗎 The doctor visits are expensive.
我以後賺錢還你嘛 I'll earn money to pay you back later.
我就只想練體操啊 I just want to do gymnastics.
賺錢還我 Pay me back?
以後都不知道可不可以養活自己 I wonder if you can even feed yourself.
還想要賺錢還我 Let alone to repay me.
你如果繼續練體操 If you keep doing gymnastics,
搞不好我要養你一輩子 I may need to support you forever.
長大了啊 A grown-up now.
都不知道自己的腳 Does he even know if his legs
是否有那個能力 are capable or not?
你真的不要再考慮一下 Are you really sure about this?
不要再讓他繼續練了好不好 Don't let him do this anymore.
黃教練 Please, Coach Huang.
他很不容易 It took him a lot
才能成爲一位體操選手 to be a gymnast.
難道你要他就這樣放棄 You really want him to stop?
體操我是不懂啦 I don't know about gymnastics.
我也知道我們阿信 But l know Ashin
一直都很認真 always practices hard.
不過黃教練 But, Coach Huang
你有看過體操選手 Have you seen any gymnast
是長短腿的嗎 with uneven leg length?
阿信 Ashin.
你上來一下 Come up here.
喔 Okay.
教練 Coach.
媽 Mom?
你怎麼在這裏 Why are you here?
阿信啊 Ashin.
先把東西收一收 Pack your things,
跟你媽回去 and go home with your mom.
啊 What?
教練 Coach
叫你東西收一收你是沒有聽到是嗎 Go pack your stuff, didn't you hear that?
每天就只想到練體操練體操 You care only gymnastics.
有想過要幫我做生意嗎 How about helping the business?
媽 Mom
你幾歲啊 How old are you now?
從現在開始 From now on,
不准你再練體操 no more gymnastics.
跟我回家學做生意賣水果 Stay home and learn the fruit business.
搞不好比練體操還有出息 It's a better prospect than gymnastics.
媽    拜託 Mom, please
教練 Coach
可是我快要比賽了勒 my game is coming.
我已經把你從比賽名單中剔除了 I've removed you from the list.
誒   你看 Hey, look.
這是我 This is me.
我昨天看到一個馬子 I saw a chick yesterday.
拉一下 Pull la.
我看到她喔 I saw her.
很漂亮喔 She is pretty.
你拉一下這邊 Pull here.
對 Right
很漂亮喔 See, she's pretty.
真正有影 What the hell.
今天要是再給我看到 If I see her today,
我一定把她變成“ 麪筋” I'll make her melted like cheese.
怎樣 What?
你不會閃遠一點喔 Don't get in the way.
不會啊 I don't want to move.
你想怎樣 What do you want?
看你想怎麼樣啊 It depends on what do you want.
我哪知道你想要怎樣 How would I know what you want?
看你想怎麼樣我就怎麼樣啦 I want what you want.
你要怎樣就過來啦 Whatever. Come here if you dare.
不要在那邊啦 Stop quacking there.
好啊！ Fine.
都不要動啦 Don't you move a step.
好嗎 Okay.
啥小 What?
誒你要幹嘛 What are you doing?
你要幹嘛 What are you doing?
你不要亂來，我的車 Don't do la. My car!
哥 Brother.
媽， 我回來囉 Mom, I'm home.
不會自己拿給她哦 Why don't you give itto her?
你是在傻什麼 Don't be silly.
去啦 Go,
真正有影 don't be so annoying.
媽 Mom.
錢是跟他有仇喔 Is money his enemy?
弄成這樣 Folded like this
怎麼少一百 How come itis 100 dollar short?
你自己問他啦 You ask him.
哥 Brother,
媽說怎麼少一百 mom said there's 100 missing.
摩托車是吃水的喔 Do you think the motorcycle runs on water?
哥說 Brother said
我沒有耳聾 I'm not deaf.
吃飯 Time to eat.
哥，媽說 Brother, mom said
知道啦 I know.
吃飯配電視就飽了啊 Having rice with TV is enough,
還需要吃菜嗎 I guess you don't need any dishes.
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請輸入您的CALL機號碼 Please enter your pager number.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
284168168
林先生您好 Hi, Mr. Lin.
今天中午12點10分 Today, at 12:10, Pickle said:
菜脯留言請您三點前到水閘門 Please be at the water gate before 3.
對方是眷村幫 The opponents are Mainlanders.
另外 And
他還要請您多帶三把扁鑽 please also bring 3 arrow chisels.
嗯 Okay.
整天到晚在外面亂晃 Fooling around all day.
是在做什麼大生意 Like he is doing some huge business.
家裏都待不住 Can't even stay home for a minute.
有辦法就不要回來 Don't come home if you're that good!
唉喲 Well.
就你們四個 Only four of you.
找不到人喔 Can't find more help?
看是要跟誰打啦 It depends on whom we are fighting.
你們很囂張嘛 You guys are very confident.
對～ Yap
現在後悔還來得及 it's not too late to regret.
來～ Come on.
抱歉 Sorry.
就是他們 It's them!
就是他們把我打成這樣 They beat me into this.
說對不起 Say you're sorry.
你爸我就原諒你們 I'll forgive you son of a bitch.
上次沒有把他手打斷 算他運氣好 He's lucky that we didn't break his arm last time.
這位看起來體格不錯喔 This one looks well-built.
打下去不知道會不會叫媽媽 Wonder if he'll call momma later.
聽不懂喔 You don't get la?
娃娃哭了 Baby calls his momma
不是要叫媽媽 when crying.
等一下誰叫媽還不知道勒 Don't know who'll call his mom yet.
警察來了 The police are here.
不要跑 Don't let him run away.
我來 I'll get him.
阿信 Ashin.
你是在幹嘛啦 What are you doing?
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
323168168
林先生 Mr. Lin,
您沒事吧 are you alright?
啊 What
我很好啊 I'm fine,
怎樣 Why?
有沒有留言啦 Any message?
今天下午3:05分 3:05 this afternoon, 045 said
045留言請您4點前到撞球間 Be at the Billiards House before 4.
一定要準時 You must be on time.
因爲他們要埋伏 'Cause they plan an ambush.
嗯 Hum.
還有什麼需要爲您 Anything else I can do for you
感謝您的來電 Thank you for calling.
你知不知道菜脯 Do you know
喜歡什麼樣類型的女生啊 What kind of girl does Pickle like?
我啦 Me.
啊 What?
我啦 I said me.
啊不然菜脯喜歡吃什麼 Well, what does Pickle like to eat?
麪筋啦 Cheese.
對喔 Right!
“ 麪筋”，“菜脯” 鈥淐heese鈥?and 鈥淧ickle
夾起來剛剛好 Perfect match.
來了來了 Here they come.
躲起來 Let's hide.
麪筋 Cheese,
演像一點啦 play your role.
我知道啦 I know.
聽說眷村仔在水閘門被人家打掛 I heard the Mainlanders were battered.
幹！一定是阿信他們 It must be Ashin and his gang.
有夠囂張 They are everywhere.
我看這樣啦 Well, how about this:
晚上來去找眷村仔喬這件事 We go to the Mainlanders tonight,
改天給他們好看 Together, we will teach Ashin's some lessons.
水啦 Good.
小姐，不好意思 Miss, Excuse me.
二號桌 Table 2.
新來的喔 You're new here?
水喔 Nice.
把馬子喔 You're after this chick?
走啦 Let's go.
借我一下借我試一下 Excuse me.
沒進去 Missed.
給你死 Kill them.
來啊～ Cheese,
麪筋 are you alright?
你有沒有怎樣 Pickle,
菜脯，人家好害怕喔 I'm so scared.
喔！你也會怕喔 Oh, you are so scared.
你給我秀秀 I need some consolation.
真正有影 What the hell.
菜脯 Pickle, hurry up.
好，我給你秀秀 I give you my consolation.
菜脯，快一點 Pickle, come on!
來了啦 Coming.
不行 You can't do that!
啥款 How's that?
林先生您好 Hi, Mr. Lin.
937留言請您儘快趕到碼頭 937 said: be at the pier as soon as possible.
好累 Fuck, So tired.
啊～ What?
喔！抱歉啦 Sorry,
我不是在跟你講啦 I wasn't talking to you.
拜拜 Bye.
菜脯 Pickle,
叫媽媽啦 Time to call momma.
（撞球場，勝二） (Billiards House. Win: 2 times)
誒他是怎樣 What's wrong with him?
不是你們體操隊的 He was your teammate, right?
怎麼每天都這張臭臉 How come he has this long face everyday?
誒這個圓的啤酒瓶仔 The round beer bottle
跟這四角的紹興酒瓶 and the square ShaoShing bottle
哪一個打架起來比較好用 which one is better for fighting?
不知道 Don't know.
你不會試試看喔 Why don't you try la.
拿這個 Take this one.
抱歉喔 Excuse me.
阿孃喂 Shit.
媽咧 Holy shit.
這不是開玩笑的 This isn't funny.
叫阿嬤都會 Whoever get hit by this will call grandma
真正有影！ What the hell.
給它拜一下 Pray to la.
請它抽菸啦 Give ita cigarette.
有一塊嗎 Do you have a dollar?
這有 Here.
林先生您好 Hi, Mr. Lin.
嗯 Yes?
742留言 742 said:
請您半個小時後去釣蝦場幫忙 He needs help at the shrimp pool 30 minutes later.
嗯 Okay.
誒，林先生 Mr. Lin
啊 What?
你之前去釣蝦場三次都打輸了 You have lost 3 fights at the shrimp pool
你這次要小心喔 So, be careful this time.
你怎麼知道啊 How do you know?
呃 Well
因爲我有幫你作紀錄啊 'cause I'm keeping records for you.
啊 What?
沒有啦 You know
因爲你跟你朋友留言都很 The messages between you and your friends
特別 are very special.
而且我們公司電腦都有紀錄啊 They're all in the company computer.
喔！這樣哦 I see.
誒你有沒有想過 Has itever occurred to you that
不要再過這種打打殺殺的生活啊 you should stop this kind of life?
沒有耶 Nope.
誒你問這麼多幹嘛 Why are you asking?
沒有啦 Nothing.
我只是想說 It seems to me, though,
你這樣每天不是都過的很緊張嗎 you life is very tense.
緊張什麼 What is there to be tense for?
誒，我很好奇勒 Hey, I'm curious
你這邊是電話祕書 You work for a pager service
還是那個什麼張老師啊 or a counseling center?
啊 Well
還有啊 One more thing:
以後不要叫我林先生啦 Don't call me 鈥淢r. Lin" anymore.
叫我阿信 Call me Ashin.
阿信 Ashin.
拜拜 Bye.
小樹 Shu
那兩碗麪端去給那桌的客人 These two bowls of noodle are for the quest over there
誒，吃快一點啦 Hey, eat faster.
看啥小 What are you looking at?
抱歉喔 Sorry.
老闆，抱歉喔 Sorry, boss.
馬上就好 Please wait a second.
小樹 Shu,
那桌客人快要吃完了 That table is finishing soon.
趕快去收一收 Go clean the table.
快點 Hurry up.
趕快去收一收 Clean the table.
老闆啊 Hey man,
哪有人這樣做生意的 this is not how you do business.
位置這麼少，客人要坐哪裏 With so few seats, where shall we be seated?
麪攤可以關一關了啦 Maybe you should shut the stall down.
趕快吃啦 Eat faster.
怎樣啊，不爽喔 What? Any problem?
現在是怎樣 You got something to say!
喔！抱歉啦 Oh, sorry!
不小心的啦 I didn't mean la.
找死喔 Are you looking for trouble?
你們如果那麼餓 If you are that hungry
不然我“ 下面”給你們吃啦 how about I let you swallow my dick?
你皮在癢了 You asked for this.
也許這次就不是不小心的囉 Maybe I mean itthis time.
怎樣 So?
免緊張啦 Take iteasy.
老大， 抽菸啦 Boss. Have a cigarette.
你們兩個膽識不錯 You two really have balls.
以後就跟我 Come join my gang.
啥小 What the Fuck.
你爸我叫木瓜啦 I am Papaya.
我爸是黑松 My dad is Pine,
你是啥小 and who the hell you are?
黑松老大 His dad is Pine, the gang boss.
對 Yeah,
就是他 that's him.
跟我們比在這邊賣水果有前途 Follow us get you farther than selling fruits.
有沒有要買 Do you want to buy any fruit?
不然我要收攤了 We're closing.
好啊 Fine,
等你們收完攤 we can solve this
一起出來玩啊 after you close the shop.
甜的勒 These are sweet.
送給你們吃啦 You can have them for free.
甜的喔 Sweet papaya.
沒關係 Don't worry.
你們忙 You guys are busy.
總會遇到的 We'll definitely be seeing each other again.
好吃耶 These are good.
你來幹嘛 What do you want?
好啦，有麻煩可以來找我啦 I see, You can come to me for your trouble.
那找你回去 I come here to ask you back.
怎麼樣 What do you say?
回去 Going back?
練體操喔 To the gymnastics team?
跟你一樣 And, be like you,
每天躲在體操館 staying in the gym everyday,
過年只休兩天 With only two days oh' during the Chinese New Year?
算了吧 Forget la.
太無聊了啦 It's too boring.
我現在才知道外面有多好玩 Now I know there is so much fun out here.
我以前怎麼那麼乖啊 How silly I was back then?
被體操綁得死死的 Tied myself to gymnastics.
哪像現在 See how free I am now?
我愛幹什麼就幹什麼 I can do whatever I want.
多爽啊 It is great!
是嗎 IS la?
體操選手一輩子只有一次巔峯期 A gymnast has only one peak period in his life,
你再不回來，就來不及了 it'll be too late if you don't come back now.
真的假的啊 What are you talking about?
你以前不是最看不起我 You used to look down on me.
現在叫我回去 But now you're asking me back.
真正有影 (What me hell)
我告訴你 Listen,
如果我是練體操的料 if I am really good at gymnastics,
一年前教練就會把我留下來了 the coach wouldn't let me go a year ago.
不要怪別人 Stop blaming others.
你自己選的 This is your choice.
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
我是阿信啦 This is Ashin.
阿信 Ashin?
今天沒有你的留言 There's no message for you today.
我知道啊 I know.
我打來 I called
是想跟你聊天啦 to talk to you.
很抱歉我們公司有規定 Sorry, but we're not allowed
不能跟客戶聊天 to chat with clients.
我又不是你客戶 I'm not your client,
我是你朋友勒 I'm a friend.
誒我在上班勒 I'm at work,
你不要鬧啦 stop bugging me.
我哪有在鬧啊 I am serious.
等你下班啦 Let's meet after you are off the clock
怎麼樣 How does that sound?
不行啦 No way.
爲什麼不行 Why not?
林先生，您不要這樣 Mr. Lin, please do not act like this.
我在上班 I'm at work.
林先生喔 Mr. Lin
好啊 Fine.
那我留言可以吧 I want to leave a message, may I?
好的，請說 Yes, Go ahead.
今天晚上九點 9 o'clock tonight
電影院 at the movie theater.
不見不散 Be there or be square.
您的留言代號是 To whom you leave this message?
Y-O-U Y, O, U.
YOU啦 YOU.
你除了玩跟打架 Is there anything meaningful to you
沒有更有意義的事情可以做嗎 other than fooling around and fight?
喂 Hello?
那你每天在這裏接電話 So your life is more meaningful
就比我有意義啦 answering phone calls every day?
感謝您的來電 Thank you for calling.
誒，你們第一次來喔 Is this your first time here?
我也第一次來勒 It is mine.
嗨～ Hi.
坐啦 Have a sit.
免緊張啊 Take iteasy.
我就跟你說宜蘭沒多大 Told you Yilan is a small place,
我們總會遇到的啦 and we'll meet again on way or the other.
抽菸啦 Have a cigarette.
現在流行抽這個啦 This is what's popular now.
怎樣 What?
你怕喔 You're scared?
誒 Hey.
阿信啊，你怎麼那麼晚纔來 Ashin, you're so late.
人家都休息了啊 Everyone had left.
不好意思啦 I'm sorry.
來 Come on.
趕快搬一搬啦 Get the cartons and move fast,
我要回去睡我的美容覺 I'll go back for my beauty sleep.
趕快搬啦 Hurry up.
誒等一下啦 Wait a second.
等一下啦 Wait up
菜脯 Pickle!
等一下 Wait for me.
菜脯 Pickle,
菜脯，有沒有怎樣 Pickle, are you okay?
爽啦 Fucking awesome.
真的假的啊 Are you serious?
嗯 Yap
誒，你最近怪怪的 You've been acting weird recently.
一個禮拜沒睡覺喔 I haven't slept for a week.
啥 What?
誒晚上陪我去把馬子 Lets go get some actions tonight.
順便教我那個 And you can teach me
“大車輪” the 鈥渂ig wheel
嘿！菜脯 Hey, Pickle.
嘿！ Hey.
你也來跳舞喔 You come here to dance, too?
打架厲害 You may know how to fight,
跳舞不一定厲害喔 but not necessarily know how to dance.
去啦，輸人不輸陣 It's your turn.
媽勒，我又不會跳舞 I don't know how.
你就跟體操一樣翻來翻去 Just as you do gymnastics.
去啦 Go.
他是我兄弟啊 He's my buddy.
阿信 Ashin.
這我兄弟啦 This is my buddy.
怎樣 So?
不要吵 Quiet.
老大，讓他難看 Boss, show him what you got.
老大，跟他拼了 Boss, beat him.
來啊 Come on.
誒小心喔 Watch out.
拜拜 Bye.
阿信我一定要讓他死 I will definitely kill Ashin.
老大 Boss,
其實你跳的不錯啊 you weren't so bad, actually.
只是那個後空翻 You just need to
還要再練一下 work on that somersault.
喝酒啦 Shut up and drink.
跳到肚子餓囉 Got hungry after dancing?
來吃麪喔 You're here for noodles?
坐啊 Have a seat.
沒有啦 Well
你那邊還有嗎 Do you have more?
有啊 Of course.
叫多少都算我的 Order all you want and it's my treat.
不要這樣啦 Come on.
不然～ How about
我跟你買 I buy from you?
你要買喔 You want to buy from me?
你不是很厲害 I thought you know your ways around.
你爸我不爽賣 I don't want to sell itto you.
怎樣 What?
你不爽喔 Are you angry?
不然你去找你朋友阿信啊 Why not ask Ashin for help?
木瓜老大 Mr. Papaya,
對不起啦 Sorry
阿信他不是故意的 Ashin didn't mean to embarrass you.
你不要跟他計較啦 Please don't be angry with him.
對不起 Sorry.
叫他來 Get him here.
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
648168168
林先生您好 Hi, Mr. Lin.
您有一則新留言 You have one new message.
菜脯約您一起吃宵夜 From Pickle: night snack together.
嗯 Okay.
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
我啦 It's me,
阿信啦 Ashin.
還在生氣喔 Are you still mad at me?
氣那麼久喔 It's been a while
不要氣了啦 Don't be mad.
我沒有啊 I am not.
沒有 No?
真的沒有 Are you sure?
今天很難得嘛 It's kind of rare that
不是去打架是去吃宵夜啊 You're going for snack instead a fight tonight.
對啊 Yeah.
你幾點下班 When you are off duty?
我來接你 I'll pick you up and
一起吃宵夜啊 we can have snack together.
很抱歉 Sorry,
我們公司有規定 We are not allowed
喔～ Come on.
你很難約耶 You're hard to get.
真正有影 What the hell
誒，看一下窗外 Look out from your window.
看一下看一下 Take a look.
我在你公司樓下 I'm downstairs by your office.
誒那是誰啊 Who is that?
我是阿信～ I am Ashin.
跟我約會吧 Let's go out together.
他是來找誰的啊 Who is he looking for?
都收攤了 Snack my ass,
還叫我來吃麪 the noodle stall is closed?
真正有影 What the hell.
菜脯～ Pickle?
菜脯？ Pickle?
在這邊啦 Here.
連你也肚子餓了喔 So you are hungry, too? Huh?
我跟你說過嘛 I told you, right?
交朋友不是比較好 Isn't it better if we are friends?
老大 Boss.
老大～ Boss.
怎麼會這樣 How could this happen?
老大 Boss.
你有沒有怎麼樣 Are you alright?
老大， 怎麼辦 Boss.
走 Go!
該怎麼辦 Do something
慘了 Damn
走 Go!
快走 Hurry up!
開門 Open the door.
急救箱 First aid kit!
哥，你怎麼啦 Brother, what's wrong?
急救箱啊 First aid kit!
快一點 Hurry up!
碘酒 Iodine.
繃帶 Bandage.
啊是怎麼了 What's going on?
你怎麼全身都是血 Why are you covered in blood?
是發生什麼事情你說啊 What happened?
到底怎樣，你快說啊 Tell me! Tell me what happened!
要說什麼 Tell you what?
人都死了 Someone died!
是要說什麼 What can I say?
哥 Brother,
你到底怎麼了 what happened to you?
跑路 I have to run away.
爲什麼 Why?
有時候你不找麻煩 Sometimes trouble finds you
麻煩也會找上你 even when you're not looking for it.
阿信 Ashin.
這個帶着 Take this with you.
沒錢是要怎麼跑路 You can't run away without money.
等一下 Wait.
來不及了 We don't have time.
等一下啦 Wait a second.
這個玉鐲你也帶着 Take this jade bracelet, too.
快走快走 Go! Hurry!
快走 Hurry up!
走遠一點 Go as far as you can.
快走遠一點 Just go.
菜脯 Pickle,
對不起 I am sorry.
阿信 Ashin,
你哥呢 Where's your brother?
不知道啦 I don't know.
再問你一次 Let me ask you again,
你哥咧 where's your brother?
就不知道嘛 I said I don't know.
有種喔 You think you have guts.
給我打 Beat him.
再囂張嘛 How about now?
再囂張啊 And now?
這是什麼 What's this?
巧克力喔 Chocolate?
還我啦 Give it back to me.
不還你啦！怎樣 Hell, no!
來拿啊 Come get it.
還我 Give it back to me.
怎樣，不還啦！怎樣 What? What are you gonna do?
老大，你有沒有怎樣 Boss, are you okay?
鼻子流血了啦 My nose is bleeding.
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
758168168
阿信 Ashin,
你你還好嗎 are you okay?
給我的留言應該都很嚇人吧 My messages are frightening, right?
快 Yes.
我只有投一塊錢 Hurry up, I only put in a dollar.
好 Okay.
610說他們老大黑松已經對你 610 said the big boss Pine ordered
下了追殺令 to kill you.
你逃不掉的 You cannot escape.
下一個 Next.
742留言說他有請他大哥幫你喬 742 said his boss tried to put in good words for you,
但是他大哥也被打了 but his boss was also thrashed.
現在其他人都不敢幫你喬 No one dares to say anything anymore.
還有呢 What else?
你弟弟小賢留言 Your little Brother Xian said
說他不怕麻煩了 he is not afraid of trouble now.
要你好好照顧自己 And you take care of yourself.
還有其他留言嗎 Anything else?
阿信 Ashin
599留言 A message from 599,
要你有耐心 you have to be patient.
一定會有出路的 There'll be a way out.
599?
誰啊 Who is it?
喂～ Hello?
菜脯 Pickle,
菜脯 Pickle.
起來啦 Time to get up.
不要吵 Leave me alone.
你不是三天不睡 You either stay up for three days
就是一次睡三天 or you sleep for three days.
你是豬喔 Are you a pig?
吃飯了啦 It's time to eat.
你去哪裏 Where did you go?
找工作啊 Looking for a job.
不然吃什麼 Or how do we feed ourselves?
你那邊有沒有錢 Do you have more money?
先借我一點啦 Lend me some.
沒有啦 I have nothing.
哪來的錢 Where do I come up with any money?
你買便當還有剩嗎 Anything left after you bought the lunchbox?
先借我一點啦 Lend me some.
沒有啦 I said no.
給你去買安喔 So you can buy amphetamine?
我們不是兄弟嗎 I thought we're buddies.
我們是兄弟勒 We're buddies!
你看我這麼難過 You enjoy seeing me
你會爽喔 as painful as this?
先借我一點啦 Just lend me some money.
吃不吃啦 You want this or not?
好 Fine.
你不吃是不是 You don't want to eat?
以後什麼都不要吃啦 Don't you eat a damn thing then.
你生氣了喔 Are you angry?
阿信 Ashin.
你不要生氣啦 Don't be angry.
不要生氣啦 Don't be angry.
我吃啦 I'll eat.
你不要生氣啦 Don't be angry.
我們會這樣 We are here like this
還不都是爲了你 all because of you.
我們是兄弟勒 We're buddies.
都不要讓我買到 Better not let me buy the drug ever.
林家祖先 The ancestors of the Lin family,
你要保佑阿信 please bless Ashin.
在外面要會想 Let him know what is right
要自己照顧自己 and be able to take care of himself.
你要保佑他平安啊 Please bless him to be safe.
老大 Boss,
坤大說 Master Kun said,
這次不管喝多少都算他的 whatever we drink today,
今天他特別招待我們 it's on him.
招待 It's a special offer.
招待個屁啊 Special offer my ass.
招待 I don't care.
這間店遲早我會把它收起來 I'll take over this place sooner or later.
是不會叫老闆喔 Don't you know how to greet us?
新來的 You're new to here?
嗯 Hum.
謝謝 Thank you.
媽咧 Shit.
認真一點啦 Be serious.
啥小啦 What the fuck.
少爺 Waiter.
桌面是不會整理一下喔 Come clean the fucking table.
你耳聾囉 Are you deaf?
你是想怎樣 What the fuck?
抱歉，抱歉 Sorry, sorry.
怎樣 What?
大哥，抱歉 Sorry, boss.
你別跟他計較 Please forgive him.
你要挺他嗎 You want to stand up for him?
你要挺他嗎 Do you want to stand up for him?
找死喔 Damn! You're dead.
老大 Boss,
抱歉啦 I'm sorry.
菜脯 Pickle.
這樣可以嗎 Is this okay?
你頭殼壞了 You're god damn nuts.
不行喔 Not enough?
這樣應該可以了吧 How about this?
菜脯 Pickle.
現在是吵夠了沒 Enough!
菜脯 Pickle,
你幹什麼啦 what are you doing?
瘋牛 Mad Ox.
你還真愛到處亂玩喔 You do like to jab around.
玩到我店裏來了 Now you're having fun in my place.
坤大 Master Kun,
你店裏什麼時候玩這麼刺激 I don't know when your joint
我怎麼不知道 has become such an exciting place.
有飯大家吃啦 There are enough for everyone.
你都不怕吃太快 But, if you want to grab them all,
把碗都給砸了 you might break the bowl.
大家都沒飯吃喔 Nothing will be left in the end.
我們年輕人就是要吃你 We are young and we want to grab.
不然你想怎樣 Any problem?
那現在都見血了 Now someone has bled.
你還想怎樣 What else do you want?
坤哥都這樣說了 Well, since Master Kun said so
帶他去看醫生 Take him to the doctor.
坤大，謝謝 Master Kun, thank you.
給你死 You're dead.
你還跑 Now you're running
還跑 Still running
好啊 Great
你還跑 Still running
跑快一點啊 It that your best
你要去哪裏啊 Where're you going?
你爸送你去啦 I'll take you son of bitch there.
把瘋牛處理掉 If you can get rid of Mad Ox,
這一百萬就你們的 this one million dollars will be yours.
謝謝坤大 Thank you, Master Kun.
沒有啦 Well,
坤大 Master Kun,
我們 We
沒關係 it's okay.
這件事就當我沒提過 Let's forget about this.
來 Cheers.
菜脯 Pickle,
臺北我住不慣 Taipei is not for me.
不會啊 I feel different.
我感覺很好啊 I am very contented here.
好在哪裏 Contented?
我們來臺北是爲了什麼 Why did we come to Taipei?
不是爲了來作別人小弟 We didn't come here to be someones thugs.
拜託勒 Come on,
怎麼會 what gave you that thought?
我們是什麼 What are we?
紹興酒瓶勒 We're ShaoShing bottles.
有多強啦 You think it's strong?
還不是一樣會破 It can still be shattered.
菜脯 Pickle.
跟我回宜蘭 Let's go back to Yilan.
怎麼回去 How?
你以爲我沒有想過喔 You think I never thought about it?
我們現在回去 If we go back now,
不是被抓去關 we'll either end up in prison
就是被人打死在路邊 or be beaten to death.
那又怎樣 So?
有問題我們可以一起解決啊 We can solve problems together.
就像以前一樣 Just as the old days.
但人是我殺的 It 's me who killed him.
以前是我不夠強 I was not strong enough
所以纔會變成這樣 so we end up like this.
我要留在臺北 I'm staying in Taipei.
你看 You'll see,
我告訴你 I'm telling you
我馬上就會做老大了 I'll become a gangster head soon.
以後發生什麼事情 If anything happens in the future,
換我罩你 it'll be my turn to cover you.
你罩我 You cover me?
你怎麼罩我 How can you cover me?
你幹嘛這樣看我啦 Why are you looking at me like this?
你想要啦我喔 Do you want to kiss me?
喝啦 Just drink some more.
菜脯？菜脯？ Pickle? Pickle?
阿信誒 Ashin,
我跟你說 you see, that night
那天晚上爲了安非他命 I wanted the amphetamine so much,
騙你出來吃麪 that I lied to get you out
害到你被人家打 and you were beaten so badly.
我真的很沒用 I'm such a loser.
對不起 I am sorry.
我不配當你的兄弟 I don't deserve to be your buddy.
你就回去宜蘭好好練體操啦 You shall go back to Yilan and do your gymnastics.
這錢跟玉佩 The money and the jade pendants
拿給我爸爸 are for my dad.
說以後他再也打不到我了 Tell him he can't beat me anymore.
要好好照顧自己 Ask him to take care of himself.
要他記得 Tell him to remember that
他曾經有個老婆和一個兒子 he had a wife and a son.
P.S. P.S.
麪筋如果問起我 If Cheese asked about me,
你就跟她說 tell her, just as the song says:
“ 忘了你， 忘了我” 鈥淔orget you, forget me."
菜脯 Pickle,
再囂張啊 Let's play tougher
起來啊 Get up!
快爬起來啊 Get up, you punk.
走 Let's go.
這樣我就可以回宜蘭了 Now, I can go back to Yilan.
阿信～ Ashin.
菜脯！ Pickle!
菜脯～ Pickle!
你爲什麼就是不聽我的 Why didn't you listen to me?
你不是說你要當老大嗎 You said you'll become the head.
你要罩我的嗎 You said you'll cover me.
菜脯～ Pickle
有留言嗎 Any message?
很多通留言 A lot.
是不是都在幹礁我 All nasty ones?
嗯 Right.
不聽了 Forget it.
你覺得 Do you think
我應該回去嗎 I should go back?
你怎麼那麼喜歡待在這裏啊 Why do you like it here so much?
阿信 Ashin,
你要不要乾脆回來練體操啊 Why don't you just come back to the gymnastic team?
我看你每次打架 You fight
都像成龍一樣翻來翻去 as good as Jackie Chan.
很厲害勒 That is amazing.
你沒看到我的棋在這裏 You didn't see my defense
照吃啦 I'll take you after all
笨象，你這隻笨象 Dumb Knight, I'm taking you down
快點，換你了 Come on, your turn
老大 Boss.
人來了 Here he is.
你還敢來 How dare you to come here?
我來 I'm here,
我來是想解決問題 because I want to solve the problem.
過來 Come here.
再過來一點 Come closer.
你真的不怕死 You're not afraid of death?
老大 Boss,
這小子如果這麼有種 if he is really not afraid of death,
乾脆就完成他的願望啦 we can make his dream come true.
那不然剁他的腳啦 We can cut oh' his legs.
剁手啦 Or the hands.
剁腳剁手 Cut off his legs, hands
連他那個也剁掉拿去喂鱷魚啦 and his dick to feed the crocodile.
你們兩個是那邊爽什麼 You guys are really enjoying this, huh?
阿信 Ashin!
你還敢來 How dare you to come here!
爸～給他死啦 Dad, let's take him out.
少爺 Master.
好了啦 Shut up.
我知道這個死孩子 I know this asshole dealt drugs
偷偷在我背後賣安非他命 behind my back.
我也知道 I also know that
我也知道是他先帶人打你 the whole mess was
纔會發生這一堆有的沒的事 because he beat you in first place.
但是不管怎麼說 Even so, it's the son of mine
今天是我黑松的兒子被打 that was beaten.
這要是傳出去能聽嗎 I can not bear to lose the face.
我問你 Let me ask you,
你明知道我不會放過你 why did you come back
你怎麼還敢回來啊 when you knew I won't be easy on you?
因爲我要翻身 'Cause I want a new start.
我要重新練體操 I want to go back to gymnastics.
體操 Gymnastics?
你是說那種翻來翻去的體操嗎 That jumping and rolling thing?
等一下就沒手沒腳了 You'll lose your hands and legs soon,
我看你要怎麼翻 I would love to see you roll
閉嘴啦 Shut up.
好 Nice,
練體操 gymnastics.
我給你一年的時間 I will give you a year.
一年內 You have to win a gold medal
你一定要給我拿到金牌 within one year.
要不然就不是在這池 If not, you won't be bathing in this one
而是在隔壁那池 but that one.
來 Hey,
集合 assemble here.
你們是從小 You're hand-picked gymnasts
就挑選出來的選手 since you were kids.
在這個中間 Over times,
也有很多人選擇離開 many chose to leave.
既然你們選擇留下 For those who chose to stay,
就請你們尊重你們自己的選擇 please respect your own choice,
也尊重這項運動 and respect this sport.
阿信 Ashin.
一二 One, two.
高一點喔 Higher.
一 One.
頂住 Hold it.
二 Two.
阿伯 Old man,
還可以吧 are you okay?
別吵 Shut up!
一二三四五六七八九十 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10.
快 Go, sprint!
衝刺衝刺喔 I said sprint!
該戒菸了吧 Time to quit smoking.
我看你這個體能啊 You're not capable of
你還不能練單項 practicing individual event yet.
來來來，起來起來起來 Get up from there.
先去給我跑操場 Go to run on the field first.
老大 Boss,
我看他差不多了 He looks exhausted.
來～來～ Let' go.
阿信 Ashin,
你爸我這次一定要給你死啊 I'll kill you this time.
有膽別跑啊 Don't go! Go to hell!
你不是很帶種 Where did you put your balls?
有膽別跑啊 Why don't you stop and fight?
謝謝你願意原諒阿信 Thank you for giving Ashin a chance.
你不要跑那麼快啦 Don't run so fast.
有一半理由是因爲你 Half the reason is of you,
另一半是因爲他自己 the other half is of he himself.
這小子個性有夠強 He is a really stubborn young man.
他的個性跟你年輕的時候很像勒 He's quite like the younger you.
像我 Me?
你也看一下 Come on.
我的體能比他好太多了吧 I'm much stronger than he is.
對啦 Yeah.
那個時候你是隊上最強的 You were the best among the team.
唉～ Alas.
強有什麼用 Strong? So what?
還不是要吃飯拉屎 You still need to eat and shit.
這小子有心想要練 He does want to do gymnastics.
你覺得他有希望嗎 Do you think he has prospects?
年底有個國際體操邀請賽 There is an international game at the end of the year.
我也沒把握他能不能上場比賽 I am not sure if he can make it.
你是教練勒 You're the coach!
這種話你也說的出來 You shouldn't say this.
好好給我操一下 Train him seriously.
不要給我漏氣喔 Don't you lose my face.
你是流氓勒 Come on, you're a gang master.
我哪敢給你漏氣喔 How would I dare to lose your face?
好啦好啦 Fine.
不要說這個啦 Quit it.
誒你看 Look
從現在我不會再逃避 I will not run away anymore
重新的喚起 Face the calling
埋藏在我心底的血液 the blood running deep within my heart.
沉住氣 Stay focused.
我的，心不再移 I will not be astray again.
屏息不放棄 Hold my breath, never give up.
慢慢的 Slowly,
朝着我的夢前進 I walk toward my dream.
忘了吧 Forget it.
混亂的事不再提 Don't mention the mess.
放了吧 Let it go.
把心思變唯一 Focus on one thing only.
我會用盡所有力 I'll do my best.
奮力的躍起在天際 Leap as high as the sky.
迎着光明 Toward the brightest.
我會更用力呼吸 I'll breath harder.
飛到另一個燦爛天空 Fly into another brilliant sky.
完美 Perfect.
落地 Landing.
阿信 Ashin
阿信 Ashin.
你過來一下 Come here.
教練 Coach.
把手放上來 Put your hand here.
撫摸它 Touch it.
把它想像成是一匹真的馬 Think of it as a real horse.
撫摸它的毛 Stroke its hair.
跟它說話 Talk to it:
感謝你 Thank you.
因爲有你 We can do this sport
我們才能從事這項運動 only because of you.
教練 Coach,
你在幹嘛 what are you doing?
跟它說話啊 Talking to it.
男子體操啊 Man gymnastics events are:
地板、鞍馬、 吊環 Floor Exercise, Pommel Horse, Still Rings
跳馬、 雙槓、 單槓 Vault, Parallel Bars, Horizontal bar
這六個項目 Six in total.
全都是冰冷的器材 They are all performed on cold facilities.
如果你沒有熱情 If you don't learn to feel them,
如果你不跟它建立關係 don't build relationships with them,
你就永遠無法控制你的恐懼 you can never overcome your fears to them.
運用你的想像力 So, use your imagination.
跟它說話 Talk to it.
懂了嗎 Get it?
所以你跟教練兩個人 So you and the coach have stroked
就站在那裏摸跳馬摸十分鐘喔 the vault for an entire 10 minutes?
對啊 Yeah.
很好笑喔 It is funny, isn't it?
不會呀 No.
把跳馬當成活的 Does it make you feel better
有讓你感覺比較好嗎 when thinking it as something alive?
好像是有點用啦 Kind of.
但我覺得最大的問題 But my biggest problem
還是在我自己身上 comes from myself.
如果沒辦法克服我的左腿 If I don't overcome my left leg,
很難會有好成績 I can never get a good result.
阿信 Ashin.
嗯 What?
其實我很羨慕你是個體操選手 Actually, I envy you because you're a gymnast.
是喔 Oh yeah?
嗯 Yes.
我曾經是個游泳選手 I was a swimmer.
媽勒 Holy crap!
真的假的 Really?
那你穿泳衣一定很好看哦 You must look great in swimming suit.
喂 Hey,
人家很認真耶 I'm serious.
好啦好啦 Fine.
那你還有在遊嗎 Do you still swim?
不遊了 Not anymore.
爲什麼 Why?
阿信 Ashin.
你要堅持下去 You must hang on.
你不光是爲了自己奮鬥 You fight not only for yourself
也是替那些曾經有夢想的人奮鬥 but for those who had dreams.
喔～ 對了 One more thing.
有一通599的留言 You have a message from 599.
她說 She said:
加油 Go for it!
我知道了 I got it.
哥 Brother,
爸快要死了 dad is dying.
媽叫我們回去幫他換衣服 Mom wants us to go home and change dad's clothes.
爸 Dad?
哥，你在幹嘛 Brother, what are you doing?
阿爸有說過 Dad said, if you feel like crying
想哭的時候就倒立 you can do handstand.
這樣眼淚就不會流下來了 So the tears won't fall down.
對啊 This is it!
把不夠的補滿 Add to what is needed.
把不足的長度補齊 Fill the short one to the right length.
很感謝你 Thank you for taking care of Ashin
阿信住這邊都託你照顧 while he's staying here.
不要這樣說 Never mind.
事情有解決就好 As long as the problems are solved.
阿信喔 Ashin
你來幹嘛 What are you doing here?
爲什麼你就是不讓我練體操啊 Why cant you just let me do gymnastics?
你把我害的還不夠慘嗎 You want to see me live in hell again?
阿信 Ashin
爲什麼你連讓我重新作人的機會 Why do you want to deprive me
都不給我 of the chance to have a new life?
我就一定得回去賣水果 You want me to sell fruit again?
我的人生是我在過的 This is my life,
不是你 not yours.
林太太 Mrs. Lin Mrs. Lin
教練 Coach,
不管我媽怎麼說 no matter what my mom said,
我這次絕對不會退出體操隊 I will not leave the team this time.
這雙鞋你先拿着 Hold the shoes first.
這雙鞋的左腳 The left one has special pad and sole
有特製加厚的鞋墊與鞋底 with just the right thickness.
長度剛好可以讓你的兩條腿 So the lengths of your legs
變得一樣長 can become even.
我想了很久了 I thought about this for a long time.
這是唯一可以解決你長短腿的辦法 It's the only solution to your legs.
謝謝教練 Thank you, coach.
你不用謝我 Not me,
要謝啊 If there's anyone to thank,
謝你媽 it's your mom.
你知道你小時候得過小兒麻痹嗎 Do you know you had Polio?
你媽一直爲這件事情很自責 She has been blaming herself for it.
她說是她沒有把你照顧好 She said it's her fault that
所以才讓你生病 led to your illness.
還好她從小 Thanks to her massaging your leg everyday
就每天幫你按摩你的腳 since you were a kid,
要不然你的左腳 or your left leg would wither
會萎縮的比現在更嚴重 even more seriously than it is now.
你懂了嗎 Do you get it?
不要動啦 Don't move.
媽，爲什麼你要按哥哥的腳啊 Mom, why are you massaging Brother's leg?
就是這樣經常按經常推 The constant massage
哥哥纔會長大啊 can make your brother grow up.
好吃的來囉 Here comes the good one.
媽 Mom,
這是什麼 what's this?
吃腿補腿啊 Eat legs for better legs.
你快要比賽了啊 Your game is coming.
吃這個田雞腿比較會跳 Frog legs can help you jump higher.
媽 Mom
我不用比賽 I am not competing,
我不用吃 so I don't have to eat.
你小時候不是最會吵 You used to say that
吵着要長大 you want to be a grown-up.
就要吃這個纔會長大 Eat this so you can be a grown-up.
知道嗎 See?
我不要吃啦 I don't want to.
吃啦 趕快吃啦 Eat it.
不要弄你弟弟啦 Don't tease your younger brother.
媽 Mom
沒辦法啊 I can't help you
你哥哥都喜歡欺負你 Your older brother has been fond of teasing you
阿爸 Dad, please bless me
你要保佑我這個月考試一百分 to get A+ in my test this month,
然後媽媽身體健康 and mom to be healthy,
還有哥哥拿到跳馬金牌 and brother to win the Vault Gold Medal.
不要一次跟你爸求那麼多啦 Don't make so many wishes.
你要把他累死喔 Your dad will be exhausted.
這我來就好 I'll take care of them.
給他死啦 Kill them.
來～ 衝刺喔衝刺喔 Come on, sprint. Sprint!
衝刺喔 Sprint!
水啦 Nice!
各位先生女士 Ladies and gentlemen,
歡迎蒞臨1994年國際體操邀請賽 Welcome to 1994 international invitation gymnastics competition.
讓我們用最熱烈的掌聲歡迎 Let's give our warmest welcome
男子組跳馬個人總決賽選手進場 to the finalists of Vault Event.
媽，這是你第一次來看哥哥比賽 Mom, it's your first time to see brother's game.
對啊 Yeah.
好多人啊 There're so many people.
你哥在哪 Where's your brother?
在那邊，在那邊 Over there.
阿爸 Dad,
阿信在那裏 Ashin's there.
你把我擋住了 You're in my way.
我怎麼看 I can't see.
在哪 Where is he?
第一位登場的選手是 Our first contestant is from
中華臺北何正樹 Chinese Taipei, Ho Zheng-Shu.
水啦 Nice!
水喔 Nice!
9.5 You got 9.5.
現在恭喜還太早 It's too early to congratulate me.
你還沒有跳 You haven鈥檛 jumped yet.
我又不一定贏得了你 I don't think I can get higher point than you.
我現在終於知道 I finally know that
要嬴別人很容易 it's easy to surpass others.
最難的是嬴自己 What's difficult is to top oneself.
站在選手立場 As a contestant,
我不希望你嬴 I don't want you to win.
但站在朋友立場 But as a friend, I hope
我希望你嬴 you have the best performance.
華生電信您好 This is Huasheng Telecom.
請問您的CALL機密碼是 May I have your pager password?
1289168168
你是 You're not
之前那位電話祕書咧 What happen to the previous girl?
您說599嗎 You mean 599?
她離職囉 She has quit.
1294599599
請問您是林先生嗎 Are you Mr. Lin?
我是 Yes, I am.
599有留言給您 599 left you a message.
請問您要聽嗎 Do you want to hear it?
好 Yes.
阿信 Ashin,
很高興認識你 it's nice to know you.
因爲你 Because of you
我才下定決心辭職 I made up my mind to quit my job.
我對你有很深的期待 I have great expectation about you.
你不只是爲了自己奮鬥 You fight not only for yourself,
也是替那些曾經有夢想的人奮鬥 but for those who once had dreams.
你還記不記得 Do you still remember
599曾經留言給你 that message from 599?
她說 She said:
如果你還有夢 If you still have a dream,
就該勇敢去追 then go for it bravely.
我記得 I remember.
嗯 Yes.
599也要勇敢去追夢了 599 is going after her dream now.
加油 Go for it.
接下來登場的是中華臺北選手 林育信 The next contestant is from Chinese Taipei, Lin Yu-shin.
阿信 Ashin!
啥款  What's up?
1978 Ashin with his dad and younger brother.
1980 Ashin learnt gymnastic leg-lift.
1983 Ashin won the first Vault Gold Medal.
1987 Ashin became a gangster.
1994 Like a black horse, as soon as Ashin returned to gymnastic world,
he won the National Golden Medal in Vault and Floor Exercise.
啥款 How's that?
眼睛不用張那麼大 Don't be so surprised.
千真萬確 Don't doubt,
這個人就是我 that's me.
原來交朋友是這種感覺 So that's what friends are like.
誒那你球棒可以還我嗎 Can I have my bat back?
誒你要不要跳啊 Are you going to jump or not?
站在那邊站那麼久 You've been standing there for so long.
你練那麼久 You've practiced for so long.
還沒準備好喔 Aren't you ready for this?
還沒～ Not yet.
體操選手不是隨時都要準備好嗎 Gymnast should always be ready.
不管什麼時候都可以上 You can do your moves at anytime.
你忘記了嗎 Don't you remember?
衝過來 Come on.
加油 Go for this!
加油 Go!
啊 Ah!
哥，快來救我啦 Brother, come to help me!
哥，快來啦 Brother, hurry up!
哥 Brother!