快 一點 啦 今天 大日子 耶
kuài  yī diǎn  la  jīn tiān  dà rì zi  yé
quick  a little  la  today  big day  ye
Hurry up, it's a big day.
你 想 讓 新娘子 等 你 一個人 喔
nǐ  xiǎng  ràng  xīn niáng zi  děng  nǐ  yī gè rén  ō
you  think  allow  bride  wait  you  A person  oh
You don't want to make the bride wait for you, do you?
老闆 一樣
lǎo bǎn  yī yàng
boss  same
The usual, boss.
錢 一樣 跟 我 媽 算
qián  yī yàng  gēn  wǒ  mā  suàn
money  same  with  I  mother  count
Put it on my mom's tab.
好 ok
hǎo  ok
good  ok
All right, no problem
1994 年
1994  nián
1994  year
那一 年 我 十六歲
nà yī  nián  wǒ  shí liù suì
That one  year  I  Sixteen years old
I was 16 that year
張雨生 的 歌聲 還 在
zhāng yǔ shēng  de  gē shēng  hái  zài
Chang Yu-Sheng  of  singing  still  in
Chang Yu-Sheng's voice was still heard on TV shows.
張學友 的 「 吻別 」 大 賣了 一百多萬 張卡帶
zhāng xué yǒu  de  「  wěn bié  」  dà  mài le  yī bǎi duō wàn  zhāng kǎ dài
Jacky Cheung  of  「  KissGoodbye  」  big  sold  more than one million  cassettes
Jacky Cheung sold more than one million cassettes for the "KissGoodbye" album.
組頭 還沒 開始 看 中華職棒
zǔ tóu  hái méi  kāi shǐ  kàn  zhōng huá zhí bàng
bookie  not yet  Start  look  CPBL
The bookies hadn't started watching CPBL
經典 的 龍 象 大戰 總是 滿場
jīng diǎn  de  lóng  xiàng  dà zhàn  zǒng shì  mǎn chǎng
classic  of  dragon  elephant  War  always  sold out
and the classic Dragon-Elephant games were always sold out.
那 年
nà  nián
that  year
That year
有 一個 皮膚 黑黑 的 女生 五度五關 ( 張惠妹 )
yǒu  yī gè  pí fū  hēi hēi  de  nǚ shēng  wǔ dù wǔ guān  (  zhāng huì mèi  )
have  One  skin  black  of  Girls  Five Lights Award  (  Chang Hui-mei  )
a girl with tanned skin won the championship on the local talent show
贏得 了 五 燈獎 的 冠軍
yíng dé  le  wǔ  dēng jiǎng  de  guān jūn
win  is  five  lights  of  champion
for five consecutive rounds.
那一 年 …
nà yī  nián  …
That one  year  …
That year...
那些 年
nà xiē  nián
those  year
Those years.
我 叫 柯景騰
wǒ  jiào  kē jǐng téng
I  call  Ko Ching-Teng
My name is Ko Ching-Teng.
同學 都 叫 我 柯騰
tóng xué  dōu  jiào  wǒ  kē téng
classmate  all  call  I  Ko-Teng
My friends called me Ko-Teng
我 國中 念 的 是 彰化 市 精誠 中學
wǒ  guó zhōng  niàn  de  shì  zhāng huà  shì  jīng chéng  zhōng xué
I  secondary  study  of  is  Changhua  city  Jingcheng  junior high
I went to Jingcheng in Changhua City for junior high school.
高中 念 的 也 是 精誠 中學
gāo zhōng  niàn  de  yě  shì  jīng chéng  zhōng xué
high school  study  of  also  is  Jingcheng  junior high
As for high school, I stuck to the same one, too.
這 是 許博淳
zhè  shì  xǔ bó chún
this  is  Hsu Bo-Chun
This is Hsu Bo-Chun.
從 國中 起 就是 我 最好 的 朋友
cóng  guó zhōng  qǐ  jiù shì  wǒ  zuì hǎo  de  péng yǒu
from  secondary  onward  is  I  best  of  friend
He has been my best friend since junior high school.
許博淳 隨時隨地 都 在 勃起
xǔ bó chún  suí shí suí dì  dōu  zài  bó qǐ
Hsu Bo-Chun  Anytime  all  in  boner
He's always getting a boner
所以 外 號 叫 「 勃起 」
suǒ yǐ  wài  hào  jiào  「  bó qǐ  」
and so  out  day  call  「  boner  」
that's why we named him "Boner".
幹
gàn
fuck
Fuck!
幹 三小
gàn  sān xiǎo
fuck  3 am
Fuck what?
死 柯騰 別 跑
sǐ  kē téng  bié  pǎo
die  Ko-Teng  don't  run
You are dead meat. Don't run.
這 是 阿和
zhè  shì  ā hé
this  is  A-Ho
This is A-Ho.
我們 從 國小 就 一直 同 班 到 高中
wǒ men  cóng  guó xiǎo  jiù  yī zhí  tóng  bān  dào  gāo zhōng
us  from  elementary school  just  Always  same  class  to  high school
We have been in the same class all the way from elementary to high school.
每一個 故事 都 有 一個 胖子
měi yī gè  gù shì  dōu  yǒu  yī gè  pàng zi
every  story  all  have  One  fat guy
There is a fat guy in every story.
阿和 就是 那一 個 胖子
ā hé  jiù shì  nà yī  ge  pàng zi
A-Ho  is  That one  piece  fat guy
A-Ho is the fat guy in our story.
你們 很 煩 耶
nǐ men  hěn  fán  yé
you  very  bother  ye
Stop bugging me.
剛剛 好啦
gāng gāng  hǎo la
just  Okay
Why not?
教官 早
jiào guān  zǎo
Instructor  early
Good morning, Sir.
早
zǎo
early
Good morning.
教官 早
jiào guān  zǎo
Instructor  early
Good morning, Sir.
早
zǎo
early
Good morning.
教官 早
jiào guān  zǎo
Instructor  early
Good morning, Sir.
教官 早
jiào guān  zǎo
Instructor  early
Good morning, Sir.
早
zǎo
early
Good morning.
教官 早
jiào guān  zǎo
Instructor  early
Good morning, Sir.
頭髮 太 長 囉
tóu fà  tài  chǎng  luō
hair  very  long  eh
Your hair is too long.
該 剪 的 要 剪 一 剪 了
gāi  jiǎn  de  yào  jiǎn  yī  jiǎn  le
should  scissors  of  want  scissors  one  scissors  is
It's time to get a haircut.
你 不要 每天 都 這樣 好不好
nǐ  bù yào  měi tiān  dōu  zhè yàng  hǎo bù hǎo
you  Do not  every day  all  such  ok
Gosh, can you stop that?
怎樣
zěn yàng
how
What?
不要 每次 都 從 後面 嚇 人 啊
bù yào  měi cì  dōu  cóng  hòu miàn  xià  rén  a
Do not  Each  all  from  Behind  scare  man  ah
Stop doing that
跟 你 講 幾次 了
gēn  nǐ  jiǎng  jǐ cì  le
with  you  speak  several times  is
I have told you a million times!
所以 咧
suǒ yǐ  liě
and so  frown
Why not?
很 浪費 啊
hěn  làng fèi  a
very  waste  ah
You totally wasted my food
我 熱狗 只吃 一 口
wǒ  rè gǒu  zhǐ chī  yī  kǒu
I  hot dog  Eat only  one  mouth
I only had one bite of that hotdog.
所以
suǒ yǐ
and so
So...
啊 你 是 不會 接 喔
a  nǐ  shì  bù huì  jiē  ō
ah  you  is  will not  then  oh
Don't you know how to catch?
曹 雞巴
cáo  jī bā
Tsao  cock
Cock Tsao.
一大 早就 那麼 雞巴
yī dà  zǎo jiù  nà me  jī bā
A big one  Long ago  like that  cock
Why are you such a jackass in the morning.
我 跟 你 說
wǒ  gēn  nǐ  shuō
I  with  you  say
You know what?
昨天 我 抽 到 Grant Hill 1: 40 的 限定 卡
zuó tiān  wǒ  chōu  dào  Grant  Hill  1:  40  de  xiàn dìng  kǎ
yesterday  I  sprout  to  Grant  Hill  1:  40  of  limited  card
I won a Grant Hill 1 to 40 limited edition card yesterday.
這 是 老曹
zhè  shì  lǎo cáo
this  is  Tsao
This is Tsao.
老曹 從 國中 跟 我 同 班 就是 一個 很 雞巴 的 人
lǎo cáo  cóng  guó zhōng  gēn  wǒ  tóng  bān  jiù shì  yī gè  hěn  jī bā  de  rén
Tsao  from  secondary  with  I  same  class  is  One  very  cock  of  man
We have been classmates ever since junior high and he has always been an ass.
所以 有 時候 我 會叫 老曹
suǒ yǐ  yǒu  shí hou  wǒ  huì jiào  lǎo cáo
and so  have  time  I  Will be called  Tsao
We called him.
(Cock, Cocky, Dumbass Tsao or "Tsao motherfucker")
這麼 雞巴
zhè me  jī bā
so  cock
Show off?
不然 你 拿 你 1: 100 的 Penny Hardaway 來換
bù rán  nǐ  ná  nǐ  1:  100  de  Penny  Hardaway  lái huàn
otherwise  you  take  you  1:  100  of  Penny  Hardaway  To change
We can switch then for your 1 to 100 Penny Hardaway cards.
我 才不 要 咧
wǒ  cái bù  yào  liě
I  never  want  frown
No way!
不要 不要 還 來
bù yào  bù yào  hái  lái
Do not  Do not  still  come
Piss off, then.
我 這 幾個 好 朋友 唯 一 的 共通點
wǒ  zhè  jǐ gè  hǎo  péng yǒu  wéi  yī  de  gòng tōng diǎn
I  this  several  good  friend  only  one  of  common point
The only thing that these boys shared in common with...
就是 喜歡 班 上 最 乖 的 好 學生
jiù shì  xǐ huan  bān  shàng  zuì  guāi  de  hǎo  xué shēng
is  like  class  on  most  good  of  good  student
was that they all had a crush on the honor student in the class.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
在 我 看起來
zài  wǒ  kàn qǐ lái
in  I  Looks like
From my point of view.
沈佳宜 只是 比 一般 的 女生 還要 再 漂亮 一點點 而已
chén jiā yí  zhǐ shì  bǐ  yī bān  de  nǚ shēng  hái yào  zài  piào liang  yī diǎn diǎn  ér yǐ
Shen Chia-Yi  just  than  general  of  Girls  But also  again  Pretty  a little bit  Just now
Shen Chia-Yi was only slightly prettier than the other girls.
真 搞 不懂
zhēn  gǎo  bù dǒng
real  clear  Do not understand
Don't know what the guys were thinking.
欸 沈佳宜
āi  chén jiā yí
sigh  Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
Yes?
妳 昨天 有 看 玫瑰 之夜 嗎
nǐ  zuó tiān  yǒu  kàn  méi guī  zhī yè  ma
you  yesterday  have  look  rose  night of  ?
Did you watch Rose Night yesterday?
妳 說 那個 太極 峽谷 的 那個 照片 啊
nǐ  shuō  nà gè  tài jí  xiá gǔ  de  nà gè  zhào piàn  a
you  say  that one  Taichi  canyon  of  that one  photo  ah
Are you talking about the Taichi Gorge photo?
對 呀 我 覺得 超 可怕 的
duì  ya  wǒ  jué de  chāo  kě pà  de
to  yeah  I  feel  super  terrible  of
Yeah, the picture was horrifying
而且 我 全身 都 起 雞皮疙瘩 了
ér qiě  wǒ  quán shēn  dōu  qǐ  jī pí gē da  le
and  I  whole body  all  onward  goose bumps  is
I got goose bumps all over.
那個 故事 聽起來 很 可怕
nà gè  gù shì  tīng qǐ lái  hěn  kě pà
that one  story  sound  very  terrible
The story sounds terrifying but...
可是 那 張照片 我 看 不太 出來 耶
kě shì  nà  zhāng zhào piàn  wǒ  kàn  bù tài  chū lái  yé
but  that  a photograph  I  look  Not too much  come out  ye
I can't really tell from the picture though
我 覺得 只是 拍攝 角度 的 問題
wǒ  jué de  zhǐ shì  pāi shè  jiǎo dù  de  wèn tí
I  feel  just  shoot  angle  of  problem
I think it was the shooting angle that does the trick.
真的 嗎
zhēn de  ma
Really  ?
You think so?
第五 課 跟 第六 課 的 考卷
dì wǔ  kè  gēn  dì liù  kè  de  kǎo juǎn
fifth  lesson  with  sixth  lesson  of  Test paper
Now, start doing the exercises for lesson five and six.
寫 不完 的 升旗 後 繼續 寫
xiě  bù wán  de  shēng qí  hòu  jì xù  xiě
write  Not finished  of  assembly  after  carry on  write
Continue after the assembly if you can't finish.
自己 寫 自己 的
zì jǐ  xiě  zì jǐ  de
self  write  self  of
Focus on your own exercises.
不可以 討論
bù kě yǐ  tǎo lùn
Can not  discuss
No discussion.
這 是 廖英宏
zhè  shì  liào yīng hóng
this  is  Liao Ying-Hung
This is Liao Ying-Hung.
廖 這個 姓
liào  zhè ge  xìng
scratch  This one  surname
His surname, Liao, is a verb in Chinese.
是個 動詞
shì gè  dòng cí
Is  verb
And it means to scratch.
既然是 個 動詞
jì rán shì  ge  dòng cí
Since it is  piece  verb
Since it's a verb
就 不能 白白 浪費
jiù  bù néng  bái bái  làng fèi
just  Can not  in vain  waste
we should make good use of this verb.
所以 我們 幫 他 取 了 個 綽號
suǒ yǐ  wǒ men  bāng  tā  qǔ  le  ge  chuò hào
and so  us  help  he  take  is  piece  nickname
Thus, we gave him a nickname.
叫 「 廖該邊 」
jiào  「  liào gāi biān  」
call  「  Groin  」
"Groin" (Scratching Groin)
該邊 當然 也 喜歡 沈佳宜
gāi biān  dāng rán  yě  xǐ huan  chén jiā yí
groin  of course  also  like  Shen Chia-Yi
"Groin" likes Shen Chia-Yi, too.
因為 該邊 喜歡 班 上 每一個 女生
yīn wèi  gāi biān  xǐ huan  bān  shàng  měi yī gè  nǚ shēng
because  groin  like  class  on  every  Girls
That's because he likes every girl in the class.
一大 清早 就 這麼
yī dà  qīng zǎo  jiù  zhè me
A big one  Early in the morning  just  so
It's early morning and everyone looks half asleep.
沒 精神
méi  jīng shén
not  spirit
Stand straight.
還 睡
hái  shuì
still  sleep
Wake up!
站 好
zhàn  hǎo
station  good
Stand straight.
還 動
hái  dòng
still  move
Stop moving.
起立
qǐ lì
stand up
Stand up.
立 正
lì  zhèng
stand  right
Attention.
敬禮
jìng lǐ
salute
Salute.
老師 好
lǎo shī  hǎo
teacher  good
Good morning, Miss Chou.
各位 同學 好 坐下
gè wèi  tóng xué  hǎo  zuò xià
Everybody  classmate  good  sit down
Good morning, everyone. Sit down.
乾隆 丁亥 年
qián lóng  dīng hai  nián
Qianlong  dynasty  year
In year 1974, it was still the Qing dynasty.
也就 在
yě jiù  zài
Also  in
So it means that.
丁亥 年 就 在 我們 乾隆 的 三十 二年
dīng hai  nián  jiù  zài  wǒ men  qián lóng  de  sān shí  èr nián
dynasty  year  just  in  us  Qianlong  of  thirty  Two years
It was the thirty second year that China was ruled under Emperor Qianlong.
其實 高中 跟 國中 差 不了多少
qí shí  gāo zhōng  gēn  guó zhōng  chà  bù liǎo duō shǎo
in fact  high school  with  secondary  different  not much
There was really not that much difference between junior high and senior high.
地獄 十七 層 跟 十六 層 的 差 別 而已
dì yù  shí qī  céng  gēn  shí liù  céng  de  chà  bié  ér yǐ
hell  Seventeen  storey  with  sixteen  storey  of  different  don't  Just now
Just a matter of how deep you are in hell.
唸書 考試 整個 很 無聊
niàn shū  kǎo shì  zhěng gè  hěn  wú liáo
study  test  entire  very  bored
Endless studies, exams... it's all very boring!
有 人物 時間 還有 再來 就是 地點
yǒu  rén wù  shí jiān  hái yǒu  zài lái  jiù shì  dì diǎn
have  character  time  and also  Come again  is  place
There is the character, the time and then it's the place.
那 地點 是 在 哪裡 呢
nà  dì diǎn  shì  zài  nǎ lǐ  ne
that  place  is  in  where  this
Where is the place?
地點 就 在 我們 的 上 元 之 …
dì diǎn  jiù  zài  wǒ men  de  shàng  yuán  zhī  …
place  just  in  us  of  on  first  it  …
The place...
但 想 辦法 找 一點 事 做 就 不會 那麼 無聊 了
dàn  xiǎng  bàn fǎ  zhǎo  yī diǎn  shì  zuò  jiù  bù huì  nà me  wú liáo  le
only  think  Method  search  a little  thing  work  just  will not  like that  bored  is
But, we can always find a way to entertain ourselves!
許博淳
xǔ bó chún
Hsu Bo-Chun
起來 念 下一 段
qǐ lái  niàn  xià yī  duàn
stand up  study  next  section
stand up and read the next section.
站起來 念 啊
zhàn qǐ lái  niàn  a
stand up  study  ah
Stand up and read.
上到 哪一 段 都 不知道
shàng dào  nǎ yī  duàn  dōu  bù zhī dào
on to  Which one  section  all  do not know
You don't even know where we are.
有沒有 在上 課 啊
yǒu méi yǒu  zài shàng  kè  a
do you have  above  lesson  ah
Hello... are you in the classroom.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
你 在 笑 什麼
nǐ  zài  xiào  shén me
you  in  smile  what
what are you laughing at?
你 念
nǐ  niàn
you  study
You read it.
汝 以 一 念 之 貞遇 人 仳離
rǔ  yǐ  yī  niàn  zhī  zhēn yù  rén  pǐ lí
you  thereby  one  study  it  meet in vain  man  separate
(Reading paragraphs from the textbook)
站起來 念
zhàn qǐ lái  niàn
stand up  study
Stand up and read.
不是 很 方便
bù shì  hěn  fāng biàn
not  very  Convenience
It's not very convenient.
什麼 叫做 「 不是 很 方便 」
shén me  jiào zuò  「  bù shì  hěn  fāng biàn  」
what  Called it  「  not  very  Convenience  」
What do you mean "not very convenient"?
站起來
zhàn qǐ lái
stand up
Stand up.
上課 打手槍
shàng kè  dǎ shǒu qiāng
attend class  masturbate
Jerking off.
上課 打手槍
shàng kè  dǎ shǒu qiāng
attend class  masturbate
Jerking off right in the class
我 教書 教 這麼 多年
wǒ  jiào shū  jiào  zhè me  duō nián
I  teach  teach  so  for many years
I have been a teacher for so many years
考試 作弊 的
kǎo shì  zuò bì  de
test  cheat  of
I have seen students who cheat
打架 的
dǎ jià  de
fight  of
get into fights
勒索 同學 的
lè suǒ  tóng xué  de
blackmail  classmate  of
black mail.
甚至 於 想 打 老師 的
shèn zhì  yú  xiǎng  dǎ  lǎo shī  de
even  in  think  hit  teacher  of
Or even those who beat up teachers!
什麼 壞 學生 我 沒 見過
shén me  huài  xué shēng  wǒ  méi  jiàn guò
what  bad  student  I  not  Seen it
I have seen all kinds of problematic students
我 就 沒 見過 像 你們 這樣 變態 的
wǒ  jiù  méi  jiàn guò  xiàng  nǐ men  zhè yàng  biàn tài  de
I  just  not  Seen it  like  you  such  abnormal  of
but just no perverts like you!
又 沒有 射
yòu  méi yǒu  shè
and  No  shoot
I didn't even ejaculate.
你 還說
nǐ  hái shuō
you  Said
And that's an excuse?
對 呀
duì  ya
to  yeah
Yeah.
我們 只是 打好 …
wǒ men  zhǐ shì  dǎ hǎo  …
us  just  Play well  …
We were just fooling around...
你 也 一樣
nǐ  yě  yī yàng
you  also  same
You, too.
你們 父母 花 這麼 多錢 把 你們 送到 學校 來 讀書
nǐ men  fù mǔ  huā  zhè me  duō qián  bǎ  nǐ men  sòng dào  xué xiào  lái  dú shū
you  parents  flower  so  Rich  take  you  Sent to  school  come  reading
Your parents spent so much money to send you to school
你們 不知道 好好 珍惜
nǐ men  bù zhī dào  hǎo hǎo  zhēn xī
you  do not know  Well  Cherish
and you guys don't even cherish how lucky you are.
什麼 是 打手槍 啊
shén me  shì  dǎ shǒu qiāng  a
what  is  masturbate  ah
What's jerk off?
上課 打手槍
shàng kè  dǎ shǒu qiāng
attend class  masturbate
Jerking off in the classroom.
喂
wèi
hey
Hey?
我 不知道 耶
wǒ  bù zhī dào  yé
I  do not know  ye
I don't know.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
你 出來 一下
nǐ  chū lái  yí xià
you  come out  a bit
come out here for a second.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
柯景騰 以後 坐 在 你 前面
kē jǐng téng  yǐ hòu  zuò  zài  nǐ  qián miàn
Ko Ching-Teng  after  sit  in  you  front
from now on, Ko Ching-Teng will sit in front of you.
你 幫 老師 好好 管管 他
nǐ  bāng  lǎo shī  hǎo hǎo  guǎn guǎn  tā
you  help  teacher  Well  look after  he
Keep an eye on him for me.
千萬不要 讓 他 把 其他 同學 帶壞
qiān wàn bù yào  ràng  tā  bǎ  qí tā  tóng xué  dài huài
please don't  allow  he  take  other  classmate  led astray
Don't let him be a bad influence on others.
順便 督 促 一下 他 功課
shùn biàn  dū  cù  yí xià  tā  gōng kè
By the way  supervise  urge  a bit  he  homework
Give him a push on his schoolwork, as well.
知不知道
zhī bù zhī dào
do you know?
Okay?
許博淳
xǔ bó chún
Hsu Bo-Chun
Hsu Bo-Chun.
以後
yǐ hòu
after
In the future
你 坐 在 謝明和 前面
nǐ  zuò  zài  xiè míng hé  qián miàn
you  sit  in  Hsieh Ming-Ho  front
you will sit in front of Hsieh Ming-Ho.
一樣
yī yàng
same
The same goes for you.
不要 給 我 作怪
bù yào  gěi  wǒ  zuò guài
Do not  give  I  mischief
Don't goof around again.
再 作怪 的 話 我 請 你 父母 到 學校 來
zài  zuò guài  de  huà  wǒ  qǐng  nǐ  fù mǔ  dào  xué xiào  lái
again  mischief  of  speech  I  please  you  parents  to  school  come
If you do, I will ask your parents to come to school.
聽到 沒有
tīng dào  méi yǒu
Hear it  No
Get it?
聽到
tīng dào
Hear it
Got it.
都 上課 去
dōu  shàng kè  qù
all  attend class  go
Now, go to your class.
謝謝 老師
xiè xiè  lǎo shī
Thank you  teacher
Thank you, sir.
雖然 沈佳宜 國中 已經 跟 我 同 班 了 三年
suī rán  chén jiā yí  guó zhōng  yǐ jīng  gēn  wǒ  tóng  bān  le  sān nián
although  Shen Chia-Yi  secondary  already  with  I  same  class  is  Three years
Even though Shen Chia-Yi and I have been in the same class ever since junior high
但 好 學生 跟 壞 學生 之間 的 距離
dàn  hǎo  xué shēng  gēn  huài  xué shēng  zhī jiān  de  jù lí
only  good  student  with  bad  student  between  of  distance
the distance between an honor student and a bad student
並沒有 因此 有 任何 的 改變
bìng méi yǒu  yīn cǐ  yǒu  rèn hé  de  gǎi biàn
not at all  therefore  have  any  of  change
always stayed the same.
換 到 這種 鳥 地方 倒霉 啊 倒霉 啊
huàn  dào  zhè zhǒng  niǎo  dì fāng  dǎo méi  a  dǎo méi  a
change  to  this kind  bird  place  bad luck  ah  bad luck  ah
It's shitty luck to sit in such a shitty seat.
到底是 誰 倒霉 啊
dào dǐ shì  sheí  dǎo méi  a
In the end is  who  bad luck  ah
Who has bad luck now?
坐 在 我 前面
zuò  zài  wǒ  qián miàn
sit  in  I  front
You are sitting in front of me now.
你 不要 再 搞 一些 幼稚 的 把戲
nǐ  bù yào  zài  gǎo  yī xiē  yòu zhì  de  bǎ xì
you  Do not  again  clear  some  naive  of  trick
You better stop your childish pranks.
造成 我 的 困擾
zào chéng  wǒ  de  kùn rǎo
Cause  I  of  Troubled
So you don't bring me unnecessary troubles.
當 好 學生 真好
dāng  hǎo  xué shēng  zhēn hǎo
that  good  student  that's nice
It must be nice to be an honor student.
只要 成績 好
zhǐ yào  chéng jī  hǎo
as long as  results  good
Just because you have good marks
就能 亂嗆 人
jiù néng  luàn qiāng  rén
can  irritate  man
doesn't mean you can boss people around.
誰 稀罕 管 你 啊
sheí  xī han  guǎn  nǐ  a
who  rare  manage  you  ah
Who cares about what you think?
欸 你 也不 用 太 管 他 啦
āi  nǐ  yě bù  yòng  tài  guǎn  tā  la
sigh  you  nor  use  very  manage  he  la
Don't mind him, don't let him bother you.
對 呀
duì  ya
to  yeah
That's right.
他 只是 上課 愛 打手槍 而已 啦
tā  zhǐ shì  shàng kè  ài  dǎ shǒu qiāng  ér yǐ  la
he  just  attend class  love  masturbate  Just now  la
He just likes to masturbate in the classroom.
幹
gàn
fuck
Fuck.
你 會 喜歡 作怪 就是 因為 你 平常 不好 好 唸書 的 關係
nǐ  huì  xǐ huan  zuò guài  jiù shì  yīn wèi  nǐ  píng cháng  bù hǎo  hǎo  niàn shū  de  guān xì
you  can  like  mischief  is  because  you  usually  not good  good  study  of  relationship
The reason you like to goof around is because you don't concentrate on your studies.
對 啊
duì  a
to  ah
Yeah.
你 好 強 喔 你 好 會 讀書 喔
nǐ  hǎo  qiáng  ō  nǐ  hǎo  huì  dú shū  ō
you  good  strong  oh  you  good  can  reading  oh
You're so clever, you are such a smart ass.
像 沈佳宜 這種 好 學生
xiàng  chén jiā yí  zhè zhǒng  hǎo  xué shēng
like  Shen Chia-Yi  this kind  good  student
A nerd like Shen Chia-Yi
逮到 機會 就 喜歡 多管閒事
dǎi dào  jī huì  jiù  xǐ huan  duō guǎn jiān shì
Caught  opportunity  just  like  busy body
likes to poke her nose into other people's business whenever she gets a chance.
整天 畫 這種 智障 的 東西
zhěng tiān  huà  zhè zhǒng  zhì zhàng  de  dōng xi
All day  draw  this kind  retard  of  thing
All you do is drawing these retarded figures every day.
沒 前途 啦
méi  qián tú  la
not  future  la
Where's the future in that?
要 你 管 啊
yào  nǐ  guǎn  a
want  you  manage  ah
It's none of your business
是 沒有 要 管 啊 只是 想 笑 一下 而已 呀
shì  méi yǒu  yào  guǎn  a  zhǐ shì  xiǎng  xiào  yí xià  ér yǐ  ya
is  No  want  manage  ah  just  think  smile  a bit  Just now  yeah
I'm pretty much minding my own business. I just want to have a good laugh.
沒品
méi pǐn
tasteless
Moron.
為什麼 你 畫 的 智障 每個 都 是 光頭 啊
wèi shén me  nǐ  huà  de  zhì zhàng  měi gè  dōu  shì  guāng tóu  a
why  you  draw  of  retard  Each one  all  is  Bald head  ah
How come every retard you drew is bald?
你 是 歧視 光頭 還 是 歧視 智障
nǐ  shì  qí shì  guāng tóu  hái  shì  qí shì  zhì zhàng
you  is  Discrimination  Bald head  still  is  Discrimination  retard
Do you discriminate against bald heads or retards?
管好 你 自己 就 好
guǎn hǎo  nǐ  zì jǐ  jiù  hǎo
Good management  you  self  just  good
Mind your own business.
你 烏龜 喔
nǐ  wū guī  ō
you  tortoise  oh
Man, you are as slow as a turtle!
拜拜
bài bài
bye bye
Bye.
柯騰
kē téng
Ko-Teng
Ko-Teng.
柯騰
kē téng
Ko-Teng
Ko-Teng.
啊
a
ah
What?
你 不要 一直 為難 沈佳宜
nǐ  bù yào  yī zhí  wéi nán  chén jiā yí
you  Do not  Always  embarrass  Shen Chia-Yi
Stop giving Shen Chia-Yi a hard time.
媽 啦
mā  la
mother  la
Yeah right.
就 這樣
jiù  zhè yàng
just  such
That's all.
還 這樣 咧
hái  zhè yàng  liě
still  such  frown
That's all???
每個 男人 都 想要 成為 最強 的 男人
měi gè  nán rén  dōu  xiǎng yào  chéng wéi  zuì qiáng  de  nán rén
Each one  man  all  Want to  become  strongest  of  man
Every man wants to be the strongest man.
我 也不 例外
wǒ  yě bù  lì wài
I  nor  exception
Including me.
總有 一天
zǒng yǒu  yī tiān
always  one day
One day
我 一定 要 成為 跟 師父 一樣 強 的 男人
wǒ  yī dìng  yào  chéng wéi  gēn  shī fù  yī yàng  qiáng  de  nán rén
I  for sure  want  become  with  master  same  strong  of  man
I will be as strong as my master.
你 已經 死了
nǐ  yǐ jīng  sǐ le
you  already  died
You are D.E.A.D.
我 的 個性 之 所以 這麼 豪邁 跟 我 的 家人 大有 關係
wǒ  de  gè xìng  zhī  suǒ yǐ  zhè me  háo mài  gēn  wǒ  de  jiā rén  dà yǒu  guān xì
I  of  personality  it  and so  so  heroic  with  I  of  family  Great  relationship
The fact that I am so reckless has got something to do with my family.
媽 洗髮精 沒了
mā  xǐ fà jīng  méi liǎo
mother  shampoo  Gone
Ma, shampoo is out.
唉唷 穿衣服 啦
āi yō  chuān yī fú  la
aw  wear clothes  la
Hey, put some clothes on.
都 這麼 大 了
dōu  zhè me  dà  le
all  so  big  is
You're a grown-up now
真的 很大 吼
zhēn de  hěn dà  hǒu
Really  Very big  roar
I know, it has grown so big, right?
我 老爸 在 家裡 也 是 脫 褲 懶
wǒ  lǎo bà  zài  jiā li  yě  shì  tuō  kù  lǎn
I  Daddy  in  Home  also  is  strip  trousers  lazy
My father also likes to walk around butt naked in the house.
今天 學校 有 打電話 來
jīn tiān  xué xiào  yǒu  dǎ diàn huà  lái
today  school  have  call  come
The school called today.
男女合 校 就 男女合 校
nán nǚ hé  xiào  jiù  nán nǚ hé  xiào
coed  school  just  coed  school
What's the big deal about coed school?
在 學校 就 專心 讀書
zài  xué xiào  jiù  zhuān xīn  dú shū
in  school  just  concentrate  reading
Concentrate at school.
不要搞 一些 有的沒的 嘛
bù yào gǎo  yī xiē  yǒu de méi de  ma
didn't  some  have or not  ma
Stop goofing around.
搞 什麼
gǎo  shén me
clear  what
What did I do?
趁熱吃 趁熱吃
chèn rè chī  chèn rè chī
eat hot  eat hot
Eat first, while it's still hot.
吃完 再說 啦
chī wán  zài shuō  la
Finished eating  Say again  la
Talk later.
你 成績 一直 都 吊 車尾 是不是 都 不 讀書
nǐ  chéng jī  yī zhí  dōu  diào  chē wěi  shì bù shì  dōu  bù  dú shū
you  results  Always  all  hang  rear  isn't it  all  no  reading
Why are your grades always in the bottom percentile?
整天 只想 搞 一些 談情 說 愛 的 事
zhěng tiān  zhǐ xiǎng  gǎo  yī xiē  tán qíng  shuō  ài  de  shì
All day  Just want to  clear  some  flirt  say  love  of  thing
Is it because you are thinking about girls all the time, is that why?
我 對 女生 沒 興趣 啦
wǒ  duì  nǚ shēng  méi  xìng qù  la
I  to  Girls  not  interest  la
No, I am not interested in girls!
我 對 男生 也 沒 興趣 啊
wǒ  duì  nán shēng  yě  méi  xìng qù  a
I  to  boy  also  not  interest  ah
I'm not interested in guys, either.
說到 談情 說 愛
shuō dào  tán qíng  shuō  ài
Speaking of  flirt  say  love
Speaking of girls.
我 那些 好 朋友
wǒ  nà xiē  hǎo  péng yǒu
I  those  good  friend
Each one of my good friend
每個人 喜歡 沈佳宜 的 方式 都 不 一樣
měi gè rén  xǐ huan  chén jiā yí  de  fāng shì  dōu  bù  yī yàng
everyone  like  Shen Chia-Yi  of  way  all  no  same
liked Shen Chia-Yi in a different way.
廖該邊 你 想 幹嘛
liào gāi biān  nǐ  xiǎng  gàn ma
Groin  you  think  what
Groin, what are you doing?
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
我 剛剛 發明 了 一個 新 魔術
wǒ  gāng gāng  fā míng  le  yī gè  xīn  mó shù
I  just  invention  is  One  new  magic
I have just invented a new magic trick
第一個 變 給 你 看
dì yī ge  biàn  gěi  nǐ  kàn
the first  change  give  you  look
I want you to be the first one to see it.
胡家瑋 你 要不要 順便 也看 一下
hú jiā wěi  nǐ  yào bù yào  shùn biàn  yě kàn  yí xià
Hu Chia-Wei  you  want  By the way  See also  a bit
Hu Chia-Wei, do you want to see it, too.
搞笑 的 嗎
gǎo xiào  de  ma
funny  of  ?
Is it a prank?
哪 是 啊 是 很 厲害 的
nǎ  shì  a  shì  hěn  lì hài  de
where  is  ah  is  very  awesome  of
No way. It's amazing.
看清楚 喔
kàn qīng chu  ō
See clearly  oh
Look closely.
該邊 的 方法 基本 上 沒錯
gāi biān  de  fāng fǎ  jī běn  shàng  méi cuò
groin  of  method  Basic  on  That's right
Basically, Groin was on the right track.
就是 逗 女孩子 開心
jiù shì  dòu  nǚ hái zi  kāi xīn
is  play  girl  Happy
It's to cheer the girls up and make them laugh.
這 隻手 也沒有
zhè  zhī shǒu  yě méi yǒu
this  Hand only  nor
Nothing in this hand, either.
看清楚 喔
kàn qīng chu  ō
See clearly  oh
Look closely.
廖該邊 你 很 無聊
liào gāi biān  nǐ  hěn  wú liáo
Groin  you  very  bored
Groin, you are such a bore.
比起 該邊 的 弱智 魔術
bǐ qǐ  gāi biān  de  ruò zhì  mó shù
Compared to  groin  of  retard  magic
Besides Groin's retarded magic.
老曹 討 女生 開心 的 方式 …
lǎo cáo  tǎo  nǚ shēng  kāi xīn  de  fāng shì  …
Tsao  beg  Girls  Happy  of  way  …
Tsao had a very different way to make girls happy.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
曹國勝
cáo guó shèng
Tsao Kuo-Sheng
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
沒人 理解
méi rén  lǐ jiě
no one  understanding
And no one gets it.
阿和 很 喜歡 看 一些 大人 在 看 的 雜誌
ā hé  hěn  xǐ huan  kàn  yī xiē  dà rén  zài  kàn  de  zá zhì
A-Ho  very  like  look  some  grown ups  in  look  of  magazine
A-Ho liked to read what grown-ups read.
對 很多 我 不 想 懂的 事 都 非常 瞭解
duì  hěn duō  wǒ  bù  xiǎng  dǒng de  shì  dōu  fēi cháng  liǎo jiě
to  a lot of  I  no  think  got it  thing  all  very much  understand
So he knew many things that we didn't.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
你 記 不 記得 我 之前 有 借 你 一張 Air Supply 的 專輯
nǐ  jì  bù  jì de  wǒ  zhī qián  yǒu  jiè  nǐ  yī zhāng  Air  Supply  de  zhuān jí
you  record  no  remember  I  prior to  have  borrow  you  One  Air  Supply  of  album
Do you remember the Air Supply album that I lent you.
嗯
ń
umm
Um... I remember.
下個月 他們 要 來 開 演唱會
xià ge yuè  tā men  yào  lái  kāi  yǎn chàng huì
next month  they  want  come  open  concert
They are coming next month.
如果 我 拿到 票 要不要 一起去
rú guǒ  wǒ  ná dào  piào  yào bù yào  yī qǐ qù
if  I  Get it  ticket  want  go together
Do you want to go if I have tickets?
去 台北 看 嗎
qù  tái běi  kàn  ma
go  Taipei  look  ?
To Taipei?
坐 火車 去 啊
zuò  huǒ chē  qù  a
sit  train  go  ah
We can take the train.
胡家瑋
hú jiā wěi
Hu Chia-Wei
Hu Chia-Wei.
要不要 一起去
yào bù yào  yī qǐ qù
want  go together
Do you want to go with us?
好啊 …
hǎo a  …
Okay  …
Yes, sure.
聽起來 很有 趣 耶
tīng qǐ lái  hěn yǒu  qù  yé
sound  Very much  interesting  ye
Sounds fun.
用 大人 的 方式 追 沈佳宜 最不著 痕跡
yòng  dà rén  de  fāng shì  zhuī  chén jiā yí  zuì bù jiáo  hén jī
use  grown ups  of  way  pursue  Shen Chia-Yi  most subtle  trace
The adult's way is the most subtle way to chase after Shen Chia-Yi.
Air Supply 是誰 啊
Air  Supply  shì shuí  a
Air  Supply  who is it  ah
Who is Air Supply?
有 人 說
yǒu  rén  shuō
have  man  say
Someone said.
展現 自己 最 笨拙 的 一面 也 是 追求 女孩 的 一種 方式
zhǎn xiàn  zì jǐ  zuì  bèn zhuō  de  yī miàn  yě  shì  zhuī qiú  nǚ hái  de  yī zhǒng  fāng shì
Show  self  most  clumsy  of  one side  also  is  pursue  girl  of  One kind  way
Showing one's clumsy side is also another way to pursuit girls
我 想
wǒ  xiǎng
I  think
I think.
勃起 充分 驗證 了 這個 方式 …
bó qǐ  chōng fèn  yàn zhèng  le  zhè ge  fāng shì  …
boner  full  verification  is  This one  way  …
Boner has tried this many times.
許博淳
xǔ bó chún
Hsu Bo-Chun
Hsu Bo-Chun.
你 可不可以 不要 再 吹了 啊
nǐ  kě bù kě yǐ  bù yào  zài  chuī le  a
you  can we  Do not  again  Blow  ah
Can you stop playing?
並不 管 用
bìng bù  guǎn  yòng
And not  manage  use
And it proves that his way doesn't work at all.
我 也有 喜歡 的 女生
wǒ  yě yǒu  xǐ huan  de  nǚ shēng
I  There are also  like  of  Girls
Me? Yes, there's also a girl I like.
只是 我們 之間 暫時 不可能
zhǐ shì  wǒ men  zhī jiān  zhàn shí  bù kě néng
just  us  between  temporarily  impossible
But it's unlikely that we can develop anything at that point in time.
沒關係
méi guān xì
it's ok
That's fine
我 會 慢慢 長大
wǒ  huì  màn man  zhǎng dà
I  can  Slowly  grow up
I will grow up.
成為 一個 配得 上 她 的 男人
chéng wéi  yī gè  pèi dé  shàng  tā  de  nán rén
become  One  worthy  on  she  of  man
One clay, I will turn to be the man that deserves her.
那一 天
nà yī  tiān
That one  day
That day.
英文 老師 不曉得 是 股票 輸 錢
yīng wén  lǎo shī  bù xiǎo de  shì  gǔ piào  shū  qián
English  teacher  do not know  is  stock  lose  money
Nobody knew if the English teacher had lost money in the stock market
還 是 月經 亂 掉
hái  shì  yuè jīng  luàn  diào
still  is  period  chaos  out
or her menstruation period went wild.
整 張 臉 跟 大 便 一樣 臭
zhěng  zhāng  liǎn  gēn  dà  biàn  yī yàng  chòu
whole  stretch  face  with  big  then  same  smell
She had a shitty face.
散發出 比 平常 更重 的 殺 氣
sàn fā chū  bǐ  píng cháng  gèng zhòng  de  shā  qì
exude  than  usually  heavier  of  kill  air
She looked like she was about to kill someone.
起立
qǐ lì
stand up
Stand up.
坐下 上課
zuò xià  shàng kè
sit down  attend class
Sit down. Let's begin
原本 我 以為
yuán běn  wǒ  yǐ wéi
original  I  think
I thought
如果 有 一天 能夠 看到 品學兼優 的 沈佳宜 出 糗
rú guǒ  yǒu  yī tiān  néng gòu  kàn dào  pǐn xué jiān yōu  de  chén jiā yí  chū  qiǔ
if  have  one day  were able  see  good grade  of  Shen Chia-Yi  out  embarrassing
it would be great fun to see the smart ass student, Shen Chia-Yi
一定 是 上 學 最大 的 樂趣
yī dìng  shì  shàng  xué  zuì dà  de  lè qù
for sure  is  on  learning  maximum  of  pleasure
makes a blunder
我 是說
wǒ  shì shuō
I  says
I meant.
原本
yuán běn
original
"I thought."
沒 帶 課本 的 站起來
méi  dài  kè běn  de  zhàn qǐ lái
not  take  textbook  of  stand up
Stand up if you didn't bring your textbook.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
學期 已經 過了 三分之一 了
xué qí  yǐ jīng  guò le  sān fēn zhī yī  le
semester  already  pass  one third  is
we have gone through a third of this semester.
每天 要 用 的 英文 課本 你 都 沒 帶
měi tiān  yào  yòng  de  yīng wén  kè běn  nǐ  dōu  méi  dài
every day  want  use  of  English  textbook  you  all  not  take
And you don't even have your English textbook with you, which we use every day.
你 有沒有 心 上課 啊
nǐ  yǒu méi yǒu  xīn  shàng kè  a
you  do you have  heart  attend class  ah
Are you serious about getting an education?
椅子
yǐ zi
chair
Chair.
你 知道 私立 學校 的 學費 很 貴 嗎
nǐ  zhī dào  sī lì  xué xiào  de  xué fèi  hěn  guì  ma
you  know  private  school  of  tuition  very  expensive  ?
Don't you know private schools are expensive?
連 最 基本 的 課本 都 不帶
lián  zuì  jī běn  de  kè běn  dōu  bù dài
even  most  Basic  of  textbook  all  Without
If you don't even have your textbook
你 來 學校 幹嘛
nǐ  lái  xué xiào  gàn ma
you  come  school  what
then why do you even bother coming to school?
來 吃 便當 啊
lái  chī  biàn dang  a
come  eat  lunchbox  ah
Here to eat your lunchbox?
便當 本來 就 要 吃 啊
biàn dang  běn lái  jiù  yào  chī  a
lunchbox  originally  just  want  eat  ah
Lunch is essential! Of course I have to eat it.
你 還蠻 會 開玩笑 的 嘛
nǐ  hái mán  huì  kāi wán xiào  de  ma
you  quite  can  joke  of  ma
You think you're very funny, huh?
你 到底有 沒有 羞恥 心 啊
nǐ  dào dǐ yǒu  méi yǒu  xiū chǐ  xīn  a
you  In the end there is  No  shame  heart  ah
Have you no shame?
手 舉 高 一點
shǒu  jǔ  gāo  yī diǎn
hand  raise  high  a little
Raise your arms higher.
再 高 一點
zài  gāo  yī diǎn
again  high  a little
Raise them higher.
你 是 沒 吃飯 是不是
nǐ  shì  méi  chī fàn  shì bù shì
you  is  not  eat  isn't it
So weak! Didn't you eat?
出去 外面 跳 十 圈 再 進來
chū qù  wài miàn  tiào  shí  quān  zài  jìn lái
Go out  outside  jump  ten  round  again  Come in
Go do 10 rounds of squat jumps outside.
我 有 叫 你 放下 來 嗎
wǒ  yǒu  jiào  nǐ  fàng xià  lái  ma
I  have  call  you  lay down  come  ?
Did I ask you to put your hands down?
舉 高
jǔ  gāo
raise  high
Higher!
I say to you today
my friends
that in spite of the difficulties and frustrations of the moment
I still have a dream
I still have a dream.
It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream
I have a dream
that one day this nation will rise up.
沈佳宜 如果 不是 那麼 假正經 其實 還 滿 可愛 的
chén jiā yí  rú guǒ  bù shì  nà me  jiǎ zhèng jīng  qí shí  hái  mǎn  kě ài  de
Shen Chia-Yi  if  not  like that  fake  in fact  still  fill  lovely  of
(Shen Chia-Yi would be kind of cute if she wasn't such a prude)
and live up the true meaning of its dream.
你 在 想 什麼 啊
nǐ  zài  xiǎng  shén me  a
you  in  think  what  ah
What are you thinking?
一 整天 都 怪怪 的
yī  zhěng tiān  dōu  guài guài  de
one  All day  all  strange  of
You've been weird all day long.
沒有 啊
méi yǒu  a
No  ah
Nothing.
要不要 帶 你 去 收驚 啊
yào bù yào  dài  nǐ  qù  shōu jīng  a
want  take  you  go  scared  ah
Do you need an exorcism?
你 想 太多 了
nǐ  xiǎng  tài duō  le
you  think  too much  is
You are thinking too much.
訓導 處 報告
xùn dǎo  chù  bào gào
discipline  place  report
Head office announcement
三年 二 班 周傑倫
sān nián  èr  bān  zhōu jié lún
Three years  two  class  Jay Chou
Jay Chou in third year
馬上 到 訓導 處 來
mǎ shàng  dào  xùn dǎo  chù  lái
immediately  to  discipline  place  come
please come to the head office now.
哎唷屌哦
āi yō diǎo ó
Oh, oh!
Sweet.
幹嘛 啊
gàn ma  a
what  ah
What?
昨天 謝謝
zuó tiān  xiè xiè
yesterday  Thank you
Thank you for yesterday.
沒差 反正 我 臉皮厚
méi chà  fǎn zhèng  wǒ  liǎn pí hòu
not bad  Anyway  I  thick skin
No big deal. I have no shame anyway.
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you.
我 看 你 乾脆 請 我 喝 飲料 好了
wǒ  kàn  nǐ  gān cuì  qǐng  wǒ  hē  yǐn liào  hǎo le
I  look  you  simply  please  I  drink  Drink  All right
Why not just buy me a drink?
不然 一直 聽 你 說 謝謝 很 奇怪
bù rán  yī zhí  tīng  nǐ  shuō  xiè xiè  hěn  qí guài
otherwise  Always  hear  you  say  Thank you  very  strange
It's weird to hear you keep on saying "thank you".
我 可以 問你 一個 問題 嗎
wǒ  kě yǐ  wèn nǐ  yī gè  wèn tí  ma
I  can  ask you  One  problem  ?
Can I ask you a question?
問 啊
wèn  a
ask  ah
Go ahead.
你 幹嘛 不 讀書
nǐ  gàn ma  bù  dú shū
you  what  no  reading
Why don't you want to study?
沒有 不 讀 啊
méi yǒu  bù  dú  a
No  no  read  ah
It's not like I don't want to
要是 我 認真 唸書 起來
yào shi  wǒ  rèn zhēn  niàn shū  qǐ lái
if  I  serious  study  stand up
I am afraid if I really tried
實力 強 到 連 我 自己 都 會 害怕
shí lì  qiáng  dào  lián  wǒ  zì jǐ  dōu  huì  hài pà
strength  strong  to  even  I  self  all  can  Afraid
I would be so good that I would even scare myself.
小心 我 一 唸書
xiǎo xīn  wǒ  yī  niàn shū
Be careful  I  one  study
You better watch out then if I do study
立刻 就 把 妳 幹掉
lì kè  jiù  bǎ  nǐ  gàn diào
Immediately  just  take  you  get rid of
I would beat you immediately.
挑一 下 啊
tiāo yī  xià  a
Pick one  under  ah
Wanna take up the challenge?
怕 你 喔
pà  nǐ  ō
fear  you  oh
Sure, why not.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
Ko Ching-Teng.
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
What?
這 是 我 自己 出 的 考卷
zhè  shì  wǒ  zì jǐ  chū  de  kǎo juǎn
this  is  I  self  out  of  Test paper
This is a quiz I made up myself.
你 拿 回家 寫
nǐ  ná  huí jiā  xiě
you  take  Return home  write
Take it and do it at home.
明天 帶來 給 我 改
míng tiān  dài lái  gěi  wǒ  gǎi
tomorrow  bring  give  I  change
Bring it back tomorrow.
真的假的 啦
zhēn de jiǎ de  la
really?  la
Are you for real?
還 愛心 考卷
hái  ài xīn  kǎo juǎn
still  Love  Test paper
A quiz made out of love.
還有 這 本 數學 參考書
hái yǒu  zhè  běn  shù xué  cān kǎo shū
and also  this  this  maths  exercise book
And here is a math exercise book.
我 用 黃色 螢光筆劃 下來 的 地方 算 三 遍
wǒ  yòng  huáng sè  yíng guāng bǐ huà  xià lái  de  dì fāng  suàn  sān  biàn
I  use  yellow  highlighted  Down  of  place  count  three  everywhere
See the questions I've highlighted in yellow? Do them three times.
下次 小考 應該 就 有 五十分 了
xià cì  xiǎo kǎo  yīng gāi  jiù  yǒu  wǔ shí fēn  le
Next time  quiz  should  just  have  50 percent  is
You will probably score at least 50% in the next quiz.
才 五十
cái  wǔ shí
only  fifty
Only 50%
我 沒說 考 好 成績 很 容易 呀
wǒ  méi shuō  kǎo  hǎo  chéng jī  hěn  róng yì  ya
I  Did not say  examine  good  results  very  easy  yeah
I didn't say it's easy to get good grades
算 完了 基本 題
suàn  wán liǎo  jī běn  tí
count  Finished it  Basic  question
I will give you some harder problems
我 再出 難 一點 的 給 你
wǒ  zài chū  nán  yī diǎn  de  gěi  nǐ
I  And then out  difficult  a little  of  give  you
after you finish the basics.
欠 你 錢 喔
qiàn  nǐ  qián  ō
owe  you  money  oh
What do I owe you?
我 幹嘛 聽 你的
wǒ  gàn ma  tīng  nǐ de
I  what  hear  your
Why should I listen to you?
因為 我 不 想 瞧不起 你
yīn wèi  wǒ  bù  xiǎng  qiáo bù qǐ  nǐ
because  I  no  think  look down  you
Because I don't want to look down on you.
媽 啦
mā  la
mother  la
Yeah right!
成績 好 就可以 瞧不起 人
chéng jī  hǎo  jiù kě yǐ  qiáo bù qǐ  rén
results  good  can  look down  man
You can be so stuck up just because you have good grades.
那 你 繼續 好了 我 又 沒差
nà  nǐ  jì xù  hǎo le  wǒ  yòu  méi chà
that  you  carry on  All right  I  and  not bad
Go on then, I don't really care
我 瞧不起 的 不是 成績 不好 的 人
wǒ  qiáo bù qǐ  de  bù shì  chéng jī  bù hǎo  de  rén
I  look down  of  not  results  not good  of  man
I don't look down on people with bad grades
我 瞧不起 的
wǒ  qiáo bù qǐ  de
I  look down  of
I look down on you because
是 一個 明明 自己 不 努力 唸書
shì  yī gè  míng míng  zì jǐ  bù  nǔ lì  niàn shū
is  One  Obviously  self  no  Effort  study
you pick on people with good grades
卻 只會 瞧不起 用功 唸書 的 人
què  zhǐ huì  qiáo bù qǐ  yòng gōng  niàn shū  de  rén
still  Only will  look down  work hard  study  of  man
while you don't even try to work hard.
穿衣服 啦
chuān yī fú  la
wear clothes  la
Put on some clothes.
不然 會 感 冒
bù rán  huì  gǎn  mào
otherwise  can  feel  risk
Otherwise you'll catch a cold.
哪有 可能
nǎ yǒu  kě néng
How can there be  may
That's impossible.
我 師父 是 李小龍 耶
wǒ  shī fù  shì  lǐ xiǎo lóng  yé
I  master  is  Bruce Lee  ye
My master is Bruce Lee.
吞下 去 再說
tūn xià  qù  zài shuō
Swallowed  go  Say again
Swallow your food before you speak.
你 衛生紙 怎麼 用 那麼 快 啊
nǐ  wèi shēng zhǐ  zěn me  yòng  nà me  kuài  a
you  toilet paper  how  use  like that  quick  ah
Why is our tissue paper running out so fast?
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
What?
考卷
kǎo juǎn
Test paper
Your quiz.
你 錯 很多 耶
nǐ  cuò  hěn duō  yé
you  error  a lot of  ye
You made so many mistakes.
你 回去 沒 看 參考書 就 直接 寫了 對不對
nǐ  huí qù  méi  kàn  cān kǎo shū  jiù  zhí jiē  xiě le  duì bù duì
you  go back  not  look  exercise book  just  direct  wrote  right
You did the problems without reading the exercise book, didn't you?
這 兩 題 你 可以 從 參考書 上 找 解答
zhè  liǎng  tí  nǐ  kě yǐ  cóng  cān kǎo shū  shàng  zhǎo  jiě dá
this  two  question  you  can  from  exercise book  on  search  answer
You can find the answers for these two problems in the exercise book.
這 一 題 比較 難
zhè  yī  tí  bǐ jiào  nán
this  one  question  Comparison  difficult
This one is harder.
不是 背 公 式 就可以 解 的
bù shì  bèi  gōng  shì  jiù kě yǐ  jiě  de
not  revise  fair  style  can  solution  of
It's not the kind of problem you can solve with a formula.
需要 用 到 這裡 跟 這裡 的 概念
xū yào  yòng  dào  zhè lǐ  gēn  zhè lǐ  de  gài niàn
need  use  to  Here  with  Here  of  concept
You need to use these theories.
我 圈 起來 了 你 回去 自己 看
wǒ  quān  qǐ lái  le  nǐ  huí qù  zì jǐ  kàn
I  round  stand up  is  you  go back  self  look
You go home and read the parts I circled.
唸書 好 煩
niàn shū  hǎo  fán
study  good  bother
It's such a pain to study.
所以 會 唸書 的 人 很 厲害 啊
suǒ yǐ  huì  niàn shū  de  rén  hěn  lì hài  a
and so  can  study  of  man  very  awesome  ah
That's why people who are good at studying rule.
你 為什麼 要 盯 柯景騰 唸書 啊
nǐ  wèi shén me  yào  dīng  kē jǐng téng  niàn shū  a
you  why  want  stare  Ko Ching-Teng  study  ah
Why are you helping Ko Ching-Teng to study?
他 成績 能 看 嗎
tā  chéng jī  néng  kàn  ma
he  results  can  look  ?
Did you see his grades?
也不 干 你的 事 啊
yě bù  gàn  nǐ de  shì  a
nor  oppose  your  thing  ah
It's none of your business.
真的 很 爛 耶
zhēn de  hěn  làn  yé
Really  very  bad  ye
They are really bad.
那 也不 干 你的 事 啊
nà  yě bù  gàn  nǐ de  shì  a
that  nor  oppose  your  thing  ah
Still, it has nothing to do with you.
來 小姐 這 是 你的 這 是 你的
lái  xiǎo jiě  zhè  shì  nǐ de  zhè  shì  nǐ de
come  miss  this  is  your  this  is  your
Miss, this is yours and this is yours.
謝謝 老闆
xiè xiè  lǎo bǎn
Thank you  boss
Thank you!
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you!
真 不像 你
zhēn  bù xiàng  nǐ
real  Not like  you
It's so not you
我 討厭 什麼 都 不 努力 卻 一點 也沒有 自覺 的 人
wǒ  tǎo yàn  shén me  dōu  bù  nǔ lì  què  yī diǎn  yě méi yǒu  zì jué  de  rén
I  hate  what  all  no  Effort  still  a little  nor  conscious  of  man
I hate people who are lazy and have no sense of self-awareness at all.
喔
ō
oh
Ok
我 又 不是 在 說你
wǒ  yòu  bù shì  zài  shuō nǐ
I  and  not  in  saying you
I'm not talking about you.
沒有 在 說 我 啊
méi yǒu  zài  shuō  wǒ  a
No  in  say  I  ah
You sure?
唸書 好無聊 哦
niàn shū  hǎo wú liáo  ó
study  so boring  Oh
It's so boring to study
為什麼 沈佳宜 可以 這樣 每天 唸書 咧
wèi shén me  chén jiā yí  kě yǐ  zhè yàng  měi tiān  niàn shū  liě
why  Shen Chia-Yi  can  such  every day  study  frown
I don't understand why Shen Chia-Yi can do this every day.
你 說說 看 啊
nǐ  shuō shuō  kàn  a
you  Talk about it  look  ah
Do you have any idea?
我 跟 你 說 哦
wǒ  gēn  nǐ  shuō  ó
I  with  you  say  Oh
Let me tell you.
這種 尖酸 的 題目 就算 解 得出 來
zhè zhǒng  jiān suān  de  tí mù  jiù suàn  jiě  dé chū  lái
this kind  bitter  of  topic  Even if  solution  inferred  come
Being able to solve these tricky math questions.
對 人生 還 是 一點 幫助 都 沒有 啦
duì  rén shēng  hái  shì  yī diǎn  bāng zhù  dōu  méi yǒu  la
to  life  still  is  a little  help  all  No  la
Does nothing good in life!
來
lái
come
Here.
怎麼 那麼 用功 啊
zěn me  nà me  yòng gōng  a
how  like that  work hard  ah
Why do you work so hard?
沒有 啊 隨便 念
méi yǒu  a  suí biàn  niàn
No  ah  casual  study
No, I just study when I feel like it.
要 念 就 要 認真 念
yào  niàn  jiù  yào  rèn zhēn  niàn
want  study  just  want  serious  study
If you want to study, study hard then.
什麼 隨便 念
shén me  suí biàn  niàn
what  casual  study
What do you mean "when you feel like it"?
好啦 我 考慮 一下
hǎo la  wǒ  kǎo lǜ  yí xià
Okay  I  consider  a bit
Fine, I will think about it.
吃 稀飯
chī  xī fàn
eat  porridge
Eat porridge.
省著 點用 喔
shěng zhe  diǎn yòng  ō
save  use it  oh
Don't finish it too quickly.
對了
duì le
correct
By the way
老闆 前 幾天 剛 進一 批 新 貨 都 沒有 拆
lǎo bǎn  qián  jǐ tiān  gāng  jìn yī  pī  xīn  huò  dōu  méi yǒu  chāi
boss  before  A few days  just  Into one  batch  new  goods  all  No  tear
there was a new shipment in the store a few days ago. The whole package was unopened
可是 他 要 整 盒 賣
kě shì  tā  yào  zhěng  hé  mài
but  he  want  whole  box  sell
so the store owner wants to sell the whole thing together.
所以 你們 覺得 要 買 整 盒 的 SKYBOX 還 是 兩 盒 CC 啊
suǒ yǐ  nǐ men  jué de  yào  mǎi  zhěng  hé  de  SKYBOX  hái  shì  liǎng  hé  CC  a
and so  you  feel  want  buy  whole  box  of  SKYBOX  still  is  two  box  CC  ah
Do you think I should buy the whole package of SKYBOX or two boxes of CC?
SKYBOX 太 貴 了
SKYBOX  tài  guì  le
SKYBOX  very  expensive  is
SKYBOX is too expensive.
所以 兩 盒 CC 囉
suǒ yǐ  liǎng  hé  CC  luō
and so  two  box  CC  eh
So, two boxes of CC?
你 昨天 是 打 幾次 啊
nǐ  zuó tiān  shì  dǎ  jǐ cì  a
you  yesterday  is  hit  several times  ah
How many times did you jerk off yesterday?
這麼 想 睡 哦
zhè me  xiǎng  shuì  ó
so  think  sleep  Oh
Why are you so tired?
打 你的 頭 啦
dǎ  nǐ de  tóu  la
hit  your  head  la
Jerk off your ass.
你 自己 頭 自己 打 不要 打 我 的 啦
nǐ  zì jǐ  tóu  zì jǐ  dǎ  bù yào  dǎ  wǒ  de  la
you  self  head  self  hit  Do not  hit  I  of  la
Mind your own business.
幹
gàn
fuck
Fuck!
起來 吃 肉圓 啦
qǐ lái  chī  ròu yuán  la
stand up  eat  meatballs  la
Get up and eat your meatballs.
你 不吃 我 把 你 吃掉 喔
nǐ  bù chī  wǒ  bǎ  nǐ  chī diào  ō
you  Do not eat  I  take  you  Eat it  oh
If you don't eat it, I'm going to finish yours, too.
沈佳宜 你 看 新 魔術
chén jiā yí  nǐ  kàn  xīn  mó shù
Shen Chia-Yi  you  look  new  magic
Shen Chia-Yi, check out my new magic.
你 白癡 耶
nǐ  bái chī  yé
you  idiot  ye
You idiot.
該邊 還不 錯 喔
gāi biān  hái bù  cuò  ō
groin  Not yet  error  oh
Not bad!
太 噁 了 啦
tài  ě  le  la
very  evil  is  la
Gross!
他 今年 變 過 最好 的
tā  jīn nián  biàn  guò  zuì hǎo  de
he  this year  change  too  best  of
It's the best this year.
今年 最好 的 對不對
jīn nián  zuì hǎo  de  duì bù duì
this year  best  of  right
Isn't it?
你們 在 幹嘛
nǐ men  zài  gàn ma
you  in  what
What are you guys doing?
新 魔術 啦
xīn  mó shù  la
new  magic  la
It's a new magic.
真的假的 我 要 看 我 要 看
zhēn de jiǎ de  wǒ  yào  kàn  wǒ  yào  kàn
really?  I  want  look  I  want  look
For real? Show me! Show me!
我 變 一次 給 你 看
wǒ  biàn  yī cì  gěi  nǐ  kàn
I  change  once  give  you  look
I will show you.
超 噁 的
chāo  ě  de
super  evil  of
It's gross.
就 假裝 有 喝 其實 沒有
jiù  jiǎ zhuāng  yǒu  hē  qí shí  méi yǒu
just  pretend  have  drink  in fact  No
Just pretend that you are drinking, but don't swallow it.
你 很 遜 耶
nǐ  hěn  xùn  yé
you  very  humble  ye
You suck.
你 好 噁 喔 你
nǐ  hǎo  ě  ō  nǐ
you  good  evil  oh  you
You are so gross.
訂正
dìng zhèng
correct
Make correction
十分 鐘
shí fēn  zhōng
10 minutes  clock
10 minutes.
依 我 的 聰明才智
yī  wǒ  de  cōng míng cái zhì
because  I  of  Ingenuity
Because I am so damn smart
五分 鐘 就 綽綽 有 餘 了
wǔ fēn  zhōng  jiù  chuò chuò  yǒu  yú  le
Five minutes  clock  just  More than enough  have  surplus  is
5 minutes is more than enough.
要 念 出來 念 啦
yào  niàn  chū lái  niàn  la
want  study  come out  study  la
Don't study in the toilet
恁 母 啊 我 尿 快 要 閃 出來 了 啦
nèn  mǔ  a  wǒ  niào  kuài  yào  shǎn  chū lái  le  la
that  mother  ah  I  urine  quick  want  flash  come out  is  la
I am going to pee in my pants.
媽 你 不要 嚇 我 啦
mā  nǐ  bù yào  xià  wǒ  la
mother  you  Do not  scare  I  la
Ma, stop scaring me.
我 嚇 你 幹嘛 啦
wǒ  xià  nǐ  gàn ma  la
I  scare  you  what  la
Why would I?
棒棒咧緊 出來
bàng bàng liě jǐn  chū lái
stick up  come out
Dump it out and come out.
快 啦
kuài  la
quick  la
Hurry up.
這 晚 還不 睏
zhè  wǎn  hái bù  kùn
this  night  Not yet  sleepy
Why are you up so late?
咧 衝 三小 啊
liě  chōng  sān xiǎo  a
frown  rush  3 am  ah
What the hell are you doing in there?
在 念 英文 啦
zài  niàn  yīng wén  la
in  study  English  la
I am studying English
英文 以後 用 不 到 啦
yīng wén  yǐ hòu  yòng  bù  dào  la
English  after  use  no  to  la
English is useless for you
I FUCK YOU
好 睏 啊 啦
hǎo  kùn  a  la
good  sleepy  ah  la
Go to sleep
I sleep late because I study English very hard.
謝明和
xiè míng hé
Hsieh Ming-Ho
八十 七 分
bā shí  qī  fēn
eighty  seven  minute
87%
好 不錯 不錯
hǎo  bù cuò  bù cuò
good  not bad  not bad
Not bad, not bad.
繼續 努力
jì xù  nǔ lì
carry on  Effort
Keep it up
張家琪
zhāng jiā qi
Chang Chia-Chi
四十 四 分
sì shí  sì  fēn
forty  four  minute
44%
家琪 要 加 油 喔
jiā qí  yào  jiā  yóu  ō
homework  want  increase  oil  oh
Work harder.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
七十 五分
qī shí  wǔ fēn
seventy  Five minutes
75%
最近 有 比較 用功 喔
zuì jìn  yǒu  bǐ jiào  yòng gōng  ō
recent  have  Comparison  work hard  oh
You have been studying hard lately?
沒有 啦 天才
méi yǒu  la  tiān cái
No  la  genius
Not really, I am a genius.
那 都要 這樣 天才 喔
nà  dōu yào  zhè yàng  tiān cái  ō
that  have to  such  genius  oh
Then, be a genius from now on.
好啦 下 課
hǎo la  xià  kè
Okay  under  lesson
Okay, Class dismiss.
記住 下禮拜 還要 考試 哦
jì zhù  xià lǐ bài  hái yào  kǎo shì  ó
remember  next week  But also  test  Oh
Remember the test next week.
還 天才 啊
hái  tiān cái  a
still  genius  ah
Genius?
真 敢 講耶
zhēn  gǎn  jiǎng yē
real  dare  Speak yeah
Are you serious?
其實 會 解 這種 題目 有 什麼 了 不起 的
qí shí  huì  jiě  zhè zhǒng  tí mù  yǒu  shén me  le  bù qǐ  de
in fact  can  solution  this kind  topic  have  what  is  Can not afford to  of
It's not a big deal that you know how to solve these problems
我 敢 跟 妳 賭
wǒ  gǎn  gēn  nǐ  dǔ
I  dare  with  you  bet
I bet you
十年 後 我 連 Log 是什麼 都 不知道
shí nián  hòu  wǒ  lián  Log  shì shén me  dōu  bù zhī dào
ten years  after  I  even  Log  What is it?  all  do not know
in 10 years time, I wouldn't even know what log is
還 是 可以 活得 好好 的
hái  shì  kě yǐ  huó de  hǎo hǎo  de
still  is  can  life  Well  of
and it makes no difference to my life.
嗯
ń
umm
Emmmm...
妳 不 相信
nǐ  bù  xiāng xìn
you  no  Believe
You don't believe me?
我 相信 啊
wǒ  xiāng xìn  a
I  Believe  ah
I do.
相信 妳 還 那麼 用功 讀書
xiāng xìn  nǐ  hái  nà me  yòng gōng  dú shū
Believe  you  still  like that  work hard  reading
Then, why do you still work so hard?
人生 本來 就 有 很多 事 是 徒勞無功 的 啊
rén shēng  běn lái  jiù  yǒu  hěn duō  shì  shì  tú láo wú gōng  de  a
life  originally  just  have  a lot of  thing  is  Futile  of  ah
You don't expect returns from everything you do.
妳 真的 很 喜歡 學 大人 講道 理 耶
nǐ  zhēn de  hěn  xǐ huan  xué  dà rén  jiǎng dào  lǐ  yé
you  Really  very  like  learning  grown ups  sermon  reason  ye
You really like to pitch high notes like adults, don't you?
像 你 這麼 幼稚 對 你的 人生 一點 幫助 也沒有
xiàng  nǐ  zhè me  yòu zhì  duì  nǐ de  rén shēng  yī diǎn  bāng zhù  yě méi yǒu
like  you  so  naive  to  your  life  a little  help  nor
It will be no help to your life whatsoever if you continue to be so childish like this.
妳 又 沒 做 過
nǐ  yòu  méi  zuò  guò
you  and  not  work  too
How would you know
妳 怎麼 知道
nǐ  zěn me  zhī dào
you  how  know
if you've never been childish ever?
很多 事 不用 做 就 知道 沒有 意義 啊
hěn duō  shì  bù yòng  zuò  jiù  zhī dào  méi yǒu  yì yì  a
a lot of  thing  No need to  work  just  know  No  meaning  ah
You know something is meaningless without trying it.
爛斃 了
làn bì  le
rotten  is
This is shit.
來 下一 隊
lái  xià yī  duì
come  next  team
Next group
聽說 被 殭屍 咬 到 也會 變 殭屍
tīng shuō  bèi  jiāng shī  yǎo  dào  yě huì  biàn  jiāng shī
heard  by  zombie  bite  to  Will also be  change  zombie
I heard you will become a zombie if you are bitten by one
我 不 相信 這 件事
wǒ  bù  xiāng xìn  zhè  jiàn shì
I  no  Believe  this  Something
I don't buy that.
這 件事 一定 是 假的 啊
zhè  jiàn shì  yī dìng  shì  jiǎ de  a
this  Something  for sure  is  fake  ah
This must be some rumors.
可是 我 覺得 一定 是有 個 依據 他 才會 講
kě shì  wǒ  jué de  yī dìng  shì yǒu  ge  yī jù  tā  cái huì  jiǎng
but  I  feel  for sure  there is  piece  basis  he  Will only  speak
But he had to learn this from somewhere, right?
怎麼辦
zěn me bàn
How to do
What are we going to do?
喂
wèi
hey
Hey.
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
What?
你 有沒有 聽到 大家 最近 都 在 聊 的 傳說 啊
nǐ  yǒu méi yǒu  tīng dào  dà jiā  zuì jìn  dōu  zài  liáo  de  chuán shuō  a
you  do you have  Hear it  everyone  recent  all  in  somewhat  of  legend  ah
Have you heard that rumor lately?
我 很 帥 這 件事 已經 變 傳說 囉
wǒ  hěn  shuài  zhè  jiàn shì  yǐ jīng  biàn  chuán shuō  luō
I  very  handsome  this  Something  already  change  legend  eh
You mean the one that every girl wants to date me?
白癡
bái chī
idiot
Moron.
好啦 幹嘛
hǎo la  gàn ma
Okay  what
Okay, what is it?
聽說 有 一批 大陸 偷渡客 偷渡 到一 半就 淹死 了
tīng shuō  yǒu  yī pī  dà lù  tōu dù kè  tōu dù  dào yī  bàn jiù  yān sǐ  le
heard  have  Batch  mainland  stowaways  smuggling  To one  Half up  Drowned  is
I heard some stowaways from China were drowned.
屍體 被 衝上岸 後
shī tǐ  bèi  chōng shàng àn  hòu
Corpse  by  washed ashore  after
And they had became zombies
都 變成 殭屍 了 耶
dōu  biàn chéng  jiāng shī  le  yé
all  become  zombie  is  ye
after their bodies were washed up on shore.
喔 你 說 那 群 殭屍 喔
ō  nǐ  shuō  nà  qún  jiāng shī  ō
oh  you  say  that  group  zombie  oh
Oh! Those zombies
我 知道 啊
wǒ  zhī dào  a
I  know  ah
I've heard about them.
他們 就 沿路 一直 跳 一直 跳 一直 跳
tā men  jiù  yán lù  yī zhí  tiào  yī zhí  tiào  yī zhí  tiào
they  just  Along the way  Always  jump  Always  jump  Always  jump
They jumped, jumped and jumped all the way here.
媽 啦
mā  la
mother  la
Shit.
那是 真的 嗎
nà shì  zhēn de  ma
That is  Really  ?
Are you for real?
廢話
fèi huà
nonsense
Of course.
一堆 人 晚上 不 睡覺 在 山 上 跳跳 跳
yī duī  rén  wǎn shàng  bù  shuì jiào  zài  shān  shàng  tiào tiào  tiào
pile  man  at night  no  go to bed  in  mountain  on  Jumping  jump
With whole bunch of people jumping around up in the hills at night
不是 殭屍 是什麼
bù shì  jiāng shī  shì shén me
not  zombie  What is it?
what do you think they are?
我 記得 前 幾天 報紙 也有 寫 吧
wǒ  jì de  qián  jǐ tiān  bào zhǐ  yě yǒu  xiě  ba
I  remember  before  A few days  newspaper  There are also  write  !
Yes, I remember seeing that on the newspaper a few days ago.
如果 他們 努力 一點 的 話
rú guǒ  tā men  nǔ lì  yī diǎn  de  huà
if  they  Effort  a little  of  speech
If they jumped harder
現在 應該 已經 跳到 八卦山 了
xiàn zài  yīng gāi  yǐ jīng  tiào dào  bā guà shān  le
now  should  already  Jump to  Baguashan Mountain  is
they should have reached Baguashan Mountain by now.
怎樣 要 去 看 嗎
zěn yàng  yào  qù  kàn  ma
how  want  go  look  ?
So, do you want to see them?
誰 要 去 看 啊
sheí  yào  qù  kàn  a
who  want  go  look  ah
No way
可是 就算 是 真的 要 看 也看 不 到 吧
kě shì  jiù suàn  shì  zhēn de  yào  kàn  yě kàn  bù  dào  ba
but  Even if  is  Really  want  look  See also  no  to  !
I don't think you can see them even if they are real.
說不定 他們 在 八卦山 上 迷了 路
shuō bu dìng  tā men  zài  bā guà shān  shàng  mí le  lù
maybe  they  in  Baguashan Mountain  on  lost  road
Maybe they got lost in Baguashan Mountain
就 直接 跳進 彰化 市 區 了 啊
jiù  zhí jiē  tiào jìn  zhāng huà  shì  qū  le  a
just  direct  jump into  Changhua  city  area  is  ah
and jumped directly into Changhua city.
別說 不可能
bié shuō  bù kě néng
Do not say  impossible
Don't think it's impossible.
殭屍 又 沒有 方向 感
jiāng shī  yòu  méi yǒu  fāng xiàng  gǎn
zombie  and  No  direction  feel
Zombies don't have a sense of direction.
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
What?
你 最近 跟 沈佳宜 好像 很有 話聊
nǐ  zuì jìn  gēn  chén jiā yí  hǎo xiàng  hěn yǒu  huà liáo
you  recent  with  Shen Chia-Yi  like  Very much  talk
You and Shen Chia-Yi seem to have a lot to talk about lately.
幫 我 一個 忙
bāng  wǒ  yī gè  máng
help  I  One  busy
Do me a favor.
該 不會 是
gāi  bù huì  shì
should  will not  is
No way.
寫 情書 這種 爛 梗 吧
xiě  qíng shū  zhè zhǒng  làn  gěng  ba
write  love letter  this kind  bad  stem  !
Don't tell me you want to write a love letter?
你 寫好
nǐ  xiě hǎo
you  Write well
You write it
我 照抄
wǒ  zhào chāo
I  copy
and I copy it
可是 一 瓶 飲料 好像 不夠 耶
kě shì  yī  píng  yǐn liào  hǎo xiàng  bù gòu  yé
but  one  jug  Drink  like  not enough  ye
I don't think one drink is enough
幫 我 告白 成功 的 話
bāng  wǒ  gào bái  chéng gōng  de  huà
help  I  confess  success  of  speech
if she says yes
我 請 你 一年 份
wǒ  qǐng  nǐ  yī nián  fèn
I  please  you  A year  portion
I will buy you one year worth.
加 一張 Grant Hill 100: 1 明星 賽 球員 卡
jiā  yī zhāng  Grant  Hill  100:  1  míng xīng  sài  qiú yuán  kǎ
increase  One  Grant  Hill  100:  1  Celebrity  compete  player  card
Plus a Grant Hill 100:1 All-Star Card.
好 一言為定
hǎo  yī yán wéi dìng
good  a deal
Alright, deal.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
Ko Ching-Teng.
你 晚上 有沒有 要 補習
nǐ  wǎn shàng  yǒu méi yǒu  yào  bǔ xí
you  at night  do you have  want  cram school
Are you going to cram school tonight?
補個 屁 呀
bǔ gè  pì  ya
make up  fart  yeah
What for?
你 這麼 笨 還不 補習
nǐ  zhè me  bèn  hái bù  bǔ xí
you  so  foolish  Not yet  cram school
You are so dumb, how can you not go!
你 管 我
nǐ  guǎn  wǒ
you  manage  I
Mind your own business.
今天 晚上 開始
jīn tiān  wǎn shàng  kāi shǐ
today  at night  Start
Starting tonight
你 留 在 學校 唸書
nǐ  liú  zài  xué xiào  niàn shū
you  stop  in  school  study
you stay here and study after school.
晚上 留 校
wǎn shàng  liú  xiào
at night  stop  school
Stay at school?
有沒有 搞錯 啊
yǒu méi yǒu  gǎo cuò  a
do you have  wrong  ah
What's your problem?
我 也會 留 啊
wǒ  yě huì  liú  a
I  Will also be  stop  ah
I will stay, too.
哪 招 啊
nǎ  zhāo  a
where  trick  ah
What the hell?
原來 沈佳宜 只要 沒有 補習
yuán lái  chén jiā yí  zhǐ yào  méi yǒu  bǔ xí
original  Shen Chia-Yi  as long as  No  cram school
It turned out that Shen Chia-Yi stayed behind to study
都 會 一個人 留 在 學校 唸書
dōu  huì  yī gè rén  liú  zài  xué xiào  niàn shū
all  can  A person  stop  in  school  study
when she didn't have to go to cram school.
欸 你 是不是 怕 那 群 偷渡 上岸 的 殭屍 跳到 這裡
āi  nǐ  shì bù shì  pà  nà  qún  tōu dù  shàng àn  de  jiāng shī  tiào dào  zhè lǐ
sigh  you  isn't it  fear  that  group  smuggling  Ashore  of  zombie  Jump to  Here
So, you asked me to stay behind at school with you
才 叫 我 陪 你 啊
cái  jiào  wǒ  péi  nǐ  a
only  call  I  accompany  you  ah
only because you are afraid of those zombies, right?
我 是 怕 你 笨
wǒ  shì  pà  nǐ  bèn
I  is  fear  you  foolish
I am just worried you're getting stupid.
對了
duì le
correct
Right.
這裡 有 封信 是 老曹 叫 我 拿給 你的
zhè lǐ  yǒu  fēng xìn  shì  lǎo cáo  jiào  wǒ  ná gěi  nǐ de
Here  have  Letter  is  Tsao  call  I  Show it  your
Tsao asked me to give you this letter.
我 親愛 的 沈佳宜 同學
wǒ  qīn ài  de  chén jiā yí  tóng xué
I  dear  of  Shen Chia-Yi  classmate
My dear Shen Chia-Yi
我 很 喜歡 你
wǒ  hěn  xǐ huan  nǐ
I  very  like  you
I like you very much.
俗話說 ： Nothing' s gonna change my love for you
sú huà shuō  ：  Nothing'  s  gonna  change  my  love  for  you
As the saying goes  ：  Nothing'  s  gonna  change  my  love  for  you
As the song goes, "Nothing's gonna change my love for you.
Making love out of nothing at all
勉強 可以 表達 我 對 你的 感覺
miǎn qiáng  kě yǐ  biǎo dá  wǒ  duì  nǐ de  gǎn jué
reluctantly  can  expression  I  to  your  feel
barely expresses my feelings for you.
這 是 你的 字 耶
zhè  shì  nǐ de  zì  yé
this  is  your  letter  ye
This is your handwriting.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
我 不得不 說 耶
wǒ  bù dé bù  shuō  yé
I  have to  say  ye
I must say
你 寫 情書 的 文筆 真的 很 差 耶
nǐ  xiě  qíng shū  de  wén bǐ  zhēn de  hěn  chà  yé
you  write  love letter  of  writing  Really  very  different  ye
you suck at writing love letters.
哪 可能
nǎ  kě néng
where  may
What do you mean?
明明 就 寫 得 氣勢 非凡 好不好
míng míng  jiù  xiě  dé  qì shì  fēi fán  hǎo bù hǎo
Obviously  just  write  get  momentum  extraordinary  ok
I am that close to William Shakespeare, okay?
有時間 幫 人家 寫 情書 啊
yǒu shí jiān  bāng  rén jiā  xiě  qíng shū  a
Have time  help  People  write  love letter  ah
Since you have the time to write love letters for someone else.
不如 用 這些 時間 拿去 背 單字
bù rú  yòng  zhè xiē  shí jiān  ná qù  bèi  dān zì
Not as well  use  these  time  Take it  revise  word
Why don't you use the time to memorize some English vocabulary?
說 真的
shuō  zhēn de
say  Really
Ok.
雖然 我 很 帥 人 聰明 又會 講 笑話
suī rán  wǒ  hěn  shuài  rén  cōng míng  yòu huì  jiǎng  xiào huà
although  I  very  handsome  man  clever  Will again  speak  joke
Even though I am cute, smart and incredibly humorous
但 妳 不要 輕易 的 喜歡 上 我
dàn  nǐ  bù yào  qīng yì  de  xǐ huan  shàng  wǒ
only  you  Do not  easily  of  like  on  I
don't fall in love with me easily.
因為 我 是 孤獨 的 風 中一 匹狼
yīn wèi  wǒ  shì  gū dú  de  fēng  zhōng yī  pǐ láng
because  I  is  lonely  of  wind  In one  Wolf
Because I am a lone wolf traveling in the wild wind.
謝謝 喔
xiè xiè  ō
Thank you  oh
Oh, thanks
我 又 不喜歡 比 我 笨 的 男生
wǒ  yòu  bù xǐ huan  bǐ  wǒ  bèn  de  nán shēng
I  and  dislike  than  I  foolish  of  boy
I'm not interested in guys who are dumber than me.
沈佳宜 不喜歡 比 她 笨 的 男生
chén jiā yí  bù xǐ huan  bǐ  tā  bèn  de  nán shēng
Shen Chia-Yi  dislike  than  she  foolish  of  boy
Shen Chia-Yi doesn't like guys that are dumber than her.
笨
bèn
foolish
Dumb?
我 是 怕 搶了 妳 全 校 第一 名 的 頭銜
wǒ  shì  pà  qiǎng le  nǐ  quán  xiào  dì yī  míng  de  tóu xián
I  is  fear  Robbed  you  whole  school  first  name  of  title
Come on, I let you win on purpose
才 一直 忍 妳 讓 妳
cái  yī zhí  rěn  nǐ  ràng  nǐ
only  Always  endure  you  allow  you
I don't study hard cause I don't want to beat you
故意 輸 給 妳 好不好
gù yì  shū  gěi  nǐ  hǎo bù hǎo
deliberately  lose  give  you  ok
and I don't want to hurt your feelings!
這 怎麼 好意思 啊
zhè  zěn me  hǎo yì si  a
this  how  Sorry  ah
Pardon me.
拜託 你 不用 這麼 忍耐
bài tuō  nǐ  bù yòng  zhè me  rěn nài
please  you  No need to  so  patience
Save your kindness, mister. You are welcome to try to beat me anytime!
敢不敢 跟 我 打一 個 賭
gǎn bù gǎn  gēn  wǒ  dǎ yī  ge  dǔ
dare  with  I  Hit one  piece  bet
I dare you to bet with me.
賭
dǔ
bet
Let's bet on...
頭髮
tóu fà
hair
Your hair.
怎麼 賭
zěn me  dǔ
how  bet
How?
如果 妳 月 考考 贏 我 的 話
rú guǒ  nǐ  yuè  kǎo kǎo  yíng  wǒ  de  huà
if  you  moon  exam  win  I  of  speech
If you beat me in the next midterm
妳 要 怎麼 整 我 都 可以
nǐ  yào  zěn me  zhěng  wǒ  dōu  kě yǐ
you  want  how  whole  I  all  can
you can do whatever you want to me.
但 如果 我 考 贏 妳 的 話
dàn  rú guǒ  wǒ  kǎo  yíng  nǐ  de  huà
only  if  I  examine  win  you  of  speech
But, if I won
妳 要 綁 一個月 的 馬尾
nǐ  yào  bǎng  yī ge yuè  de  mǎ wěi
you  want  tie  a month  of  ponytail
you will have to wear a ponytail for a month.
隨便 啊
suí biàn  a
casual  ah
Sure, whatever.
反正 又 不可能
fǎn zhèng  yòu  bù kě néng
Anyway  and  impossible
It's not like you would win anyway!
這種 超 雞巴 的 自信 我 又 被 電 到了
zhè zhǒng  chāo  jī bā  de  zì xìn  wǒ  yòu  bèi  diàn  dào le
this kind  super  cock  of  confidence  I  and  by  electricity  Arrived
I was struck by her cocky confidence right away.
喂
wèi
hey
Hey, you.
三 更 半夜 不 睡覺
sān  gèng  bàn yè  bù  shuì jiào
three  more  midnight  no  go to bed
Why on earth you need to study freaking English
背 什麼 死人 骨頭 英文
bèi  shén me  sǐ rén  gǔ tou  yīng wén
revise  what  dead  bone  English
in the middle of the night?
I fuck you
I fuck you too
I fuck your mother.
你 幹嘛 幹嘛 啦
nǐ  gàn ma  gàn ma  la
you  what  what  la
What's wrong with you?
Fuck you fuck you
I love you
I LOVE YOU
老闆
lǎo bǎn
boss
Hey, Ma'am.
來 碗 超 帥 的 光頭
lái  wǎn  chāo  shuài  de  guāng tóu
come  bowl  super  handsome  of  Bald head
A super hot and charming jar head, please.
三八啦 光頭 哪有 帥 的
sān bā la  guāng tóu  nǎ yǒu  shuài  de
idiot  Bald head  How can there be  handsome  of
Idiot, how can a jar head be handsome?
有 啦
yǒu  la
have  la
Of course there is.
不信 你 剪剪 看
bù xìn  nǐ  jiǎn jiǎn  kàn
Do not believe  you  cut  look
Give it a try if you don't believe me.
不 欠 你 啦
bù  qiàn  nǐ  la
no  owe  you  la
Here, I don't owe you any more.
不要 弄 啦
bù yào  nòng  la
Do not  do  la
Stop that.
我 在 補習班 聽說
wǒ  zài  bǔ xí bān  tīng shuō
I  in  cram school  heard
Rumor has it that Inoue Takehiko has died a couple weeks ago!
井上雄彥 啊 前 幾個 禮拜 出車禍 死了
jǐng shàng xióng yàn  a  qián  jǐ gè  lǐ bài  chū chē huò  sǐ le
Inoue Takehiko  ah  before  several  worship  car accident  died
I heard that he died in a car accident.
是 喔
shì  ō
is  oh
Really.
難怪 我 感覺 他 畫 風 有 點 變
nán guài  wǒ  gǎn jué  tā  huà  fēng  yǒu  diǎn  biàn
No wonder  I  feel  he  draw  wind  have  point  change
No wonder I felt something was different in his drawing style.
突然 變 強 而已 這種 天才 怎麼 可能 說 死 就 死 啊
tú rán  biàn  qiáng  ér yǐ  zhè zhǒng  tiān cái  zěn me  kě néng  shuō  sǐ  jiù  sǐ  a
suddenly  change  strong  Just now  this kind  genius  how  may  say  die  just  die  ah
More powerful that is, how can such a genius die just like that.
你 覺不覺 得
nǐ  jué bù jué  dé
you  don't think  get
Don't you think...
覺得 怎樣
jué de  zěn yàng
feel  how
Think What?
你 覺不覺 得 沈佳宜 有 點 喜歡 我
nǐ  jué bù jué  dé  chén jiā yí  yǒu  diǎn  xǐ huan  wǒ
you  don't think  get  Shen Chia-Yi  have  point  like  I
Don't you think Shen Chia-Yi likes me?
不然 今天 怎麼 綁 馬尾
bù rán  jīn tiān  zěn me  bǎng  mǎ wěi
otherwise  today  how  tie  ponytail
If not, why would she wear a ponytail today?
也許 喔
yě xǔ  ō
Maybe  oh
Maybe!
沈佳宜 怎麼 知道 我 喜歡 綁 馬尾 的 女生 啊
chén jiā yí  zěn me  zhī dào  wǒ  xǐ huan  bǎng  mǎ wěi  de  nǚ shēng  a
Shen Chia-Yi  how  know  I  like  tie  ponytail  of  Girls  ah
How did Shen Chia-Yi know I like girls who wear ponytails?
是嗎
shì ma
is it
You too?
我 一直 一直 都 很 喜歡 綁 馬尾 的 女生 啊
wǒ  yī zhí  yī zhí  dōu  hěn  xǐ huan  bǎng  mǎ wěi  de  nǚ shēng  a
I  Always  Always  all  very  like  tie  ponytail  of  Girls  ah
I always like girls who wear ponytails.
我 也 是
wǒ  yě  shì
I  also  is
So do!
我 不知道 沈佳宜 為什麼 贏了 還要 綁 馬尾
wǒ  bù zhī dào  chén jiā yí  wèi shén me  yíng le  hái yào  bǎng  mǎ wěi
I  do not know  Shen Chia-Yi  why  Won  But also  tie  ponytail
I don't know why Shen Chia-Yi wore a ponytail that day even though she won the bet.
但 從此 以後
dàn  cóng cǐ  yǐ hòu
only  Since then  after
However, ever since then
努力 用功 讀書 竟然 變成 一件 非常 熱血 的 事
nǔ lì  yòng gōng  dú shū  jìng rán  biàn chéng  yī jiàn  fēi cháng  rè xiè  de  shì
Effort  work hard  reading  actually  become  One  very much  enthusiastic  of  thing
studying hard had become an enthusiastic thing for me.
幾 千 塊 錢 的 班 費 不見了
jǐ  qiān  kuài  qián  de  bān  fèi  bù jiàn le
some  thousand  piece  money  of  class  expenses  gone
The class funds went missing.
第六 節課 的時候 班長 檢查 還 在
dì liù  jié kè  de shí hòu  bān zhǎng  jiǎn chá  hái  zài
sixth  class  when  Squad leader  an examination  still  in
It was still here when the class leader checked about an hour ago.
現在 要 放學 了
xiàn zài  yào  fàng xué  le
now  want  school out  is
Now school is almost finished.
偷錢 的 人 還會 有 誰
tōu qián  de  rén  hái huì  yǒu  sheí
Stealing money  of  man  Will also be  have  who
Who else could have stolen that money?
一定 是 你們 班 上 自己 的 同學
yī dìng  shì  nǐ men  bān  shàng  zì jǐ  de  tóng xué
for sure  is  you  class  on  self  of  classmate
It must be someone sitting in this classroom!
把 錢 偷走 的 再不 自 首 的 話
bǎ  qián  tōu zǒu  de  zài bu  zì  shǒu  de  huà
take  money  Stolen  of  No again  self  first  of  speech
Whoever stole that money, you better turn yourself in right now.
就 不要 怪 教官 不 客氣
jiù  bù yào  guài  jiào guān  bù  kè qì
just  Do not  strange  Instructor  no  polite
Otherwise, don't blame me for being too harsh afterwards.
好
hǎo
good
Fine.
不敢 承認 也沒有 關係
bù gǎn  chéng rèn  yě méi yǒu  guān xì
Dare not  recognition  nor  relationship
It's okay if no one wants to admit it
反正 這個 小偷 就 在 你們 這個 班 上
fǎn zhèng  zhè ge  xiǎo tōu  jiù  zài  nǐ men  zhè ge  bān  shàng
Anyway  This one  Thief  just  in  you  This one  class  on
I guarantee that the thief is sitting right here in this room.
他 一定 覺得 自己 很 聰明
tā  yī dìng  jué de  zì jǐ  hěn  cōng míng
he  for sure  feel  self  very  clever
The person must thinks that he can get away with this.
好
hǎo
good
Good
很好
hěn hǎo
well
very good.
現在 每一個 人 把 紙 筆 拿出來
xiàn zài  měi yī gè  rén  bǎ  zhǐ  bǐ  ná chū lái
now  every  man  take  paper  pen  take it out
Now, take out your pen, everyone.
寫下 你 認為 可能是 小偷 的 人 的 名字
xiě xià  nǐ  rèn wéi  kě néng shì  xiǎo tōu  de  rén  de  míng zì
Write down  you  think  maybe  Thief  of  man  of  first name
And write down the name of the person that you think it's most likely to be the thief.
投 票 結果 前 三 名
tóu  piào  jié guǒ  qián  sān  míng
throw  ticket  result  before  three  name
The top three named
把 書包 倒 在 講台 上 讓 我 檢查
bǎ  shū bāo  dào  zài  jiǎng tái  shàng  ràng  wǒ  jiǎn chá
take  schoolbag  pour  in  Podium  on  allow  I  an examination
will have to bring your bags forward, and I will check them personally.
立刻
lì kè
Immediately
Now!
馬上 把 隨堂測 驗 紙 拿出來
mǎ shàng  bǎ  suí táng cè  yàn  zhǐ  ná chū lái
immediately  take  with test  test  paper  take it out
Take out your paper right now.
曹國勝
cáo guó shèng
Tsao Kuo-Sheng
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
你 幹什麼
nǐ  gàn shén me
you  what are you doing?
What are you doing?
教官
jiào guān
Instructor
Sir.
你 憑 什麼 叫 我們 懷疑 自己 的 同學
nǐ  píng  shén me  jiào  wǒ men  huái yí  zì jǐ  de  tóng xué
you  because of  what  call  us  doubt  self  of  classmate
Who do you think you are to have us suspect our own classmates?
我 是 教官 還 是 你 是 教官
wǒ  shì  jiào guān  hái  shì  nǐ  shì  jiào guān
I  is  Instructor  still  is  you  is  Instructor
Now who is the supervisor? Are you or am I?
你 是 教官
nǐ  shì  jiào guān
you  is  Instructor
You are, sir.
但 你 是個 爛 人 啦
dàn  nǐ  shì gè  làn  rén  la
only  you  Is  bad  man  la
But you are an ass hole!
你 說 什麼
nǐ  shuō  shén me
you  say  what
What did you say?
我 說你 爛 人
wǒ  shuō nǐ  làn  rén
I  saying you  bad  man
I said you are an asshole.
柯景騰 曹國勝
kē jǐng téng  cáo guó shèng
Ko Ching-Teng  Tsao Kuo-Sheng
Ko Ching-Teng, Tsao Kuo-Sheng
我 看 你們 兩個 是 做賊 心虛
wǒ  kàn  nǐ men  liǎng gè  shì  zuò zéi  xīn xū
I  look  you  two  is  thief  guilty
I think you guys are bluffing
把 你們 的 書包 給 我 拿 過來 第一個 檢查
bǎ  nǐ men  de  shū bāo  gěi  wǒ  ná  guò lái  dì yī ge  jiǎn chá
take  you  of  schoolbag  give  I  take  come  the first  an examination
bring your bags now and I will check yours first.
報告 教官
bào gào  jiào guān
report  Instructor
Excuse me, Sir.
你 不可以 這樣
nǐ  bù kě yǐ  zhè yàng
you  Can not  such
You have no right to do that
不可以 怎麼樣
bù kě yǐ  zěn me yàng
Can not  how is it
I have no right to do what?
不可以 叫 我們 投 這種 票
bù kě yǐ  jiào  wǒ men  tóu  zhè zhǒng  piào
Can not  call  us  throw  this kind  ticket
You can't ask us to write down names and vote on such a thing.
不可以 叫 我們 懷疑 自己 的 同學
bù kě yǐ  jiào  wǒ men  huái yí  zì jǐ  de  tóng xué
Can not  call  us  doubt  self  of  classmate
You can't ask us to suspect our own classmates.
大 不了 大家 再把 錢 繳 一次 就 好了
dà  bù liǎo  dà jiā  zài bǎ  qián  jiǎo  yī cì  jiù  hǎo le
big  No more  everyone  Again  money  deliver  once  just  All right
We can just all pay the fees again.
這 也 沒什麼
zhè  yě  méi shén me
this  also  it's nothing
It's no big deal.
對 啊
duì  a
to  ah
Exactly.
再 繳 一次 就 好了 嘛
zài  jiǎo  yī cì  jiù  hǎo le  ma
again  deliver  once  just  All right  ma
We can just pay again.
妳 不要 以為 你 成績 好 說 什麼 都 沒有關係
nǐ  bù yào  yǐ wéi  nǐ  chéng jī  hǎo  shuō  shén me  dōu  méi yǒu guān xì
you  Do not  think  you  results  good  say  what  all  It does not matter
Being an honor student doesn't mean that you can say whatever you want.
把 你的 書包 拿 過來
bǎ  nǐ de  shū bāo  ná  guò lái
take  your  schoolbag  take  come
Bring your bag over here.
我們 不要
wǒ men  bù yào
us  Do not
No way.
我們 又 不是 小偷
wǒ men  yòu  bù shì  xiǎo tōu
us  and  not  Thief
We are not thieves.
爛 人
làn  rén
bad  man
Douche.
你 說 什麼
nǐ  shuō  shén me
you  say  what
What did you say?
爛 人 啦
làn  rén  la
bad  man  la
I said you are a douchebag.
統統 把 書包 給 我 拿 過來
tǒng tǒng  bǎ  shū bāo  gěi  wǒ  ná  guò lái
all  take  schoolbag  give  I  take  come
Bring your bags over now, all of you.
不要
bù yào
Do not
No.
教官
jiào guān
Instructor
Sir
我 現在 合理 的 懷疑 你 沒有 小雞雞
wǒ  xiàn zài  hé lǐ  de  huái yí  nǐ  méi yǒu  xiǎo jī jī
I  now  reasonable  of  doubt  you  No  dick
I now suspect that you have no balls.
褲子 脫下
kù zi  tuō xià
pants  Take off
Take your pants off now.
你 說 什麼
nǐ  shuō  shén me
you  say  what
What did you say?
褲子 脫下 啦
kù zi  tuō xià  la
pants  Take off  la
Take your pants off.
把 書包 拿 過來
bǎ  shū bāo  ná  guò lái
take  schoolbag  take  come
Bring your bags over.
要 就 給 你 啦
yào  jiù  gěi  nǐ  la
want  just  give  you  la
Fine, here you go!
你們 不要 一直 看 我
nǐ men  bù yào  yī zhí  kàn  wǒ
you  Do not  Always  look  I
Stop staring at me.
我 覺得很 丟臉
wǒ  jué de hěn  diū liǎn
I  Feel very  Lose face
It's very embarrassing. I feel so ashamed.
一點 都 不丟 臉 啊
yī diǎn  dōu  bù diū  liǎn  a
a little  all  Not lost  face  ah
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
妳 超 厲害 的 耶
nǐ  chāo  lì hài  de  yé
you  super  awesome  of  ye
You kicked ass!
半 蹲 不用 太 認真 啦
bàn  dūn  bù yòng  tài  rèn zhēn  la
half  squat  No need to  very  serious  la
Don't need to be too serious about this.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
稍微 休息 一下
shāo wéi  xiū xí  yí xià
a little  rest  a bit
Relax a bit.
蹲個 意思意思 就 好了 啊
dūn gè  yì sī yì sī  jiù  hǎo le  a
squatting  meaning  just  All right  ah
Just pretend, it's no big deal.
反正 那些 老師 根本 沒 在 看
fǎn zhèng  nà xiē  lǎo shī  gēn běn  méi  zài  kàn
Anyway  those  teacher  simply  not  in  look
Those teachers are not watching anyway.
偶 爾 當 一下 壞 學生 很 爽 的
ǒu  ěr  dāng  yí xià  huài  xué shēng  hěn  shuǎng  de
accidentally  you  that  a bit  bad  student  very  happy  of
It's kind of nice to be a bad student once in a while, isn't it?
好 丟臉
hǎo  diū liǎn
good  Lose face
I am so ashamed.
認識 妳 從 國中 到 現在
rèn shi  nǐ  cóng  guó zhōng  dào  xiàn zài
know  you  from  secondary  to  now
Ever since I knew you from junior high
剛剛 是 我 唯 一 覺得 妳 比 我 厲害 的時候
gāng gāng  shì  wǒ  wéi  yī  jué de  nǐ  bǐ  wǒ  lì hài  de shí hòu
just  is  I  only  one  feel  you  than  I  awesome  when
that was the only time I was amazed by how tough you really are.
沈佳宜 妳 超正 點 的 耶
chén jiā yí  nǐ  chāo zhèng  diǎn  de  yé
Shen Chia-Yi  you  awesome  point  of  ye
Shen Chia-Yi, you rock!
哭 起來 也 超正 的
kū  qǐ lái  yě  chāo zhèng  de
weep  stand up  also  awesome  of
You look so pretty even when you cry.
對 啊
duì  a
to  ah
Yeah.
超正 的
chāo zhèng  de
awesome  of
Super duper cool.
令人 刮目相看
lìng rén  guā mù xiāng kàn
It is  admiration
Unbelievably cool.
不像 考卷 所有 複雜 困難 的 問題 都 能 得到 一個 解答
bù xiàng  kǎo juǎn  suǒ yǒu  fù zá  kùn nán  de  wèn tí  dōu  néng  dé dào  yī gè  jiě dá
Not like  Test paper  all  complex  difficult  of  problem  all  can  get  One  answer
Unlike quizzes
真實 人生 裡有 些事 永遠 也沒有 答案
zhēn shí  rén shēng  li yǒu  xiē shì  yǒng yuǎn  yě méi yǒu  dá àn
real  life  inside  Some things  forever  nor  answer
you never find a correct answer in life.
到底是 誰 偷了 班 費 沒有 人 知道
dào dǐ shì  sheí  tōu le  bān  fèi  méi yǒu  rén  zhī dào
In the end is  who  Stolen  class  expenses  No  man  know
No one really knew who stole our money, but no one really cared.
只 記得 那天 的 沈佳宜 真的
zhǐ  jì de  nèi tiān  de  chén jiā yí  zhēn de
only  remember  That day  of  Shen Chia-Yi  Really
All I remembered from that day was Shen Chia-Yi's face
好 美好 美
hǎo  měi hǎo  měi
good  Beautiful  beautiful
beautifully and delicately engraved in my heart.
六年 前 剛剛 踏進 精誠 中學 國中 部 的時候
liù nián  qián  gāng gāng  tà jìn  jīng chéng  zhōng xué  guó zhōng  bù  de shí hòu
Six years  before  just  enter  Jingcheng  junior high  secondary  part  when
Six years ago, when we first stepped in to Jing-Cheng high school
十二歲 的 我們 懵懵 懂懂
shí èr suì  de  wǒ men  měng měng  dǒng dǒng
Twelve years old  of  us  ignorant  understand
we were all young and immature.
雖然 對於 未來 有 無限 的 想像
suī rán  duì wū  wèi lái  yǒu  wú xiàn  de  xiǎng xiàng
although  for  future  have  unlimited  of  imagine
Although we had great dreams about our future
卻 不知道 能 在 這裡 學習 到 什麼 收穫 到 什麼
què  bù zhī dào  néng  zài  zhè lǐ  xué xí  dào  shén me  shōu huò  dào  shén me
still  do not know  can  in  Here  Learn  to  what  reward  to  what
we weren't really sure what we were going to learn and encounter during these years.
幸 好 一路上 有 師 長 的 諄諄 教誨
xìng  hǎo  yī lù shàng  yǒu  shī  chǎng  de  zhūn zhūn  jiào huì
favor  good  Along the way  have  teacher  long  of  repeatedly  Teach
Thanks to the teachers who led us and furnished us with abundant knowledge.
同學 們也 建立 了 深厚 的 情誼
tóng xué  men yě  jiàn lì  le  shēn hòu  de  qíng yì
classmate  Also too  set up  is  deep  of  Friendship
Thanks to all the peers who accompanied us throughout the years
一起 經歷 困難 挫折 也 一起 攜 手 成長
yì qǐ  jīng lì  kùn nán  cuò zhé  yě  yì qǐ  xié  shǒu  chéng zhǎng
together  experience  difficult  frustration  also  together  carry  hand  growing up
with bitter and sweet memories.
我 說 精誠 中學 就是 我們 的 青春
wǒ  shuō  jīng chéng  zhōng xué  jiù shì  wǒ men  de  qīng chūn
I  say  Jingcheng  junior high  is  us  of  youth
Ching-Chen high school represents our young and crazy days
也 是 最美 好 的 行囊
yě  shì  zuì měi  hǎo  de  xíng nāng
also  is  most beautiful  good  of  Luggage
it gave us the most wonderful times of our life.
畢業 典禮 後
bì yè  diǎn lǐ  hòu
graduate  ceremony  after
From now on
讓 我們 用力 的 張開 翅膀 飛 向 各自 不同 的 夢想
ràng  wǒ men  yòng lì  de  zhāng kāi  chì bǎng  fēi  xiàng  gè zì  bù tóng  de  mèng xiǎng
allow  us  Forced  of  Open  wing  fly  toward  respective  different  of  dream
it's time for us to spread our wings and chase our dreams.
各位 同學
gè wèi  tóng xué
Everybody  classmate
So long, my friends.
我們 珍重 再見
wǒ men  zhēn zhòng  zài jiàn
us  treasure  Goodbye
So long, my friends.
真 羨慕 妳
zhēn  xiàn mù  nǐ
real  envy  you
How I envy you.
國中 三年 高中 三年 都 有 這麼 多 人 追 妳
guó zhōng  sān nián  gāo zhōng  sān nián  dōu  yǒu  zhè me  duō  rén  zhuī  nǐ
secondary  Three years  high school  Three years  all  have  so  much  man  pursue  you
You have so many guys chasing after you throughout the years!
被 喜歡 其實是 很不 錯
bèi  xǐ huan  qí shí shì  hěn bù  cuò
by  like  Actually  Very bad  error
Yes, it's quite nice to be liked by someone.
但是
dàn shì
but
But...
妳 該 不會 想說 被 這麼 多 人 追 其實 很 困擾 吧
nǐ  gāi  bù huì  xiǎng shuō  bèi  zhè me  duō  rén  zhuī  qí shí  hěn  kùn rǎo  ba
you  should  will not  Want to say  by  so  much  man  pursue  in fact  very  Troubled  !
Don't tell me that you feel annoyed because you are too popular.
不是 啦
bù shì  la
not  la
No
我 只是 覺得 自己 是個 很 幸福 的 人
wǒ  zhǐ shì  jué de  zì jǐ  shì gè  hěn  xìng fú  de  rén
I  just  feel  self  Is  very  happy  of  man
I just think that I am a very lucky girl.
那 妳 決定 好了 嗎
nà  nǐ  jué dìng  hǎo le  ma
that  you  Decision  All right  ?
So, have you decided?
決定 什麼
jué dìng  shén me
Decision  what
Decided what?
決定 跟 誰 在 一起 啊
jué dìng  gēn  sheí  zài  yì qǐ  a
Decision  with  who  in  together  ah
Decided whom you want to be with.
幹嘛 啊 連 我 都 不能 說 喔
gàn ma  a  lián  wǒ  dōu  bù néng  shuō  ō
what  ah  even  I  all  Can not  say  oh
Come on, you can't even tell me?
如果 …
rú guǒ  …
if  …
Ok, if...
… 我 會 很 高興 的
…  wǒ  huì  hěn  gāo xìng  de
…  I  can  very  happy  of
I will be really happy.
畢業 快樂
bì yè  kuài lè
graduate  happy
Happy graduation.
終於 聯考 了
zhōng wū  lián kǎo  le
at last  exam  is
Finally, the colleague entrance exam came.
對 我 來說 聯考 好像 不是 去 考 大學
duì  wǒ  lái shuō  lián kǎo  hǎo xiàng  bù shì  qù  kǎo  dà xué
to  I  For example  exam  like  not  go  examine  university
To me, the exam was more like a test for Shen Chia-Yi's special training programs
而是 驗 收 沈佳宜 對 我 的 特訓 成果
ér shì  yàn  shōu  chén jiā yí  duì  wǒ  de  tè xùn  chéng guǒ
Instead  test  collect  Shen Chia-Yi  to  I  of  training  Results
rather than an exam for college.
升 大學 前 最後 一個 夏天 的 主題 是 咸咸 的 海水
shēng  dà xué  qián  zuì hòu  yī gè  xià tiān  de  zhǔ tí  shì  xián xián  de  hǎi shuǐ
arise  university  before  At last  One  summer  of  theme  is  together  of  seawater
We spent most of our time at the beach during the summer before college.
真的 很 幼稚
zhēn de  hěn  yòu zhì
Really  very  naive
They are so childish
超 幼稚 的
chāo  yòu zhì  de
super  naive  of
I know, so childish.
你 應該 不太 喜歡 幼稚 的 男生 吧
nǐ  yīng gāi  bù tài  xǐ huan  yòu zhì  de  nán shēng  ba
you  should  Not too much  like  naive  of  boy  !
You don't really like childish guys, do you?
嗯
ń
umm
No.
那 你 覺得 裡面 誰 最 幼稚
nà  nǐ  jué de  lǐ miàn  sheí  zuì  yòu zhì
that  you  feel  inside  who  most  naive
Who do you think is the most childish one among them all.
柯騰 吧
kē téng  ba
Ko-Teng  !
Ko-Teng, maybe?
那 我 呢
nà  wǒ  ne
that  I  this
How about me?
你 很 幼稚 耶
nǐ  hěn  yòu zhì  yé
you  very  naive  ye
You are so childish.
畢業 了 耶
bì yè  le  yé
graduate  is  ye
Now that we have graduated
你們 有沒有 想過 以後 要 幹嘛
nǐ men  yǒu méi yǒu  xiǎng guò  yǐ hòu  yào  gàn ma
you  do you have  Thought about it  after  want  what
have you thought about what you want to do in the future?
我 想去 科學 園區 上班
wǒ  xiǎng qù  kē xué  yuán qū  shàng bān
I  Want to go  Science  Park  to work
I want to work in the Hsinchu Science and Industrial Park
分股 票 賺 大 錢
fēn gǔ  piào  zhuàn  dà  qián
Share  ticket  earn  big  money
so I can get stocks for bonuses and tons of money.
然後 娶 沈佳宜
rán hòu  qǔ  chén jiā yí
then  marry  Shen Chia-Yi
And then I can marry Shen Chia-Yi...
或 胡家瑋
huò  hú jiā wěi
or  Hu Chia-Wei
or Hu Chia-Wei.
誰 要 嫁給 你 啊
sheí  yào  jià gěi  nǐ  a
who  want  Marry  you  ah
Who wants to marry you?
我 想 出國 唸書 耶
wǒ  xiǎng  chū guó  niàn shū  yé
I  think  Go abroad  study  ye
I want to study abroad.
你 出國 很 浪費 錢 啦
nǐ  chū guó  hěn  làng fèi  qián  la
you  Go abroad  very  waste  money  la
It'll be such a waste of money, okay?
你 靠腰 哦
nǐ  kào yāo  ó
you  cry  Oh
Oh, fuck off.
出國 唸書
chū guó  niàn shū
Go abroad  study
Study abroad?
我 也想 出國 唸書
wǒ  yě xiǎng  chū guó  niàn shū
I  also want  Go abroad  study
I want to study abroad, too.
去 申請 公費 留學 念 MBA
qù  shēn qǐng  gōng fèi  liú xué  niàn  MBA
go  apply  public  scholarship  study  MBA
Maybe I will apply for government scholarships and get an MBA degree
我 想 一直 打 籃球 下去 打進 校 隊
wǒ  xiǎng  yī zhí  dǎ  lán qiú  xià qù  dǎ jìn  xiào  duì
I  think  Always  hit  basketball  Go on  Scored on  school  team
I want to keep on playing basketball.
最後 打進 美國職籃
zuì hòu  dǎ jìn  měi guó zhí lán
At last  Scored on  NBA
And maybe one day make my way to NBA.
家瑋 呢
jiā wěi  ne
Chia-Wei  this
What about you, Chia-Wei?
我 啊
wǒ  a
I  ah
Me?
找個 有 錢 人 嫁 掉 就 好啦
zhǎo gè  yǒu  qián  rén  jià  diào  jiù  hǎo la
Find a  have  money  man  marry  out  just  Okay
I think I will find myself a rich man to marry.
干 你 屁 事
gàn  nǐ  pì  shì
oppose  you  fart  thing
Go away.
沈佳宜 咧
chén jiā yí  liě
Shen Chia-Yi  frown
What about you, Shen Chia-Yi?
我 對 自己 的 未來 其實 沒有 太多 想像
wǒ  duì  zì jǐ  de  wèi lái  qí shí  méi yǒu  tài duō  xiǎng xiàng
I  to  self  of  future  in fact  No  too much  imagine
I don't expect much about my future, really.
還有 一個人 還沒 說 耶
hái yǒu  yī gè rén  hái méi  shuō  yé
and also  A person  not yet  say  ye
Ko-Teng, it's your turn
我 想成 為一 個 很 厲害 的 人
wǒ  xiǎng chéng  wéi yī  ge  hěn  lì hài  de  rén
I  think of  For one  piece  very  awesome  of  man
I want to be a kickass person.
你 這 有 說 跟 沒說 根本 一樣 嘛
nǐ  zhè  yǒu  shuō  gēn  méi shuō  gēn běn  yī yàng  ma
you  this  have  say  with  Did not say  simply  same  ma
What are you talking about?
怎樣 才是 厲害 的 人 啊
zěn yàng  cái shì  lì hài  de  rén  a
how  Is it  awesome  of  man  ah
What is a kickass person?
讓 這個 世界 因為 有 了 我 而有 一點點 的 不 一樣
ràng  zhè ge  shì jiè  yīn wèi  yǒu  le  wǒ  ér yǒu  yī diǎn diǎn  de  bù  yī yàng
allow  This one  world  because  have  is  I  And there is  a little bit  of  no  same
I want the world to be a little bit better because of me.
而 我 的 世界 不過 就是 妳 的 心
ér  wǒ  de  shì jiè  bù guò  jiù shì  nǐ  de  xīn
and  I  of  world  but  is  you  of  heart
And you are the only person that is going to make my world better.
喂 幹嘛
wèi  gàn ma
hey  what
Hello. Yes?
我 只會 唸書
wǒ  zhǐ huì  niàn shū
I  Only will  study
I am a nerd
我 只會 唸書
wǒ  zhǐ huì  niàn shū
I  Only will  study
I am a bookworm.
從 國中 到 高中
cóng  guó zhōng  dào  gāo zhōng
from  secondary  to  high school
Ever since junior high and high school.
我 就 只會 唸書
wǒ  jiù  zhǐ huì  niàn shū
I  just  Only will  study
All I did was studying
卻 還 是 考 不好
què  hái  shì  kǎo  bù hǎo
still  still  is  examine  not good
I still screwed it up.
不管 妳 念 哪 間學校
bù guǎn  nǐ  niàn  nǎ  jiān xué xiào
Regardless of  you  study  where  School
No matter which university you go to
有 件事 我 想 跟 妳 說
yǒu  jiàn shì  wǒ  xiǎng  gēn  nǐ  shuō
have  Something  I  think  with  you  say
there is something that I want to say to you.
拜託 你
bài tuō  nǐ
please  you
Please.
不要 現在 跟 我 講 你 喜歡 我
bù yào  xiàn zài  gēn  wǒ  jiǎng  nǐ  xǐ huan  wǒ
Do not  now  with  I  speak  you  like  I
Don't tell me you like me now
我 喜歡 妳
wǒ  xǐ huan  nǐ
I  like  you
I do like you
妳 早就 知道了 啊
nǐ  zǎo jiù  zhī dào le  a
you  Long ago  Got it  ah
and you knew that already.
那 你 要 跟 我 說 什麼 啦
nà  nǐ  yào  gēn  wǒ  shuō  shén me  la
that  you  want  with  I  say  what  la
What do you want to tell me, then?
聯考 放榜了
lián kǎo  fàng bǎng le
exam  results released
The results were out.
阿和 考 上了 清大 經濟
ā hé  kǎo  shàng le  qīng dà  jīng jì
A-Ho  examine  On the  Tsing Hua  Economics
A-Ho got into Economics Major in National Tsing Hua University
朝 未來 出國 留學 的 路 邁進
cháo  wèi lái  chū guó  liú xué  de  lù  mài jìn
dynasty  future  Go abroad  scholarship  of  road  Move forward
which means he made one step forward to his overseas dream.
該邊 考 上了 逢甲 資工
gāi biān  kǎo  shàng le  féng jiǎ  zī gōng
groin  examine  On the  Feng Chia  Information Engineering
Groin got into Information Engineering at Feng Chia University
也 算是 踏上 了 科學 園區 之路
yě  suàn shì  tà shàng  le  kē xué  yuán qū  zhī lù
also  Be  set foot on  is  Science  Park  Road
to become one of those Science Park smart engineers.
老曹 呢 考 上了 成 大 化工
lǎo cáo  ne  kǎo  shàng le  chéng  dà  huà gōng
Tsao  this  examine  On the  completed  big  Chemical Engineering
Tsao got into Chemical Engineering at Cheng Kung University.
看 樣子 以後 要 去 美國職籃 是有 一點 難度
kàn  yàng zi  yǐ hòu  yào  qù  měi guó zhí lán  shì yǒu  yī diǎn  nán dù
look  Look like  after  want  go  NBA  there is  a little  difficult
So I guess it's most unlikely that he would make it into NBA.
沈佳宜 雖然 失常
chén jiā yí  suī rán  shī cháng
Shen Chia-Yi  although  abnormal
Although Shen Chia-Yi didn't do as well as she expected
但 還 是 考 上了 師範學院
dàn  hái  shì  kǎo  shàng le  shī fàn xué yuàn
only  still  is  examine  On the  Normal University
she still got into University of Education
想到 將來 沈佳宜 當 老師 的 樣子 就 覺得 非常 適合 她
xiǎng dào  jiāng lái  chén jiā yí  dāng  lǎo shī  de  yàng zi  jiù  jué de  fēi cháng  shì hé  tā
think  future  Shen Chia-Yi  that  teacher  of  Look like  just  feel  very much  Suitable for  she
I could totally imagine Shen Chia-Yi being a teacher, it really suits her.
送 你
sòng  nǐ
send  you
Here, for you.
這 什麼
zhè  shén me
this  what
What is this?
我 自己 畫 的
wǒ  zì jǐ  huà  de
I  self  draw  of
I drew it myself.
有 點 醜
yǒu  diǎn  chǒu
have  point  ugly
Not my best work
不過 還可以
bù guò  hái kě yǐ
but  is acceptable
but I think it's okay.
謝謝 囉
xiè xiè  luō
Thank you  eh
Thanks.
沈佳宜 上 大學 以後
chén jiā yí  shàng  dà xué  yǐ hòu
Shen Chia-Yi  on  university  after
Shen Chia-Yi, promise me something.
不要 太 快 讓 別 的 男生 追到 妳
bù yào  tài  kuài  ràng  bié  de  nán shēng  zhuī dào  nǐ
Do not  very  quick  allow  don't  of  boy  Catch up  you
Don't let boys get you too soon after you go to college.
好不好
hǎo bù hǎo
ok
Ok?
你 在 說 什麼 啊
nǐ  zài  shuō  shén me  a
you  in  say  what  ah
What are you talking about?
( 你 是 我 最 珍貴 的 人 ）
(  nǐ  shì  wǒ  zuì  zhēn guì  de  rén  ）
(  you  is  I  most  precious  of  man  ）
You Are the Apple of My Eye.
喔 對了 還有 勃起
ō  duì le  hái yǒu  bó qǐ
oh  correct  and also  boner
Oh, yes, as for the masturbating Boner.
一直 打手槍 的 勃起 重考
yī zhí  dǎ shǒu qiāng  de  bó qǐ  zhòng kǎo
Always  masturbate  of  boner  resit exam
He decided to stay and take the college entrance exam again.
重考 重考 陪 我 重考 啦
zhòng kǎo  zhòng kǎo  péi  wǒ  zhòng kǎo  la
resit exam  resit exam  accompany  I  resit exam  la
Take the entrance exam next year with me please!
我 也來 到 人生 的 下一站
wǒ  yě lái  dào  rén shēng  de  xià yí zhàn
I  Also come  to  life  of  next stop
I have also come to the next stage in my life
一間 沒有 沈佳宜 的 大學
yī jiàn  méi yǒu  chén jiā yí  de  dà xué
one  No  Shen Chia-Yi  of  university
a school without Shen Chia-Yi
沒想到 我 第一個 牽 手 的 女孩 不是 沈佳宜
méi xiǎng dào  wǒ  dì yī ge  qiān  shǒu  de  nǚ hái  bù shì  chén jiā yí
did not expect  I  the first  hold  hand  of  girl  not  Shen Chia-Yi
I never thought that Shen Chia-Yi would not be the first girl that I hold hands with.
而是 而是 一個 叫
ér shì  ér shì  yī gè  jiào
Instead  Instead  One  call
Instead of her, it was a girl named...
叫 什麼
jiào  shén me
call  what
Named...
你 好 我 叫 許可欣
nǐ  hǎo  wǒ  jiào  xǔ kě xīn
you  good  I  call  Hsu Ke-Shin
Hello, my name was Hsu Ke-Shin.
你 好 我 叫 柯景騰
nǐ  hǎo  wǒ  jiào  kē jǐng téng
you  good  I  call  Ko Ching-Teng
Hi, my name is Ko Ching-Teng.
宿舍 有 很多 奇奇怪怪 的 傳說
sù shè  yǒu  hěn duō  qí qí guài guài  de  chuán shuō
dorm room  have  a lot of  strange  of  legend
There were many weird stories in the dormitory.
大部分 都 跟 鬼 有 關
dà bù fèn  dōu  gēn  guǐ  yǒu  guān
most  all  with  ghost  have  close
Most of them were ghost stories.
不過
bù guò
but
But
其中 有 一個 跟 四腳 獸 有 關 的 傳說
qí zhōng  yǒu  yī gè  gēn  sì jiǎo  shòu  yǒu  guān  de  chuán shuō
among them  have  One  with  Four feet  beast  have  close  of  legend
there's one story about a four-legged beast.
絕對 是 真的
jué duì  shì  zhēn de
absolute  is  Really
It was definitely real...
我 的 室友 來自 四面八方
wǒ  de  shì yǒu  lái zì  sì miàn bā fāng
I  of  roommate  From  in all directions
My roommates came from all walks of life.
孝綸 是個 肌肉 狂 整天 舉 啞鈴
xiào lún  shì gè  jī ròu  kuáng  zhěng tiān  jǔ  yǎ líng
Hsiao-Lun  Is  muscle  insane  All day  raise  dumbbell
Hsiao-Lun was a muscle maniac, who did nothing but lifted weights all day long.
超級 宅 的 義智
chāo jí  zhái  de  yì zhì
super  house  of  Yi-Chi
The ultimate weirdo is Yi-Chi.
隨時 都 在 看 動漫 幾乎 不去 上課
suí shí  dōu  zài  kàn  dòng màn  jī hū  bù qù  shàng kè
at any time  all  in  look  anime  almost  Do not go  attend class
He was never in the classroom because he's always reading Manga.
從 大一 就 開始 準備 考 研究所 的 建漢
cóng  dà yī  jiù  kāi shǐ  zhǔn bèi  kǎo  yán jiū suǒ  de  jiàn hàn
from  Freshman  just  Start  ready  examine  graduate school  of  prepare
Chien-Han, who started to prepare for graduate school from the day he arrived
無時無刻 都 在 唸書
wú shí wú kè  dōu  zài  niàn shū
All the time  all  in  study
was studying twenty four seven.
幸 好 我們 還有 共 通 的 話題
xìng  hǎo  wǒ men  hái yǒu  gòng  tōng  de  huà tí
favor  good  us  and also  all  through  of  topic
Luckily, we had some common interests to talk about.
是不是 飯島愛 太 老了
shì bù shì  fàn dǎo ài  tài  lǎo le
isn't it  Iijima Ai  very  old
See, Iijima Ai is way too old.
奶頭 都 黑 掉了
nǎi tóu  dōu  hēi  diào le
nipple  all  black  Lost
Her tits have turned dark.
小澤圓 看起來 比較 可口
xiǎo zé yuán  kàn qǐ lái  bǐ jiào  kě kǒu
Madoza Ozawa  Looks like  Comparison  tasty
Emmm... Madoza Ozawa looks hotter and yummier
大 浦安娜 也不錯
dà  pǔ ān nà  yě bù cuò
big  Anna Ohura  also not bad
Anna Ohura is not too bad, either
我 那邊 有 個 叫 人類 補 奸計 劃 的 好 東西
wǒ  nà biān  yǒu  ge  jiào  rén lèi  bǔ  jiān jì  huà  de  hǎo  dōng xi
I  there  have  piece  call  Humanity  mend  Treacherous  divide  of  good  thing
I have some nice stuff called the Human Sex Program.
等一下 一起 看 啊
děng yī xià  yì qǐ  kàn  a
Wait  together  look  ah
Let's watch it together later.
看 卡通 人物 做愛 也 太 奇怪 了 吧
kàn  kǎ tōng  rén wù  zuò ài  yě  tài  qí guài  le  ba
look  cartoon  character  make love  also  very  strange  is  !
Don't you think it's too weird to watch cartoon characters having sex?
還有 跟 狗 還有 跟 鰻魚 的 咧
hái yǒu  gēn  gǒu  hái yǒu  gēn  mán yú  de  liě
and also  with  dog  and also  with  eel  of  frown
There're ones with dogs and eels, too.
那是 手機 還沒 普及 的 年代
nà shì  shǒu jī  hái méi  pǔ jí  de  nián dài
That is  Mobile phone  not yet  universal  of  Age
That was the time before mobile phones were common.
到了 晚上 一堆男生 就像 集體 中邪 一樣
dào le  wǎn shàng  yī duī nán shēng  jiù xiàng  jí tǐ  zhōng xié  yī yàng
Arrived  at night  a group of boys  as if  collective  bewitched  same
At night, all the guys acted like they casted a spell.
在 公共 電話 前 大 排長龍
zài  gōng gòng  diàn huà  qián  dà  pái cháng lóng
in  public  phone  before  big  queue
Everyone one of us was lining up in front the telephone booth
小 可愛 我 好 想你 喔
xiǎo  kě ài  wǒ  hǎo  xiǎng nǐ  ō
small  lovely  I  good  miss you  oh
I miss you so much my sweetie little pumpkin pie
每個 小時 都 固定 想你 十次 啊
měi gè  xiǎo shí  dōu  gù dìng  xiǎng nǐ  shí cì  a
Each one  hour  all  fixed  miss you  ten times  ah
I miss you 10 times every hour on a regular basis.
真的 啊
zhēn de  a
Really  ah
It's true.
那 你 有沒有 好 想 我
nà  nǐ  yǒu méi yǒu  hǎo  xiǎng  wǒ
that  you  do you have  good  think  I
So do you miss me this much, too?
一個 小時 想 幾次
yī gè  xiǎo shí  xiǎng  jǐ cì
One  hour  think  several times
How many times per hour?
有沒有 十次
yǒu méi yǒu  shí cì
do you have  ten times
10 times at least?
喂
wèi
hey
Hey.
喂 你 還沒 睡 吧
wèi  nǐ  hái méi  shuì  ba
hey  you  not yet  sleep  !
You are not asleep yet, are you?
還沒 啊
hái méi  a
not yet  ah
No, not yet.
快 睡 啦
kuài  shuì  la
quick  sleep  la
Go to sleep
每天 晚上 我 都 跟 沈佳宜 講 電話
měi tiān  wǎn shàng  wǒ  dōu  gēn  chén jiā yí  jiǎng  diàn huà
every day  at night  I  all  with  Shen Chia-Yi  speak  phone
I talked to Shen Chia-Yi every night.
有 時 講 到 她 睡著
yǒu  shí  jiǎng  dào  tā  shuì zhe
have  time  speak  to  she  sleep
Sometimes, she fell asleep in the middle of our conversations.
有 時 講 到 我 連 吃飯 的 錢 都 用光光
yǒu  shí  jiǎng  dào  wǒ  lián  chī fàn  de  qián  dōu  yòng guāng guāng
have  time  speak  to  I  even  eat  of  money  all  use up
Sometimes I spent all my money on phone calls and left no money for food.
迎新 晚 會 下禮拜 啊
yíng xīn  wǎn  huì  xià lǐ bài  a
welcome  night  can  next week  ah
Welcome party? Next week.
下禮拜
xià lǐ bài
next week
Next week.
那 我 跟 妳 說 喔
nà  wǒ  gēn  nǐ  shuō  ō
that  I  with  you  say  oh
Listen.
妳 可不可以 不要 下去 跳舞
nǐ  kě bù kě yǐ  bù yào  xià qù  tiào wǔ
you  can we  Do not  Go on  dancing
Can you please not dance with anyone?
不要 下去 跳舞 為什麼
bù yào  xià qù  tiào wǔ  wèi shén me
Do not  Go on  dancing  why
Why not?
因為
yīn wèi
because
Because...
雖然 我 還沒 追到 妳 啊
suī rán  wǒ  hái méi  zhuī dào  nǐ  a
although  I  not yet  Catch up  you  ah
Ok, I know we are not seeing each other yet.
不過 那些 追 都 沒 追過 妳 的 男生
bù guò  nà xiē  zhuī  dōu  méi  zhuī guò  nǐ  de  nán shēng
but  those  pursue  all  not  caught up  you  of  boy
But those guys who you don't even know.
怎麼 可以 牽 妳 的 手
zěn me  kě yǐ  qiān  nǐ  de  shǒu
how  can  hold  you  of  hand
Can you not let them hold your hands?
我 自己 都 沒 牽 過 耶
wǒ  zì jǐ  dōu  méi  qiān  guò  yé
I  self  all  not  hold  too  ye
I haven't even held them myself.
那 你 呢
nà  nǐ  ne
that  you  this
What about you?
你 沒 下去 跳 啊
nǐ  méi  xià qù  tiào  a
you  not  Go on  jump  ah
You didn't dance with anyone?
我 就 不 相信 你 沒有 牽 其他 女生 的 手
wǒ  jiù  bù  xiāng xìn  nǐ  méi yǒu  qiān  qí tā  nǚ shēng  de  shǒu
I  just  no  Believe  you  No  hold  other  Girls  of  hand
I don't believe you didn't hold any girl's hands.
是有 稍微 牽 一下 啦
shì yǒu  shāo wéi  qiān  yí xià  la
there is  a little  hold  a bit  la
Oh, well... yeah, but only a little bit.
不過 那是 因為
bù guò  nà shì  yīn wèi
but  That is  because
That's because...
我 把 對方 想成 妳 啊
wǒ  bǎ  duì fāng  xiǎng chéng  nǐ  a
I  take  other side  think of  you  ah
I imagined that she was you.
你 少 噁心了 我 才不 相信 咧
nǐ  shǎo  ě xīn le  wǒ  cái bù  xiāng xìn  liě
you  few  disgusted  I  never  Believe  frown
Oh please, I don't believe you.
真的 啦
zhēn de  la
Really  la
Really.
那 我 也可以 把 對方 想成 是 你 啊
nà  wǒ  yě kě yǐ  bǎ  duì fāng  xiǎng chéng  shì  nǐ  a
that  I  Can also be  take  other side  think of  is  you  ah
Then I can also imagine the guy I dance with was you.
不要 鬧 啦
bù yào  nào  la
Do not  trouble  la
No man, I'm for real.
好啦 說 真的 喔
hǎo la  shuō  zhēn de  ō
Okay  say  Really  oh
All right, I am serious.
不可以 被 牽 喔
bù kě yǐ  bèi  qiān  ō
Can not  by  hold  oh
Don't let anyone hold your hands.
嗯 掰掰
ń  bāi bāi
umm  bye bye
Bye.
終於 上 大學 後 的 第一個 聖誕 節 來了
zhōng wū  shàng  dà xué  hòu  de  dì yī ge  shèng dàn  jié  lái le
at last  on  university  after  of  the first  Christmas  holiday  coming
Finally, it was the first Christmas after we entered college.
喂
wèi
hey
Hey.
我們 這樣 算 約會 嗎
wǒ men  zhè yàng  suàn  yuē huì  ma
us  such  count  date  ?
Is this considered a date?
幹嘛 問 我
gàn ma  wèn  wǒ
what  ask  I
Why ask me?
台北 怎麼 那麼 冷
tái běi  zěn me  nà me  lěng
Taipei  how  like that  cold
Why is it so cold in Taipei?
換我 換我 快點
huàn wǒ  huàn wǒ  kuài diǎn
for me  for me  Faster
Hurry up, my turn for a picture!
快點 啦 快走 了
kuài diǎn  la  kuài zǒu  le
Faster  la  Brisk walking  is
Hurry up! It's leaving.
沒有 拍到
méi yǒu  pāi dào
No  photographed
Oops, I didn't get it.
你
nǐ
you
You.
不要 跑
bù yào  pǎo
Do not  run
Come back.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
Ko Ching-Teng.
你 真的 很 喜歡 我 嗎
nǐ  zhēn de  hěn  xǐ huan  wǒ  ma
you  Really  very  like  I  ?
Do you really like me a lot?
喜歡 啊
xǐ huan  a
like  ah
Yes, I do.
很 喜歡 啊
hěn  xǐ huan  a
very  like  ah
Very much
我 總 覺得 你 把 我 想 得 太好了
wǒ  zǒng  jué de  nǐ  bǎ  wǒ  xiǎng  dé  tài hǎo le
I  collect  feel  you  take  I  think  get  Great
I always feel that you give me too much credit
我 根本 沒有 你 想 的 那麼 好
wǒ  gēn běn  méi yǒu  nǐ  xiǎng  de  nà me  hǎo
I  simply  No  you  think  of  like that  good
I'm not as good as you think
你 喜歡 我 讓 我 覺得 有 點 怪怪 的
nǐ  xǐ huan  wǒ  ràng  wǒ  jué de  yǒu  diǎn  guài guài  de
you  like  I  allow  I  feel  have  point  strange  of
I feel weird about the fact that you like me.
哪裡 奇怪
nǎ lǐ  qí guài
where  strange
What's so weird about it?
我 也會有 你 不知道 的 一面 啊
wǒ  yě huì yǒu  nǐ  bù zhī dào  de  yī miàn  a
I  There will be  you  do not know  of  one side  ah
There is another side of me that you don't know about
在 家裡 我 也會 很 邋遢
zài  jiā li  wǒ  yě huì  hěn  lā tà
in  Home  I  Will also be  very  sloppy
I am very sloppy at home.
嗯 …
ń  …
umm  …
Emm...
也會有 起床氣
yě huì yǒu  qǐ chuáng qì
There will be  get up
I get very grumpy when I wake up early.
也會 因為 一點 小事 就 跟 我 妹 發脾氣
yě huì  yīn wèi  yī diǎn  xiǎo shì  jiù  gēn  wǒ  mèi  fā pí qì
Will also be  because  a little  Small matter  just  with  I  younger sister  loose the temper
And I get pissed off with my little sister at times just for minor stuff
我 就
wǒ  jiù
I  just
I am... you know.
很 普通 啊
hěn  pǔ tōng  a
very  ordinary  ah
Very ordinary.
說不定 你 喜歡 上 的
shuō bu dìng  nǐ  xǐ huan  shàng  de
maybe  you  like  on  of
Maybe, the person that you like
只是 你 想像 出來 的 我
zhǐ shì  nǐ  xiǎng xiàng  chū lái  de  wǒ
just  you  imagine  come out  of  I
is in your imagination
我 沒 那麼 會想 像
wǒ  méi  nà me  huì xiǎng  xiàng
I  not  like that  Would think  like
I am not that imaginative.
真的
zhēn de
Really
Look.
你 仔細 想想
nǐ  zǐ xì  xiǎng xiǎng
you  careful  Think about it
Think carefully.
你 有 那麼 喜歡 我 嗎
nǐ  yǒu  nà me  xǐ huan  wǒ  ma
you  have  like that  like  I  ?
Do you like me that much?
喜歡 啊
xǐ huan  a
like  ah
Hell yeah.
你 很 幼稚 耶
nǐ  hěn  yòu zhì  yé
you  very  naive  ye
You are so childish.
你 都 沒有 仔細 想
nǐ  dōu  méi yǒu  zǐ xì  xiǎng
you  all  No  careful  think
You didn't even think through it.
你 想 好再 跟 我 說
nǐ  xiǎng  hǎo zài  gēn  wǒ  shuō
you  think  Good again  with  I  say
Think about it carefully before you tell me.
沈佳宜 是什麼 意思 呢
chén jiā yí  shì shén me  yì si  ne
Shen Chia-Yi  What is it?  meaning  this
What did Shen Chia-Yi mean?
她是 不是 想 委婉 的 拒絕 我 呢
tā shì  bù shì  xiǎng  wěi wǎn  de  jù jué  wǒ  ne
She is  not  think  tactful  of  Refuse  I  this
Was she trying to turn me down in a nice way?
我 很 害怕
wǒ  hěn  hài pà
I  very  Afraid
I was afraid.
一直 以來 我 都 以為 我 自己 是個 超 有 自信 的 人
yī zhí  yǐ lái  wǒ  dōu  yǐ wéi  wǒ  zì jǐ  shì gè  chāo  yǒu  zì xìn  de  rén
Always  since  I  all  think  I  self  Is  super  have  confidence  of  man
For a long time, I always thought that I am a confident guy.
但 那 時 我 才 發現
dàn  nà  shí  wǒ  cái  fā xiàn
only  that  time  I  only  Find
At that moment, I realized that
原來 在 喜歡 的 女孩 面前 我 是個 膽小鬼
yuán lái  zài  xǐ huan  de  nǚ hái  miàn qián  wǒ  shì gè  dǎn xiǎo guǐ
original  in  like  of  girl  before  I  Is  coward
I was really a coward in front of the girl I liked.
妳 許 什麼 願 啊
nǐ  xǔ  shén me  yuàn  a
you  perhaps  what  want  ah
What do you wish for?
自己 寫 自己 的 不可以 偷看
zì jǐ  xiě  zì jǐ  de  bù kě yǐ  tōu kàn
self  write  self  of  Can not  peep
Write your own, no peeking.
這麼 小氣
zhè me  xiǎo qì
so  stingy
Come on, I just want to have a look.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
我 很 喜歡 妳
wǒ  hěn  xǐ huan  nǐ
I  very  like  you
I like you very much
非常 喜歡 妳
fēi cháng  xǐ huan  nǐ
very much  like  you
I like you a lot.
總有 一天 我 一定 要 追到 妳
zǒng yǒu  yī tiān  wǒ  yī dìng  yào  zhuī dào  nǐ
always  one day  I  for sure  want  Catch up  you
One day you will be mine.
百分之 一千萬 一定 會 追到 妳
bǎi fēn zhī  yī qiān wàn  yī dìng  huì  zhuī dào  nǐ
100%  much  for sure  can  Catch up  you
One day, I will make you mine.
你 想 知道 答案 嗎
nǐ  xiǎng  zhī dào  dá àn  ma
you  think  know  answer  ?
Do you want to know the answer?
我 現在 就可以 告訴 你
wǒ  xiàn zài  jiù kě yǐ  gào su  nǐ
I  now  can  tell  you
I can tell you right now.
不要
bù yào
Do not
No
我 沒有 問 妳
wǒ  méi yǒu  wèn  nǐ
I  No  ask  you
I didn't ask you.
所以 妳 也不 可以 拒絕 我
suǒ yǐ  nǐ  yě bù  kě yǐ  jù jué  wǒ
and so  you  nor  can  Refuse  I
So you can't turn me down.
你 真的 不 想 知道
nǐ  zhēn de  bù  xiǎng  zhī dào
you  Really  no  think  know
You really don't want to know?
拜託 不要 現在 告訴 我
bài tuō  bù yào  xiàn zài  gào su  wǒ
please  Do not  now  tell  I
Please don't tell me now.
請 讓 我 繼續 喜歡 妳
qǐng  ràng  wǒ  jì xù  xǐ huan  nǐ
please  allow  I  carry on  like  you
Just let me keep on liking you.
每一個 男生 都 想 在 自己 心上人 面前
měi yī gè  nán shēng  dōu  xiǎng  zài  zì jǐ  xīn shàng rén  miàn qián
every  boy  all  think  in  self  Sweetheart  before
Every guy wants to show his strongest side.
展現 自己 最強 的 一面
zhǎn xiàn  zì jǐ  zuì qiáng  de  yī miàn
Show  self  strongest  of  one side
Especially in front of the girl he likes.
而 我 又 應該 展現 什麼 給 沈佳宜 看 呢
ér  wǒ  yòu  yīng gāi  zhǎn xiàn  shén me  gěi  chén jiā yí  kàn  ne
and  I  and  should  Show  what  give  Shen Chia-Yi  look  this
So what should I show to Shen Chia-Yi?
我 想 了 很久 終於 有 一天 我 悟 出了 答案
wǒ  xiǎng  le  hěn jiǔ  zhōng wū  yǒu  yī tiān  wǒ  wù  chū le  dá àn
I  think  is  long time  at last  have  one day  I  realize  Out  answer
It took me a long time before the answer suddenly hit me one day.
你 就 去 廁所 尿尿 是 會 怎樣 啊
nǐ  jiù  qù  cè suǒ  niào niào  shì  huì  zěn yàng  a
you  just  go  toilet  pee  is  can  how  ah
Why can't you just go pee in the toilet?
很 遠 耶
hěn  yuǎn  yé
very  far  ye
Man, it's far.
你 要 出門 啊
nǐ  yào  chū mén  a
you  want  Go out  ah
Hey, are you going out?
順便 幫 我 拿去 倒 一下
shùn biàn  bāng  wǒ  ná qù  dào  yí xià
By the way  help  I  Take it  pour  a bit
Empty this for me on your way out, will you?
有沒有 搞錯 啊
yǒu méi yǒu  gǎo cuò  a
do you have  wrong  ah
You fucking serious?
幫 同學 倒 尿 也 是 友情 的 …
bāng  tóng xué  dào  niào  yě  shì  yǒu qíng  de  …
help  classmate  pour  urine  also  is  Friendship  of  …
Come on, just do me a favor...
你們 不覺 得
nǐ men  bù jué  dé
you  Do not feel  get
Don't you guys think.
是 時候 戰鬥 了 嗎
shì  shí hou  zhàn dòu  le  ma
is  time  fighting  is  ?
It's time to battle?
我們 來
wǒ men  lái
us  come
Come on.
打架 吧
dǎ jià  ba
fight  !
Let's fight
我 要 辦 比賽
wǒ  yào  bàn  bǐ sài
I  want  manage  game
I am organizing a competition.
有沒有人 要 參加 的
yǒu méi yǒu rén  yào  cān jiā  de
Anyone  want  participate  of
Anyone wants to join me?
有沒有人 要 參加 比賽
yǒu méi yǒu rén  yào  cān jiā  bǐ sài
Anyone  want  participate  game
Anyone wants to join the competition?
有沒有人 要 打架 的
yǒu méi yǒu rén  yào  dǎ jià  de
Anyone  want  fight  of
Anyone wants to fight?
我 有 辦 打架 比賽
wǒ  yǒu  bàn  dǎ jià  bǐ sài
I  have  manage  fight  game
Fighting competition, anyone?
要不要 參加 比賽
yào bù yào  cān jiā  bǐ sài
want  participate  game
Do you want to fight in a competition?
要不要 參加 格鬥 比賽
yào bù yào  cān jiā  gé dòu  bǐ sài
want  participate  fighting  game
Do you want to fight in a combat tournament?
有沒有人 要 打架
yǒu méi yǒu rén  yào  dǎ jià
Anyone  want  fight
Anyone wants to fight?
有沒有人 要
yǒu méi yǒu rén  yào
Anyone  want
Anyone wants to join?
我 可以 看完 嗎
wǒ  kě yǐ  kàn wán  ma
I  can  Read  ?
Can I stay until you guys finish?
一般 運動 有 什麼 了 不起
yī bān  yùn dòng  yǒu  shén me  le  bù qǐ
general  sport  have  what  is  Can not afford to
What's the big deal with the regular sports?
當然 自由 格鬥 比較 屌 啊
dāng rán  zì yóu  gé dòu  bǐ jiào  diǎo  a
of course  free  fighting  Comparison  cock  ah
Combat is definitely cooler.
真的 啦 妳 一定 要 來 看 喔
zhēn de  la  nǐ  yī dìng  yào  lái  kàn  ō
Really  la  you  for sure  want  come  look  oh
Seriously, you have to be here
我 剛 已經 貼出 海報 了
wǒ  gāng  yǐ jīng  tiē chū  hǎi bào  le
I  just  already  posted  poster  is
I just put out posters.
到時候 一定 大 爆滿
dào shí hou  yī dìng  dà  bào mǎn
By the time  for sure  big  full
It's going to be a full house.
你 為什麼 要 辦 這麼 危險 的 比賽
nǐ  wèi shén me  yào  bàn  zhè me  wéi xiǎn  de  bǐ sài
you  why  want  manage  so  Danger  of  game
Why do you want to organize such a dangerous competition?
你們 學校 都 不用 唸書 的 嗎
nǐ men  xué xiào  dōu  bù yòng  niàn shū  de  ma
you  school  all  No need to  study  of  ?
Don't you guys need to study and look after your marks?
就是 因為 大家 都 只會 唸書
jiù shì  yīn wèi  dà jiā  dōu  zhǐ huì  niàn shū
is  because  everyone  all  Only will  study
Exactly! People study way too hard.
所以 才 需要 運動 一下
suǒ yǐ  cái  xū yào  yùn dòng  yí xià
and so  only  need  sport  a bit
That's why they need to exercise
我 要 幫 他們 特訓
wǒ  yào  bāng  tā men  tè xùn
I  want  help  they  training
I want to give them some trainings.
還不 就是 打架
hái bù  jiù shì  dǎ jià
Not yet  is  fight
It's just a fight.
這麼說 也可以 啦
zhè me shuō  yě kě yǐ  la
so  Can also be  la
Fine, if you really want to put it that way
有 時候 我 真的 很不 瞭解 你
yǒu  shí hou  wǒ  zhēn de  hěn bù  liǎo jiě  nǐ
have  time  I  Really  Very bad  understand  you
I really don't get you sometimes.
簡單 啦
jiǎn dān  la
simple  la
You can nail this easily
我 以為 大學 裡 都 是 娘炮
wǒ  yǐ wéi  dà xué  lǐ  dōu  shì  niáng pào
I  think  university  inside  all  is  sissy
I thought everyone in college was a pussy
我 錯了
wǒ  cuò le
I  wrong
I was wrong.
有 個 硬漢 叫 建偉
yǒu  ge  yìng hàn  jiào  jiàn wěi
have  piece  tough guy  call  Chien-Wei
There was a tough guy named Chien-Wei.
他 是 胎拳社 的 副主 將 黑帶
tā  shì  tāi quán shè  de  fù zhǔ  jiāng  hēi dài
he  is  taekwondo  of  deputy  will  black belt
He was the second chair of the taekwondo club, a black belt.
看起來 很 臭屁
kàn qǐ lái  hěn  chòu pì
Looks like  very  cocky
He looked cocky.
看起來 很 強
kàn qǐ lái  hěn  qiáng
Looks like  very  strong
And he looked tough.
正合 我 意
zhèng hé  wǒ  yì
coincide  I  thought
Just the kind of guy that I was looking for.
比 照 天下 第一 武道 大會 的 規定
bǐ  zhào  tiān xià  dì yī  wǔ dào  dà huì  de  guī dìng
than  according to  world  first  martial arts  General Assembly  of  Regulations
We follow the rules of the highest martial arts order in the world.
不可以 殺死 對方
bù kě yǐ  shā sǐ  duì fāng
Can not  Kill  other side
No killing.
不可以 出 界
bù kě yǐ  chū  jiè
Can not  out  boundary
You cannot go outside of the boundaries.
不可以 踢 小雞雞
bù kě yǐ  tī  xiǎo jī jī
Can not  kick  dick
No kicking on penises.
倒地 後 數 到 十 沒有 爬起來 也 算 輸
dǎo dì  hòu  shù  dào  shí  méi yǒu  pá qǐ lái  yě  suàn  shū
Fell to the ground  after  number  to  ten  No  climb up  also  count  lose
You lose if you are knocked down and unable to get up after the referee counts to 10.
預備
yù bèi
preparation
Ready!
穿上
chuān shàng
Put on
Put it on.
三小 啊
sān xiǎo  a
3 am  ah
What the hell?
穿上 它 我 才敢 打 你
chuān shàng  tā  wǒ  cái gǎn  dǎ  nǐ
Put on  it  I  dare  hit  you
Wear it so I know I won't kill you.
穿 你的 屁股 啦
chuān  nǐ de  pì gu  la
wear  your  butt  la
Go fuck yourself.
開始
kāi shǐ
Start
Go
我 要 殺死 你
wǒ  yào  shā sǐ  nǐ
I  want  Kill  you
I am going to kill you.
快 羚羊 拳
kuài  líng yáng  quán
quick  antelope  fist
Punch him with Gazelle punch.
站起來
zhàn qǐ lái
stand up
Stand up.
柯騰
kē téng
Ko-Teng
Ko-Teng.
趕快 啦
gǎn kuài  la
hurry up  la
Hurry up.
快 反擊
kuài  fǎn jí
quick  Counterattack
Fight back.
柯騰 快 反擊
kē téng  kuài  fǎn jí
Ko-Teng  quick  Counterattack
Ko-Teng, fight back.
打 他的 肝臟
dǎ  tā de  gān zàng
hit  his  liver
Beat him up.
站起來 打 他 起來
zhàn qǐ lái  dǎ  tā  qǐ lái
stand up  hit  he  stand up
Stand up and beat him, stand up.
1…2…3…4…5…6…7… One... Two... Three... Four... Five... Six... Seven.
柯騰 站起來
kē téng  zhàn qǐ lái
Ko-Teng  stand up
Ko-Teng stand up.
你 再不 起來
nǐ  zài bu  qǐ lái
you  No again  stand up
Stand up now.
我 就 要 數 完了 耶
wǒ  jiù  yào  shù  wán liǎo  yé
I  just  want  number  Finished it  ye
Time is running out.
柯騰
kē téng
Ko-Teng
Ko-Teng.
快 反擊
kuài  fǎn jí
quick  Counterattack
Fight back.
那 誰 好正 喔
nà  sheí  hǎo zhèng  ō
that  who  so good  oh
Who is that? She's so hot.
剛剛 比賽 結束 的時候 我 都 沒有 看到 妳
gāng gāng  bǐ sài  jié shù  de shí hòu  wǒ  dōu  méi yǒu  kàn dào  nǐ
just  game  End  when  I  all  No  see  you
Hey! I didn't see you when the game was over
我 還 以為 被 打 昏 了 耶
wǒ  hái  yǐ wéi  bèi  dǎ  hūn  le  yé
I  still  think  by  hit  dusk  is  ye
I thought I was knocked out...
妳 剛剛 有 看到 那 男 的 嗎
nǐ  gāng gāng  yǒu  kàn dào  nà  nán  de  ma
you  just  have  see  that  man  of  ?
Did you see that guy?
他 超 厲害 的 耶
tā  chāo  lì hài  de  yé
he  super  awesome  of  ye
He kicked my ass so bad
我 一直 閃 不開 他的 腳
wǒ  yī zhí  shǎn  bù kāi  tā de  jiǎo
I  Always  flash  not open  his  foot
I couldn't get away from him.
很好 玩 嗎
hěn hǎo  wán  ma
well  joke  ?
Was it fun?
還不 錯 啊
hái bù  cuò  a
Not yet  error  ah
Not bad!
妳 來 看 我 超 開心 的 耶
nǐ  lái  kàn  wǒ  chāo  kāi xīn  de  yé
you  come  look  I  super  Happy  of  ye
I was so excited when I saw you!
我 問你 很好 玩 嗎
wǒ  wèn nǐ  hěn hǎo  wán  ma
I  ask you  well  joke  ?
Answer my question, was it fun?
幹嘛 啦
gàn ma  la
what  la
Now what?
你 辦 這 什麼 奇怪 的 比賽 啊
nǐ  bàn  zhè  shén me  qí guài  de  bǐ sài  a
you  manage  this  what  strange  of  game  ah
Why did you insist on organizing such a weird competition?
你 辦 這 比賽 的 意義 到底 在 哪裡
nǐ  bàn  zhè  bǐ sài  de  yì yì  dào dǐ  zài  nǎ lǐ
you  manage  this  game  of  meaning  in the end  in  where
What's the meaning of it?
妳 不覺 得很 炫 嗎
nǐ  bù jué  de hěn  xuàn  ma
you  Do not feel  Very much  show off  ?
Don't you think it's super cool?
兩個 男人 之間 一定 要 分出 勝負 那種 …
liǎng gè  nán rén  zhī jiān  yī dìng  yào  fēn chū  shèng fù  nà zhǒng  …
two  man  between  for sure  want  Separate  outcome  that kind  …
That kind of... win or lose between two men.
還不 就是 打架
hái bù  jiù shì  dǎ jià
Not yet  is  fight
It's just violence.
柯景騰
kē jǐng téng
Ko Ching-Teng
Ko Ching-Teng.
你 特地 辦 一個 比賽 把 自己 搞 受傷
nǐ  tè dì  bàn  yī gè  bǐ sài  bǎ  zì jǐ  gǎo  shòu shāng
you  specially  manage  One  game  take  self  clear  Injured
You organized a game to get yourself hurt.
你 怎麼會 這麼 幼稚 啊
nǐ  zěn me huì  zhè me  yòu zhì  a
you  how come  so  naive  ah
Why are you so childish?
幼稚
yòu zhì
naive
Childish?
對 就是 幼稚
duì  jiù shì  yòu zhì
to  is  naive
Right, childish.
很 幼稚
hěn  yòu zhì
very  naive
Very childish.
我 問你
wǒ  wèn nǐ
I  ask you
Let me ask you something.
你 辦 這 奇怪 的 比賽 到底 讓 你 學到 什麼
nǐ  bàn  zhè  qí guài  de  bǐ sài  dào dǐ  ràng  nǐ  xué dào  shén me
you  manage  this  strange  of  game  in the end  allow  you  Learned  what
What exactly did you learn from this game?
學
xué
learning
"Learn"?
不 見 得 做什麼 事情 都 一定 要 學到 什麼 吧
bù  jiàn  dé  zuò shén me  shì qíng  dōu  yī dìng  yào  xué dào  shén me  ba
no  see  get  doing what  thing  all  for sure  want  Learned  what  !
Why do I have to learn something from everything that I do?
至少 讓 你 學到 了 辦 這種 比賽 會 受傷
zhì shǎo  ràng  nǐ  xué dào  le  bàn  zhè zhǒng  bǐ sài  huì  shòu shāng
at least  allow  you  Learned  is  manage  this kind  game  can  Injured
At least you learned that having a competition like this will get yourself hurt.
而 受 這種 傷 一點 必要 都 沒有
ér  shòu  zhè zhǒng  shāng  yī diǎn  bì yào  dōu  méi yǒu
and  receive  this kind  wound  a little  necessary  all  No
And it is totally unnecessary.
你 真的 很 幼稚
nǐ  zhēn de  hěn  yòu zhì
you  Really  very  naive
You are so childish.
你 身上 的 傷 我 只能 說是 你 活該
nǐ  shēn shang  de  shāng  wǒ  zhǐ néng  shuō shì  nǐ  huó gāi
you  Body  of  wound  I  Can only  Said to be  you  deserve it
See those bruises on your face? You deserve it
我 幼稚
wǒ  yòu zhì
I  naive
I am childish?
妳 知不知道 這 格鬥 賽 對 我 來說 是 很棒 的 經驗 啊
nǐ  zhī bù zhī dào  zhè  gé dòu  sài  duì  wǒ  lái shuō  shì  hěn bàng  de  jīng yàn  a
you  do you know?  this  fighting  compete  to  I  For example  is  great  of  experience  ah
Do you know this competition is a fantastic experience for me?
妳 可不可以 單純 替 我 高興 就 好啊
nǐ  kě bù kě yǐ  dān chún  tì  wǒ  gāo xìng  jiù  hǎo a
you  can we  simple  for  I  happy  just  Okay
Can't you just be happy for me?
你 以後 還要 辦 這種 比賽
nǐ  yǐ hòu  hái yào  bàn  zhè zhǒng  bǐ sài
you  after  But also  manage  this kind  game
So you are going to do it again?
當然 要 辦 啊
dāng rán  yào  bàn  a
of course  want  manage  ah
Of course I will do it again.
為什麼 不 辦
wèi shén me  bù  bàn
why  no  manage
Why not?
幼稚
yòu zhì
naive
Grow up will you?
妳 為什麼 總要 否定 對 我 很 重要 的 東西 呀
nǐ  wèi shén me  zǒng yào  fǒu dìng  duì  wǒ  hěn  zhòng yào  de  dōng xi  ya
you  why  Eventually  negative  to  I  very  important  of  thing  yeah
Why do you always look down on things that matter to me?
對 你 很 重要 的 東西 竟然是 讓 你 傷害 你 自己 嗎
duì  nǐ  hěn  zhòng yào  de  dōng xi  jìng rán shì  ràng  nǐ  shāng hài  nǐ  zì jǐ  ma
to  you  very  important  of  thing  Turned out to be  allow  you  hurt  you  self  ?
Things that matter to you are things that hurt you?
對 啦
duì  la
to  la
Fine
我 就是 幼稚
wǒ  jiù shì  yòu zhì
I  is  naive
I am childish.
才會 追 妳 這種 努力 用功 讀書 的 女生
cái huì  zhuī  nǐ  zhè zhǒng  nǔ lì  yòng gōng  dú shū  de  nǚ shēng
Will only  pursue  you  this kind  Effort  work hard  reading  of  Girls
And that's why I would go after such a good school girl like you
我 就是 幼稚 才有 辦法 追 妳 這麼 久
wǒ  jiù shì  yòu zhì  cái yǒu  bàn fǎ  zhuī  nǐ  zhè me  jiǔ
I  is  naive  Only have  Method  pursue  you  so  long
I am this naive so I could chase you for so long.
那 你 就 不要 追 了 啊
nà  nǐ  jiù  bù yào  zhuī  le  a
that  you  just  Do not  pursue  is  ah
Stop trying then.
笨蛋
bèn dàn
fool
Idiot.
對 啦 我 就是 笨蛋 啦
duì  la  wǒ  jiù shì  bèn dàn  la
to  la  I  is  fool  la
Right! I am an idiot.
大 笨蛋
dà  bèn dàn
big  fool
Moron.
大 笨蛋 才能 追 妳 那麼 久
dà  bèn dàn  cái néng  zhuī  nǐ  nà me  jiǔ
big  fool  Ability to  pursue  you  like that  long
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase after you for such a long time.
你 什麼 都 不懂
nǐ  shén me  dōu  bù dǒng
you  what  all  Do not understand
You don't understand anything.
我 就是 什麼 都 不懂 啦
wǒ  jiù shì  shén me  dōu  bù dǒng  la
I  is  what  all  Do not understand  la
No, I don't understand anything.
成長 最 殘酷 的 部份 就是
chéng zhǎng  zuì  cán kù  de  bù fèn  jiù shì
growing up  most  cruel  of  part  is
The cruelest part in “growing up”
女孩 永遠 比 同年 齡 的 男孩 成熟
nǚ hái  yǒng yuǎn  bǐ  tóng nián  líng  de  nán hái  chéng shú
girl  forever  than  same year  age  of  boy  mature
is that girls are always more mature than guys of the same age.
女孩 的 成熟 沒有 一個 男孩 招架 得住
nǚ hái  de  chéng shú  méi yǒu  yī gè  nán hái  zhāo jià  dé zhù
girl  of  mature  No  One  boy  hold  Live
No guys can handle girls at their age.
大吵一架
dà chǎo yī jià
an argument
What? A big fight?
所以 這次 吵完架 就 不會 在 一起 了 喔
suǒ yǐ  zhè cì  chǎo wán jià  jiù  bù huì  zài  yì qǐ  le  ō
and so  this time  quarrel  just  will not  in  together  is  oh
Does that mean you are not going to be a couple after this?
你 有 什麼 毛病 啊
nǐ  yǒu  shén me  máo bìng  a
you  have  what  Faulty  ah
What's your problem?
真的假的 不 打算 和 好
zhēn de jiǎ de  bù  dǎ suàn  hàn  hǎo
really?  no  intend  and  good
For real? Not plans of making up?
也就 是說 我 有 機會 囉
yě jiù  shì shuō  wǒ  yǒu  jī huì  luō
Also  says  I  have  opportunity  eh
Oh yes, so I have a chance now?
老曹 自 以為 熱血
lǎo cáo  zì  yǐ wéi  rè xiè
Tsao  self  think  enthusiastic
Tsao took off right away on his motorcycle
騎著 摩托車 從 台南 直接 衝 到 台北
qí zhe  mó tuō chē  cóng  tái nán  zhí jiē  chōng  dào  tái běi
Ride on  scooter  from  Tainan  direct  rush  to  Taipei
and rode from Tainan to Taipei.
準備 跟 沈佳宜 告白
zhǔn bèi  gēn  chén jiā yí  gào bái
ready  with  Shen Chia-Yi  confess
He was ready to confess his love to Shen Chia-Yi.
阿和 則 買 了 最近 一 班 的 火車 票
ā hé  zé  mǎi  le  zuì jìn  yī  bān  de  huǒ chē  piào
A-Ho  rule  buy  is  recent  one  class  of  train  ticket
A-Ho, on the other hand, bought a ticket for the next train.
結論 是
jié lùn  shì
in conclusion  is
It turned out that
火車 比較 快
huǒ chē  bǐ jiào  kuài
train  Comparison  quick
the train is faster
雖然 我們 一直 很有 話聊
suī rán  wǒ men  yī zhí  hěn yǒu  huà liáo
although  us  Always  Very much  talk
I know we have always been good friends.
可是 其實 我 早就 知道 你 喜歡 的 是 柯騰
kě shì  qí shí  wǒ  zǎo jiù  zhī dào  nǐ  xǐ huan  de  shì  kē téng
but  in fact  I  Long ago  know  you  like  of  is  Ko-Teng
But somehow I always knew that Ko-Teng is the one.
我 一直 學 不會 的 事
wǒ  yī zhí  xué  bù huì  de  shì
I  Always  learning  will not  of  thing
Being childish is something that
就是 你 最 討厭 的 幼稚
jiù shì  nǐ  zuì  tǎo yàn  de  yòu zhì
is  you  most  hate  of  naive
I can never learn.
可是 每次 你 罵 柯騰 幼稚 的時候 我 都 很 嫉妒
kě shì  měi cì  nǐ  mà  kē téng  yòu zhì  de shí hòu  wǒ  dōu  hěn  jí dù
but  Each  you  accuse  Ko-Teng  naive  when  I  all  very  Jealousy
Even though you said you hate childish guys.
因為 其實 你 罵 他 幼稚 的時候
yīn wèi  qí shí  nǐ  mà  tā  yòu zhì  de shí hòu
because  in fact  you  accuse  he  naive  when
Every time when you called Ko-Teng childish
真的 很 漂亮
zhēn de  hěn  piào liang
Really  very  Pretty
I can tell how much you like that childishness in him.
你 跟 我 說這 些 做什麼
nǐ  gēn  wǒ  shuō zhè  xiē  zuò shén me
you  with  I  Say this  some  doing what
Why are you telling me this now?
如果 我 什麼 都 不做
rú guǒ  wǒ  shén me  dōu  bù zuò
if  I  what  all  Do not do
If I don't do anything now
你們 遲早會 和 好
nǐ men  chí zǎo huì  hàn  hǎo
you  Sooner or later  and  good
you guys will get back together eventually.
對不對
duì bù duì
right
Right?
對不起
duì bù qǐ
I am sorry
I am sorry.
這 一次 我 想趁 人 之危
zhè  yī cì  wǒ  xiǎng chèn  rén  zhī wēi
this  once  I  take advantage  man  danger
Since you guys are not in good terms now, I would like to take my chances.
看見 那個 畫面 老曹 的 機車 重新 發動 繼續 往前
kàn jiàn  nà gè  huà miàn  lǎo cáo  de  jī chē  chóng xīn  fā dòng  jì xù  wǎng qián
see  that one  screen  Tsao  of  scooter  Reappear  launch  carry on  Forward
When Tsao saw A-Ho and Shen Chia-Yi walked across the street, he took off again.
這 一次 他 不知不覺 就 繞 了 台灣 整整 一圈
zhè  yī cì  tā  bù zhī bù jué  jiù  rào  le  tái wān  zhěng zhěng  yī quān
this  once  he  unconsciously  just  around  is  Taiwan  full  A circle
This time, he rode his way around the whole island.
老曹 繞 回 台南 時
lǎo cáo  rào  huí  tái nán  shí
Tsao  around  return  Tainan  time
When Tsao made it to Tainan
因為 恍 神 醒來 已經 騎 到了 嘉義
yīn wèi  huǎng  shén  xǐng lái  yǐ jīng  qí  dào le  jiā yì
because  seemingly  god  wake up  already  ride  Arrived  Chiayi
he took the wrong exit so he went straight to Chiayi.
於是 老曹 乾脆 又 繼續 往上 騎 再接 再 厲 又 繞 了 台灣 一圈
wū shì  lǎo cáo  gān cuì  yòu  jì xù  wǎng shàng  qí  zài jiē  zài  lì  yòu  rào  le  tái wān  yī quān
then  Tsao  simply  and  carry on  Go up  ride  Re-connect  again  whetstone  and  around  is  Taiwan  A circle
Then he thought why not just take another round around Taiwan.
不過 這次 他 在 中途 停下來 載 我
bù guò  zhè cì  tā  zài  zhōng tú  tíng xià lái  zài  wǒ
but  this time  he  in  halfway  stop  load  I
This time, he stopped to picked me up.
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
What?
操
cāo
fuck
Fuck.
幹嘛
gàn ma
what
What do you want?
還 手 啦
hái  shǒu  la
still  hand  la
Hit me back.
你 以為 我 想 啊
nǐ  yǐ wéi  wǒ  xiǎng  a
you  think  I  think  ah
What's your freaking problem?
白癡 耶
bái chī  yé
idiot  ye
Idiot?
失 戀 了
shī  liàn  le
lose  love  is
I was heart broken
我 失去 了 沈佳宜
wǒ  shī qù  le  chén jiā yí
I  lose  is  Shen Chia-Yi
I had lost Shen Chia-Yi.
我 的 青春 什麼 都 不 剩 了
wǒ  de  qīng chūn  shén me  dōu  bù  shèng  le
I  of  youth  what  all  no  leftovers  is
There was nothing left in me
失 戀 那 幾個 月 我 認識 了 很多 女生
shī  liàn  nà  jǐ gè  yuè  wǒ  rèn shi  le  hěn duō  nǚ shēng
lose  love  that  several  moon  I  know  is  a lot of  Girls
I met quite a lot of girls after I lost Shen Chia-Yi.
只是 那些 女生 的 名字 清一色 都 是 四個 字
zhǐ shì  nà xiē  nǚ shēng  de  míng zì  qīng yī sè  dōu  shì  sì gè  zì
just  those  Girls  of  first name  uniform  all  is  Four  letter
It's just that they all happened to be Japanese.
為此 我 感到 相當 空虛
wèi cǐ  wǒ  gǎn dào  xiāng dāng  kōng xū
to this end  I  feel  quite  emptiness
For that, I felt there was something missing in my heart.
櫻木花道 說的 好
yīng mù huā dào  shuō de  hǎo
Sakuragi Hanamichi  Said  good
Sakuragi Hanamichi was right.
左手 只是 輔助
zuǒ shǒu  zhǐ shì  fǔ zhù
Left hand  just  help
You can only use one hand, your left hand.
因為 右手 要 拿 滑鼠
yīn wèi  yòu shǒu  yào  ná  huá shǔ
because  Right hand  want  take  mouse
Because you need your right hand on the mouse.
我們 這樣 每天 打手槍 到底有 什麼 意義
wǒ men  zhè yàng  měi tiān  dǎ shǒu qiāng  dào dǐ yǒu  shén me  yì yì
us  such  every day  masturbate  In the end there is  what  meaning
What's the point of us masturbating all day long?
意義 是 蝦 小
yì yì  shì  xiā  xiǎo
meaning  is  shrimp  small
Who cares?
林 北 只 聽過 精液
lín  běi  zhǐ  tīng guò  jīng yè
forest  north  only  Heard of it  semen
As long as I get to ejaculate, who cares!
沒 聽過 意義
méi  tīng guò  yì yì
not  Heard of it  meaning
I am coming, I am coming, I AM COMING!
現在 光是 大學 畢業 已經 不夠
xiàn zài  guāng shì  dà xué  bì yè  yǐ jīng  bù gòu
now  just  university  graduate  already  not enough
Even though getting a diploma might not be crucial
雖然 說 學歷 並不 代表 一切
suī rán  shuō  xué lì  bìng bù  dài biǎo  yī qiè
although  say  education  And not  represent  all
but a bachelor degree seems to be not enough
我 跟 阿和 之間 有 很長 一段 時間 沒有 聯絡
wǒ  gēn  ā hé  zhī jiān  yǒu  hěn zhǎng  yī duàn  shí jiān  méi yǒu  lián luò
I  with  A-Ho  between  have  very long  A paragraph  time  No  connection
I admit that I might be childish, just like how Shen Chia-Yi described me.
面對 自己 的 好 朋友
miàn duì  zì jǐ  de  hǎo  péng yǒu
face  self  of  good  friend
A-Ho has been a really good friend of mine.
卻 連 裝 一下 祝福 的 語氣 都 覺得 勉強
què  lián  zhuāng  yí xià  zhù fú  de  yǔ qì  dōu  jué de  miǎn qiáng
still  even  dress  a bit  blessing  of  Tone  all  feel  reluctantly
But I just couldn't bring myself to congratulate him.
雖然 我們 現在 念 不同 的 大學
suī rán  wǒ men  xiàn zài  niàn  bù tóng  de  dà xué
although  us  now  study  different  of  university
It'd be nice to plan things ahead.
可是 我們 可以 討論 看看 研究所 的 方向
kě shì  wǒ men  kě yǐ  tǎo lùn  kàn kàn  yán jiū suǒ  de  fāng xiàng
but  us  can  discuss  Look at it  graduate school  of  direction
We should start thinking about graduate schools.
如果 說 妳 是 真的 想 當 老師 的 話
rú guǒ  shuō  nǐ  shì  zhēn de  xiǎng  dāng  lǎo shī  de  huà
if  say  you  is  Really  think  that  teacher  of  speech
If you really want to be a teacher.
那 我 建議 妳 可以 去 選 教育 研究所
nà  wǒ  jiàn yì  nǐ  kě yǐ  qù  xuǎn  jiào yù  yán jiū suǒ
that  I  Suggest  you  can  go  choose  education  graduate school
Then getting a Master of education would be nice.
這樣 子 以後 月薪 也可以 多 一點 嘛幾 千 塊 錢 吧 至少
zhè yàng  zi  yǐ hòu  yuè xīn  yě kě yǐ  duō  yī diǎn  ma jǐ  qiān  kuài  qián  ba  zhì shǎo
such  offspring  after  salary  Can also be  much  a little  how much  thousand  piece  money  !  at least
At least people will pay you more in the future.
阿和 和 沈佳宜 只 在 一起 短短 的 五個 月
ā hé  hàn  chén jiā yí  zhǐ  zài  yì qǐ  duǎn duǎn  de  wǔ gè  yuè
A-Ho  and  Shen Chia-Yi  only  in  together  Short  of  Five  moon
A-Ho was with Shen Chia-Yi for only five months.
不過 那 也 夠 讓 我 嫉妒 的 了
bù guò  nà  yě  gòu  ràng  wǒ  jí dù  de  le
but  that  also  enough  allow  I  Jealousy  of  is
But that was more than enough to make me jealous like hell.
幹 有 鬼 啊
gàn  yǒu  guǐ  a
fuck  have  ghost  ah
Fuck, what's happening?
靠北 啊
kào běi  a
By North  ah
Shit.
有 鬼 啊 有 鬼 啊
yǒu  guǐ  a  yǒu  guǐ  a
have  ghost  ah  have  ghost  ah
Fuck, what's going on!
快 閃 啊 閃 啊 有 鬼 啊 有 鬼 殺 來了
kuài  shǎn  a  shǎn  a  yǒu  guǐ  a  yǒu  guǐ  shā  lái le
quick  flash  ah  flash  ah  have  ghost  ah  have  ghost  kill  coming
Ghost! Ghost! Let's get the hell out of here!
鬼 在 哪裡 鬼 在 哪裡
guǐ  zài  nǎ lǐ  guǐ  zài  nǎ lǐ
ghost  in  where  ghost  in  where
Shit... ghost? Where? Where?
太 扯 了
tài  chě  le
very  raise  is
This is crazy, man!
我 媽媽 說 我 家 附近 的 旅館 整個 倒下 來
wǒ  mā mā  shuō  wǒ  jiā  fù jìn  de  lǚ guǎn  zhěng gè  dào xià  lái
I  mum  say  I  house  nearby  of  hotel  entire  Fall down  come
My mom just called and said that the hotel next to my house just collapsed.
你 家 不是 在 台北 嗎
nǐ  jiā  bù shì  zài  tái běi  ma
you  house  not  in  Taipei  ?
You are from Taipei, aren't you?
震央 在 台北
zhèn yāng  zài  tái běi
epicenter  in  Taipei
So the epicenter is in Taipei?
這裡 人 太多 了 基地台 超載
zhè lǐ  rén  tài duō  le  jī dì tái  chāo zài
Here  man  too much  is  Base station  overload
It's too crowded here, the system is probably overloaded.
人少 的 地方 搞 不好 才會 通 耶
rén shǎo  de  dì fāng  gǎo  bù hǎo  cái huì  tōng  yé
few people  of  place  clear  not good  Will only  through  ye
Try to give it a shot at somewhere less crowded.
這 理論 對 嗎
zhè  lǐ lùn  duì  ma
this  theory  to  ?
Are you sure?
不知道
bù zhī dào
do not know
I don't know.
喂
wèi
hey
Hello.
柯騰 啊
kē téng  a
Ko-Teng  ah
Ko-Teng?
我 沒事
wǒ  méi shì
I  Nothing
I am safe, don't worry.
可 街上 都 是 人 耶
kě  jiē shàng  dōu  shì  rén  yé
may  Street  all  is  man  ye
Everyone is out on the street, though.
嚇 死 我 了
xià  sǐ  wǒ  le
scare  die  I  is
Thank god
我 剛 聽說 震央 在 台北
wǒ  gāng  tīng shuō  zhèn yāng  zài  tái běi
I  just  heard  epicenter  in  Taipei
I heard that the epicenter is in Taipei.
整個 旅館 都 垮 下來
zhěng gè  lǚ guǎn  dōu  kuǎ  xià lái
entire  hotel  all  fail  Down
And the whole building collapsed
總之
zǒng zhī
In short
anyway.
你 沒事 就 好
nǐ  méi shì  jiù  hǎo
you  Nothing  just  good
Good to hear that you are safe.
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you.
那
nà
that
Alright then
沒事 我 就 …
méi shì  wǒ  jiù  …
Nothing  I  just  …
better go.
我 很 感動
wǒ  hěn  gǎn dòng
I  very  Moving
Wait a minute
真的
zhēn de
Really
I am touched, really.
妳 感動 個頭 啦
nǐ  gǎn dòng  ge tóu  la
you  Moving  head  la
Yeah right.
妳 可是 我 追 了 N 年 的 女生 耶
nǐ  kě shì  wǒ  zhuī  le  N  nián  de  nǚ shēng  yé
you  but  I  pursue  is  N  year  of  Girls  ye
You are the girl that I chased for years!
要是 妳 不見了
yào shi  nǐ  bù jiàn le
if  you  gone
Who else is going to share this memory with me
我 找 誰 回憶 我們 的 故事 啊
wǒ  zhǎo  sheí  huí yì  wǒ men  de  gù shì  a
I  search  who  Memories  us  of  story  ah
if you are gone.
你 還說 呢
nǐ  hái shuō  ne
you  Said  this
Hey, come on.
這 兩年 你 都 沒 打 給 我
zhè  liǎng nián  nǐ  dōu  méi  dǎ  gěi  wǒ
this  Two years  you  all  not  hit  give  I
You didn't even try to contact me in the past two years.
你 也 沒 打 給 我 好不好
nǐ  yě  méi  dǎ  gěi  wǒ  hǎo bù hǎo
you  also  not  hit  give  I  ok
You didn't call either.
真 敢 講
zhēn  gǎn  jiǎng
real  dare  speak
How dare you mention it.
那 妳 最近 都 在 幹嘛
nà  nǐ  zuì jìn  dōu  zài  gàn ma
that  you  recent  all  in  what
So, what have you been doing lately?
沒 幹嘛 啊
méi  gàn ma  a
not  what  ah
Nothing much, really.
還不 就 上課 唸書
hái bù  jiù  shàng kè  niàn shū
Not yet  just  attend class  study
Same old thing, studying.
那 你 呢
nà  nǐ  ne
that  you  this
What about you?
你 該 不會 常 翹 課 吧
nǐ  gāi  bù huì  cháng  qiào  kè  ba
you  should  will not  common  outstanding  lesson  !
Still skipping classes?
當然 啊
dāng rán  a
of course  ah
Of course
我 本來 就 不喜歡 唸書 啊
wǒ  běn lái  jiù  bù xǐ huan  niàn shū  a
I  originally  just  dislike  study  ah
I never liked studying anyway
我 是 為了 妳 才 念 的 耶
wǒ  shì  wèi le  nǐ  cái  niàn  de  yé
I  is  in order to  you  only  study  of  ye
I only studied because of you.
哇 說的 這麼 好聽
wa  shuō de  zhè me  hǎo tīng
wow  Said  so  Nice
Wow! So sweet.
那天 晚上 我們 聊 了 很多 回憶
nèi tiān  wǎn shàng  wǒ men  liáo  le  hěn duō  huí yì
That day  at night  us  somewhat  is  a lot of  Memories
We had a long chat that night, talking about the old days.
好多 好多 用功 讀書 只為了 更 靠近 她 的 日子
hǎo duō  hǎo duō  yòng gōng  dú shū  zhǐ wèi le  gèng  kào jìn  tā  de  rì zi
many  many  work hard  reading  Just for  more  near  she  of  day
The old days when I tried everything to get closer to her.
那 妳 有 男朋友 了 嗎
nà  nǐ  yǒu  nán péng yǒu  le  ma
that  you  have  boyfriend  is  ?
So, do you have a boyfriend now?
要 你 管 啊
yào  nǐ  guǎn  a
want  you  manage  ah
It's none of your business.
我
wǒ
I
I...um...
後來 跟 阿和 在 一起 過
hòu lái  gēn  ā hé  zài  yì qǐ  guò
later  with  A-Ho  in  together  too
I... was with A-Ho for a while
我 知道 啊
wǒ  zhī dào  a
I  know  ah
I know
我 有 聽 他 說
wǒ  yǒu  tīng  tā  shuō
I  have  hear  he  say
I heard.
但 後來 為什麼 分手
dàn  hòu lái  wèi shén me  fēn shǒu
only  later  why  Break up
Why did you guys split up?
我 一直 不 想 問 他 想到 就 度 爛
wǒ  yī zhí  bù  xiǎng  wèn  tā  xiǎng dào  jiù  dù  làn
I  Always  no  think  ask  he  think  just  degree  bad
I didn't want to ask him cause that just made me want to kick his ass.
他 對 妳 不好 嗎
tā  duì  nǐ  bù hǎo  ma
he  to  you  not good  ?
Was he mean to you?
也不 是
yě bù  shì
nor  is
Not really
我 只是 覺得 阿和 不夠 喜歡 我
wǒ  zhǐ shì  jué de  ā hé  bù gòu  xǐ huan  wǒ
I  just  feel  A-Ho  not enough  like  I
I just felt that he didn't like me that much.
阿和 很 喜歡 妳
ā hé  hěn  xǐ huan  nǐ
A-Ho  very  like  you
No, A-Ho was crazy about you, head over heels!
被 你 喜歡 過 很 難 覺得 別人 有 那麼 喜歡 我
bèi  nǐ  xǐ huan  guò  hěn  nán  jué de  bié rén  yǒu  nà me  xǐ huan  wǒ
by  you  like  too  very  difficult  feel  other people  have  like that  like  I
Having being loved by you makes it harder for me to feel other's love.
哇 這麼 感 人 啊
wa  zhè me  gǎn  rén  a
wow  so  feel  man  ah
You are kidding me right?
你 不要 破壞 氣氛 喔 現在
nǐ  bù yào  pò huài  qì fēn  ō  xiàn zài
you  Do not  damage  mood  oh  now
Don't ruin it now.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Hey, Shen Chia-Yi.
我 可不可以 問 妳
wǒ  kě bù kě yǐ  wèn  nǐ
I  can we  ask  you
Can I ask you a question?
為什麼 當時 沒有 想要 和 我 在 一起 啊
wèi shén me  dāng shí  méi yǒu  xiǎng yào  hàn  wǒ  zài  yì qǐ  a
why  then  No  Want to  and  I  in  together  ah
Why didn't you want to be with me at that time?
常常 聽到 人家 說 啊
cháng cháng  tīng dào  rén jiā  shuō  a
often  Hear it  People  say  ah
You know...
戀愛 最美 好 的時候
liàn ài  zuì měi  hǎo  de shí hòu
in love  most beautiful  good  when
People always say that the most wonderful time of a relationship
就是 暖昧 的時候
jiù shì  nuǎn mèi  de shí hòu
is  ambiguous  when
happens before it really happens.
等到 真正 在 一起 了
děng dào  zhēn zhèng  zài  yì qǐ  le
wait until  real  in  together  is
When two people are together.
很多 感覺 都 會 消失 不 見
hěn duō  gǎn jué  dōu  huì  xiāo shī  bù  jiàn
a lot of  feel  all  can  disappear  no  see
The magic vanishes easily.
所以 我 就 想 乾脆 就 讓 你 再 追 我 久 一點
suǒ yǐ  wǒ  jiù  xiǎng  gān cuì  jiù  ràng  nǐ  zài  zhuī  wǒ  jiǔ  yī diǎn
and so  I  just  think  simply  just  allow  you  again  pursue  I  long  a little
So I thought it'd be better if I let you chase me longer.
不然 等 你 追到 我 之後 就 變 懶 了 那 我 不是 很 虧 嗎
bù rán  děng  nǐ  zhuī dào  wǒ  zhī hòu  jiù  biàn  lǎn  le  nà  wǒ  bù shì  hěn  kuī  ma
otherwise  wait  you  Catch up  I  after that  just  change  lazy  is  that  I  not  very  lose  ?
Otherwise, if we got together right away, it'd be less fun.
妳 真的 很 雞巴 耶
nǐ  zhēn de  hěn  jī bā  yé
you  Really  very  cock  ye
Man, that's slack!
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
妳 相信 有 平行 時 空 嗎
nǐ  xiāng xìn  yǒu  píng xíng  shí  kōng  ma
you  Believe  have  parallel  time  empty  ?
Do you believe in parallel universe?
也許 在 那個 平行 時空裡 我們 是 在 一起 的
yě xǔ  zài  nà gè  píng xíng  shí kōng lǐ  wǒ men  shì  zài  yì qǐ  de
Maybe  in  that one  parallel  time and space  us  is  in  together  of
Maybe in that universe, we are together.
真 羨慕 他們 啊
zhēn  xiàn mù  tā men  a
real  envy  they  ah
How I envy them.
謝謝你 喜歡 我
xiè xiè nǐ  xǐ huan  wǒ
thank you  like  I
Thank you for liking me.
我 也 很 喜歡
wǒ  yě  hěn  xǐ huan
I  also  very  like
Yes.
當年 喜歡 妳 的 我
dāng nián  xǐ huan  nǐ  de  wǒ
then  like  you  of  I
Thank you for letting me like you in those years.
妳 永遠 是 我 眼中 的 蘋果
nǐ  yǒng yuǎn  shì  wǒ  yǎn zhōng  de  píng guǒ
you  forever  is  I  Eyes  of  apple
You are always the apple of my eye.
大四 了
dà sì  le
senior  is
Then it came to Senior year.
我 身邊 的 每一個 人 都 在 準備 考 研究所
wǒ  shēn biān  de  měi yī gè  rén  dōu  zài  zhǔn bèi  kǎo  yán jiū suǒ
I  Around  of  every  man  all  in  ready  examine  graduate school
Everyone around me was preparing for grad schools
我 不曉得 我 將來 想做 什麼
wǒ  bù xiǎo de  wǒ  jiāng lái  xiǎng zuò  shén me
I  do not know  I  future  Want to do it  what
I had no idea what I wanted to do at that time.
可是 每個人 都 在 唸書 弄得 我 很 緊張
kě shì  měi gè rén  dōu  zài  niàn shū  nòng de  wǒ  hěn  jǐn zhāng
but  everyone  all  in  study  Confused  I  very  tension
Everyone was studying so hard and it made me nervous.
只好 跟著 大家 一起 跑 圖書館
zhǐ hǎo  gēn zhe  dà jiā  yì qǐ  pǎo  tú shū guǎn
Had to  Follow  everyone  together  run  library
So I decided to join them in the library.
但 莫名 其妙 的 我 卻 開始 在 網路上寫 起了 小說
dàn  mò míng  qí miào  de  wǒ  què  kāi shǐ  zài  wǎng lù shàng xiě  qǐ le  xiǎo shuō
only  Inexplicable  wonderful  of  I  still  Start  in  blog  get up  story
And out of the blue, I started to write stories on my blog.
老曹 退 伍 後 沒去 美國 打 NBA
lǎo cáo  tuì  wǔ  hòu  méi qù  měi guó  dǎ  NBA
Tsao  retreat  five  after  Did not go  USA  hit  NBA
Tsao didn't make his way to NBA.
反而 跑 去 二手 車廠 賣 車
fǎn ér  pǎo  qù  èr shǒu  chē chǎng  mài  chē
instead  run  go  second hand  depot  sell  car
He ended up selling second hand cars.
他 是 天生 好 手
tā  shì  tiān shēng  hǎo  shǒu
he  is  Born  good  hand
And it turned out he's pretty good at it.
平均 每 兩天 就可以 賣出 一 台車
píng jūn  měi  liǎng tiān  jiù kě yǐ  mài chū  yī  tái chē
average  every  Two days  can  sells  one  car
On average, he sells one car every other day.
嚇 死人 了
xià  sǐ rén  le
scare  dead  is
Unbelievable.
引擎 聲 它 騙 不了人 的
yǐn qíng  shēng  tā  piàn  bù liǎo rén  de
engine  sound  it  cheat  nobody  of
The engine never lies.
來
lái
come
Here.
你的 右腳 輕 踩 一下 油門
nǐ de  yòu jiǎo  qīng  cǎi  yí xià  yóu mén
your  Right foot  light  step on  a bit  accelerator
Put your foot on the gas gently.
是不是 還沒 改 喔
shì bù shì  hái méi  gǎi  ō
isn't it  not yet  change  oh
Hear that sound?
還沒 改 之前 它 的 聲線 就 已經 非常 的 飽滿
hái méi  gǎi  zhī qián  tā  de  shēng xiàn  jiù  yǐ jīng  fēi cháng  de  bǎo mǎn
not yet  change  prior to  it  of  voice  just  already  very much  of  full
It's this powerful before we upgrade it, can you imagine if we do?
當 它 上路 之後 轉速 到達 兩千 TURBO
dāng  tā  shàng lù  zhī hòu  zhuǎn sù  dào dá  liǎng qiān  TURBO
that  it  On the road  after that  rpm  Arrivals  two thousand  TURBO
I bet it is going to run over 2000 rpm when it hits the road.
馬力 可說是 隨傳 隨到
mǎ lì  kě shuō shì  suí chuán  suí dào
horsepower  Can be said to be  preach  with
The horsepower is beyond your imagination.
怎麼樣 啊 喜歡 吧
zěn me yàng  a  xǐ huan  ba
how is it  ah  like  !
What do you think? You like it?
喜歡
xǐ huan
like
I like it.
喜歡 的 話 我們 上路 開 一段 怎麼樣
xǐ huan  de  huà  wǒ men  shàng lù  kāi  yī duàn  zěn me yàng
like  of  speech  us  On the road  open  A paragraph  how is it
Well then, how about we take this beast out for a ride?
好
hǎo
good
Okay.
GO
該邊 考 上了 公務員
gāi biān  kǎo  shàng le  gōng wù yuán
groin  examine  On the  Civil servants
Groin passed the government worker's exam.
在 永 和 市立 圖書館 當 行政 課員
zài  yǒng  hàn  shì lì  tú shū guǎn  dāng  xíng zhèng  kè yuán
in  long  and  city  library  that  administrative  classmate
He is now working as a librarian.
每天 都 在 騙 無知 的 小美眉
měi tiān  dōu  zài  piàn  wú zhī  de  xiǎo měi méi
every day  all  in  cheat  ignorance  of  young girl
Which he gets to play perform magic to young innocent girls every day.
同學 看清楚 這 本 書 吹 口氣 吧
tóng xué  kàn qīng chu  zhè  běn  shū  chuī  kǒu qì  ba
classmate  See clearly  this  this  book  blow  Tone  !
See this book? Blow on it.
看 仔細 喔
kàn  zǐ xì  ō
look  careful  oh
Now, pay attention.
你 神經病 啊
nǐ  shén jīng bìng  a
you  numb  ah
Are you nuts?
給 我 站住
gěi  wǒ  zhàn zhù
give  I  stop
Stop there.
阿和 那個 胖子 在 當 保險 業務
ā hé  nà gè  pàng zi  zài  dāng  bǎo xiǎn  yè wù
A-Ho  that one  fat guy  in  that  insurance  business
A-Ho became an insurance sales man.
很 喜歡 開車 的 他
hěn  xǐ huan  kāi chē  de  tā
very  like  drive  of  he
He loves driving his car.
平均 一天 有 十二 個 小時 都 待 在 車 上 雖然 有 點 狼狽
píng jūn  yī tiān  yǒu  shí èr  ge  xiǎo shí  dōu  dài  zài  chē  shàng  suī rán  yǒu  diǎn  láng bèi
average  one day  have  twelve  piece  hour  all  treat  in  car  on  although  have  point  Embarrassed
Every day he spends about 12 hours in it, even though it's tough
但 他 一定 會 成功 的
dàn  tā  yī dìng  huì  chéng gōng  de
only  he  for sure  can  success  of
I do believe he will succeed one day.
畢竟 他 可是 我們 之間 唯 一 追到 過 沈佳宜 的 人 啊
bì jìng  tā  kě shì  wǒ men  zhī jiān  wéi  yī  zhuī dào  guò  chén jiā yí  de  rén  a
after all  he  but  us  between  only  one  Catch up  too  Shen Chia-Yi  of  man  ah
After all he is the only person who has officially dated Shen Chia-Yi.
喂 李先生 嗎
wèi  lǐ xiān shēng  ma
hey  Mr Li  ?
Hello, is this Mr. Lee?
是 是 我 是
shì  shì  wǒ  shì
is  is  I  is
Yes, speaking.
對 啊 就是 上次 跟 您 提過 的 那個 壽險 型保 單 喔
duì  a  jiù shì  shàng cì  gēn  nín  tí guò  de  nà gè  shòu xiǎn  xíng bǎo  dān  ō
to  ah  is  Last time  with  you  mentioned  of  that one  life insurance  warranty  single  oh
Hi, remember the insurance plan that I talked to you about last time?
我 已經 把 資料 都 準備 好了
wǒ  yǐ jīng  bǎ  zī liào  dōu  zhǔn bèi  hǎo le
I  already  take  data  all  ready  All right
I have already gathered all the information for you.
那是 不是 跟 您 約個 時間 到 您 公司 去 跟 您 做個 詳細 的 說明
nà shì  bù shì  gēn  nín  yuē gè  shí jiān  dào  nín  gōng sī  qù  gēn  nín  zuò ge  xiáng xì  de  shuō míng
That is  not  with  you  Appointment  time  to  you  company  go  with  you  do  detailed  of  Description
Just wondering when is a good time to pay you a visit in your office.
勃起 大學 畢業 後 先去 當兵 然後 立刻 飛去 美國 念 碩士
bó qǐ  dà xué  bì yè  hòu  xiān qù  dāng bīng  rán hòu  lì kè  fēi qù  měi guó  niàn  shuò shì
boner  university  graduate  after  Go first  Soldier  then  Immediately  Fly away  USA  study  master's degree
Boner flew to America for graduate school immediately after his military service.
勃起 的 英文 很 爛
bó qǐ  de  yīng wén  hěn  làn
boner  of  English  very  bad
Boner's English sucked
我 真 不知道 他 是 哪 來 的 勇氣 去 美國 玩 大 冒險
wǒ  zhēn  bù zhī dào  tā  shì  nǎ  lái  de  yǒng qì  qù  měi guó  wán  dà  mào xiǎn
I  real  do not know  he  is  where  come  of  courage  go  USA  joke  big  adventure
I don't know how the hell he had the guts to go to the States.
大概 真的 很想 換 個國 家 打手槍 吧
dà gài  zhēn de  hěn xiǎng  huàn  gè guó  jiā  dǎ shǒu qiāng  ba
probably  Really  Want to  change  Country  house  masturbate  !
Perhaps he wanted to masturbate in a different country.
如果 書念 不會 就 儘管 回來 知道 嗎
rú guǒ  shū niàn  bù huì  jiù  jǐn guǎn  huí lái  zhī dào  ma
if  Read the book  will not  just  in spite of  come back  know  ?
If you can't stand it, just come back, understand?
媽 妳 不要 亂 講話 啦
mā  nǐ  bù yào  luàn  jiǎng huà  la
mother  you  Do not  chaos  Speak  la
Ma, stop talking nonsense
媽媽 是 跟 你 說 真的 啦
mā mā  shì  gēn  nǐ  shuō  zhēn de  la
mum  is  with  you  say  Really  la
I am serious.
你 如果 書念 不好 就 回來
nǐ  rú guǒ  shū niàn  bù hǎo  jiù  huí lái
you  if  Read the book  not good  just  come back
If it's too hard, then just come back
媽媽 不會 罵 你 啦
mā mā  bù huì  mà  nǐ  la
mum  will not  accuse  you  la
I will not blame you, I promise.
媽 我 知道 啦
mā  wǒ  zhī dào  la
mother  I  know  la
Fine, I got it.
來 跟 爸爸 說 再見 一下
lái  gēn  bà ba  shuō  zài jiàn  yí xià
come  with  father  say  Goodbye  a bit
Okay, it's dad's turn to say good-bye now.
勃起 這 一 飛 兩年 又 過去 了
bó qǐ  zhè  yī  fēi  liǎng nián  yòu  guò qù  le
boner  this  one  fly  Two years  and  past  is
Two years gone by while Boner was overseas.
對了 還有 胡家瑋
duì le  hái yǒu  hú jiā wěi
correct  and also  Hu Chia-Wei
Oh, yes, and there is Hu Chia-Wei.
那一 個 只會 畫 智障 光頭 的 胡家瑋
nà yī  ge  zhǐ huì  huà  zhì zhàng  guāng tóu  de  hú jiā wěi
That one  piece  Only will  draw  retard  Bald head  of  Hu Chia-Wei
That girl who always drew retarded stuff in her books.
現在 有 了 另外 一個 名字
xiàn zài  yǒu  le  lìng wài  yī gè  míng zì
now  have  is  In addition  One  first name
She now has another name.
彎彎
wān wān
Wan Wan
Wan Wan.
所以 囉 最後 會 實現 夢想 的
suǒ yǐ  luō  zuì hòu  huì  shí xiàn  mèng xiǎng  de
and so  eh  At last  can  achieve  dream  of
So it proves that those who realize their dreams
往往 不是 最有 才華 的 人
wǎng wǎng  bù shì  zuì yǒu  cái huá  de  rén
often  not  Most  Talented  of  man
are often not the most clever ones in school.
而是 直到 最後 也 絕不 放棄 的 那一 個人
ér shì  zhí dào  zuì hòu  yě  jué bù  fàng qì  de  nà yī  gè rén
Instead  until  At last  also  no way  give up  of  That one  people
But they are definitely those who persist till the end
我 很 高興 我 看走眼 了
wǒ  hěn  gāo xìng  wǒ  kàn zǒu yǎn  le
I  very  happy  I  mistake  is
I am very glad that I was wrong.
當 勃起 把 外國 學歷 騙 回 台灣 的時候
dāng  bó qǐ  bǎ  wài guó  xué lì  piàn  huí  tái wān  de shí hòu
that  boner  take  Foreign  education  cheat  return  Taiwan  when
When Boner came home with a foreign degree
我 接到 了 一 通 電話
wǒ  jiē dào  le  yī  tōng  diàn huà
I  Received  is  one  through  phone
I received a phone call.
喂
wèi
hey
Hello.
喂 老朋友 在 忙 嗎
wèi  lǎo péng yǒu  zài  máng  ma
hey  Old friend  in  busy  ?
Hello, old friend, are you busy?
當然 忙 啊
dāng rán  máng  a
of course  busy  ah
Of course I am busy
不管 這 件事 第一個 要 告訴 你
bù guǎn  zhè  jiàn shì  dì yī ge  yào  gào su  nǐ
Regardless of  this  Something  the first  want  tell  you
I don't care, there is something that I want you to be the first to know.
怎樣
zěn yàng
how
What is it?
有空 讓 我 再 追 妳 一次 啊
yǒu kòng  ràng  wǒ  zài  zhuī  nǐ  yī cì  a
free time  allow  I  again  pursue  you  once  ah
You got time for me to go after you again?
這次 恐怕 不行 喔
zhè cì  kǒng pà  bù xíng  ō
this time  I am afraid  No  oh
Not this time, I am afraid.
為什麼
wèi shén me
why
Why?
欸 快 一點 啦
āi  kuài  yī diǎn  la
sigh  quick  a little  la
Hurry up!
今天 大日子 耶
jīn tiān  dà rì zi  yé
today  big day  ye
It's a big day today.
欸 你 想 讓 新娘子 等 你 一個人 喔
āi  nǐ  xiǎng  ràng  xīn niáng zi  děng  nǐ  yī gè rén  ō
sigh  you  think  allow  bride  wait  you  A person  oh
You want to make the bride wait for you?
乾杯
gān bēi
Cheers
Cheers.
後悔 了 吧
hòu huǐ  le  ba
regret  is  !
Regret it now?
當年 我 這麼 好 追 你們 全 都 去 追 沈佳宜 啦
dāng nián  wǒ  zhè me  hǎo  zhuī  nǐ men  quán  dōu  qù  zhuī  chén jiā yí  la
then  I  so  good  pursue  you  whole  all  go  pursue  Shen Chia-Yi  la
I was so available back then, but you guys all went for Shen Chia-Yi.
那 我 現在 追 還 來得及 嗎
nà  wǒ  xiàn zài  zhuī  hái  lái de jí  ma
that  I  now  pursue  still  Come and get it  ?
So does that mean I still have a chance?
你 很 爛 耶
nǐ  hěn  làn  yé
you  very  bad  ye
You suck!
其實 啊
qí shí  a
in fact  ah
I got to tell you something
我 以前 沒有 認真 追過 沈佳宜
wǒ  yǐ qián  méi yǒu  rèn zhēn  zhuī guò  chén jiā yí
I  before  No  serious  caught up  Shen Chia-Yi
I wasn't really serious about chasing after Shen Chia-Yi before.
為什麼
wèi shén me
why
Why?
因為 我 看 你們 大家 都 追 她
yīn wèi  wǒ  kàn  nǐ men  dà jiā  dōu  zhuī  tā
because  I  look  you  everyone  all  pursue  she
I just didn't want to miss out.
所以 我 才跟 著 追 她 的 啊
suǒ yǐ  wǒ  cái gēn  jiáo  zhuī  tā  de  a
and so  I  Only with it  manifest  pursue  she  of  ah
Everyone went after her, so I did, too.
比起 我 啊
bǐ qǐ  wǒ  a
Compared to  I  ah
In comparison to me
我 真的 覺得 你們 很不 要 臉 耶
wǒ  zhēn de  jué de  nǐ men  hěn bù  yào  liǎn  yé
I  Really  feel  you  Very bad  want  face  ye
I must say, you guys are shameless.
人家 現在 已經 成為 別人 的 新娘子 了
rén jiā  xiàn zài  yǐ jīng  chéng wéi  bié rén  de  xīn niáng zi  le
People  now  already  become  other people  of  bride  is
She is the bride today, but none of you is the groom.
你們 竟然 還有 臉 來 參加 這個 婚禮
nǐ men  jìng rán  hái yǒu  liǎn  lái  cān jiā  zhè ge  hūn lǐ
you  actually  and also  face  come  participate  This one  wedding
How dare you guys show your faces at this wedding.
真的 是有 夠 厚 臉皮 的
zhēn de  shì yǒu  gòu  hòu  liǎn pí  de
Really  there is  enough  thick  skin  of
Shameless!
許博淳
xǔ bó chún
Hsu Bo-Chun
Hsu Bo-Chun.
我 聽 你 在 喇叭
wǒ  tīng  nǐ  zài  lǎ bā
I  hear  you  in  speaker
Kiss my ass.
喝酒 啦
hē jiǔ  la
drink  la
Just drink!
好歹 我 也 曾經 追到 過 好不好
hǎo dǎi  wǒ  yě  céng jīng  zhuī dào  guò  hǎo bù hǎo
Whatever the outcome  I  also  once  Catch up  too  ok
Oh, please, I have dated her, haven't I?
那是 詐胡 啦
nà shì  zhà hú  la
That is  fraud  la
That was a scam.
對 啊 詐胡 啦
duì  a  zhà hú  la
to  ah  fraud  la
Exactly, cheater!
對了 對了
duì le  duì le
correct  correct
Hey,
我們 來 打個賭
wǒ men  lái  dǎ gè dǔ
us  come  make a bet
let's make a bet.
我們 猜 拳
wǒ men  cāi  quán
us  guess  fist
Let's do paper, scissors stone.
最 輸 的 那一 個人
zuì  shū  de  nà yī  gè rén
most  lose  of  That one  people
The loser
等一下 要 在 新郎 新娘 進場 的時候 伸 腳 把 新郎 絆倒
děng yī xià  yào  zài  xīn láng  xīn niáng  jìn chǎng  de shí hòu  shēn  jiǎo  bǎ  xīn láng  bàn dào
Wait  want  in  bridegroom  bride  approach  when  extend  foot  take  bridegroom  stumble
will have to trip the groom when they walk in later.
太 突然 了 啦 超 糗 的
tài  tú rán  le  la  chāo  qiǔ  de
very  suddenly  is  la  super  embarrassing  of
What the hell was that? It's embarrassing!
你們 這樣 很 壞 耶 一點 都 不懂 得 祝福
nǐ men  zhè yàng  hěn  huài  yé  yī diǎn  dōu  bù dǒng  dé  zhù fú
you  such  very  bad  ye  a little  all  Do not understand  get  blessing
You guys are mean. Can't you just show some love to the couple?
你 不懂 啦
nǐ  bù dǒng  la
you  Do not understand  la
You won't understand.
如果 你 真的 非常 喜歡 過 一個 女生 就 會 知道
rú guǒ  nǐ  zhēn de  fēi cháng  xǐ huan  guò  yī gè  nǚ shēng  jiù  huì  zhī dào
if  you  Really  very much  like  too  One  Girls  just  can  know
If you really like a girl.
要 真心 祝福 她 跟 別人 永遠 幸福 快樂 根本 是 不可能 的 事
yào  zhēn xīn  zhù fú  tā  gēn  bié rén  yǒng yuǎn  xìng fú  kuài lè  gēn běn  shì  bù kě néng  de  shì
want  sincere  blessing  she  with  other people  forever  happy  happy  simply  is  impossible  of  thing
It is impossible to see her marry to another guy and still bless them.
對 啊
duì  a
to  ah
That's right.
像 我們 這種 背後 放 箭 的 才 叫做 真愛
xiàng  wǒ men  zhè zhǒng  bèi hòu  fàng  jiàn  de  cái  jiào zuò  zhēn ài
like  us  this kind  behind  put  arrow  of  only  Called it  Love
True love means someone should sneak up and stabs the groom in the back.
對 真愛
duì  zhēn ài
to  Love
Correct.
絆死 他
bàn sǐ  tā
stumble  he
Trip him!
我 錯了
wǒ  cuò le
I  wrong
But I am wrong.
原來 當 你 真的 非常 非常 喜歡 一個 女孩
yuán lái  dāng  nǐ  zhēn de  fēi cháng  fēi cháng  xǐ huan  yī gè  nǚ hái
original  that  you  Really  very much  very much  like  One  girl
In fact, when you really like a girl, you'd be happy for her.
當 她 有 人 疼 有 人 愛
dāng  tā  yǒu  rén  téng  yǒu  rén  ài
that  she  have  man  pain  have  man  love
When you see her finding her Mr. Right.
你 會 真心 真 意 的 祝福 她
nǐ  huì  zhēn xīn  zhēn  yì  de  zhù fú  tā
you  can  sincere  real  thought  of  blessing  she
You will want them to be together.
永遠 幸福 快樂
yǒng yuǎn  xìng fú  kuài lè
forever  happy  happy
And to live happily ever after.
來 靠近 一點 喔
lái  kào jìn  yī diǎn  ō
come  near  a little  oh
Come closer.
再 一個 來 喔
zài  yī gè  lái  ō
again  One  come  oh
One more, ready
一 二 三 來
yī  èr  sān  lái
one  two  three  come
1, 2, 3, go.
好 OK
hǎo  OK
good  OK
OK
恭喜 恭喜 新婚 愉快
gōng xǐ  gōng xǐ  xīn hūn  yú kuài
Congratulations  Congratulations  Newly married  happy
Congratulations, happy marriage.
快快 快
kuài kuài  kuài
Fast  quick
Come, quickly
我 要 在 沈佳宜 旁邊
wǒ  yào  zài  chén jiā yí  páng biān
I  want  in  Shen Chia-Yi  next to
I want to stand next to Shen Chia-Yi.
我們 要 拍多 一點
wǒ men  yào  pāi duō  yī diǎn
us  want  shoot more  a little
We should take more photos.
要 拍 美 一點 喔
yào  pāi  měi  yī diǎn  ō
want  photograph  beautiful  a little  oh
How do I look? Get a pretty one for me.
好 來 喔 來 喔
hǎo  lái  ō  lái  ō
good  come  oh  come  oh
All right. Here it comes.
準備 好了
zhǔn bèi  hǎo le
ready  All right
Ready.
來 一 二 三 來
lái  yī  èr  sān  lái
come  one  two  three  come
Ok, one, two, three, go.
再一次 喔 來 喔 來 喔 來 喔 再一次 喔 來
zài yī cì  ō  lái  ō  lái  ō  lái  ō  zài yī cì  ō  lái
one more time  oh  come  oh  come  oh  come  oh  one more time  oh  come
One more, one, two, three... done.
OK
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you.
新郎 大哥 打個 商量
xīn láng  dà gē  dǎ gè  shāng liáng
bridegroom  Big brother  Make a fight  discuss
Hey, man, we have a suggestion.
什麼 商量
shén me  shāng liáng
what  discuss
About what?
我們 紅包 包 這麼 多
wǒ men  hóng bāo  bāo  zhè me  duō
us  red envelope  wrap  so  much
See, the thing is that we have loaded you with cash.
想親 新娘 不知道 可不可以 耶
xiǎng qīn  xīn niáng  bù zhī dào  kě bù kě yǐ  yé
think kiss  bride  do not know  can we  ye
Don't you think we have the right to kiss the bride?
新娘 說 好 我 就 沒 問題 呀
xīn niáng  shuō  hǎo  wǒ  jiù  méi  wèn tí  ya
bride  say  good  I  just  not  problem  yeah
Well, I am fine if she says fine.
好啊
hǎo a
Okay
Well, fine.
想親 新娘 可以
xiǎng qīn  xīn niáng  kě yǐ
think kiss  bride  can
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
不過 呢 等一下 你們 要 怎樣 親新娘
bù guò  ne  děng yī xià  nǐ men  yào  zěn yàng  qīn xīn niáng
but  this  Wait  you  want  how  kiss bride
You can kiss the bride.
就 要 先 怎麼 親我
jiù  yào  xiān  zěn me  qīn wǒ
just  want  first  how  kiss me
But you have to kiss me first.
這樣 才 公平 啊
zhè yàng  cái  gōng píng  a
such  only  fair  ah
Kiss me the way you want to kiss her, so that's fair.
沒 聽說 過來 賓 要 親新娘
méi  tīng shuō  guò lái  bīn  yào  qīn xīn niáng
not  heard  come  guest  want  kiss bride
Bullshit!
還要 過 關斬將 的
hái yào  guò  guān zhǎn jiàng  de
But also  too  hurdle  of
What kind of rule is that?
對 啊
duì  a
to  ah
Yeah, no way.
你 這樣 太 小氣 了 啦
nǐ  zhè yàng  tài  xiǎo qì  le  la
you  such  very  stingy  is  la
Don't be stingy.
這樣 不對 啦
zhè yàng  bù duì  la
such  wrong  la
That is not right.
那 就 沒 辦法 囉
nà  jiù  méi  bàn fǎ  luō
that  just  not  Method  eh
Well then... sorry.
哈哈 哈 你們 打 的 如意 算 …
hā hā  hā  nǐ men  dǎ  de  rú yì  suàn  …
Haha  ha  you  hit  of  Wishful  count  …
Ha, ha... Look at yourself, guys.
幹嘛 啊
gàn ma  a
what  ah
What?
昨天 謝謝
zuó tiān  xiè xiè
yesterday  Thank you
Thank you for yesterday.
真的假的 啦
zhēn de jiǎ de  la
really?  la
Are you for real?
還 愛心 考卷 咧
hái  ài xīn  kǎo juǎn  liě
still  Love  Test paper  frown
A quiz made out of love...
你 錯 很多 耶
nǐ  cuò  hěn duō  yé
you  error  a lot of  ye
You made so many mistakes.
你 回去 沒 看 參考書 就 直接 寫 對不對
nǐ  huí qù  méi  kàn  cān kǎo shū  jiù  zhí jiē  xiě  duì bù duì
you  go back  not  look  exercise book  just  direct  write  right
You did the problems without reading the exercise book, didn't you?
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
Shen Chia-Yi.
妳 超正 點 的
nǐ  chāo zhèng  diǎn  de
you  awesome  point  of
You were so cool when you shouted at him.
哭 起來 也 超正 的
kū  qǐ lái  yě  chāo zhèng  de
weep  stand up  also  awesome  of
You look so pretty when you cry, too.
雖然 我 還沒 追到 妳
suī rán  wǒ  hái méi  zhuī dào  nǐ
although  I  not yet  Catch up  you
Even though we are not seeing each other yet.
不過 那些 追 都 沒 追過 妳 的 男生
bù guò  nà xiē  zhuī  dōu  méi  zhuī guò  nǐ  de  nán shēng
but  those  pursue  all  not  caught up  you  of  boy
But those guys who you don't even know.
怎麼 可以 牽 你的 手
zěn me  kě yǐ  qiān  nǐ de  shǒu
how  can  hold  your  hand
Can you not let them hold your hands?
我 自己 都 沒 牽 過
wǒ  zì jǐ  dōu  méi  qiān  guò
I  self  all  not  hold  too
I haven't even held them myself.
你 特地 辦 個 比賽 把 自己 搞 受傷
nǐ  tè dì  bàn  ge  bǐ sài  bǎ  zì jǐ  gǎo  shòu shāng
you  specially  manage  piece  game  take  self  clear  Injured
You held this game and got yourself hurt.
你 怎麼會 這麼 幼稚 啊
nǐ  zěn me huì  zhè me  yòu zhì  a
you  how come  so  naive  ah
How can you be so childish?
幼稚
yòu zhì
naive
Childish?
就是 幼稚
jiù shì  yòu zhì
is  naive
Yes, childish.
很 幼稚
hěn  yòu zhì
very  naive
Very childish and totally immature.
笨蛋
bèn dàn
fool
Idiot.
對 啦 我 就是 笨蛋 啦
duì  la  wǒ  jiù shì  bèn dàn  la
to  la  I  is  fool  la
Yes, I am an idiot.
大 笨蛋
dà  bèn dàn
big  fool
Moron.
大 笨蛋 才會 追 妳 這麼 久
dà  bèn dàn  cái huì  zhuī  nǐ  zhè me  jiǔ
big  fool  Will only  pursue  you  so  long
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase you for such a long time.
你 什麼 都 不懂
nǐ  shén me  dōu  bù dǒng
you  what  all  Do not understand
You don't understand anything.
我 就是 什麼 都 不懂 啦
wǒ  jiù shì  shén me  dōu  bù dǒng  la
I  is  what  all  Do not understand  la
You're right, I don't!
對不起
duì bù qǐ
I am sorry
Sorry
是 我 太 幼稚 了
shì  wǒ  tài  yòu zhì  le
is  I  very  naive  is
I was the immature one.
其實 會 解 這種 題目 有 什麼 了 不起 的
qí shí  huì  jiě  zhè zhǒng  tí mù  yǒu  shén me  le  bù qǐ  de
in fact  can  solution  this kind  topic  have  what  is  Can not afford to  of
Being able to solve these tricky math questions does not help anything in life!
我 敢 跟 妳 賭
wǒ  gǎn  gēn  nǐ  dǔ
I  dare  with  you  bet
You want to bet?
十年 後 我 連 LOG 是什麼 都 不知道
shí nián  hòu  wǒ  lián  LOG  shì shén me  dōu  bù zhī dào
ten years  after  I  even  LOG  What is it?  all  do not know
I won't even know what “log” means ten years later.
還 是 可以 活得 好好 的
hái  shì  kě yǐ  huó de  hǎo hǎo  de
still  is  can  life  Well  of
And it doesn't make my life any harder.
嗯
ń
umm
Emmmm.
妳 不 相信
nǐ  bù  xiāng xìn
you  no  Believe
You don't believe me
我 相信 啊
wǒ  xiāng xìn  a
I  Believe  ah
I do believe you.
相信 還 那麼 用功 讀書
xiāng xìn  hái  nà me  yòng gōng  dú shū
Believe  still  like that  work hard  reading
Then, why do you still work so hard?
人生 本來 就 有 很多 事 是 徒勞無功 的 啊
rén shēng  běn lái  jiù  yǒu  hěn duō  shì  shì  tú láo wú gōng  de  a
life  originally  just  have  a lot of  thing  is  Futile  of  ah
You don't expect returns from everything you do.
你 想 知道 答案 嗎
nǐ  xiǎng  zhī dào  dá àn  ma
you  think  know  answer  ?
Do you want to know the answer?
如果 柯景騰 跟 我 告白 的 話 我 會 很 高興 的
rú guǒ  kē jǐng téng  gēn  wǒ  gào bái  de  huà  wǒ  huì  hěn  gāo xìng  de
if  Ko Ching-Teng  with  I  confess  of  speech  I  can  very  happy  of
If Ko Ching-Teng comes and confesses to me I will be very happy.
沈佳宜
chén jiā yí
Shen Chia-Yi
我 喜歡 妳
wǒ  xǐ huan  nǐ
I  like  you
I like you very much.
(Ok, let's be together)
真 羨慕 他們 呢
zhēn  xiàn mù  tā men  ne
real  envy  they  this
How I envy them.
謝謝你 喜歡 我
xiè xiè nǐ  xǐ huan  wǒ
thank you  like  I
Thank you for liking me.
那 我 就 繼續 幼稚 下去 囉
nà  wǒ  jiù  jì xù  yòu zhì  xià qù  luō
that  I  just  carry on  naive  Go on  eh
Well then, I am just going to keep on acting childish.
一定 要 喔
yī dìng  yào  ō
for sure  want  oh
Sure, why not!
(Happy Marriage, to the apple of my eye)
洋基 耶
yáng jī  yé
Yankee  ye
Hey, Yankees.
真的 耶
zhēn de  yé
Really  ye
Yeah!
阿建
ā jiàn
A-Chian
A- Chian.
柯騰
kē téng
Ko-Teng
Hey, Ko-Teng.
你 有沒有 想過 把 我們 的 故事 寫成 小說 啊
nǐ  yǒu méi yǒu  xiǎng guò  bǎ  wǒ men  de  gù shì  xiě chéng  xiǎo shuō  a
you  do you have  Thought about it  take  us  of  story  Written in  story  ah
Have you thought about writing our story?
早就 想 啦
zǎo jiù  xiǎng  la
Long ago  think  la
Of course I did!
只是 還想 不 到書 名 不知道 怎麼 開頭
zhǐ shì  hái xiǎng  bù  dào shū  míng  bù zhī dào  zěn me  kāi tóu
just  Think too  no  To the book  name  do not know  how  beginning
I just haven't come up a good name to start with.
我 打手槍 那 件事 可不可以 不要 寫
wǒ  dǎ shǒu qiāng  nà  jiàn shì  kě bù kě yǐ  bù yào  xiě
I  masturbate  that  Something  can we  Do not  write
Hey, can you leave out the part which I was masturbating?
一定 寫
yī dìng  xiě
for sure  write
Sorry man... that has to be in the story.
如果 你 真的 要 寫 的 話
rú guǒ  nǐ  zhēn de  yào  xiě  de  huà
if  you  Really  want  write  of  speech
If you really are going to write it.
記得 把 我 寫 帥 一點 啊
jì de  bǎ  wǒ  xiě  shuài  yī diǎn  a
remember  take  I  write  handsome  a little  ah
Don't forget to let your readers know how handsome I am.
順便 幫 我 徵 女 友
shùn biàn  bāng  wǒ  zhēng  nǚ  yǒu
By the way  help  I  summon  woman  friend
By the way, can you put in some dating advertisements for me, too!
拜託 你 不是 要 追 彎彎
bài tuō  nǐ  bù shì  yào  zhuī  wān wān
please  you  not  want  pursue  Wan Wan
Come on, I thought you are going after Wan Wan?
都 追 啦
dōu  zhuī  la
all  pursue  la
Haha, doesn't really matter.
This is the last image we shot before wrapping up shooting.
The director conspired with the make-up artist to prank the cast.
And painted Michelle Chen's face into...