1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
字幕中文翻译：静默的风
如转载使用  请保留译者信息

2
00:00:10,010 --> 00:00:15,000
制作本字幕纯属个人兴趣交流
任何单位和个人不得作为商业用途

3
00:00:15,010 --> 00:00:20,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

4
00:00:30,910 --> 00:00:35,330
…这里有一份来自国王陛下的公告

5
00:00:35,490 --> 00:00:39,370
在这种情况下 为了我们的祖国

6
00:00:39,540 --> 00:00:42,780
我呼吁所有的城市和乡村

7
00:00:42,950 --> 00:00:47,530
保持正确和适当的行为

8
00:00:47,700 --> 00:00:51,240
四月九日
因为任何不必要的行动或主张

9
00:00:51,240 --> 00:00:54,950
四月九日
会产生严重的后果

10
00:00:54,950 --> 00:00:57,540
四月九日
上帝保佑你们

11
00:00:57,540 --> 00:01:00,490
四月九日
上帝拯救丹麦

12
00:01:00,660 --> 00:01:06,740
克里斯蒂安·雷克斯 于阿马林堡 一九四〇年四月九日

13
00:01:08,330 --> 00:01:12,280
在一九四〇年四月九日的早晨 德国军队通过丹麦和德国的边境

14
00:01:12,490 --> 00:01:16,450
毫无准备和装备最差的丹麦军队与欧洲最强大的军事力量对抗

15
00:01:16,660 --> 00:01:21,660
在南部的日德兰半岛发生了极其艰难的战斗

16
00:01:38,030 --> 00:01:40,190
少尉 中尉告诉我
Second lieutenant, the lieutenant told me

17
00:01:40,190 --> 00:01:41,990
开车送你去训练场
to drive you to the training area.

18
00:01:45,330 --> 00:01:47,700
军营里有一种紧张的气氛
There is a tense mood at the barracks.

19
00:01:47,870 --> 00:01:50,350
他们在跟哥本哈根联络
They have communicated with Copenhagen.

20
00:01:50,350 --> 00:01:51,080
但没人通话
But nobody wants to talk.

21
00:01:51,240 --> 00:01:54,370
我像你一样知之甚少 中士
I know just as little as you, sergeant.

22
00:01:58,640 --> 00:02:00,620
一九四〇年四月八日

23
00:02:00,620 --> 00:02:05,030
她不回答 所以我小心翼翼地向她靠近
Then she won't answer,so I lean carefully towards her.

24
00:02:05,200 --> 00:02:07,580
- 你知道她说什么吗？ - 不知道
- You know what she says then?  - No.

25
00:02:07,740 --> 00:02:10,910
该死的 她不需要一个士兵
Hell, she doesn't wan't a soldier.

26
00:02:11,080 --> 00:02:13,910
我们需要加快速度 我们赶时间
We need to speed up. We are in a hurry.

27
00:02:15,740 --> 00:02:19,490
- 你都做了些什么？ - 跟着我父亲一起干活
- What have you done?  - Worked with my father.

28
00:02:19,660 --> 00:02:23,120
我好久没见到英格丽了
I haven't seen Ingrid as much.

29
00:02:23,280 --> 00:02:26,080
你很快就会见到她
You'll see her again soon.

30
00:02:26,240 --> 00:02:29,160
- 你呢？ 格拉姆  - 是啊 我呢？
- What about you, Gram?  - Yeah, What about me?

31
00:02:29,330 --> 00:02:32,950
- 你做了什么？ - 可能你不想知道
- So, what have you done?  - Like you wan't to know.

32
00:02:33,120 --> 00:02:36,200
然后你可以用它开玩笑 以我的名义
Then you can joke with it,on my behalf.

33
00:02:36,370 --> 00:02:39,080
- 你总认为我最坏  - 是的
- You always think the worst of me.  - Yes.

34
00:02:39,240 --> 00:02:42,280
快点 格拉姆 请告诉我们
Come on, Gram.Please tell us.

35
00:02:42,450 --> 00:02:45,200
要是你们真的不想知道就好了
If you really wan't to know.

36
00:02:45,370 --> 00:02:48,260
我一直在家 在我的家乡
I have just been home, at my folks place.

37
00:02:48,260 --> 00:02:49,950
我洗衣服
Gotten my clothes washed.

38
00:02:50,120 --> 00:02:52,240
读读书
Read a book.

39
00:02:52,410 --> 00:02:56,990
有时我会以你的名义伤心难过 格拉姆
Sometimes I get really sad on your behalf, Gram

40
00:02:57,160 --> 00:02:59,780
格拉姆？
Gram?

41
00:02:59,950 --> 00:03:03,120
你为什么认为 我们的通行证被吊销了？
Why do you think,our passes have been revoked?

42
00:03:03,280 --> 00:03:06,530
你可能会得到相同的答案 这是让人惊恐的考验
You probably got the same answer.It's a test alarming.

43
00:03:06,700 --> 00:03:09,160
这仅仅是一场演习
It is just a drill.

44
00:03:42,570 --> 00:03:45,200
- 少尉  - 中尉
- Second lieutenant.  - Lieutenant.

45
00:03:45,370 --> 00:03:49,240
现在我们又在这里了 新的一批狼就要来了
Now we're here again.Another round of the wolf is coming.

46
00:03:49,410 --> 00:03:52,160
我认为 这可能不只是一场演习
I thought that,its probably not just a drill.

47
00:03:52,320 --> 00:03:55,510
我们收到晚上在基尔(德国北部港市)装运
We received information about night shipments

48
00:03:55,510 --> 00:03:57,070
军事装备的情报
of military equipment in Kiel.

49
00:03:57,240 --> 00:04:01,730
获悉有一辆军列正北上
A train with troops was seen going north,

50
00:04:01,730 --> 00:04:03,200
驶向边境
towards the border.

51
00:04:03,370 --> 00:04:05,530
这听起来不妙
That doesn't sound good.

52
00:04:05,700 --> 00:04:08,480
你的担忧 总参谋部同样也有
The General Staff shares your worries,

53
00:04:08,480 --> 00:04:10,240
所有的通行证都被吊销了
all passes are revoked.

54
00:04:11,570 --> 00:04:14,340
他们派了一个摩托车排下来
They have sent a motorcycle platoon down,

55
00:04:14,350 --> 00:04:15,700
我们将支援那些人
which we will be supporting.

56
00:04:15,870 --> 00:04:19,030
士官班德格阿得带领
Led by a sergeant Bundgaard.

57
00:04:22,910 --> 00:04:25,410
报告 二二五及随行人员报到
225 with entourage, reporting.

58
00:04:25,570 --> 00:04:28,310
你迟到了 放下箱子 拿武器
You are late. Drop the bags, get weapons.

59
00:04:28,310 --> 00:04:30,780
参加射击训练
Join the shooting exercise.

60
00:04:30,950 --> 00:04:35,200
三个士兵 叫他们打扫厨房一星期
The three privates.Give them kitchen duty for the week.

61
00:04:35,370 --> 00:04:38,740
明白 中尉 打扫厨房一星期
Roger, lieutenant.Kitchen duty for a week.

62
00:04:42,070 --> 00:04:44,160
好极了
Perfect.

63
00:04:45,870 --> 00:04:48,660
二二一 射击
221, fire.

64
00:04:48,820 --> 00:04:50,530
好枪法
Good shot.

65
00:04:50,700 --> 00:04:53,490
二一二 射击
212, fire.

66
00:04:56,280 --> 00:04:58,030
再试一次
Try again.

67
00:05:00,910 --> 00:05:04,990
二一二 集中注意力 我们来这里不是为了好玩
212, concentrate.We aren't here for the fun of it.

68
00:05:05,160 --> 00:05:07,380
我不知道我最害怕的是谁
I don't know who I am most afraid of.

69
00:05:07,390 --> 00:05:08,570
拉森还是德国人
Lassen or the Germans.

70
00:05:08,740 --> 00:05:11,690
如果你嘲笑我 我就打不中
I can't if you laugh at me.

71
00:05:11,700 --> 00:05:13,740
反正你打不到任何东西
You don't hit anything anyways.

72
00:05:13,910 --> 00:05:16,410
来点喝的吗？
Something to drink?

73
00:05:16,570 --> 00:05:18,860
咖啡 谢谢 咖啡
Coffee, thanks.Cognac.

74
00:05:21,200 --> 00:05:23,780
我认为 德国人将要去挪威
If you ask me,the Germans are going to Norway.

75
00:05:23,950 --> 00:05:26,040
他们不会在挪威水域
They wan't the Norwegian waters.

76
00:05:26,040 --> 00:05:27,860
丹麦没有战略价值
Denmark have no strategic value.

77
00:05:28,030 --> 00:05:32,820
我们的南部邻居还没有预见到
Our southern neighbors haven't exactly been predictable.

78
00:05:36,410 --> 00:05:38,160
谢谢
Thank you.

79
00:05:39,030 --> 00:05:42,910
你一定是累了 你什么时候醒来的？
You must be tired.When did you wake up?

80
00:05:43,070 --> 00:05:44,910
三点
At three o'clock.

81
00:05:45,070 --> 00:05:47,950
我试着溜出去 但当然
I tried to sneak out, but of course

82
00:05:47,950 --> 00:05:49,410
我把整个家都吵醒了
i woke up the whole home.

83
00:05:49,570 --> 00:05:52,610
现在 你不让你妻子有不必要的担心吗？
Now, you didn't make your wife unnecessarily worried?

84
00:05:52,780 --> 00:05:57,280
我什么也没说 但我的妻子知道我很好
I said nothing,but my wife knows me too well.

85
00:05:59,320 --> 00:06:00,950
这不是德国人第一次调动
It's not the first time the Germans move,

86
00:06:00,950 --> 00:06:03,240
不会有任何事情发生
without anything happening.

87
00:06:03,410 --> 00:06:07,150
- 我们来看看  - 我们结束了射击训练
- Let's see.  - We are ending the shooting exercise.

88
00:06:08,700 --> 00:06:11,610
接下来练习自行车
Next exercise are by the bikes.

89
00:06:11,620 --> 00:06:13,610
去拿自行车 行动
Go to the bikes. Move!

90
00:06:15,240 --> 00:06:18,150
- 嗨 格拉姆  - 见到你很高兴
- Hi, Gram.  - Good to see you.

91
00:06:18,320 --> 00:06:20,790
你大部分击中了你的枪靶？
Are you better at hitting your targets?

92
00:06:20,790 --> 00:06:22,360
去拿自行车 快
Go to the bikes, faster!

93
00:06:25,700 --> 00:06:28,570
准备好了 中士
Ready sergeant.Ready sergeant.

94
00:06:30,200 --> 00:06:32,780
很好 首先练习更换前轮胎
Perfect, first exercise, change front tire.

95
00:06:32,780 --> 00:06:34,650
两分钟 开始
Two minutes. Proceed!

96
00:06:42,990 --> 00:06:45,900
- 你拿着它们？ - 是的
- You have them?  - Yes.

97
00:06:46,070 --> 00:06:48,030
帮助这里 快点
Help here, come on!

98
00:06:54,990 --> 00:06:57,610
给我的轮胎 快 快点
Hand me the tire Faster. Come on.

99
00:07:02,320 --> 00:07:06,280
- 抓住它  - 把轮子弄回去
- Hold it here.  - Get that wheel back on.

100
00:07:06,450 --> 00:07:11,030
- 抓住 装上去  - 拧那些螺母
- Hold on. Up with it.  - Screw those nuts back in.

101
00:07:19,110 --> 00:07:22,990
准备好了 中士
Ready sergeant.Ready sergeant.

102
00:07:23,150 --> 00:07:25,530
很好
Good.

103
00:07:26,650 --> 00:07:28,950
- 中尉  - 再做一遍
- Lieutenant.  - Do it again.

104
00:07:29,110 --> 00:07:31,560
一个半分钟做完
Do it in under one and a half minute

105
00:07:31,560 --> 00:07:33,860
在一个半分钟吗？ 明白
Under one and a half? Roger.

106
00:07:36,110 --> 00:07:38,420
好 再做一次 这次的时间是
Good. Again, this time under one,

107
00:07:38,430 --> 00:07:41,450
一个半分钟 继续
and a half minute. Proceed!

108
00:07:41,610 --> 00:07:43,860
你们还等什么？
What are you waiting for?

109
00:07:45,530 --> 00:07:47,780
快点 拉森 快
Come on, Lassen.Faster!

110
00:07:47,950 --> 00:07:50,360
一个半分钟…
One and a half minute...

111
00:07:50,360 --> 00:07:52,780
他一定喝了尿壶
He must have drunk from the piss pot.

112
00:08:05,360 --> 00:08:09,190
科尔丁 你想的更多的是面包吗？
Kolding, you wan't more of that bread?

113
00:08:09,360 --> 00:08:10,840
是 加斯特森 我想它
Yes, Justesen. I wan't it.

114
00:08:10,840 --> 00:08:12,900
是否还有更多的空间？
Are there room for more?

115
00:08:13,070 --> 00:08:15,610
冷静 你一定回不了家
Chill out. You shall not roll home.

116
00:08:15,780 --> 00:08:18,820
当有许多人的时候 你是多么可笑傲慢 你这个哥本哈根人
Funny how big you are you Copenhageners,when you are many.

117
00:08:18,990 --> 00:08:21,610
但当你独处的时候…
But when you are alone...

118
00:08:21,780 --> 00:08:24,360
…你变得像老鼠一样安静
...you become quiet as mice.

119
00:08:24,530 --> 00:08:27,440
你认为 我们将持续多久？ 格拉姆
How long do you think,we will continue, Gram?

120
00:08:27,610 --> 00:08:30,530
直到我们在一个半分钟内完成
Till we can do it in one and a half minute.

121
00:08:30,700 --> 00:08:34,530
我们已经尽力了 那是不可能的
We have tried.It's not going happen.

122
00:08:34,700 --> 00:08:38,070
那会儿 中尉只是对我们的努力视而不见
The sec. lieutenant just wan't to see us work hard.

123
00:08:38,240 --> 00:08:41,610
他老婆可能没有给他想要的
The wife probably didn't give him what he wanted.

124
00:08:41,780 --> 00:08:44,860
这是你的长官 你在说什么啊
It's your officer, you are talking about.

125
00:08:45,030 --> 00:08:47,740
他听不到我说的
He can't hear me.

126
00:08:47,900 --> 00:08:51,570
除非你去告发我 室长先生
Unless you are going to tell on me,mr. room chairman.

127
00:09:07,940 --> 00:09:10,420
中尉 我从中校那里带来一份
Lieutenant, I have an important message

128
00:09:10,420 --> 00:09:11,780
重要的命令
from the lieutenant colonel.

129
00:09:11,940 --> 00:09:15,570
停止训练 返回军营
Stop the drill and return to the barracks.

130
00:09:15,740 --> 00:09:18,490
饭后 他们必须准备上床睡觉
After a meal they must go to bed in preparedness.

131
00:09:18,650 --> 00:09:20,300
发生了什么事？
What has happened?

132
00:09:20,300 --> 00:09:21,650
有新的情报信息
There is new intelligence information.

133
00:09:21,820 --> 00:09:23,780
一支德国车队…
A German convoy...

134
00:09:23,940 --> 00:09:26,170
…正在向边境移动
...are moving towards the border,

135
00:09:26,170 --> 00:09:27,740
据说有一公里长
it's said to be kilometers long.

136
00:09:27,900 --> 00:09:30,650
中校不想引起恐慌…
The lieutenant colonel doesn't want to cause panic...

137
00:09:30,820 --> 00:09:33,460
…因此 这事必须描述
...and therefore it has to be mentioned

138
00:09:33,470 --> 00:09:35,030
为演习的一部分
as a part of the drill.

139
00:09:37,030 --> 00:09:39,240
卡拉斯特格斯中士 取消用餐
Sergeant Klostergaard, cancel the meal!

140
00:09:39,240 --> 00:09:41,740
我们骑车回军营
We ride to the barracks.

141
00:09:41,900 --> 00:09:45,860
听到命令了吧 起立 取自行车
You heard the lieutenant!Stand up! Go to the bikes!

142
00:10:03,690 --> 00:10:05,650
立正
Stand at attention!

143
00:10:05,820 --> 00:10:10,610
之后 你们会得到四十发子弹和急救包
After this you will all receive 40 rounds and a first aid kit.

144
00:10:10,780 --> 00:10:14,280
下一步你们将回自己的房间 准备上床睡觉
Next you will go to your rooms and go to bed in preparedness.

145
00:10:14,440 --> 00:10:17,110
你们必须穿着制服和靴子
You need to keep on the uniforms and boots.

146
00:10:17,110 --> 00:10:19,400
装备必须准备就绪
The equipment has to be ready.

147
00:10:19,570 --> 00:10:23,730
从现在开始 你们必须时刻戴着你们的狗牌（士兵身份牌）
And from now on you have to wear your dog tag at all times.

148
00:10:25,070 --> 00:10:27,150
向右转
Turn right!

149
00:10:28,150 --> 00:10:30,230
开始
Initiate!

150
00:10:40,320 --> 00:10:42,900
每个人四十发子弹？
40 rounds each?

151
00:11:01,690 --> 00:11:04,980
你还认为这只是一次训练吗？ 格拉姆
Do you still think it's just a drill, Gram?

152
00:11:06,190 --> 00:11:08,780
他们应该知道是怎么回事
They deserve to know what's going on.

153
00:11:08,940 --> 00:11:13,070
是的 但这不是我们的决定 少尉
Yes. But it's not our decision to make,second lieutenant.

154
00:13:01,320 --> 00:13:03,900
我是三号边检站 现在有大部队
Border station 3 here. Now there is massive

155
00:13:03,900 --> 00:13:05,900
在对面集结
activity on the other side.

156
00:13:05,910 --> 00:13:08,070
德国军队 你能听到我说话吗？
German side. Can you hear me?

157
00:13:08,080 --> 00:13:11,000
我重复 大部队在集结
I repeat. Massive activity on the

158
00:13:11,230 --> 00:13:14,480
收到 有德军越过边境吗？
Received.Have the Germans crossed the border?

159
00:13:14,650 --> 00:13:16,370
没有 还没越过
No, it hasn't been crossed,

160
00:13:16,370 --> 00:13:18,810
但我们能听到大部队集结
but we can hear massive activity.

161
00:13:18,980 --> 00:13:22,270
他们有多少人？ 我们是说有多少人？
How many are they? How many are we speaking of?

162
00:13:22,440 --> 00:13:27,190
很难说清楚 我们看不到他们 我们只能听到他们的声音
It's hard to say. We can't see them,we can only hear them.

163
00:13:27,360 --> 00:13:30,400
中校希望我们做什么？
What does the lieutenant colonel want us to do?

164
00:13:30,570 --> 00:13:33,060
他们必须留在原地 直到他们得到新的命令
They must stay put,till they get new orders.

165
00:13:33,230 --> 00:13:34,780
三号边境站 留在原地
Border station 3, stay put.

166
00:13:34,790 --> 00:13:37,270
保持冷静 等待新的命令
Stay calm and wait for new orders.

167
00:13:37,440 --> 00:13:42,730
- 是 长官 明白  - 帕兹堡 库拉萨 现在是伦斯
- Yes sir. Roger that.  - Padborg, Krusa and now Rens.

168
00:13:42,900 --> 00:13:47,020
毫无疑问 发生了什么事
There are any longer no doubt about what's happening.

169
00:13:47,190 --> 00:13:50,900
再给我联系日德兰半岛的首席长官
Give me the chief for the Jutland division again.

170
00:13:55,150 --> 00:13:58,560
哈泽斯莱乌和桑德堡均处于戒备状态
Haderslev and Sonderborg are also in a state of alert.

171
00:13:58,730 --> 00:14:00,230
他们正在等待离开军营
They are awaiting clearance to leave the barracks.

172
00:14:00,400 --> 00:14:03,650
他们有五十公里远 第一时间取决于我们自己
They are 50 kilometers away.The first hour depends on us.

173
00:14:03,820 --> 00:14:06,730
中校 日德兰半岛首席长官在了
Lieutenant colonel? The chief for the Jutland Division.

174
00:14:06,900 --> 00:14:09,060
切入通话
Cut the speaker.

175
00:14:11,650 --> 00:14:14,930
少将 我们明确地了解到
Major general? We have clear indication

176
00:14:14,930 --> 00:14:17,360
军队增加活动的迹象
about increasing troop activity.

177
00:14:17,520 --> 00:14:21,150
请求派遣我们的部队向边境推进
Requesting to send my troops towards the border.

178
00:14:21,310 --> 00:14:25,060
让他们进入防御阵地
And let them go in defensive positions.

179
00:14:25,230 --> 00:14:27,680
我知道 少将
I'm aware of that major general,

180
00:14:27,680 --> 00:14:29,770
但我们离边境有十公里
but we are 10 kilometers from the border.

181
00:14:29,940 --> 00:14:32,920
如果我们等到他们越过边境
If we wait till the border is crossed,

182
00:14:32,920 --> 00:14:35,520
我们将没有时间进入阵地
we won't have time to go into position.

183
00:14:37,980 --> 00:14:40,500
必须和总参谋部试着沟通
Have the General Staff tried to talk

184
00:14:40,500 --> 00:14:42,270
对一些有判断力的大臣
some sense to the minister?

185
00:14:42,440 --> 00:14:46,650
审议关于最新升级的…
Regarding the latest escalation in consideration...

186
00:14:50,150 --> 00:14:52,900
是 长官 少将
Yes sir, major general.

187
00:14:54,560 --> 00:14:57,150
我们会尽力的
We will do our best.

188
00:15:02,270 --> 00:15:06,270
到目前为止 还没有消息 目前我们要保持高度戒备
So far, no news. We stay on high alert at the moment.

189
00:15:06,440 --> 00:15:08,320
这是首相的评估
It's the prime minister evaluation,

190
00:15:08,330 --> 00:15:10,060
动员丹麦人…
that any Danish mobilization...

191
00:15:10,230 --> 00:15:13,310
…可以被看作是一种对抗 使局势恶化
...can be seen as a confrontation and worsen the situation.

192
00:15:13,480 --> 00:15:16,430
防御演习是一种挑衅吗？
Defensive maneuvers are a provocation?

193
00:15:16,430 --> 00:15:18,110
那么德国人调动军队算不算？
And the German mobilization is not?

194
00:15:18,270 --> 00:15:21,880
中尉 如果你有问题的话
Lieutenant, if you have a problem with the order,

195
00:15:21,880 --> 00:15:23,150
请你保留
keep it to yourself.

196
00:15:24,860 --> 00:15:28,230
各位 确保你们的部队准备就绪
Men. Make sure your troops are ready to go.

197
00:15:28,400 --> 00:15:31,480
是 中校
Yes sir, lieutenant colonel.

198
00:15:40,310 --> 00:15:42,770
- 卡拉斯特格斯中士  - 到 长官
- Sergent Klostergaard.  - Yes sir.

199
00:15:42,940 --> 00:15:45,810
- 宿舍检查睡觉  - 是 长官
- Inspection of the sleeping hall.  - Yes sir.

200
00:15:53,230 --> 00:15:56,020
难道我们不应该在防御阵地吗？
Shouldn't we already be in defensive positions?

201
00:15:56,190 --> 00:16:01,650
是的 我们不去那里 你得感谢首相
Yes. For that you can thank the prime minister that we are not.

202
00:16:18,860 --> 00:16:21,400
我可以看下这张照片吗？
Can I see the picture?

203
00:16:31,940 --> 00:16:35,020
- 我可以要回吗？ - 可以 别紧张
- Can I have it back?  - Yes yes. Take it easy

204
00:16:37,770 --> 00:16:40,890
我们可以做的不多
There are not much we can do.

205
00:16:42,520 --> 00:16:46,480
并不是所有人都能开好枪 来吧
It's not everyone who shoot that well.Come.

206
00:16:53,350 --> 00:16:56,480
嘿 拉森 要睡觉吗？
Hey Lassen. Getting any sleep?

207
00:16:57,150 --> 00:17:00,100
不想睡
Not so much.

208
00:17:00,270 --> 00:17:03,310
- 你紧张了？ 拉森  - 是的
- Are you nervous, Lassen?  - Yes.

209
00:17:03,480 --> 00:17:07,230
像这样的弹药 你不是每天都能得到的
It's not everyday you get ammunition like this.

210
00:17:07,400 --> 00:17:11,480
- 四十发子弹并不多  - 不多 这不多
- 40 rounds each isn't much.  - No it's not.

211
00:17:15,230 --> 00:17:18,480
你能分点给我们吗？
Can we have some of yours?

212
00:17:18,650 --> 00:17:23,390
不是我要 我有机枪 这是给隆格伦的
It's not for me. I have the machine gun.It's for Lundgren.

213
00:17:23,560 --> 00:17:26,850
我不想 不允许我们这样做 安徒生
I don't think,we are allowed to do that, Andersen.

214
00:17:27,020 --> 00:17:30,770
拉森 你的射击在这里不是最好的 对吧？
Lassen, you aren't exactly the best shot here, right?

215
00:17:30,940 --> 00:17:34,390
但隆格伦…我们知道他用步枪能做什么
But Lundgren... We know what he can do with a riffle.

216
00:17:34,560 --> 00:17:37,390
- 只要一半  - 完全正确 二十发
- Just half.  - Exactly. 20 rounds.

217
00:17:37,560 --> 00:17:41,060
这对我们大家都好
It's for all our sakes.

218
00:17:41,890 --> 00:17:43,980
- 好  - 很好
- Ok.  - Good.

219
00:17:50,440 --> 00:17:53,690
拉森 别给 不要这样做
Lassen, don't.Don't do it.

220
00:17:53,850 --> 00:17:55,400
我们允许领取四十发
We have received 40 rounds each.

221
00:17:55,410 --> 00:17:57,600
没有人应该得到更多或更少
No one should get more or less.

222
00:17:57,770 --> 00:18:01,890
- 还有你俩应该躺在床上  - 是 室长先生
- And you two should be in bed.  - Yes sir, room chairman.

223
00:18:03,560 --> 00:18:06,020
- 拉森 我说真的  - 格拉姆 没事了
- Lassen, I mean it.  - Gram, it's okay.

224
00:18:06,190 --> 00:18:09,390
- 我很好  - 是啊 有什么问题吗？
- It's fine by me.  - Yeah, what's the problem?

225
00:18:09,560 --> 00:18:13,350
这不是你该做的决定 你知道的
It's not your decision to make,and you know it.

226
00:18:19,310 --> 00:18:23,190
- 格拉姆 你不想打胜仗吗？ - 我当然想打胜仗了
- Gram, don't you want to win?  - Of course I want to win.

227
00:18:23,350 --> 00:18:25,460
你是德国人 对吗？
You are German, right?

228
00:18:25,460 --> 00:18:27,640
也许你对这场胜利不感兴趣？
Maybe you are not interested in a victory?

229
00:18:27,810 --> 00:18:30,560
我可以自豪地称自己是丹麦人
I'm proud to be able to call myself Danish.

230
00:18:30,730 --> 00:18:34,310
- 但你不是  - 一点儿都没错
- But you are not.  - That's exactly what I am.

231
00:18:34,480 --> 00:18:36,680
- 你爸爸是德国人 对吗？ - 是啊
- Your dad is German, correct?  - Yeah.

232
00:18:36,850 --> 00:18:40,890
- 那么你就是德国人  - 你比我想像的更蠢
- Then you're German.  - You are more stupid than I thought.

233
00:18:41,060 --> 00:18:43,600
这不是一场游戏
It's not a game.

234
00:18:43,770 --> 00:18:47,430
我们不应该保存一些实力在那里吗？
Shouldn't we save some strength over there?

235
00:18:47,600 --> 00:18:48,620
回去睡觉
Go back to sleep.

236
00:18:48,620 --> 00:18:51,430
当你唧唧歪歪的时候 真的很难睡着
It's pretty hard when you're jabbering.

237
00:18:51,600 --> 00:18:54,480
没有人跟你说话 贾斯特逊
Nobody spoke to you, Justesen.

238
00:18:54,640 --> 00:18:58,850
我是说 安徒生 现在去躺着
I mean it, Andersen.Lay down, right now.

239
00:18:59,020 --> 00:19:02,520
- 或者怎样？ - 就躺在你床上
- Or what?  - Just go lay down in your bed.

240
00:19:02,690 --> 00:19:05,640
- 这里怎么了？ - 立正
- What's going on here?  - Attention!

241
00:19:07,940 --> 00:19:10,430
你们应该上床睡觉了
You should have gone to bed prepared!

242
00:19:10,600 --> 00:19:11,070
另外看你们这副德性
Then you look like this!

243
00:19:11,070 --> 00:19:14,850
我必须用其他方式处理四个混蛋 比起我盯着你们要好
I have other shit 4 to do,than keeping my eyes on you!

244
00:19:15,020 --> 00:19:18,640
上衣的纽扣 扣起来有这么难吗？
How hard is it to button a jacket?

245
00:19:23,730 --> 00:19:26,020
你扣错了
You have buttoned it wrong!

246
00:19:30,690 --> 00:19:32,920
二二五你是室长 你负有责任
225 you are room chairman. It's your responsibility.

247
00:19:32,930 --> 00:19:34,640
不要使大家精神涣散
Keep it together!

248
00:19:34,810 --> 00:19:37,270
是 中士
Sergent, yes sir!

249
00:19:39,890 --> 00:19:42,560
把上衣扣好
Get those jackets buttoned.

250
00:19:47,060 --> 00:19:50,640
二二三 写完你的信 休息一下
223, finish your letter and get some rest.

251
00:19:53,230 --> 00:19:56,680
两分钟后 这个宿舍要完全安静
Two minutes, then this hallis totally quiet!

252
00:20:01,270 --> 00:20:03,140
开始
Proceed!

253
00:20:31,930 --> 00:20:35,770
- 你需要点烟吗？ 少尉  - 看我好像需要
- You need a light Second lieutenant?- Looks like I do.

254
00:20:46,230 --> 00:20:49,770
- 你的人都在睡觉吗？ - 他们正在努力
- Are your men sleeping?  - They are trying.

255
00:20:49,930 --> 00:20:51,930
穿着宽松的制服很难入睡
It's hard in full uniform.

256
00:20:52,100 --> 00:20:55,520
我认为这个命令对每个人都有重要意义
I thought that order were meant for everyone.

257
00:20:55,680 --> 00:20:58,720
除了军官
Except officers.

258
00:21:01,060 --> 00:21:04,270
- 你是班德格阿得？ - 是的
- You are Bundgaard?  - Yes.

259
00:21:04,430 --> 00:21:08,140
据我了解 我们支援你的排
It's my understanding that we are supporting your platoon.

260
00:21:08,310 --> 00:21:12,180
- 如果越过边界  - 当他们越过时会受到惩罚
- If the border is crossed.- When it gets crossed.

261
00:21:13,680 --> 00:21:16,640
我们最有可能首先与他们遭遇
We are most likely the first to meet them.

262
00:21:16,810 --> 00:21:19,640
这样做 有人会死去
Somebody is going to do it.

263
00:21:20,850 --> 00:21:24,970
- 我可以吗？ - 当然可以
- Can I?  - Of course.

264
00:21:37,980 --> 00:21:41,970
那么 呃…骑自行车快速到达那里
Then, eh... Pedal extra fast down there.

265
00:21:42,140 --> 00:21:45,470
- 我们需要你们  - 我们会在那里的
- We're going to need you.  - We'll be there.

266
00:21:45,640 --> 00:21:48,390
我们比你想像的快
We are faster than you think.

267
00:21:48,560 --> 00:21:52,180
- 火柴留着  - 谢谢
- Keep the matches.  - Thanks.

268
00:21:56,600 --> 00:22:00,140
- 士官班德格阿得  - 少尉
- Sergent Bundgaard.  - Second lieutenant.

269
00:22:25,390 --> 00:22:29,100
如果德国人想攻击 他们已经这么做了
If the Germans wanted to attack,they'd had already done so.

270
00:22:29,270 --> 00:22:32,390
有人正在谈判 正如我们所说的
There are somebody who are negotiating as we speak.

271
00:22:32,560 --> 00:22:36,970
任何一方都不希望发生冲突
Neither party wants a conflict.

272
00:22:46,970 --> 00:22:49,890
无线电室发生了一些状况
Something is happening in the radio room.

273
00:22:53,890 --> 00:22:56,930
三号边检站 再说一遍 重复
Border station 3, come again. Repeat.

274
00:22:57,100 --> 00:23:00,260
我重复一遍 德国军队正在移动
I repeat.The German troops are moving.

275
00:23:00,430 --> 00:23:03,350
你们看到了什么？
What can You see?

276
00:23:04,680 --> 00:23:07,680
我们看到了步兵和装甲车
We can see infantry and armored vehicles.

277
00:23:07,850 --> 00:23:10,610
他们正朝我们开进
They are coming straight towards us.

278
00:23:10,610 --> 00:23:12,720
德国人越过边境了吗？
Have the Germans crossed the border?

279
00:23:14,720 --> 00:23:17,470
三号边检站
Border station 3.

280
00:23:19,060 --> 00:23:22,970
他们越过了 我们正在被侵略 做什么…？
They crossed it. We are being overrun.What do...?

281
00:23:24,510 --> 00:23:29,760
三号边检站 重复报告 三号边检站 快点
Border station 3, repeat message.Border station 3, come in.

282
00:23:31,640 --> 00:23:36,140
你们听到了 敌人已越过边境
You heard it yourselves.The enemy has crossed the border.

283
00:23:36,310 --> 00:23:38,760
丹麦正处于战争状态
Denmark is at war.

284
00:23:38,930 --> 00:23:43,220
先生们 现在我们表现的时刻到了
Gentlemen. Now is the time to show what we are made of.

285
00:23:44,680 --> 00:23:47,970
警报 拉响警报 快点
Alarm! Raise the alarm. Come on!

286
00:24:27,640 --> 00:24:30,140
取自行车 快点
To the bikes! Hurry up!

287
00:24:35,720 --> 00:24:38,140
在这里 科尔丁
Here you go, Kolding.

288
00:24:43,970 --> 00:24:48,220
- 准备好出发  - 是 中士
- Prepare to take off!  - Sergent, yes sir!

289
00:24:51,970 --> 00:24:53,100
下一个
Next.

290
00:24:53,260 --> 00:24:57,260
少尉 二一九 四连二排 机枪
Second lieutenant. 219, 4th company,2nd platoon. Machine gun.

291
00:24:58,300 --> 00:25:00,010
下一个
Next.

292
00:25:00,180 --> 00:25:03,850
少尉 二二三 四连二排 辅助人员
Second lieutenant. 223, 4th company,2nd platoon, helper.

293
00:25:05,930 --> 00:25:08,850
- 下一个  - 二一七 四连二排
- Next man.  - 217, 4th company, 2nd platoon.

294
00:25:09,010 --> 00:25:11,550
- 辅助人员  - 下一个
- Helper.  - Next.

295
00:25:15,180 --> 00:25:18,720
- 二三三 协助安装三脚架  - 是 长官
- 233 help with the tripod.  - Yes sir.

296
00:25:25,010 --> 00:25:27,100
- 准备好了？ - 是 长官
- Ready?  - Yes sir!

297
00:25:27,260 --> 00:25:30,680
- 二一七 你准备好了？ 你准备好了？ 二一二  - 是 中士
- 217, are you ready? Are you ready, 212?  - Sergent, yes sir!

298
00:25:30,850 --> 00:25:33,600
把枪抬高 二一九 你准备好了？
Get that weapon higher up.219, are you ready?

299
00:25:33,760 --> 00:25:35,720
是 中士
Sergent, yes sir!

300
00:25:40,470 --> 00:25:44,260
德国人已经突破了三个地方 其中一个是库拉萨
The Germans have broken through 3 places.One of them is Krusa

301
00:25:44,430 --> 00:25:47,180
他们正在十号公路上向我们推进
They are heading straight towards us on highway 10.

302
00:25:47,350 --> 00:25:50,300
如果我们拖住他们 就很难北上
If we hold it, it'll be hard for the them to go north.

303
00:25:50,470 --> 00:25:52,510
有报告吗
Any reports?

304
00:25:52,680 --> 00:25:55,600
哈泽斯莱乌和桑德堡的援兵应该在路上了
Haderslev and Sonderborg should be on their way.

305
00:25:55,760 --> 00:25:58,850
我们必须停止前进 直到增援部队抵达
We need to stop the advancement till reinforcements arrive.

306
00:25:59,010 --> 00:26:01,430
当增援部队抵达时 我们把他们打回去了
When that happens we push them back.

307
00:26:01,600 --> 00:26:04,590
桑德·霍斯楚普 新的命令和报告都是在这里形成的
Sonder Hostrup. New orders and reports comes form here.

308
00:26:04,760 --> 00:26:08,050
我们在隆托夫特比尔会合 同时你必须抵抗
We meet up at Lundtoftebjerg.You have to make stand meanwhile.

309
00:26:08,220 --> 00:26:12,720
我们会尽力而为的 中尉
We will do our best lieutenant.Lieutenant.

310
00:26:14,470 --> 00:26:16,390
立正
Attention!

311
00:26:18,850 --> 00:26:23,140
- 车队准备出发  - 好 中士
- Platoon ready for take off.  - Roger, sergeant.

312
00:26:29,350 --> 00:26:31,970
一支德国装甲师已经越过边境
A German armor division have crossed the border!

313
00:26:32,140 --> 00:26:36,220
这不是演习 丹麦正处于战争状态
This is not a drill! Denmark is at war!

314
00:26:36,390 --> 00:26:38,300
战斗
Fight well!

315
00:26:38,470 --> 00:26:41,340
排 跟着我
Platoon, follow me!

316
00:27:07,840 --> 00:27:10,720
排 准备上车
Platoon! Get ready to mount up!

317
00:27:12,260 --> 00:27:14,260
上车
Mount up!

318
00:28:48,840 --> 00:28:50,970
快
Faster!

319
00:29:01,840 --> 00:29:04,510
停…下车
Stop!Stop! Dismount!

320
00:29:06,090 --> 00:29:08,380
准备好了
Be ready!

321
00:29:23,510 --> 00:29:26,050
这是摩托车队
It's the motorcycle platoon.

322
00:29:31,550 --> 00:29:35,380
- 也许是结束了？ - 我不这么认为
- Maybe it's over with?  - I don't think so.

323
00:29:37,380 --> 00:29:39,340
停
Stop!

324
00:29:40,880 --> 00:29:44,010
中尉 我们刚进入阵地
Lieutenant, we only just made it into positions.

325
00:29:44,180 --> 00:29:47,630
我们就截住了几辆装甲车 我们也杀死了一些步兵
We stopped a couple of armors.We also got some infantry.

326
00:29:47,800 --> 00:29:49,840
- 但这太多了  - 他们有多少人？
- But it was too much.- How many are they?

327
00:29:50,010 --> 00:29:54,380
一支或两支摩托车队协助装甲车队
One or two motorized companies with assisting armor.

328
00:29:54,550 --> 00:29:57,470
我们正在北面建立合适的防御阵地
We are going north to setup proper defense.

329
00:29:57,630 --> 00:29:59,470
我们必须在隆托夫特比尔坚守
We got to hold Lundtoftebjerg.

330
00:29:59,470 --> 00:30:01,760
隆托夫特比尔已经陷落
Lundtoftebjerg has fallen.

331
00:30:01,930 --> 00:30:03,990
下一步我们就要在这里建立阵地
Then we got to set up here.

332
00:30:03,990 --> 00:30:06,420
地势太开阔 跟我们一起
The terrain is too open, come with us.

333
00:30:06,590 --> 00:30:08,880
我们必须坚守隆托夫特比尔 直到
We need to hold Lundtoftebjerg till

334
00:30:08,880 --> 00:30:10,420
哈泽斯莱乌和桑德堡的援兵到达这里
Haderslev and Sonderborg gets here.

335
00:30:10,590 --> 00:30:12,950
你还没看到前方是什么样的
You haven't seen what's up ahead.

336
00:30:12,950 --> 00:30:14,220
你可以做你想做的
You can do what you want.

337
00:30:14,380 --> 00:30:18,340
我要服从命令 没有时间了
I will follow my orders.There is no time for this.

338
00:30:18,510 --> 00:30:23,130
桑德 你必须和他谈谈
Sand.You have to talk to him.

339
00:30:26,050 --> 00:30:29,840
- 我和他一起  - 小心 少尉
- I'm with him.  - Take care second lieutenant.

340
00:30:30,010 --> 00:30:32,260
摩托车排 我们会继续
Motorcycle platoon, we will continue.

341
00:30:43,340 --> 00:30:45,720
发生了什么事？
What's happening?

342
00:31:00,510 --> 00:31:03,260
- 卡拉斯特格斯中士  - 到 长官
- Sergent Klostergaard!  - Yes sir!

343
00:31:12,380 --> 00:31:15,800
我们最好的机枪 找时机打击他们的装甲车
The machine guns are our best chance against their armor.

344
00:31:15,970 --> 00:31:18,920
我们可以分成三组 并且在交火中俘获他们
We can split them in three and catch them in crossfire.

345
00:31:19,090 --> 00:31:22,550
增援部队多久到达？
How long till the reinforcements arrives?

346
00:31:22,720 --> 00:31:24,760
- 至少二十分钟  - 很好
- At least 20 minutes.  - Good.

347
00:31:24,920 --> 00:31:27,450
桑德 把一班部署在森林线上
Sand, get first squad in the tree line.

348
00:31:27,450 --> 00:31:29,550
我带二班部署在水沟里
I'll take second squad down the gutter.

349
00:31:29,720 --> 00:31:31,610
三班 在山上
Third squad, on the hill.

350
00:31:31,610 --> 00:31:33,460
机枪手 等我的信号
Machine gunners,wait for my signal.

351
00:31:33,630 --> 00:31:38,170
当他们看到步兵接近的时候 用唯一的卡宾枪射击
The carbines only shoot when they see infantry getting close.

352
00:31:38,340 --> 00:31:40,880
- 是 长官  - 行动
- Yes sir!  - Proceed!

353
00:31:42,170 --> 00:31:46,010
一班跟我上 二班等待中尉命令
First squad on me! Second squad wait for the lieutenants orders!

354
00:31:46,170 --> 00:31:48,710
三班跟我上
Third squad, on me!

355
00:31:50,920 --> 00:31:53,130
二班
Second squad!

356
00:31:59,260 --> 00:32:04,590
二一九 以树作掩体 二一二 辅助机枪
219, make emplacement by the tree!212 support the machine gun!

357
00:32:04,760 --> 00:32:07,920
去那边五十米处
Go 50 meters that way!

358
00:32:08,090 --> 00:32:11,050
- 我们的位置在这里 二二五  - 明白
- We take position here, 225!  - Roger!

359
00:32:35,840 --> 00:32:37,630
在这里
Here.

360
00:33:26,210 --> 00:33:30,000
地方不错 二一九 我们等待中尉的命令
Nice place, 219.We wait for the lieutenants orders.

361
00:33:30,170 --> 00:33:33,340
要点 遏制住他们冲过来的装甲车
Short, controlled bursts against their armor.

362
00:33:33,500 --> 00:33:36,000
明白 少尉
Roger, second lieutenant.

363
00:33:36,170 --> 00:33:39,250
摩托车排在哪里？
Where did the motorcycle platoon go?

364
00:33:39,420 --> 00:33:42,880
我需要你全部的注意力放在这条路上
I need your full attention on that road there.

365
00:33:43,050 --> 00:33:45,250
是 长官
Yes sir!

366
00:34:01,800 --> 00:34:05,800
我很饿 我今天连咖啡都没喝
I am so hungry. I haven't even gotten my coffee today

367
00:34:05,960 --> 00:34:09,500
- 你想的就是这个？ - 我是认真的 格拉姆
- Is that all you think about?  - I mean it, Gram.

368
00:34:09,670 --> 00:34:12,250
我不能没有我的第一杯咖啡
I don't function without my first cup of coffee.

369
00:34:12,420 --> 00:34:15,000
你和你的咖啡
You and your coffee.

370
00:34:21,210 --> 00:34:22,700
二三三 就位 只有机枪
233, take position. Only the machine guns

371
00:34:22,700 --> 00:34:25,130
给出信号才射击
that shoots at the given signal.

372
00:34:25,300 --> 00:34:29,000
你们其余的人等到步兵出现
The rest of you wait till the infantry shows.

373
00:34:48,090 --> 00:34:50,710
有逆风
There is headwind.

374
00:34:52,800 --> 00:34:55,460
日出
It's sunrise.

375
00:35:01,340 --> 00:35:05,340
- 狩猎的好条件  - 嘘 科尔丁
- Great conditions for hunting.Shh, Kolding.

376
00:35:44,040 --> 00:35:46,040
等等
Wait.

377
00:35:54,250 --> 00:35:57,340
- 下来 二二五  - 收到
- Get down more, 225.  - Roger.

378
00:36:07,710 --> 00:36:09,460
收到
Ready.

379
00:36:22,460 --> 00:36:24,130
收到
Ready

380
00:36:34,790 --> 00:36:36,500
开火 开火
Open fire! Open fire!

381
00:36:46,130 --> 00:36:48,960
- 安徒生 它们反弹了  - 我知道
- Andersen, they are ricocheting!  - I know!

382
00:37:02,000 --> 00:37:04,250
我需要一个新的弹匣
I need a new mag!

383
00:37:07,790 --> 00:37:10,630
二三三 等到步兵出现
233, wait till the infantry shows.

384
00:37:19,590 --> 00:37:21,460
开火
Open fire!

385
00:37:32,590 --> 00:37:34,500
我装弹
I'm reloading!

386
00:37:45,670 --> 00:37:49,500
他们准备用机枪射击 二二五 掩护右侧
They are going for the machine gun!225, cover right flank!

387
00:37:49,670 --> 00:37:52,040
你也是 二一二
You too, 212!

388
00:37:55,540 --> 00:37:58,370
在路的右边两辆装甲车
Two armored vehicles to the right of the road!

389
00:37:58,540 --> 00:38:00,370
收到
Roger that!

390
00:38:03,960 --> 00:38:06,040
需要一个新的弹匣
Need a new mag!

391
00:38:15,250 --> 00:38:19,040
- 快点 二三三  - 在上子弹 等会儿 少尉
- Come on, 233!  - On it, sec. lieutenant!

392
00:38:35,380 --> 00:38:37,290
二一二 你在哪里？
212, where are you?

393
00:38:37,460 --> 00:38:40,960
- 我装弹  - 二三三 快点 封住道路
- I'm reloading!  - 233, come on. Cover the road!

394
00:38:41,130 --> 00:38:43,330
是 长官
Yes sir!

395
00:38:49,210 --> 00:38:51,960
少尉 帮帮我们
Second lieutenant, help us!

396
00:38:52,120 --> 00:38:54,960
我撤退
I'm pulling back!

397
00:38:56,670 --> 00:38:59,170
我们撤退
We are pulling back!

398
00:38:59,330 --> 00:39:02,370
快点 回去 二一二 在他们后面
Come on! Get back! 212, after them!

399
00:39:06,170 --> 00:39:08,710
二一九 我们撤退
219, we are pulling back!

400
00:39:20,000 --> 00:39:22,710
你打它 该死 我拿下了
You hit it!Hell, I got it!

401
00:39:24,120 --> 00:39:27,580
射杀他们 射杀他们…科尔丁
Shoot them! Shoot them! Shoot them, Kolding!

402
00:39:31,830 --> 00:39:32,870
科尔丁 趴下
Kolding, get down!

403
00:39:37,420 --> 00:39:39,620
纳斯科威 帮他
Norreskov, help him!

404
00:39:42,920 --> 00:39:45,420
- 严重吗？ - 是啊 严重
- Is it bad?  - Yeah, it's bad!

405
00:39:45,580 --> 00:39:47,830
我们需要帮助
We need help!

406
00:39:50,580 --> 00:39:52,250
纳斯科威
Norreskov!

407
00:39:56,500 --> 00:39:58,870
我们撤退
We are pulling back!

408
00:40:17,750 --> 00:40:23,330
我们要带他离开这里 科尔丁
We got to get him away from here.Kolding.

409
00:40:23,500 --> 00:40:27,580
- 少尉 我们得走了  - 科尔丁 看着我
- Second lieutenant, we got to go!  - Kolding, look at me.

410
00:40:31,670 --> 00:40:35,790
二三三 拿弹药袋 现在就做 拿这些袋子
233, take the munitions bag!Do it now, take those bags!

411
00:40:35,960 --> 00:40:38,050
这里没有更多的事要做了
There is nothing more to do here!

412
00:40:38,060 --> 00:40:40,120
我们什么都做不了 快点
We can't do anything else! Come on!

413
00:40:41,580 --> 00:40:45,210
二一九 拿机枪 留下三脚架
219, take the machine gun! Leave the tripod!

414
00:40:47,250 --> 00:40:49,120
快点
Come on!

415
00:41:05,120 --> 00:41:08,580
安徒生 科尔丁在哪里？
Andersen, where is Kolding?

416
00:41:10,660 --> 00:41:13,330
- 科尔丁在哪里？ - 快点 跟着我
- Where is Kolding?  - Come on, follow me!

417
00:41:13,500 --> 00:41:16,330
- 科尔丁在哪里？ - 控制一下自己
- Where is Kolding?  - Control yourself!

418
00:41:16,500 --> 00:41:17,930
告诉我 他在哪里？
Tell me, where is he?

419
00:41:17,940 --> 00:41:21,040
科尔丁死了 跟着我 撤离
Kolding is dead! Follow me! Get moving!

420
00:41:21,210 --> 00:41:22,540
快点
Come on!

421
00:41:22,710 --> 00:41:26,290
撤离 纳斯科威
Get moving.Norreskov!

422
00:41:26,460 --> 00:41:28,210
这条路
This way!

423
00:41:37,710 --> 00:41:39,660
到农场的房子里
Down to the farm house there.

424
00:41:41,160 --> 00:41:44,460
- 二一二 把所有的自行车都放在小屋里  - 是 长官
- 212, get all the bikes in the shed.  - Yes sir.

425
00:41:46,910 --> 00:41:49,330
快点 走吧
Come on. Move it.

426
00:42:02,410 --> 00:42:04,620
快点 二一二
Come on, 212.

427
00:42:05,960 --> 00:42:08,200
进去
Get in.

428
00:42:15,790 --> 00:42:18,080
二一九 守住这里的窗户
219, take the window here.

429
00:42:19,870 --> 00:42:22,660
二二三 守住那边的窗户
223, take that window over there.

430
00:42:22,830 --> 00:42:25,410
- 二二五 守住那个窗户  - 好
- 225, take that window there.  - Roger.

431
00:42:25,580 --> 00:42:28,500
把枪给我
Give me that weapon.

432
00:42:28,660 --> 00:42:31,830
振作起来 那么我们可以活着出去
Get your shit together,so we can get out alive.

433
00:42:32,000 --> 00:42:34,790
这里 如果你看到了什么…你在干什么？
Here! If you sees anything...What are you doing?

434
00:42:34,960 --> 00:42:37,290
- 不  - 放松…
- No!  - Relax! Relax!

435
00:42:37,460 --> 00:42:41,040
- 趴在地上 夫人 立刻 趴下  - 哦…嘿 不
- Get down on the floor ma'am, now! Down!  - O...h no.

436
00:42:41,790 --> 00:42:45,700
夫人 保持冷静
Ma'am, stay calm.

437
00:42:45,870 --> 00:42:48,750
- 我们在这里不会呆很久  - 好吧
- We are not here very long.  - Okay.

438
00:43:16,910 --> 00:43:19,200
二一九 那里有人吗？
219, anyone there?

439
00:43:23,580 --> 00:43:26,240
我没看到任何人
I can't see anyone.

440
00:43:37,620 --> 00:43:41,370
- 还有什么？ - 没有
- Still nothing?  - No.

441
00:43:50,290 --> 00:43:53,450
我不认为会有人来
I don't think anyone will come.

442
00:44:04,120 --> 00:44:06,310
抱歉 夫人 你有没有地方
Sorry ma'am, do you have a place where the

443
00:44:06,310 --> 00:44:08,490
得到一些水 让那士兵擦把脸？
soldier can get some water in his face?

444
00:44:08,660 --> 00:44:10,790
- 有 这边  - 二二三
- Yes. This way.  - 223.

445
00:44:10,950 --> 00:44:12,990
- 就这？ - 是的
- This one?  - Yes.

446
00:44:20,120 --> 00:44:22,120
跟我来
Follow me.

447
00:44:24,040 --> 00:44:25,950
二二五
225.

448
00:44:32,700 --> 00:44:37,370
我们将往北走 一直到桑德·霍斯楚普
We will go north.Up to Sonder Hostrup.

449
00:44:37,540 --> 00:44:41,120
找到中校 那里是指挥中心
Get hold of the lieutenant colonel.There is the command center.

450
00:44:41,290 --> 00:44:45,490
- 在那里我们可以得到新的命令  - 所以我们继续走吗？
- There we can get new orders.  - So we continue?

451
00:44:45,660 --> 00:44:49,450
你认为呢？ 二三三
What else do you think, 233?

452
00:44:49,620 --> 00:44:53,200
没什么 少尉 我准备好了
Nothing second lieutenant.I'm ready.

453
00:44:55,040 --> 00:44:57,410
二二五
225.

454
00:44:59,120 --> 00:45:02,160
我需要一位副手
I need a second in command.

455
00:45:02,330 --> 00:45:04,370
那就是你
That is you.

456
00:45:05,700 --> 00:45:09,200
二一九 归还二三三的枪
219, return 233's weapon.

457
00:46:04,620 --> 00:46:06,870
过来
Come here.

458
00:46:13,410 --> 00:46:17,580
那里 现在你洗好了 可爱的男孩
There. Now you good to go.Sweet boy.

459
00:46:23,200 --> 00:46:25,240
那里
There.

460
00:46:29,030 --> 00:46:31,490
我们要行动了
We are moving out.

461
00:46:44,870 --> 00:46:47,950
- 我们将继续走  - 是 长官 先生们
- We'll countinue.  - Yes sir. Gentlemen.

462
00:46:59,990 --> 00:47:02,370
- 夫人  - 你们可以躲在这里
- Ma'am.  - You can hide here.

463
00:47:02,530 --> 00:47:06,200
你们可以在干草棚里 没有人会找到你们
You can have the hayloft.Nobody will find you there.

464
00:47:06,370 --> 00:47:08,680
还要如何帮助？
And how would that help?

465
00:47:08,680 --> 00:47:10,740
这能挽救年轻孩子们的生命
It would save the young boys life.

466
00:47:13,080 --> 00:47:15,700
我会尽全力保护所有的人
I'll protect the men with everything I got.

467
00:47:15,870 --> 00:47:20,160
随着战争的持续 我不想把他们藏起来
I don't want to hide them,as the war continues.

468
00:47:20,330 --> 00:47:24,780
二十年前 这里是德国的 现在是丹麦的
20 years ago this was Germany,and now it's Denmark.

469
00:47:24,950 --> 00:47:26,710
也许我应该感到惭愧
Maybe I should be ashamed,

470
00:47:26,710 --> 00:47:28,820
但对我来说 这不意味着什么 真的
but it never meant anything for me, really.

471
00:47:28,990 --> 00:47:31,990
这对我来说意味着很多
It means a lot for me.

472
00:47:32,870 --> 00:47:35,620
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your help.

473
00:47:47,780 --> 00:47:50,120
立正
Attention!

474
00:47:53,700 --> 00:47:56,410
我不知道中尉发生了什么…
I don't know what happened to the lieutenant...

475
00:47:56,580 --> 00:47:59,780
…卡拉斯特格斯中士或许在排里其他人之中
...sergeant Klostergaard or the rest of the platoon.

476
00:47:59,950 --> 00:48:04,530
我们就是剩下的 现在我们知道了 我们面对的是什么人
We are, what's left. Now we know what we're up against.

477
00:48:06,780 --> 00:48:09,570
我们今天已经失去了一位好战友
We have lost a good soldier today.

478
00:48:09,740 --> 00:48:11,280
二一七
217.

479
00:48:13,490 --> 00:48:17,660
他战斗了 但死于上帝的旨意
He fought, but succumbed to gods will.

480
00:48:18,740 --> 00:48:23,450
他的死给了我们所有人一个教训 我们要提高警惕
Let his death be a lesson to us all.We all have to be alert.

481
00:48:26,820 --> 00:48:28,740
在我后面
After me.

482
00:49:29,240 --> 00:49:31,410
二排 四连的
2nd squad, 4th company.

483
00:49:39,570 --> 00:49:41,610
停
Stop!

484
00:49:43,990 --> 00:49:48,490
二一九 看看你是否可以得到一些弹药 其余人 在此待命
219, see if you can get some ammunition.The rest, wait here.

485
00:49:50,110 --> 00:49:52,490
仍然联系不上
There is still no contact.

486
00:49:52,660 --> 00:49:56,320
- 中校  - 少尉
- Lieutenant colonel.  - Second lieutenant.

487
00:49:56,490 --> 00:50:01,160
桑德·霍斯楚普 呼叫 请接收…你能听到我吗？
Sonder Hostrup calling. Come in.Come in. Can you hear me?

488
00:50:01,320 --> 00:50:04,990
我重复 这里是桑德·霍斯楚普 请接收
I repeat.Sonder Hostrup here. Come in.

489
00:50:07,950 --> 00:50:10,210
你是在隆托夫特比尔？
You were at Lundtoftebjerg?

490
00:50:10,210 --> 00:50:13,860
是的 我们在阵地上并没坚持多久
Yes. We didn't hold the position so long.

491
00:50:14,030 --> 00:50:18,200
他们人太多了 我们受到了装甲车和步兵的攻击
They were too many. We were attacked by both armor and infantry.

492
00:50:18,360 --> 00:50:20,780
- 你的中尉在哪里？ - 我不知道
- Where is your lieutenant?  - I'm not sure.

493
00:50:20,950 --> 00:50:24,160
我想 中尉被俘虏了吧
I think,the lieutenant was captured

494
00:50:24,320 --> 00:50:27,780
或许其余的排投降了
Or surrendered with the rest of the platoon.

495
00:50:27,950 --> 00:50:30,110
摩托车排怎么样？
What about the motorcycle platoon?

496
00:50:30,280 --> 00:50:36,110
士官班德格阿得向北转移 设置了新的阵地
Sergent Bundgaard moved north to new a new position.

497
00:50:36,280 --> 00:50:41,070
但我们并没有被击败 我们准备好接受下一个命令
But we are not defeated.We are ready for the next order.

498
00:50:41,240 --> 00:50:44,570
把电台搬上卡车 转移
Get the radio up in the truck.Move it!

499
00:50:46,530 --> 00:50:48,860
你要离开吗？
Are you leaving?

500
00:50:49,030 --> 00:50:50,990
跟我一起走
Walk with me.

501
00:50:56,530 --> 00:50:57,740
谢谢你
Thank you.

502
00:51:04,570 --> 00:51:06,990
- 抽支烟吗？ - 好 请
- Cigarette?  - Yes, please.

503
00:51:12,110 --> 00:51:15,860
我们从哈泽斯莱乌和桑德堡得到消息
We have information from Haderslev and Sonderborg.

504
00:51:17,240 --> 00:51:20,190
他们不来了 少尉
They are not coming, Second lieutenant.

505
00:51:20,190 --> 00:51:22,240
不会有任何增援？
There will be no reinforcements?

506
00:51:25,820 --> 00:51:27,820
可是为什么？
But why?

507
00:51:27,990 --> 00:51:32,700
他们说 他们在那里可以做更多的事
They said that they could do more where they were.

508
00:51:32,860 --> 00:51:35,000
这是我们听到的最后情况
It was the last thing we heard before

509
00:51:35,000 --> 00:51:37,150
在所有通讯停止之前
all communications stopped.

510
00:51:37,320 --> 00:51:39,130
最有可能的是电话线
The telephone lines have most likely

511
00:51:39,130 --> 00:51:41,240
已被敌人破坏了
been sabotaged by the enemy.

512
00:51:41,400 --> 00:51:44,710
联合防线怎么样？
What about the joint defensive line?

513
00:51:44,710 --> 00:51:46,400
这是不可能发生的
It's not going to happen down here.

514
00:51:46,990 --> 00:51:51,280
边境地区都丢失了 所有部队都撤回了…
The border areas are lost.All units have pulled back...

515
00:51:51,450 --> 00:51:57,570
…或投降 所以战役会转移到更远的北方
...or surrendered, so the battle will be moved further north.

516
00:52:03,320 --> 00:52:07,990
- 有来自哥本哈根的消息吗？ - 没有 我们和他们失去了联系
- Any news from Copenhagen?  - No. We have no contact with them.

517
00:52:11,700 --> 00:52:14,990
那么你的命令是什么？ 中校
So what are your orders then,lieutenant colonel?

518
00:52:15,150 --> 00:52:19,860
我们撤回到哈泽斯莱乌 并且加入驻军
We pull back to Haderslev,and join the garrison.

519
00:52:21,030 --> 00:52:24,950
然后将在那里建立一条新的防线
Then there will be created a new defensive line there.

520
00:52:27,200 --> 00:52:30,450
这将是一个难熬的一天 桑德
It's going to be a long day, Sand.

521
00:52:32,030 --> 00:52:35,690
- 中校  - 少尉
- Lieutenant colonel.  - Second lieutenant.

522
00:52:54,780 --> 00:52:57,320
立正
Attention!

523
00:52:58,740 --> 00:53:01,860
有一些新情况
There are some news.

524
00:53:02,030 --> 00:53:05,570
哈泽斯莱乌的增援部队不来了
The reinforcements from Haderslev aren't coming.

525
00:53:05,740 --> 00:53:08,360
而且桑德堡的也不来了
And not from Sonderborg either.

526
00:53:08,530 --> 00:53:11,030
我们要去哈泽斯莱乌
We need to get to Haderslev.

527
00:53:11,200 --> 00:53:15,150
并协助驻军保卫城市
And assist the garrison in protection of the town.

528
00:53:15,320 --> 00:53:17,530
我可以问个问题吗？
May I ask a question?

529
00:53:17,700 --> 00:53:22,240
不 二三三 你不可以 我们抄近路穿过森林
No, 233, you may not. We take a shortcut through the forest.

530
00:53:22,400 --> 00:53:25,860
我们必须在德国人之前 达到的哈泽斯莱乌 明白吗？
We should reach Haderslev before the Germans. Understood?

531
00:53:26,030 --> 00:53:29,360
- 明白 少尉  - 跟着我
- Roger, second lieutenant.  - Follow me.

532
00:54:00,780 --> 00:54:03,070
少尉
Second lieutenant?

533
00:54:03,820 --> 00:54:07,030
- 嗯 二一二  - 我的后轮胎爆了
- Yes, 212.  - I have a flat back tire.

534
00:54:07,190 --> 00:54:10,860
我们在这里短暂停留 二一九 你帮一下
We do a short stop here. 219, you help.

535
00:54:16,110 --> 00:54:20,360
二三三 站在那里警戒 二二三 那边
233, stand guard over there. 223, over there.

536
00:54:23,940 --> 00:54:27,690
- 二二五 你来自于那地区 对吗？ - 是的 少尉
- 225, you are from the area, right?  - Yes, second lieutenant.

537
00:54:27,860 --> 00:54:31,650
去哈泽斯莱乌最快的是哪条路？ 我想远离主要道路
The fastest way to Haderslev? I want to stay off the main road.

538
00:54:31,820 --> 00:54:36,070
我不想暴露行踪 你有什么想法？
And I don't want to be in the open.What are you thinking?

539
00:54:36,240 --> 00:54:40,070
如果我们继续这样走 我们要走这条路…
If we continue the way we are going to hit this road...

540
00:54:40,230 --> 00:54:42,730
…然后我们通过奥本罗
...and then we go through Aabenraa.

541
00:54:42,900 --> 00:54:46,360
从那里 我们可以直接去哈泽斯莱乌
And from there, we can go straight to Haderslev.

542
00:54:46,530 --> 00:54:50,360
- 这应该是可行的  - 很好 我们就这么做
- It should be doable.  - Good, that's what we'll do.

543
00:54:52,070 --> 00:54:54,400
- 少尉  - 嗯
- Second lieutenant?  - Yes.

544
00:54:54,570 --> 00:55:00,860
二二三 纳斯科威 科尔丁 二一七 他们…他是个很好的朋友
223. Norreskov. Kolding, 217.They... he was a dear friend.

545
00:55:06,480 --> 00:55:09,940
- 让他们快点  - 是 少尉
Make sure they hurry up.  - Yes, second lieutenant.

546
00:55:10,110 --> 00:55:13,730
二一二 二一九 你们得快点了
212, 219. You have to hurry up with that.

547
00:55:18,610 --> 00:55:20,860
继续
Proceed.

548
00:55:30,730 --> 00:55:33,320
你有一位重要的人离开了？
Did You have a great leave?

549
00:55:35,320 --> 00:55:38,980
- 是的 少尉  - 你有家人吗？
- Yes, second lieutenant.  - Do You have family?

550
00:55:40,230 --> 00:55:43,190
我订婚了
I'm engaged.

551
00:55:44,360 --> 00:55:48,110
- 那封信是给她的吗？ - 是的
- Was that letter to her?  - Yes.

552
00:55:53,110 --> 00:55:56,230
日期定了吗？
Is the date set?

553
00:55:56,400 --> 00:56:00,440
还没 但希望是这个夏天
Not yet,but hopefully this summer.

554
00:56:05,030 --> 00:56:08,190
那么我们必须让你回家
Then we must get You home again.

555
00:56:14,530 --> 00:56:18,820
纳斯科威 你是四连自行车二排的一员
Norreskov, You are a part of 4th company, 2nd bicycle platoon.

556
00:56:20,480 --> 00:56:22,860
你并不孤单
You are not alone.

557
00:56:24,360 --> 00:56:26,610
收到
Received.

558
00:56:35,860 --> 00:56:38,570
最后一点 快
And the last bit. Come on.

559
00:56:50,360 --> 00:56:54,400
我们快到了 加把劲
We're almost there. Do it faster.

560
00:56:55,860 --> 00:56:57,980
拜托 给我们更多的时间
Come on. Give us a some more time.

561
00:56:58,150 --> 00:57:01,480
我没有更多的时间给你
I have no more time to give You.

562
00:57:03,730 --> 00:57:07,150
- 战争不会等你  - 我做不了这么快
- The war is not waiting for You.  - I can't do it any faster.

563
00:57:07,320 --> 00:57:10,440
- 你必须快  - 你算老几？
- You have to.  - Who the hell do you think you are?

564
00:57:10,610 --> 00:57:13,820
- 继续  - 什么？
- Get going.  - What?

565
00:57:13,980 --> 00:57:16,320
- 有什么问题吗？ - 我正在努力…
- What's the problem?  - I'm trying...

566
00:57:16,480 --> 00:57:18,520
- 你有什么疑问？ - 没有
- Are you in any doubt?  - No.

567
00:57:18,690 --> 00:57:22,070
- 你忘了你的任务吗？ - 没有
- Have you forgotten your job?  - No.

568
00:57:22,230 --> 00:57:25,860
- 没有 少尉  - 那么把那辆自行车修好
- No, second lieutenant.  - Then finish up that bike.

569
00:57:26,020 --> 00:57:28,480
是 长官
Yes sir.

570
00:57:31,270 --> 00:57:35,440
- 命令是不容讨论的  - 是 少尉
- Never discuss an order.  - Yes, second lieutenant.

571
00:57:56,730 --> 00:58:02,440
- 准备好了 少尉  - 我们将继续前进 二三三 二二三
- Ready, second lieutenant.  - We'll continue. 233, 223.

572
00:58:35,860 --> 00:58:38,360
四连二排
2nd squad, 4th company.

573
00:58:40,190 --> 00:58:44,230
你们能帮忙吗？ 二二三 二三三 帮助他们
Can you lend a hand? 223, 233, help them!

574
00:58:52,400 --> 00:58:54,600
跟着我
Follow me.

575
00:59:09,860 --> 00:59:13,230
二二五 你和我一起走
225, You go with me.

576
00:59:13,400 --> 00:59:15,850
- 你们留在这里  - 是 长官
- You stay here.  - Yes sir.

577
00:59:33,480 --> 00:59:37,480
您好 你们想买一些便宜的牛奶吗？ 只要两克朗（货币名称）
Hello. Do you want to buy some cheap milk?Only two kroner.

578
00:59:40,230 --> 00:59:42,600
嘿 你在这儿干什么？
Hey, what are you doing here?

579
00:59:42,770 --> 00:59:46,310
你们买一些便宜的牛奶吗？ 只要两克朗
What to buy some cheap milk? Only two kroner.

580
00:59:46,480 --> 00:59:48,560
- 士官班德格阿得  - 到
- Sergent Bundgaard.  - Yes.

581
00:59:48,730 --> 00:59:51,230
- 怎么回事？ - 少尉
- What's going on?  - Second lieutenant.

582
00:59:51,400 --> 00:59:53,670
计划在这里设立阵地
The plan was to set up positions here,

583
00:59:53,670 --> 00:59:56,190
但当地人都聚集到这片区域了
but the locals are flocking the area.

584
00:59:56,350 --> 01:00:01,350
他们拒绝离开 隆托夫特比尔怎么样？
They refuse to leave. How did Lundtoftebjerg go?

585
01:00:01,520 --> 01:00:03,850
- 我们并没有坚持很久  - 有什么损失吗？
- We didn't hold it very long.  - Any losses?

586
01:00:04,020 --> 01:00:07,480
一人 科尔丁
One man. Kolding.

587
01:00:07,650 --> 01:00:09,350
增援部队没来
No reinforcements are coming.

588
01:00:09,520 --> 01:00:12,730
- 哈泽斯莱乌或桑德堡都没来？ - 没来
- Neither Haderslev or Sonderborg?  - No.

589
01:00:12,900 --> 01:00:15,850
- 命令是什么？ - 我们在哈泽斯莱乌建立防线
- What's the orders?  - We set up defense in Haderslev.

590
01:00:16,020 --> 01:00:19,270
内陆防线到目前为止没有任何效果
A defensive line so far inland has no effect.

591
01:00:19,440 --> 01:00:20,940
这是命令
That's the order.

592
01:00:21,100 --> 01:00:23,850
我不想在一场毫无意义的战斗中牺牲我的人
I'm not sacrificing my men in a pointless battle.

593
01:00:24,020 --> 01:00:27,980
带你的人转移到哈泽斯莱乌 明白吗？
Gather your men and move to Haderslev.Understood?

594
01:00:28,150 --> 01:00:30,560
- 都明白了吗？ - 是
- Are we clear?  - Yes.

595
01:00:30,730 --> 01:00:33,850
- 我可以看看你的东西吗？ - 可以
- Can I see what You have there?  - Yes.

596
01:00:36,520 --> 01:00:41,560
- 你是怎么弄到的？ - 德国飞机都把它们扔了一上午
- How did You get this?  - German planes dropped them all morning.

597
01:00:41,730 --> 01:00:42,730
少尉
Second lieutenant.

598
01:00:42,730 --> 01:00:47,100
德国飞机已经把这些东西都扔到了这里
German planes have dropped this all over this place.

599
01:00:47,900 --> 01:00:52,100
“通告丹麦士兵和丹麦公民”
"Oprop! To Danish soldiers and the Danish people."

600
01:00:53,850 --> 01:00:57,940
要求我们 不要抵抗 是挪威语
Requesting us, not to resist.In Norwegian.

601
01:00:59,400 --> 01:01:02,190
德国人来了
The Germans are coming!

602
01:01:07,810 --> 01:01:10,100
德国人来了
The Germans are coming!

603
01:01:11,270 --> 01:01:15,350
进入阵地 控制公路
Get into positions! Get of the road!

604
01:01:18,480 --> 01:01:20,690
让这些孩子离开这里
Get these children away from here!

605
01:01:20,700 --> 01:01:22,390
少尉 命令是什么？
Second lieutenant, what's the orders?

606
01:01:22,560 --> 01:01:26,440
二一九 架起机枪 二一二 快让平民离开公路
219, Set up the machine gun! 212, Start getting people off the road!

607
01:01:27,900 --> 01:01:30,600
快 离开
Faster! Leave!

608
01:01:32,270 --> 01:01:35,310
引导平民赶快离开
Lead people away now!

609
01:01:36,190 --> 01:01:37,770
离开
Go away!

610
01:01:41,940 --> 01:01:44,600
快点 该死的 弗雷德里克
Come on, god damn it! Frederik!

611
01:01:46,270 --> 01:01:50,310
快点 弗雷德里克
Come on! Frederik!

612
01:01:50,480 --> 01:01:52,810
弗雷德里克 跑
Frederik! Run!

613
01:01:54,150 --> 01:01:56,020
离开 弗雷德里克
Let go! Frederik!

614
01:02:02,150 --> 01:02:04,730
跑
Run!

615
01:02:06,980 --> 01:02:08,480
装甲车
Armor!

616
01:02:20,060 --> 01:02:21,850
找掩体
Take cover!

617
01:02:22,640 --> 01:02:25,230
拉森 带她离开
Lassen, get her away!

618
01:02:29,890 --> 01:02:33,480
少尉 命令是什么？
Second lieutenant, what's the orders?

619
01:02:39,020 --> 01:02:41,830
自行车排 我们撤退
Bicycle platoon, we are pulling back!

620
01:02:41,830 --> 01:02:43,480
快 我们撤退
Come on! We are pulling back!

621
01:02:50,640 --> 01:02:52,980
快点 快…
Come on, come on, come on!

622
01:03:01,810 --> 01:03:05,060
- 谁会驾驶卡车？ - 我会
- Who can ride a truck?  - I can.

623
01:03:05,230 --> 01:03:08,060
- 二一九 帮忙把自行车拿上来  - 是 长官
- 219, help getting the bikes up.  - Yes sir.

624
01:03:08,230 --> 01:03:10,730
快 大家上车
Come on! Get up, all of you!

625
01:03:10,890 --> 01:03:13,350
快 大家上车
Come on! Get it up!

626
01:03:51,100 --> 01:03:54,060
- 让我们去公路  - 是
- Get us of the main road.  - Yes.

627
01:04:54,850 --> 01:04:57,560
- 飞机…  - 靠边
- Planes, planes! Pull in to the side.

628
01:05:50,930 --> 01:05:53,720
我们继续向哈泽斯莱乌行进
We continue towards Haderslev.

629
01:06:16,930 --> 01:06:23,020
如果我们继续往朗姆克劳斯特韦屈走 我们应该能够避开德国人
If we go on Logumklostervej,we should be able to avoid the Germans.

630
01:06:23,180 --> 01:06:25,310
就这样
Do it.

631
01:06:27,140 --> 01:06:31,180
- 你知道这地方？ - 在哈泽斯莱乌出生和长大
- Do you know the area?  - Born and raised in Haderslev.

632
01:06:31,350 --> 01:06:34,850
- 那么你现在要回家了？ - 看来好像是
- So you are going home now?  - Looks like it.

633
01:06:43,810 --> 01:06:46,470
你今天表现不错
You did well today.

634
01:06:49,100 --> 01:06:50,630
恕我直言
With all due respect.

635
01:06:50,640 --> 01:06:55,060
军队溃败的实在太快了
The military is just something to finish quickly.

636
01:06:55,220 --> 01:06:57,470
你想做些什么吗？
What do you want to do?

637
01:06:59,060 --> 01:07:02,930
我想成为一名商人 少尉
I want to be a merchant,second lieutenant.

638
01:07:03,100 --> 01:07:06,470
- 商人？ - 商人
- Merchant?  - Merchant.

639
01:07:06,640 --> 01:07:10,220
找个可爱的姑娘 生养一大堆孩子
Find a cute girl,get loads of children.

640
01:07:12,220 --> 01:07:15,220
我喜欢简单
I like it simple.

641
01:07:15,970 --> 01:07:20,640
如果你喜欢简单 军队一定非常适合你
If you like it simple, the military must be something for you then.

642
01:07:55,310 --> 01:07:59,060
我已经骑着车在周围转了十次 还是站在这里
I could have turned those bikes around ten times while standing here.

643
01:07:59,220 --> 01:08:01,640
是啊 德国人接近了 他们来了
Yeah, towards the Germans. They are coming.

644
01:08:01,810 --> 01:08:05,680
那你最好快点 这边是封闭的
Then you better hurry.The sideways are closed.

645
01:08:09,310 --> 01:08:13,390
- 班德格阿得 上尉  - 上尉不让我们进去
Bundgaard. Captain. The captain won't let us in.

646
01:08:13,560 --> 01:08:16,560
你们在我们的行进路线上 你们可以绕着城市走
You are in our line of fire. You can go around the city.

647
01:08:16,720 --> 01:08:21,720
- 他们可以随时来这里  - 没有人会从南方来
- They can be here any time.  - No one gets in from the south.

648
01:08:21,890 --> 01:08:25,470
- 我必须跟上校谈谈  - 你可以在广场上找到他
- I have to speak to the colonel.  - You can find him at the square.

649
01:08:25,640 --> 01:08:28,680
你可以跟他说 你已经拆掉了车子
You can speak to him,when You have removed the vehicles.

650
01:08:28,850 --> 01:08:31,640
我有了关于德国人推进的情报
I have information regarding the German advance.

651
01:08:31,810 --> 01:08:35,550
我有我的命令 少尉
And I have my orders, second lieutenant.

652
01:08:41,100 --> 01:08:43,930
- 你还没有参加战斗吧？ - 还没有 没有
- You haven't been in combat yet?  - Not yet, no.

653
01:08:44,100 --> 01:08:45,800
我想也是
I thought so.

654
01:08:45,970 --> 01:08:50,890
在等待你的时候 我们已经失去了在边境上的士兵们
We have lost men by the border while waiting for you.

655
01:08:51,060 --> 01:08:54,550
放我们一马
Cut us some slack.

656
01:08:58,310 --> 01:09:02,010
打开 以便卡车可以通过
Open up so the truck can fit through.

657
01:09:02,180 --> 01:09:04,050
谢谢 继续走
Thanks. Go on.

658
01:09:07,470 --> 01:09:09,720
我们将帮助巩固兵营
We will help fortify the barracks.

659
01:09:09,890 --> 01:09:12,720
我们将向上校报告 我们的到来
We will announce our arrival to the colonel.

660
01:09:12,890 --> 01:09:14,660
一个很好的人给了我这些
A person was nice giving these to me.

661
01:09:14,660 --> 01:09:17,100
你们都应该抽烟休息一下
You all deserve a smoking break.

662
01:09:17,260 --> 01:09:20,180
- 谢谢  - 少尉
- Thanks.  - Second lieutenant.

663
01:09:21,720 --> 01:09:23,800
走了
Get going!

664
01:09:43,350 --> 01:09:46,140
…在沃延斯 谁收听过电台 上校
...in Vojens, who heard it over the radio, colonel.

665
01:09:46,300 --> 01:09:49,010
- 下车  - 保密
- Get off.  - Keep it to Yourself.

666
01:09:49,180 --> 01:09:52,840
- 努力去查实  - 所有的电话线都断了
- Try get it verified.  - All telephone lines are dead.

667
01:09:53,010 --> 01:09:55,840
找另一台电话或电台
Find another telephone or a radio then.

668
01:09:56,010 --> 01:09:58,390
哈兹上校？ 桑德少尉
Colonel Hartz? Second lieutenant Sand,

669
01:09:58,390 --> 01:10:01,090
四连自行车二排
4th company, 2nd bicycle platoon.

670
01:10:01,260 --> 01:10:04,220
海因茨中校要求我 向您报到
Lieutenant colonel Hintz asked me,to report to you.

671
01:10:04,390 --> 01:10:08,430
你忙了一早上 我们没能提供帮助 我表示歉意
You've had a busy morning. My apologies, that we couldn't help.

672
01:10:08,600 --> 01:10:11,430
不过我们被命令留下来保卫城市
But we got ordered to stay and protect the city.

673
01:10:11,600 --> 01:10:14,720
整个上午飞机已经把它们扔到了丹麦的城镇
Planes have dropped them over Danish towns all morning.

674
01:10:14,890 --> 01:10:16,570
我已经看过了
I've seen it before,

675
01:10:16,580 --> 01:10:18,890
但它只是一张纸 没有更多的意义
but it's just a piece of paper, and nothing more.

676
01:10:19,050 --> 01:10:22,640
德国人配备了摩托化步兵和装甲车
The Germans will come with motorized infantry and armored vehicles.

677
01:10:22,800 --> 01:10:26,010
- 这不是一场势均力敌的较量  -  你知道了 又如何
- It's not a fair fight.  - You know, how it is.

678
01:10:26,180 --> 01:10:31,010
- 命令就是命令 尼尔森？ - 上校
- Orders are orders. Nielsen?  - Colonel.

679
01:10:31,180 --> 01:10:35,220
带桑德和他的人去靠近道路的阵地
Lead Sand and his men to the positions at the approaching road.

680
01:10:35,390 --> 01:10:37,680
他们需要一些帮助
They need some assistance.

681
01:10:37,840 --> 01:10:41,050
收到 上校 我有个人丢了他的枪
Roger, colonel. One of my men have lost his weapon.

682
01:10:41,220 --> 01:10:44,220
并且我们需要弹药 有点糟糕
And we need ammunition. Tend to that too.

683
01:10:44,390 --> 01:10:46,800
上帝保佑国王和祖国
God, king and fatherland.

684
01:10:50,050 --> 01:10:53,680
上校给了我们一个新的阵地 把包放下
The colonel have given us a new position to hold. Drop your bags.

685
01:10:53,840 --> 01:10:57,930
安徒生 你会得到一把新枪 其余人获得新的弹药
Andersen, you'll get a new weapon.The rest gets new ammunition.

686
01:10:59,680 --> 01:11:02,390
- 枪？ - 这是我的
- Weapon?  - That's me.

687
01:11:02,550 --> 01:11:04,720
- 谢谢  - 弹药？
- Thanks.  - Ammunition?

688
01:11:09,260 --> 01:11:12,220
你们之间分享
Share it between you.

689
01:11:22,680 --> 01:11:24,840
快 赶紧
Come on. Hurry up!

690
01:11:28,050 --> 01:11:30,090
跟着我
Follow me!

691
01:11:41,220 --> 01:11:45,260
我们在这里有人 我们还有人在这里
We have men in position here.And we have men in position here.

692
01:11:45,430 --> 01:11:49,470
是否有新的命令我们需要马上知道 跟我来
Are there new orders we need to know straight away.Follow me.

693
01:11:52,720 --> 01:11:55,630
请离开道路
Please get off the road.

694
01:11:55,800 --> 01:11:57,840
快离开这里
Get away from here!

695
01:12:00,550 --> 01:12:04,130
上校要求我们协助你们 你们有什么武器？
The colonel asked us to assist you.What weapon do You have?

696
01:12:04,300 --> 01:12:07,260
机枪在这里 但仅有的枪手在广场那边
Machine gun here,But only riffles on the other.

697
01:12:07,430 --> 01:12:12,220
我们需要两名枪手在那边 安徒生 纳斯科威
We need two rifflemen over there.Andersen, Norreskov.

698
01:12:13,140 --> 01:12:14,930
抢占阵地
Take position there.

699
01:12:15,090 --> 01:12:18,930
安徒生 你负责 小心
Andersen, you're in charge.Take care.

700
01:12:19,090 --> 01:12:22,380
收到 少尉 进入阵地
Roger, second lieutenant.Go into position.

701
01:12:34,010 --> 01:12:36,470
跟着我
Follow me!

702
01:12:38,340 --> 01:12:40,840
- 发生了什么事  - 德国人来了
- What's happening?  - The Germans are coming!

703
01:12:41,010 --> 01:12:42,800
远离窗户
Get away from the window!

704
01:12:44,590 --> 01:12:46,340
跟上
Come with!

705
01:12:50,760 --> 01:12:54,340
- 你们认为有这个时间吗？ - 归还杯子
- Do you think there's time for this?  - Return the cups.

706
01:12:54,510 --> 01:12:58,260
- 仅仅是一杯咖啡  - 你快点喝完 贾斯特森
- Just one cup of coffee.  - You have to do it fast then, Justesen.

707
01:12:58,430 --> 01:13:01,630
我接管指挥 格拉姆 拉森在这里
I'll take over the command.Gram, Lassen, there.

708
01:13:01,800 --> 01:13:05,590
格拉姆站着 拉森趴着 贾斯特森 靠门的位置
Gram up, Lassen down.Justesen, take position by the door.

709
01:13:05,760 --> 01:13:10,050
你的位置在那里 你的位置在拐角处
You take position there.You take position at the corner there.

710
01:13:10,220 --> 01:13:13,800
- 拉森 你应该进一步  - 在这里我能看到他们
- Lassen, you have to move further in.  - I can see them here.

711
01:13:13,970 --> 01:13:18,090
- 我在这里视线清晰  - 叫你怎么做就怎么做 士兵
- I have a clear sight from here.- Do as you are told, soldier.

712
01:14:17,430 --> 01:14:19,380
装甲车
Armor!

713
01:14:25,090 --> 01:14:28,550
他们太近了 我们撤退
They are too close!We are pulling back!

714
01:14:31,300 --> 01:14:33,340
抢占那个阵地
Take position there!

715
01:14:35,220 --> 01:14:38,340
- 我撤退 掩护我  - 我在掩护
- I'm pulling back! Cover me!  - I'm covering!

716
01:14:44,010 --> 01:14:46,670
纳斯科威 过来
Norreskov, come!

717
01:14:52,010 --> 01:14:54,210
我们必须走了 快
We have to go, now!

718
01:14:59,800 --> 01:15:04,210
安徒生 我掩护你 安徒生 跑…
Andersen, I'm covering you! Andersen! Run! Run!

719
01:15:04,380 --> 01:15:07,210
- 跑  - 确保你掩护他
- Run!  - Make sure you're covering him!

720
01:15:08,300 --> 01:15:10,050
进去
Get in!

721
01:15:17,010 --> 01:15:18,460
杀了他
Shoot him!

722
01:15:18,630 --> 01:15:22,800
- 少尉  - 安徒生 纳斯科威 撤退
- Second lieutenant!  - Andersen, Norreskov, pull back!

723
01:15:22,970 --> 01:15:27,760
撤退 回到新的阵地 快 掩护他们
Pull back! Back to a new position here!Come on, cover them!

724
01:15:31,550 --> 01:15:34,960
现在 掩护射击 到这里来
Now! Covering fire!Get in here!

725
01:15:36,970 --> 01:15:40,760
- 只有你能拖住他们  - 是 长官
- Hold them as long as You can!  - Yes sir!

726
01:15:40,920 --> 01:15:43,840
我没子弹了
I'm out of ammunition!

727
01:15:46,340 --> 01:15:49,670
- 打机关枪  - 最后三发
- Hit that machine gun!  - Last three!

728
01:15:49,840 --> 01:15:53,510
我们需要弹药 少尉
We need ammunition,second lieutenant!

729
01:15:55,510 --> 01:15:57,170
在这里
Here.

730
01:16:03,380 --> 01:16:06,340
我们撤退 拉森
We are pulling back! Lassen!

731
01:16:06,510 --> 01:16:09,590
- 来了  - 跑 拉森
- Coming!  - Run, Lassen!

732
01:16:14,340 --> 01:16:17,630
贾斯特森 轮到你了 回来
Justesen, It's your turn. Get back!

733
01:16:17,800 --> 01:16:21,590
格拉姆 掩护道路右侧的贾斯特森
Gram, cover Justesen to the right side of the road.

734
01:16:26,090 --> 01:16:29,260
贾斯特森…
Justesen! Justesen!

735
01:16:29,420 --> 01:16:33,090
拉森 你跑出去拉贾斯特森
Lassen, You'll run out and get Justesen!

736
01:16:33,260 --> 01:16:35,420
格拉姆 你要掩护我们
Gram, You have to cover us!

737
01:16:35,590 --> 01:16:37,590
- 格拉姆 掩护我们  - 把他弄出来
- Cover us, Gram!  - Get him out!

738
01:16:37,760 --> 01:16:41,550
士兵 掩护我们 拉森 我们得走了 快
Soldiers, cover us!Lassen, we have to go! Now!

739
01:16:43,130 --> 01:16:46,380
拉森 把他带到这里
Lassen, take him here!

740
01:16:46,550 --> 01:16:49,590
拉森 快点 我们要把他拉回来
Lassen! Come on!We'll pull him back.

741
01:16:52,340 --> 01:16:56,260
把他放在这里…止血
Put him here! Put him here!Stop the bleeding!

742
01:16:56,420 --> 01:16:59,300
你听到了吗？ 止血
Are you listening? Stop the bleeding!

743
01:17:04,630 --> 01:17:07,960
向后退 我后面
Pull back! Behind me!

744
01:17:08,130 --> 01:17:09,840
快
Come on!

745
01:17:11,260 --> 01:17:15,920
少尉 纳斯科威 我们现在该怎么办？
Second lieutenant! Norreskov! What should we do now?

746
01:17:16,090 --> 01:17:19,840
格拉姆 撤退 快 快…
Gram, pull back!Now! Now! Now!

747
01:17:22,130 --> 01:17:25,250
看着我 呼吸…
Look at me. Breathe! Breathe!

748
01:17:26,630 --> 01:17:28,670
少尉
Second lieutenant!

749
01:17:32,130 --> 01:17:35,590
少尉 我们正在失去他
Second lieutenant, we are losing him!

750
01:17:35,760 --> 01:17:39,460
我们几乎没有子弹了
We literally have no ammunition left!

751
01:17:40,710 --> 01:17:45,590
- 贾斯特森 看着我  - 少尉 我们要怎么做？
- Justesen, look at me.Sec.  - lieutenant, what are we going to do?

752
01:17:45,760 --> 01:17:49,050
少尉 命令是什么？
Second lieutenant, what's the orders?

753
01:17:53,800 --> 01:17:58,300
少尉 我们需要更好的照顾他
Second lieutenant, we need better care for him here.

754
01:17:58,460 --> 01:18:02,170
- 看着我 贾斯特森  - 少尉
- Look at me, Justesen.  - Second lieutenant!

755
01:18:02,340 --> 01:18:06,750
- 我不想死  - 命令是什么 少尉
- I don't want to die!  - What are the orders, second lieutenant?

756
01:18:08,500 --> 01:18:10,670
结束了
It's over.

757
01:18:10,840 --> 01:18:13,550
结束了
It's over!

758
01:18:32,300 --> 01:18:36,420
放下你的枪…
Drop your weapons.Drop your weapons!

759
01:18:39,210 --> 01:18:41,380
放下你的枪 举起手
Drop those weapons!Hands up!

760
01:18:41,550 --> 01:18:43,960
你怎么说“别开枪 我们投降”的？
How do you say "don't shoot, we surrender"?

761
01:18:44,130 --> 01:18:47,500
别开枪 我们投降（德语）
Nicht schiessen.Wir kapitulieren.

762
01:18:47,670 --> 01:18:51,420
别开枪 我们投降
Nicht schiessen. Wir kapitulieren.

763
01:18:53,420 --> 01:18:57,210
别开枪 别开枪
Nicht schiessen!Nicht schiessen!

764
01:18:57,380 --> 01:19:01,090
别开枪 我们投降
Nicht schiessen! Wir kapitulieren!

765
01:19:01,250 --> 01:19:05,040
- 别开枪  - 举起你的手
- Nicht schiessen!  - Hold up your hands.

766
01:19:05,210 --> 01:19:09,380
别开枪 我们投降 别开枪
Nicht schiessen! Wir kapitulieren!Nicht schiessen!

767
01:19:09,550 --> 01:19:14,290
- 举起手来…  - 只是把手举高
- Hande hoch! Hande hoch!  - Just keep those hands high up.

768
01:19:14,460 --> 01:19:18,210
- 去我身后 士兵们  - 举起手来
- Get behind me, soldiers.  - Hande hoch!

769
01:19:18,380 --> 01:19:22,210
别开枪 快去我身后 去我身后
Nicht schiessen! Get behind me now. Get behind me.

770
01:19:22,380 --> 01:19:26,960
别开枪 没有武器 我们投降
Nicht schiessen.Keine Waffen! Wir kapitulieren!

771
01:21:22,880 --> 01:21:26,040
站起来…
Aufstehen! Aufstehen!

772
01:21:26,210 --> 01:21:30,580
- 现在 把战俘带走  - 大家都站起来
- Die Gefangenen wegfuhren.  - Jetzt!Stand up, everybody.

773
01:21:31,830 --> 01:21:35,830
- 两个两个 跟着我  - 走吧 向前
- Two and two, after me.  - Los! Vorwarts.

774
01:21:39,750 --> 01:21:42,460
齐步走
March!

775
01:21:59,040 --> 01:22:02,080
少尉 你会说英语吗？
Leutnant, spricht jemand bei Ihnen Deutsch?

776
01:22:02,250 --> 01:22:05,580
- 格拉姆  - 我会说德语
- Gram.  - Ich spreche Deutsch.

777
01:22:07,790 --> 01:22:11,540
- 这就没有必要了  - 这就没有必要了
- Das ist nicht notwendig.  - It isn't necessary.

778
01:22:11,710 --> 01:22:15,130
我是中尉贝克尔 来自一七〇步兵师
Ich bin Oberleutnant Becker von der 170. Infanteriedivision.

779
01:22:15,290 --> 01:22:19,290
我是中尉贝克尔 来自一七〇步兵师
I am Oberleutnant Becker from the 170th infantry division.

780
01:22:19,460 --> 01:22:22,960
- 少尉桑德  - 这是少尉桑德
- Second lieutenant Sand.  - Das ist Leutnant Sand.

781
01:22:24,580 --> 01:22:28,370
你由我负责监管 你将被带回军营
Sie unterstehen meiner Obhut und werden in die Kaserne gebracht.

782
01:22:28,540 --> 01:22:34,620
你由我负责监管 你将被带回军营
You are in my custody, and will be sent back to your barracks.

783
01:22:34,790 --> 01:22:36,870
我有一个问题
Ich hatte eine Frage.

784
01:22:37,040 --> 01:22:40,580
你为什么要这样抵抗这么长时间？
Warum um alles haben Sie so lange gekampft?

785
01:22:40,750 --> 01:22:45,460
他想知道我们为什么要抵抗这么长时间
He want to know why we kept fighting for so long.

786
01:22:45,630 --> 01:22:48,790
我不明白 你什么意思？
I don't understand. What do you mean?

787
01:22:48,960 --> 01:22:52,420
这是没有必要的 我们不得不付出如此多的的生命
Es war nicht notwendig, dass so viele das Leben lassen mussten.

788
01:22:52,580 --> 01:22:56,080
你们的政府已经投降了
Ihre Regierung hat bereits kapituliert.

789
01:22:59,420 --> 01:23:02,420
这是一种不必要的 无谓的牺牲
It have been an unnecessary waste of life.

790
01:23:02,580 --> 01:23:06,420
因为我们的政府已经在很久以前投降了
Because our government had already surrendered long time ago.

791
01:23:10,330 --> 01:23:12,580
你不知道吗？
Das wussten Sie nicht?

792
01:23:12,750 --> 01:23:15,210
你不知道吗？
You didn't know?

793
01:23:16,170 --> 01:23:20,210
不知道 我真的不知道 我们什么时候投降的？
No, I did not know that.When did we surrender?

794
01:23:20,370 --> 01:23:23,040
我们什么时候投降的？
Wann haben wir kapituliert?

795
01:23:23,210 --> 01:23:27,830
- 几小时前  - 几小时前
- Vor ein paar Stunden.  - A couple of hours ago.

796
01:23:30,040 --> 01:23:34,750
好了 你会喜欢我的 驾车回军营
Gut. Sie konnen gerne in meinem Wagen mit in die Kaserne fahren.

797
01:23:34,920 --> 01:23:39,080
欢迎你和他一起回军营
You are welcome to wide with him back to the barracks.

798
01:23:39,250 --> 01:23:42,210
不 谢谢 我想和我的人一起去
No thanks, I would like to go with my men.

799
01:23:42,370 --> 01:23:46,790
不 谢谢 我想和我的人一起去
Nein, danke. Er mochte gerne mit seinen Mannern fahren.

800
01:23:46,960 --> 01:23:49,210
我明白了
Ich verstehe.

801
01:25:49,750 --> 01:25:53,540
是的 这令人失望…
Yes, it was both disappointing...

802
01:25:53,710 --> 01:25:59,370
…但欣慰 它很快就结束了
...and a relief, that it was over quickly.

803
01:25:59,540 --> 01:26:03,330
没有很多的丹麦人倒下
Without that many fallen Danes.

804
01:26:03,500 --> 01:26:08,200
我们不得不投降 我们不能接受德国
We had to surrender.We couldn't take on Germany.

805
01:26:08,370 --> 01:26:12,410
我们当然不喜欢它 那是肯定的
Of course we didn't like it. That's for sure.

806
01:26:12,580 --> 01:26:17,250
他们不应该占领我们的国家
They shouldn't occupy our country.

807
01:26:18,410 --> 01:26:22,120
你不能骄傲 你已经杀了人
You can't be proud of,that you have killed people.

808
01:26:22,290 --> 01:26:25,040
这就是全部
And that's what it's all about.

809
01:26:25,210 --> 01:26:29,250
你杀的越多 更容易赢得胜利
The more you kill, the easier it gets to win.

810
01:26:29,410 --> 01:26:33,080
我不得不同意诸如此类的结果 因为有一些事情…
I can't let stuff like that go,because there were things...

811
01:26:33,250 --> 01:26:37,700
…这是非常艰难的 但…
...that were pretty tough. But...

812
01:26:37,870 --> 01:26:40,250
…但没有什么可以做的
...but there is nothing to do about it.

813
01:26:40,410 --> 01:26:44,830
没有什么可以做的 这种情况我经历了
Nothing to do about it. It was a situation I went through.

814
01:26:45,000 --> 01:26:48,700
我爸爸认识我所有的伙伴 然后他说:
My father knows all my comrades.Then he said:

815
01:26:48,870 --> 01:26:51,830
“我要告诉你
"This I will tell you.

816
01:26:52,000 --> 01:26:56,080
我宁愿听到 那就是听到…
I would rather have heard, or hear...

817
01:26:56,250 --> 01:27:02,580
弗罗泽投降 不是你没有战斗过”
Frode had fallen, than that You haven't fought."

818
01:27:04,620 --> 01:27:10,290
你是孤独的 没有女朋友 妻子或孩子
You are alone and have neither a girlfriend, wife or kids.

819
01:27:10,450 --> 01:27:13,120
因此 如果最坏的情况发生…
So if the worst were to happen...

820
01:27:13,290 --> 01:27:18,330
…那么它就不会是最大的灾难
...then it wouldn't be the greatest of disasters.

821
01:27:18,500 --> 01:27:23,450
从一开始 他们说
From the top, they said:

822
01:27:24,620 --> 01:27:27,620
这不是徒劳的
It was not in vain.

823
01:27:27,790 --> 01:27:30,200
但代价…
But the price...

824
01:27:30,370 --> 01:27:33,330
…有些是很高的
...it was high, for some.

825
01:27:40,000 --> 01:27:45,000
英文字幕：Alkochef
感谢Alkochef发布本片英文字幕
English subtitles: Alkochef

826
01:27:45,010 --> 01:27:50,000
字幕中文翻译：静默的风
如转载使用 请保留译者信息

827
01:27:50,010 --> 01:27:55,000
制作本字幕纯属个人兴趣交流
任何单位和个人不得作为商业用途

828
01:27:55,010 --> 01:28:00,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

829
01:28:00,520 --> 01:28:07,850
剧终
谢谢观赏

