1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
字幕来源｜南山石　颇感兴趣@CMCT团队
后期｜Lee.

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

3
00:00:21,830 --> 00:00:27,630
[底特律市　周二 凌晨 1:37]

4
00:00:41,160 --> 00:00:45,790
关于布置还有什么问题吗 没有了吧
Nobody got no questions about the layout, right? No questions?

5
00:00:45,960 --> 00:00:47,710
没了
No.

6
00:00:49,290 --> 00:00:50,750
我还是再讲一次吧
Let's go over this shit one more time.

7
00:00:50,920 --> 00:00:52,880
入口在这儿
They got a small dinger on the entrance door.

8
00:00:53,050 --> 00:00:56,000
我去叫他们开门 然后李维和我进去
I'm gonna get them to open it. Then me and Levine are going in, right?

9
00:00:56,150 --> 00:01:00,490
亚祖和亚柏上屋顶这度门 封着它
Giolito and Pederson, you go over to this overhead door and you block it.

10
00:01:00,660 --> 00:01:03,530
明白吗 亚劳和亚林去后门
OK? Rondell and Leppert, hit the back door.

11
00:01:04,490 --> 00:01:07,290
没问题 小事一件
No problem. It's a piece of cake.

12
00:01:07,550 --> 00:01:09,430
麦基和克莱 你们守着前园
McKee and Cline, you're gonna be in the yard

13
00:01:09,600 --> 00:01:10,810
别让他们逃跑
in case we get some jump-outs.

14
00:01:10,870 --> 00:01:12,330
有人出来就抓他
You all catch somebody trying to jump out...

15
00:01:12,400 --> 00:01:14,920
- 福里  - 失陪
- Foley.  - Excuse me a second.

16
00:01:16,760 --> 00:01:18,130
飞虎队在哪
Where in the hell is SWAT?

17
00:01:19,300 --> 00:01:22,430
- 老大 我叫他们别来了  - 什么
- Boss, I cancelled the SWAT team.  - You what?

18
00:01:22,590 --> 00:01:24,850
事无大小也要有飞虎队
I wouldn't raid a church bingo game without SWAT.

19
00:01:26,140 --> 00:01:29,680
不过是偷车贼 机械工而已
These guys are carjackers. They're mechanics.

20
00:01:29,850 --> 00:01:32,940
我们能搞定的 飞虎队乱开枪 只会毁坏证物
We can handle this. We don't need SWAT blowing holes in all my evidence.

21
00:01:33,110 --> 00:01:36,570
还可能会打伤人 我们自己来
Besides, they might shoot somebody. Let's do this.

22
00:01:37,690 --> 00:01:40,070
这是你的行动 我只是个观察者
This is your operation. I'm just an observer.

23
00:01:41,150 --> 00:01:43,070
但我会留心观察
But I'll be watching.

24
00:01:43,240 --> 00:01:46,660
那观察我不靠飞虎队吧 信我
Just observe how I don't have to use SWAT, and trust me on this.

25
00:01:48,680 --> 00:01:51,910
准备好了 有没有人要去小便
Everybody's ready, right? Nobody need to take a nervous piss?

26
00:01:52,080 --> 00:01:54,000
准备好了 好了吗
We got this. OK?

27
00:01:55,130 --> 00:01:56,460
出发
Let's mount up.

28
00:02:03,550 --> 00:02:06,390
今早的气温是五十五度
This is Dick Purtan. We've got 55 degrees outside this morning.

29
00:02:06,560 --> 00:02:08,890
现在是戴安娜·露丝的
Now here's Motown's own Diana Ross and the Supremes,

30
00:02:09,060 --> 00:02:10,810
“来看我”
and "Come See About Me".

31
00:02:59,980 --> 00:03:03,820
喂 过来 你干什么
Hey, hey! Come on. What are you doing?

32
00:03:07,260 --> 00:03:08,750
波比 他们来了
Bobby, they're here.

33
00:03:53,160 --> 00:03:54,750
没遇到麻烦吧
Any trouble with the hijack?

34
00:03:54,910 --> 00:03:57,620
- 十分顺利  - 小事
- Right where you say it is.  - Piece of cake, man.

35
00:03:57,790 --> 00:04:00,080
- 有没有人受伤  - 没有
- Anybody hurt?  - No.

36
00:04:00,250 --> 00:04:04,170
好我不想有人无端端受伤
Good. I don't like to see people unnecessarily injured.

37
00:04:04,340 --> 00:04:05,880
没有人受伤
Nobody got hurt.

38
00:04:08,260 --> 00:04:10,050
- 锁匙呢  - 你还没货车呢 兄弟
- Keys?  - Ain't your truck yet, man.

39
00:04:10,110 --> 00:04:11,430
没钱免谈
Not till we see some money.

40
00:04:11,600 --> 00:04:13,600
我不过想看看车尾厢
I just want to look in the back.

41
00:04:27,780 --> 00:04:28,860
好
Yes!

42
00:04:29,100 --> 00:04:32,500
[美国政府资产]

43
00:04:36,580 --> 00:04:39,790
- 我们的钱呢  - 给他
- Where's our money?  - Pay him.

44
00:04:47,800 --> 00:04:50,100
[“奇妙世界”酒店]

45
00:04:51,890 --> 00:04:53,300
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.

46
00:05:37,890 --> 00:05:39,680
是不是该叫飞虎队来
You think we should have used SWAT?

47
00:05:40,520 --> 00:05:43,690
- 操飞虎队  - 我同意 操飞虎队
- Fuck SWAT.  - That's what I say. Fuck SWAT.

48
00:05:53,870 --> 00:05:57,790
- 有人 现在怎办  - 杀了他
- Some guy. What should I do?  - Kill him.

49
00:06:01,830 --> 00:06:04,130
你好 这是非法地下拆车吗
How you doing? Is this the illegal chop shop?

50
00:06:04,290 --> 00:06:06,130
你经营非法的地下拆车 是吗
One of them illegal places where they chop up cars?

51
00:06:06,290 --> 00:06:08,050
我老婆的别克在外面
'Cause I got a Buick out here, belong to my wife.

52
00:06:08,110 --> 00:06:10,590
我想你们屠了我老婆的汽车 因为八婆不听话
I want to get this shit chopped up, because the bitch ain't acting right.

53
00:06:10,760 --> 00:06:12,680
你出来看看好吗
Can you take a look at it for me, please?

54
00:06:14,340 --> 00:06:15,760
上 上 上
Go, go, go!

55
00:06:22,940 --> 00:06:23,940
上
Go!

56
00:06:36,780 --> 00:06:38,660
他们有机关枪
They got fucking machine guns.

57
00:06:47,340 --> 00:06:50,130
- 你还说他们没有枪  - 他们一定是改变了世界观
- I thought you said they had no guns!  - They must've changed their world view.

58
00:06:56,600 --> 00:06:58,180
拿鸟枪来
Get the 12-gauge.

59
00:07:35,720 --> 00:07:37,340
应该叫飞虎队来
We should've called SWAT.

60
00:07:40,060 --> 00:07:42,430
警察 举起手
Police! Hands in the air!

61
00:07:43,350 --> 00:07:46,810
可恶 上呀 上
Shit! Move it! Go! Go!

62
00:07:51,900 --> 00:07:53,110
搞什么
What the...?

63
00:08:01,990 --> 00:08:03,870
亚德 来呀
Daniel, come on!

64
00:08:26,980 --> 00:08:29,270
掩护我 我跟亚杜进去
Y'all cover me! I'm going in with Todd.

65
00:08:46,000 --> 00:08:47,580
不
No!

66
00:09:08,690 --> 00:09:11,690
阿克塞尔 你在喝咖啡吗
Axel, you on a coffee break?

67
00:09:13,730 --> 00:09:16,070
去抓那王八
Go get that son of a bitch.

68
00:09:25,040 --> 00:09:27,290
唏 老大 唏 唏
Hey, Boss. Hey, man! Hey!

69
00:09:28,500 --> 00:09:30,210
可恶
Shit!

70
00:10:09,790 --> 00:10:10,830
有人跟着我们
We got a tail.

71
00:10:12,830 --> 00:10:14,580
干掉那小丑
Wax that clown.

72
00:11:01,550 --> 00:11:03,130
该死的
God damn it!

73
00:11:14,890 --> 00:11:16,350
帮帮我
Help me, man.

74
00:12:09,700 --> 00:12:11,620
警察 我在追谋杀犯
Police officer! Trying to catch a goddamned killer!

75
00:12:11,780 --> 00:12:12,830
快让开 走开
Move it! Move it!

76
00:12:12,990 --> 00:12:16,370
- 别挡我的路 我是警察  - 你冷静点
- Get the fuck out of my way! I'm a cop!  - Take it easy.

77
00:12:16,540 --> 00:12:19,170
请你滚开 好吗
Man, get the fuck out of here, all right?

78
00:12:24,420 --> 00:12:26,130
谢谢
Thank you.

79
00:12:26,670 --> 00:12:30,050
我叫博史迪 你有身份证明吗
My name's Steve Fulbright. Could I see some ID, please?

80
00:12:30,220 --> 00:12:32,600
我是底特律警察
Hey, man, I am a Detroit police officer.

81
00:12:32,760 --> 00:12:34,430
叫阿克塞尔 我的警章呢
My name is Axel... Where's my shit?

82
00:12:35,770 --> 00:12:39,650
我是底特律警察 谋杀犯现在跑了
I'm a Detroit police officer. I am chasing a killer who's getting away now.

83
00:12:39,810 --> 00:12:42,060
- 我们知道  - 你们知道什么
- We know.  - You know what?

84
00:12:42,230 --> 00:12:43,480
我们知道
We know.

85
00:12:44,900 --> 00:12:46,570
福里警官 实情是
What's happened here, Detective Foley,

86
00:12:46,740 --> 00:12:49,820
你介入了联邦政府的调查
is you got yourself in the middle of a federal investigation.

87
00:12:49,990 --> 00:12:51,240
调查什么 利息税
What is this, income tax?

88
00:12:51,410 --> 00:12:54,740
那混蛋刚杀死了一个底特律警察
The fucking guy in the truck just shot a Detroit police officer!

89
00:12:54,910 --> 00:12:58,370
但重要的是我们现在不抓他
It's very important he not be apprehended at this time.

90
00:13:00,750 --> 00:13:02,790
我们想知道的是他要去哪
We want to know where he's going with what he's got

91
00:13:02,960 --> 00:13:04,420
把赃物卖给谁
and who he's selling it to.

92
00:13:04,920 --> 00:13:09,050
- 是毒品吗  - 我们不是毒品调查科
- This drugs?  - We're not DEA.

93
00:13:14,430 --> 00:13:16,770
我们很感激你的合作
We appreciate your cooperation on this.

94
00:14:17,480 --> 00:14:20,290
我跟华府查过 姓博的没问题
I checked with Washington. This guy, Fulbright, is kosher.

95
00:14:20,460 --> 00:14:23,330
他有高度秘密任务 不能动他
He's working on something so classified, they got the ladder up behind him.

96
00:14:23,500 --> 00:14:26,000
嘿 阿克塞尔 按联邦政府的指示
Hey, Axel, if the federal government wants these guys running loose,

97
00:14:26,170 --> 00:14:27,290
我们该停止调查吧
shouldn't we close down the investigation?

98
00:14:27,460 --> 00:14:28,420
操联邦政府
Fuck the federal government.

99
00:14:28,480 --> 00:14:31,170
我要的是杀亚杜的凶手 你找到什么
I want the man that killed Todd. Now, what you got?

100
00:14:31,340 --> 00:14:33,720
没什么 车牌是假的
Not a hell of a lot. Plates on the van were phony.

101
00:14:34,010 --> 00:14:35,720
车房的人是被处决的
The dead mechanics were executed.

102
00:14:36,030 --> 00:14:38,220
只有一人有枪 而且还在枪袋
Only one was strapped, it was still holstered.

103
00:14:38,390 --> 00:14:41,140
两个杀手身上有三万元现金
Plus, the bodies of the two shooters had 30,000 in cash.

104
00:14:41,390 --> 00:14:42,350
是高价杀手
That's high-priced heat.

105
00:14:42,520 --> 00:14:44,810
只找到圣地牙哥驾驶执照
Only ID on both these shooters were San Diego drivers' licenses.

106
00:14:44,980 --> 00:14:47,110
圣地牙哥警察有他们的记录
San Diego PD's got a sheet on these guys.

107
00:14:47,270 --> 00:14:49,730
是职业杀手 通常为毒贩工作
Enforcers for hire, mostly for the Tijuana drug dealers.

108
00:14:49,900 --> 00:14:51,400
你说这事情跟毒品有关
You think this is about drugs?

109
00:14:51,570 --> 00:14:53,860
其中一名杀手的公文箱里
An attache case which may belong to one of the shooters

110
00:14:54,030 --> 00:14:56,740
有加州“奇妙世界”酒店毛巾
had a towel in it from the Wonder World Hotel in California.

111
00:14:56,910 --> 00:14:58,370
“奇妙世界”
Wonder World?

112
00:14:59,540 --> 00:15:01,410
另一部汽车呢 有什么资料
Did you check out that car they shot Todd from?

113
00:15:01,580 --> 00:15:02,750
在机场租的
Yeah, rental from the airport.

114
00:15:02,910 --> 00:15:05,250
是俄克拉荷马城的何医生租的
The renter's a Dr. Oliver Hirsch from Oklahoma City.

115
00:15:05,420 --> 00:15:06,790
- 是偷来的身份证  - 对了
- Stolen ID?  - Yeah.

116
00:15:06,960 --> 00:15:08,420
何医生说他的钱包被人偷了
Doctor said his wallet was lifted

117
00:15:08,590 --> 00:15:10,630
当他在游乐场游玩的时候
while he was on vacation at an amusement park.

118
00:15:10,800 --> 00:15:12,880
那个游乐场是“奇妙世界”吧
I hope you're gonna tell me the amusement park was Wonder World.

119
00:15:13,050 --> 00:15:14,420
对了
Yeah.

120
00:15:15,930 --> 00:15:20,180
- 失陪  - “奇妙世界”
- Excuse me.  - Wonder World.

121
00:15:21,430 --> 00:15:22,640
嘿
Hey.

122
00:15:24,060 --> 00:15:26,810
我知道你一直陪着他
I understand that you were with him at the end.

123
00:15:28,270 --> 00:15:30,150
是的 他死前一直在讲你
Yeah. His last words were about you.

124
00:15:32,990 --> 00:15:36,280
那不像我的亚杜 阿克塞尔
That does not sound like my Douglas, Axel.

125
00:15:36,450 --> 00:15:37,860
你再说一次
Try again.

126
00:15:40,580 --> 00:15:42,450
实际上 他最后一句话是
Actually, his last words were,

127
00:15:42,620 --> 00:15:45,790
阿克塞尔 你在喝咖啡吗 去抓那王八
"Axel, are you on a coffee break? Go and get that son of a bitch".

128
00:15:45,960 --> 00:15:48,670
这就是他的遗言
Those were his last words.

129
00:15:51,630 --> 00:15:54,010
那才像我的亚杜
That sounds like my Douglas.

130
00:15:55,380 --> 00:15:57,590
不错 是个好主意
Yeah, it sounds like a good idea, too.

131
00:16:12,900 --> 00:16:14,940
- 喂  - 喂 我叫阿克塞尔·福里
- Hello.  - Hello, my name's Axel Foley.

132
00:16:15,110 --> 00:16:16,450
我找比利 罗斯伍德
I'm looking for Billy Rosewood.

133
00:16:16,610 --> 00:16:19,110
欢迎光临比佛利山警署
Welcome to the Beverly Hills Police Department.

134
00:16:19,280 --> 00:16:22,450
要听英文 请按一 井号键
To continue this message in English, press one, pound.

135
00:16:22,620 --> 00:16:25,370
要听西班牙文 请按二 星号键
For Spanish, press two, star.

136
00:16:25,540 --> 00:16:28,210
波斯语 请按三 井号键
For Farsi, press three, pound.

137
00:16:29,000 --> 00:16:32,460
有露宿者在你的草坪 按一五
If you have homeless people on your lawn, press 15.

138
00:16:33,130 --> 00:16:36,590
骚动谣言热线 按一七
If you need the riot rumour hotline, press 17.

139
00:16:38,220 --> 00:16:41,140
嘿 找比利·罗斯伍德按什么键
Hey! Which button for Billy Rosewood?

140
00:16:47,560 --> 00:16:49,690
有没有一位罗斯伍德
Rosewood? In the house?

141
00:16:51,690 --> 00:16:54,360
勒·罗斯伍德 莫伊·勒·罗斯伍德
Le Rosewood. Moi le Rosewood.

142
00:17:09,870 --> 00:17:11,250
进来
Come in.

143
00:17:12,710 --> 00:17:14,380
门是开着的
It's open.

144
00:17:30,190 --> 00:17:32,730
- 阿克塞尔·福里  - 比利 你好吗
- Axel Foley!  - Billy, how you doing?

145
00:17:32,900 --> 00:17:36,320
- 我真不敢相信  - 看看你的办公室 看看
- I don't believe it.  - Look at your office! Look at this!

146
00:17:36,480 --> 00:17:40,900
有三扇窗 百叶帘还有植物
You got three windows in here, venetian blinds, and a ficus.

147
00:17:41,070 --> 00:17:43,740
你办公室有肥大健康的植物
One of them big, healthy ficus in your office.

148
00:17:44,580 --> 00:17:47,990
不单止是植物 看
Not just the ficus. Look.

149
00:17:48,580 --> 00:17:50,500
你办公室有冰箱
You got a refrigerator in your office?

150
00:17:50,670 --> 00:17:53,250
胡佛的办公室也没有冰箱
Man, J. Edgar Hoover didn't even have a refrigerator in his office.

151
00:17:53,420 --> 00:17:55,920
只有卷发器 风筒 诸如此类
Just maybe some hair curlers and a dryer or something.

152
00:17:56,630 --> 00:17:58,510
你当上了探长是吗
What they promote you to, captain or something?

153
00:17:58,670 --> 00:18:00,920
我是DDO-JSIQC
I'm DDO-JSIOC.

154
00:18:01,090 --> 00:18:03,840
DDO-JSIQC 那是什么
The JG-Joe-Joe-C? What is that?

155
00:18:04,010 --> 00:18:06,260
是各部门行动司令联合系统
It stands for "Deputy Director of Operations

156
00:18:06,430 --> 00:18:09,310
我是行动组的副组长
for Joint Systems Interdepartmental Operational Command".

157
00:18:11,100 --> 00:18:12,190
好
OK.

158
00:18:13,350 --> 00:18:16,110
这是洛杉矶
Here we are. Los Angeles.

159
00:18:16,270 --> 00:18:18,940
全球最伟大的城市之一 阿克塞尔
One of the greatest cities in the world, Axel, divided.

160
00:18:19,110 --> 00:18:21,150
但基于地理环境分成很多区域
Divided by its unique geography.

161
00:18:21,320 --> 00:18:24,740
- 地理环境  - 洛杉矶是个大城市
- Geography?  - LA is a vast metropolis,

162
00:18:24,910 --> 00:18:28,580
贫富悬殊的现象遍及辽阔的地域
with social and economic imbalances spread over an enormous distance.

163
00:18:28,740 --> 00:18:31,000
贼人劫比佛利山
A criminal hits here, Beverly Hills,

164
00:18:31,160 --> 00:18:33,210
西好莱坞和市中心
then here, West Hollywood, then here, downtown.

165
00:18:33,370 --> 00:18:35,750
那该由谁负责呢 集体责任
Whose responsibility is it? Everybody's?

166
00:18:36,960 --> 00:18:41,380
不可能 案子于是交这儿处理 越过了界线的罪案都交我这儿
Impossible. So it all comes here. Every crime that crosses a green line.

167
00:18:41,550 --> 00:18:44,970
- 绿线  - 司法的绿线
- A green line?  - Green lines of jurisdiction.

168
00:18:45,140 --> 00:18:48,470
比佛利山 西好莱坞 市中心 山谷区 桑塔莫妮卡
Beverly Hills, West Hollywood, downtown, the Valley, Santa Monica.

169
00:18:48,640 --> 00:18:52,140
警察不会过界 阿克塞尔 但罪犯会
Peace officers respect these green lines, Axel, but the criminal doesn't.

170
00:18:52,310 --> 00:18:54,520
所以 当犯人越过绿界
So whenever a criminal crosses between green lines,

171
00:18:54,690 --> 00:18:57,110
那便是我这儿的案件了
that's when the DDO-JSIOC goes to work.

172
00:18:57,270 --> 00:18:59,020
比利 听来很够威
That's very impressive, Billy.

173
00:18:59,190 --> 00:19:02,150
我控制绿线
I control the green lines, and Axel...

174
00:19:02,320 --> 00:19:06,820
控制绿线的人控制南加州
...whoever controls the green lines controls southern California.

175
00:19:09,410 --> 00:19:10,790
比利 你找我吗
You wanted to see me, Billy?

176
00:19:11,910 --> 00:19:14,660
是的 约翰 警方抓了两个小贼
Oh, yes I did, Jon. The sheriff's department nabbed two guys

177
00:19:14,830 --> 00:19:16,960
在停车场做案的
pulling a stall-and-hook in a mall parking lot.

178
00:19:17,130 --> 00:19:19,880
手法跟上星期梅市的案件相似
It's the same MO as those jobs on Melrose last week.

179
00:19:20,280 --> 00:19:22,210
好 我马上去跟他们谈谈
Beautiful. I'll run out there and talk to them.

180
00:19:22,380 --> 00:19:24,510
疑犯在凡奈斯 我去告诉他们你就过去
They're holding 'em in Van Nuys. I'll call and tell them you're coming.

181
00:19:24,680 --> 00:19:26,510
- 好的  - 约翰
- Good. All right.  - Jon...

182
00:19:26,680 --> 00:19:28,350
这是我的朋友
I want you to meet a friend of mine.

183
00:19:28,510 --> 00:19:31,100
阿克塞尔·福里 这位是约翰
Axel Foley. Axel, Jon Flint.

184
00:19:31,270 --> 00:19:35,140
你好 我听过关于你的事 底特律来的
How are you? I've heard about you. You're from Detroit, right?

185
00:19:35,310 --> 00:19:36,810
塔格特常提起你
Taggart used to talk about you.

186
00:19:36,980 --> 00:19:39,980
塔格特呢 我想跟他打招呼
Hey. Taggart! Where is he? I'd love to say hello to him.

187
00:19:40,150 --> 00:19:42,940
那你得去凤凰城 他退休了
Then you'll have to fly to Phoenix. Taggart's retired.

188
00:19:43,450 --> 00:19:46,450
整天在树林找打丢了的高尔夫球
Spends his days lost in the woods looking for his golf balls.

189
00:19:47,470 --> 00:19:50,410
也是我的梦想 希望很快成真
That's a dream I'm not too far from myself.

190
00:19:50,580 --> 00:19:53,580
你来加州干吗 阿克塞尔 渡假
So what brings you to California, Axel? Vacation?

191
00:19:53,750 --> 00:19:57,420
- 我来找一个杀人凶手  - 在比佛利山
- I'm looking for a killer.  - In Beverly Hills?

192
00:19:57,580 --> 00:20:01,040
- 不“奇妙世界”  - “奇妙世界”
- No. Wonder World.  - Wonder World?

193
00:20:01,210 --> 00:20:04,050
你是说福星兔发了狂吗
You mean Rufus Rabbit has gone berserko?

194
00:20:04,220 --> 00:20:07,050
不 我上司在地下拆车场被人枪杀
No. My boss got gunned down in a chop shop.

195
00:20:07,220 --> 00:20:09,840
杀手坐一辆淡黄色的福特货车跑了
The killer got away in a cream-coloured Ford truck,

196
00:20:10,010 --> 00:20:12,140
- 车应在这儿  - 车牌
- and I think it might be out here.  - Plates?

197
00:20:12,310 --> 00:20:15,560
假的 但我有点线索指向“奇妙世界”
Plates were phony. We got some evidence that points to Wonder World.

198
00:20:15,640 --> 00:20:17,850
所以我想到那儿走走
So what I want to do is go down to Wonder World and look around

199
00:20:17,920 --> 00:20:20,690
问几个问题 可能会找到头绪
and ask some questions. Maybe I can find something out.

200
00:20:20,860 --> 00:20:22,150
你在那认识人吗
Would y'all know somebody there?

201
00:20:22,320 --> 00:20:25,110
当然 迪艾利 他是保安主管
Absolutely. Ellis DeWald is the head of park security.

202
00:20:25,280 --> 00:20:27,610
掌管全国最大私人保安队伍
Runs the biggest private security force in America.

203
00:20:27,780 --> 00:20:29,410
可以给我介绍吗
Can you introduce me to him?

204
00:20:29,570 --> 00:20:32,620
等我处理完凡奈斯的事 好吗
As soon as I have a talk with the perps in Van Nuys, all right?

205
00:20:33,070 --> 00:20:35,750
你先去 我会通知迪艾利一声
You go on out. I'll call DeWald, tell him you're coming.

206
00:20:36,320 --> 00:20:38,790
他很好人 是我老友 那儿见
He's a great guy. He's a pal of mine. I'll meet you out there.

207
00:20:39,160 --> 00:20:40,420
好极了 谢谢
Great. Thanks.

208
00:20:40,580 --> 00:20:43,590
你会喜欢“奇妙世界”很好玩的
You'll love Wonder World. It's a great place.

209
00:20:43,750 --> 00:20:47,880
还有 阿克塞尔 别忘记 我们这儿做事讲分寸
Axel, don't forget, we play by the rules around here.

210
00:20:48,550 --> 00:20:50,390
我听过塔格特的故事
I've heard Taggart's stories.

211
00:20:55,220 --> 00:20:58,390
“奇妙世界”在哪一条绿线后面
Which one of those green lines is Wonder World behind?

212
00:21:17,870 --> 00:21:20,290
- 他在那 好  - 过来
- There he is!  - OK, come on!

213
00:21:23,880 --> 00:21:26,210
你好 先生 欢迎光临 有什么可效劳
Hello, sir, welcome to Wonder World. Can I help you?

214
00:21:26,620 --> 00:21:30,340
我想跟迪艾利先生谈谈
Yes, I'd like to talk to one of the park executives, a Mr. Ellis DeWald.

215
00:21:30,510 --> 00:21:31,430
请问有没有预约
Do you have an appointment?

216
00:21:31,770 --> 00:21:35,140
- 应该有 我叫阿克塞尔 福里  - 好的
- I'm supposed to. My name's Axel Foley.  - OK.

217
00:21:35,500 --> 00:21:37,180
对不起 先生 名单上没你名字
I'm sorry, sir. I don't have you on the list.

218
00:21:37,930 --> 00:21:39,310
可能还未打电话来
Maybe they haven't called yet.

219
00:21:39,480 --> 00:21:41,730
是比佛利山的蓬探员
A Detective Flint from the Beverly Hills Police Department

220
00:21:41,900 --> 00:21:43,860
替我安排的
was supposed to call and get me squared away.

221
00:21:44,020 --> 00:21:46,480
对不起 先生 如果没预约的话
I'm sorry, sir, but if you don't have an appointment for park business,

222
00:21:46,650 --> 00:21:47,980
入场需要买票
you will have to buy a ticket.

223
00:21:49,570 --> 00:21:52,110
- 多少钱  - 三十五元
- How much is a ticket?  - Thirty-five dollars.

224
00:21:52,440 --> 00:21:53,480
三十五元
Thirty-five dollars?!

225
00:21:53,610 --> 00:21:57,240
可以玩足全场的游戏和看表演
That allows you and your party access to all the rides, shows and attractions.

226
00:21:57,410 --> 00:22:00,250
等等 我不要玩什么游戏
Wait a minute. Look, I don't want to go on any rides,

227
00:22:00,410 --> 00:22:01,830
也不想看表演
and I don't have any party. It's just me.

228
00:22:02,000 --> 00:22:04,380
我只想跟保安主管谈谈
All I wanna do is talk to the director of security.

229
00:22:05,130 --> 00:22:07,840
先生 请站过来 好吗
Excuse me, sir, would you step out of line for a moment, please?

230
00:22:08,570 --> 00:22:11,970
- 什么  - 先生 请你过来
- What line?  - Just step over here, please, sir.

231
00:22:12,190 --> 00:22:13,600
谢谢
Thank you.

232
00:22:16,100 --> 00:22:17,100
先生 有问题吗
Is there a problem, sir?

233
00:22:17,260 --> 00:22:18,770
对了 我来告诉你问题是什么
Yeah, I'll tell you what the problem is.

234
00:22:18,930 --> 00:22:20,560
是三十五元 那就是问题所在
Thirty-five dollars, that's what the problem is.

235
00:22:20,730 --> 00:22:21,850
如果你觉得价格贵的话
If the admission seems high,

236
00:22:22,020 --> 00:22:24,480
我们建议你可以去“幻想乐园”
we suggest you go down the road to Fantasy Park.

237
00:22:24,650 --> 00:22:27,440
他们的票价可能较合你口味 先生
You might find their ticket price more to your liking, sir.

238
00:22:27,720 --> 00:22:30,780
问题是 我是来找迪艾利 他是你上司
The point is, I'm here to see Ellis DeWald. Is he your boss?

239
00:22:30,950 --> 00:22:33,910
对 迪先生是保安和客务主管
Yes. Mr. DeWald is head of security and guest relations.

240
00:22:34,300 --> 00:22:38,120
- 你有约了他吗  - 我应该是约了他的
- Do you have an appointment?  - I'm supposed to have an appointment.

241
00:22:38,440 --> 00:22:41,370
应该是 不等于是 对吗 先生
"Supposed to" is not having, is it, sir?

242
00:22:45,250 --> 00:22:47,210
对不起
Excuse me.

243
00:22:54,010 --> 00:22:57,390
- 一张  - 给你 谢谢
- One, please.  - There you go. Thank you.

244
00:22:57,630 --> 00:22:58,850
谢谢
Thank you.

245
00:23:01,060 --> 00:23:02,640
你知道吗 你应该叫裁缝
You know, you should have your tailor

246
00:23:02,810 --> 00:23:04,350
把上身裁得宽一点
cut the jacket a little wider in the chest.

247
00:23:04,520 --> 00:23:06,400
这样你的枪便不会现出来
That way your gun won't bulge in the back.

248
00:23:13,320 --> 00:23:14,740
谢谢
Thank you.

249
00:23:26,290 --> 00:23:27,920
戴夫叔叔
Uncle Dave.

250
00:23:43,810 --> 00:23:44,850
怎么了
What's going on?

251
00:24:02,600 --> 00:24:06,000
[公司主管办公室]

252
00:24:41,370 --> 00:24:43,490
“外星人袭地球”
"Alien Attack"?

253
00:25:00,890 --> 00:25:02,510
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?

254
00:25:02,680 --> 00:25:05,310
不 只是有点好奇
I was just curious what Alien Attack is.

255
00:25:07,690 --> 00:25:08,940
你看着
Watch.

256
00:25:11,110 --> 00:25:14,070
注意 注意 这是红色警报
Attention! Attention! This is a red alert.

257
00:25:14,230 --> 00:25:16,570
外星太空船正侵袭本市
Alien spacecraft are invading the city.

258
00:25:16,740 --> 00:25:19,860
请从速上地铁撤退
Board the subway trains for immediate evacuation.

259
00:26:00,110 --> 00:26:01,490
很过瘾
This is wild.

260
00:26:01,660 --> 00:26:04,320
不错 相当受欢迎
Yes, it's one of our more popular attractions.

261
00:26:05,910 --> 00:26:08,910
对不起 但你进来干吗
Excuse me, but... what are you doing in here?

262
00:26:09,620 --> 00:26:11,160
你说得对 我该走了
You're right. I gotta go.

263
00:26:11,260 --> 00:26:14,500
我要去开会 多谢你的示范
I have a meeting, but thanks for the show.

264
00:26:20,760 --> 00:26:22,630
看看九号隧道
Punch up tunnel nine. Take a look.

265
00:26:27,010 --> 00:26:30,640
- 你想怎办  - 找谷巴来对付他
- What do you want to do?  - I'll send Cooper. Get him.

266
00:27:19,020 --> 00:27:20,900
对不起
Excuse me.

267
00:27:21,070 --> 00:27:22,940
- 嘿  - 这不公平嘛
- Hey!  - That's not fair.

268
00:27:23,580 --> 00:27:26,160
维修部我要去给炼上油
Maintenance. I gotta go grease a chain.

269
00:27:26,320 --> 00:27:29,330
- 很多噪音 听到吗  - 对不起
- Hear how dry it sounds?  - Sorry.

270
00:27:30,990 --> 00:27:33,450
算了 来吧
Come on. Let's go.

271
00:27:46,090 --> 00:27:47,510
- 妈咪  - 妈咪 这儿呀
- Hi, Mom!  - Mom, up here!

272
00:27:47,680 --> 00:27:52,180
- 妈咪 这儿呀  - 我们在这
- Hi, Mommy! Up here!  - We're here!

273
00:27:57,060 --> 00:27:59,650
- 放那个人下来  - 这要等
- Bring that man down.  - I can't until it goes all...

274
00:27:59,820 --> 00:28:02,360
- 放他下来 可恶  - 不要
- I said bring it down, God damn it.  - Don't...

275
00:28:04,700 --> 00:28:06,780
不要呀 不要啊 老天
Don't. Don't! Jesus!

276
00:28:14,410 --> 00:28:17,920
- 搞什么鬼  - 什么事
- What the hell?  - What's going on?

277
00:28:44,110 --> 00:28:45,570
“蜘蛛”红色讯号
Code red on The Spider.

278
00:28:52,780 --> 00:28:55,080
“奇妙世界”阿克塞尔
Wonder World? Axel!

279
00:29:10,140 --> 00:29:12,550
- 妈妈呀  - 救命呀
- Mama!  - Help!

280
00:29:15,430 --> 00:29:17,390
救命呀
Help! Please!

281
00:29:17,560 --> 00:29:19,310
噢 可恶
Oh, shit!

282
00:29:28,070 --> 00:29:29,990
噢 主啊 你看
Oh, my God. Look!

283
00:29:54,430 --> 00:29:57,430
- 你没事吧  - 没事 但别放手
- Are you all right?  - I'm OK, just don't let go.

284
00:30:17,410 --> 00:30:19,450
“奇妙世界”附近的车辆
All units in the vicinity of Wonder World,

285
00:30:19,620 --> 00:30:22,870
马上到现场协助拯救行动
proceed immediately to assist in emergency rescue.

286
00:30:23,040 --> 00:30:24,500
阿克塞尔
Axel!

287
00:31:29,860 --> 00:31:30,980
嗨
Hi!

288
00:31:32,740 --> 00:31:34,110
看到这条绳子吗
You see this rope?

289
00:31:34,280 --> 00:31:36,990
我们试试沿着绳子滑落地面
We're gonna try to slide down this rope all the way to the ground.

290
00:31:37,500 --> 00:31:40,790
- 真的  - 试试看
- We are?  - We're gonna try.

291
00:31:45,290 --> 00:31:48,540
把手给我 揽着我的颈
Gimme your hand. I want you to come up and hold on to my neck.

292
00:31:49,840 --> 00:31:51,380
来呀 没事的
Come on. It's OK.

293
00:31:54,300 --> 00:31:56,300
揽紧我的颈
You gonna grab onto my neck really tight.

294
00:31:56,470 --> 00:32:00,010
明白吗 来呀 抱紧
OK? Come on. Hold on really tight.

295
00:32:00,180 --> 00:32:02,560
揽紧 喂 太紧了
Hold on tight... Not too tight!

296
00:32:10,820 --> 00:32:12,270
拿手来
Give me your hand.

297
00:32:13,150 --> 00:32:16,860
别这样 拿你的手来
Come on. None of that. Give me your hand. It's OK. Come on.

298
00:32:17,030 --> 00:32:18,450
来呀
It's OK.

299
00:32:21,410 --> 00:32:22,660
会没事的
Come on.

300
00:32:27,710 --> 00:32:29,000
别放手 千万别放手
Hang on! Hang on tight!

301
00:32:35,170 --> 00:32:36,920
好了来呀 上来呀
Come on. Come on up.

302
00:33:17,240 --> 00:33:20,890
主管跟底城警方证实了你的身份
Our head of security has confirmed your identity with the Detroit police.

303
00:33:24,160 --> 00:33:26,600
但他们和我
But neither they nor I...

304
00:33:29,230 --> 00:33:32,270
都不明白你来“奇妙世界”干什么
...understand what you're doing at Wonder World.

305
00:33:32,670 --> 00:33:35,440
我说过了 我来查案 我认为我来对了
I told you, I was investigating a crime. I think I'm in the right place,

306
00:33:35,610 --> 00:33:37,280
因为我才进来十分钟便有人向我开枪
because I've been here for ten minutes and I've already been shot at.

307
00:33:37,870 --> 00:33:40,780
你是说我们的客务人员
Yes. Some of our guest relations people, you said.

308
00:33:42,660 --> 00:33:44,660
小姐带监控影带来了
Miss Perkins is here with the surveillance tapes.

309
00:33:45,360 --> 00:33:47,070
叫她进来
Send her right in.

310
00:33:55,920 --> 00:33:58,170
影带从“蜘蛛”的维修隧道开始
This starts in The Spider maintenance tunnel.

311
00:34:03,600 --> 00:34:05,510
那是我 从隧道出来
There I am, coming down the tunnel.

312
00:34:09,940 --> 00:34:10,810
那是什么
What is that?

313
00:34:11,150 --> 00:34:13,520
影轨雪花 监视器是循环运作的
Tracking fuzz. The monitors are all on a loop.

314
00:34:17,150 --> 00:34:19,690
福里先生 我看不到有枪手
I don't see any gunman, Mr. Foley.

315
00:34:19,860 --> 00:34:21,450
那你以为我开枪射什么鬼
Who the fuck do you think I was shooting at?

316
00:34:22,000 --> 00:34:23,740
预备请律师吧 福里
You better start thinking about a lawyer, Foley.

317
00:34:23,910 --> 00:34:25,700
影带没显示枪手
The tapes don't show your gunman.

318
00:34:25,870 --> 00:34:27,740
影带也没显示其它东西 山先生
They don't show something else, Mr. Sanderson.

319
00:34:28,400 --> 00:34:31,000
他们没有显示福里先生在机件故障时表现的勇气
They don't show Mr. Foley's courage when the ride malfunctioned.

320
00:34:31,160 --> 00:34:33,500
他冒着生命危险救出两个小朋友
He risked his life to save two children.

321
00:34:33,670 --> 00:34:35,130
对了 影带没有显示这个
Yeah, they don't show that shit.

322
00:34:35,290 --> 00:34:37,090
那的确是令人敬配的表现
Well, that would be very impressive,

323
00:34:37,250 --> 00:34:41,050
但我们怎知故障不是你弄出来的
if we knew for sure you didn't cause the malfunction in the first place.

324
00:34:42,430 --> 00:34:45,180
- 迪先生  - 带他进来
- Mr. DeWald.  - Send him in.

325
00:34:45,900 --> 00:34:48,260
福里先生 迪先生
Mr. Foley, Mr. DeWald.

326
00:34:49,130 --> 00:34:52,270
可恶 乌龟王八蛋 就是他了
You fuck! Motherfucker... That's him!

327
00:34:53,350 --> 00:34:55,940
我就是要找这个王八蛋
Motherfucker! That's the fucking guy I'm looking for!

328
00:34:56,220 --> 00:34:58,020
奥文 这是什么回事
Orrin, you want to tell me what's going on here?

329
00:34:58,190 --> 00:35:00,730
他上周末杀了个底特律警察
This fucking guy shot a Detroit police officer last weekend!

330
00:35:01,150 --> 00:35:05,740
上周 我上周末在拉谷的泳屋渡假
Last weekend? I was at my beach house in Laguna last weekend.

331
00:35:06,010 --> 00:35:07,780
你在拉谷的泳屋渡假
Your beach home in Laguna?

332
00:35:09,120 --> 00:35:11,250
等等 我想我认错人了 对不起
Wait, hold on, I think I got the wrong guy. I'm sorry.

333
00:35:11,410 --> 00:35:14,370
真是一场 一场大误会
I'm sorry, this is a big... I'm cool. This is a big misunderstanding.

334
00:35:14,540 --> 00:35:16,420
我不知道你在泳屋
I didn't know you were at your beach...

335
00:35:16,590 --> 00:35:19,750
该死的拉谷的泳屋 你这死王八蛋
...fucking beach house in Laguna! You motherfucker!

336
00:35:20,220 --> 00:35:23,800
- 布小姐 报警  - 他们刚来了
- Miss Bruce, call the police.  - They just walked in.

337
00:35:26,460 --> 00:35:27,240
阿克塞尔
Axel!

338
00:35:27,510 --> 00:35:28,800
就是他了 他是杀人凶手
That's the guy! That's the killer!

339
00:35:30,310 --> 00:35:31,810
迪艾利
Ellis DeWald?

340
00:35:32,640 --> 00:35:33,810
阿克塞尔
Axel!

341
00:35:38,820 --> 00:35:41,070
艾利 这次真是多得你关照
We really appreciate this, Ellis.

342
00:35:41,530 --> 00:35:44,860
你朋友走运 山先生不想事情曝光
Your friend is lucky Mr. Sanderson doesn't want any publicity.

343
00:35:45,280 --> 00:35:50,330
别让他和他的幻想接近我和游乐场
You just keep him and his delusions out of my face and out of my park.

344
00:35:50,720 --> 00:35:52,190
艾利 没问题 我会照办
No problem, Ellis. You got it, babe.

345
00:35:52,280 --> 00:35:55,620
我们星期日还打球吗
By the way, are we still on for Sunday?

346
00:35:56,990 --> 00:35:58,540
你带钱来吧 傻瓜
Bring your money, sucker.

347
00:35:58,710 --> 00:36:01,340
你还有时间的话 我想
All right. When you have a little more time, I'd like to...

348
00:36:01,500 --> 00:36:04,300
现在不成 或者迟些吧
Not right now. Later, perhaps.

349
00:36:04,470 --> 00:36:06,220
谢谢
Thanks.

350
00:36:13,520 --> 00:36:15,230
来了
Here we go.

351
00:36:17,020 --> 00:36:18,350
谢谢
Thank you.

352
00:36:19,940 --> 00:36:22,020
比利 你喝惯的
And the usual for you, Billy.

353
00:36:25,860 --> 00:36:26,990
谢谢
Thanks a lot.

354
00:36:27,700 --> 00:36:29,910
福里 会不会是你搞错
Isn't it just possible that you're mistaken, Foley?

355
00:36:31,030 --> 00:36:34,290
凶手和艾利只是人有相似
That Ellis DeWald just resembles Todd's killer?

356
00:36:34,450 --> 00:36:37,210
我亲眼看见他 是迪艾利
I made the guy in Detroit. It was DeWald.

357
00:36:37,370 --> 00:36:40,250
他可是南加州
DeWald is the head of the largest private police department

358
00:36:40,420 --> 00:36:42,250
最大的保安主管
in Southern California.

359
00:36:43,050 --> 00:36:45,800
他跟洛杉矶警方合作
I mean, he works with us, with the LAPD.

360
00:36:45,970 --> 00:36:48,840
还有州长 他是大众情人
Hell, with the governor's office. Everybody loves him.

361
00:36:49,010 --> 00:36:50,550
他今晚就要接受颁奖
He's even getting an award tonight,

362
00:36:50,720 --> 00:36:53,890
是全国保安机构协会颁的
from the National Association of Security Agencies.

363
00:36:55,520 --> 00:36:58,770
阿克塞尔 我明白你心情烦燥
Axel, it's understandable that you're distraught

364
00:36:58,940 --> 00:37:02,360
你要讨个公道 也许还想报仇
and looking for justice, not to mention revenge.

365
00:37:02,520 --> 00:37:06,280
但会不会是你太心急太着迷
But isn't it just possible that you want it so much

366
00:37:06,440 --> 00:37:09,740
看见相似的人就当是杀人凶手
that you saw your killer in a man who bore a slight resemblance?

367
00:37:09,910 --> 00:37:13,370
我们当差的经常遇到这等事
We run into this all the time in police work, Axel.

368
00:37:13,540 --> 00:37:15,120
亚迪今晚去什么地方颁奖
Where is DeWald getting that award tonight?

369
00:37:15,290 --> 00:37:16,580
阿克塞尔 别
Axel, don't.

370
00:37:17,330 --> 00:37:21,580
你朋友亚迪是坏人 懂吗
Hey, Flint, your friend DeWald is foul, OK? I know he's foul.

371
00:37:21,750 --> 00:37:25,000
所以我要去颁奖礼 给他压力
I'm going to this awards show tonight. I'm gonna put some pressure on him.

372
00:37:25,170 --> 00:37:27,550
说不定他会惊喜来做蠢事
And maybe I'll panic him into doing something stupid.

373
00:37:28,050 --> 00:37:30,590
阿克塞尔 你要出席的话
Axel, if you go to that dinner tonight...

374
00:37:31,930 --> 00:37:33,350
我跟你一起去
...I'm going with you.

375
00:37:33,510 --> 00:37:35,430
来“落日旅舍”接我吧
Pick me up at the Sunset Motel.

376
00:38:10,550 --> 00:38:12,050
别动 王八蛋
Freeze, motherfucker!

377
00:38:15,470 --> 00:38:20,310
- 福里警官  - 你是戴夫叔叔 喂
- Detective Foley?  - You're Uncle Dave! Hey!

378
00:38:20,480 --> 00:38:22,980
天啊 我差点向戴夫叔叔开枪
Hey, Uncle... Oh, my God, I almost shot Uncle Dave!

379
00:38:23,150 --> 00:38:28,110
真不好意思 对不起 幸会 戴夫叔叔
I'm so embarrassed. I'm sorry. Nice to meet you! Uncle Dave!

380
00:38:28,280 --> 00:38:31,200
接待处放我们进来的 福里先生 你别介意
The front desk let us in to wait, Mr. Foley. I hope you don't mind.

381
00:38:31,360 --> 00:38:34,490
不 没问题 是戴夫叔叔嘛
No, it's fine. It's Uncle Dave!

382
00:38:34,660 --> 00:38:37,870
戴夫叔叔 戴夫叔叔 嘿 请坐
Uncle Dave! Uncle Dave! Hey, have a seat.

383
00:38:38,040 --> 00:38:40,160
- 谢谢  - 我是你忠实的粉丝
- Thank you.  - I was such a fan of yours.

384
00:38:40,330 --> 00:38:43,080
- 谢谢 孩子  - 戴夫叔叔
- Thank you, son.  - Uncle Dave...

385
00:38:43,250 --> 00:38:45,670
多谢你错爱
You're very kind.

386
00:38:45,840 --> 00:38:49,960
福里警官 我的游乐场有什么事
Detective Foley, what's going on at my park?

387
00:38:50,520 --> 00:38:53,300
- 你以为有事吗  - 我敢肯定
- You think there's something going on?  - I have no doubts.

388
00:38:53,610 --> 00:38:55,890
- 什么  - 我敢肯定
- What?  - I have no doubts...

389
00:38:56,760 --> 00:38:58,140
但毫无头绪
...nor do I have any ideas.

390
00:38:59,320 --> 00:39:02,520
两星期前 福里警官
Exactly two weeks ago, Detective Foley,

391
00:39:03,060 --> 00:39:07,400
范罗渣 游乐场的主管
Roger Fry, the park's chief operating officer...

392
00:39:07,570 --> 00:39:10,650
我的好朋友 失踪了
...and my friend, disappeared.

393
00:39:10,820 --> 00:39:12,620
游乐场是范罗渣设计的
Roger Fry designed the park,

394
00:39:12,730 --> 00:39:16,200
大型建筑至小买部他都亲力亲为
every nook and cranny of it, from the landscaping to the concession stands.

395
00:39:16,370 --> 00:39:18,120
你说他失踪是什么意思
What do you mean he just disappeared?

396
00:39:18,280 --> 00:39:19,450
给他看看字条
Show him the note.

397
00:39:20,500 --> 00:39:24,160
是罗渣失踪那天收到的
I received this interoffice the day Roger disappeared.

398
00:39:25,380 --> 00:39:28,210
“事关重大 生死由关”罗渣
"This is important, life and death. Roger"

399
00:39:29,590 --> 00:39:31,840
- 什么事关重大  - 我不知道
- What was so important?  - I don't know.

400
00:39:32,010 --> 00:39:33,880
他失踪那天在干什么
What was he doing the day he disappeared?

401
00:39:35,150 --> 00:39:39,140
没什么特别 大抵是例行检查
It was nothing special. He was probably doing one of his usual inspections.

402
00:39:41,130 --> 00:39:42,930
整个游乐场都是他设计的
You say this guy designed the whole park?

403
00:39:43,260 --> 00:39:44,390
不错
Yes.

404
00:39:46,900 --> 00:39:49,690
- 他对这处了如指掌  - 当然
- And he knew the place cold, right?  - Of course.

405
00:39:51,150 --> 00:39:52,940
你在想什么
So what are you thinking?

406
00:39:53,110 --> 00:39:54,990
他一定是发现了
I'm thinking that he must've found something

407
00:39:55,160 --> 00:39:56,780
不见得光的事了
that someone didn't want him to find.

408
00:39:56,950 --> 00:40:00,410
在“奇妙世界”究竟会是什么呢
At Wonder World? What on earth could that be?

409
00:40:00,580 --> 00:40:03,910
是个天真快乐的地方嘛
It's a place of childhood innocence and fun.

410
00:40:04,490 --> 00:40:05,960
还有生死由关
And life and death.

411
00:40:10,590 --> 00:40:13,150
- 你见过戴夫叔叔  - 对
- You met Uncle Dave?  - Yep.

412
00:40:13,500 --> 00:40:15,560
戴夫叔叔
Uncle Dave.

413
00:40:17,050 --> 00:40:19,930
难以置信 我也想见他呀
I don't believe it. I'd give anything to have been with you.

414
00:40:20,240 --> 00:40:23,970
- 他有表现“扭扭宁宁”吗  - 没有
- Did he do the Oki-Doki Shuffle?  - No.

415
00:40:33,780 --> 00:40:34,900
警徽
Outstanding.

416
00:40:37,110 --> 00:40:41,990
- 罗斯伍德 DDO-JSIQC  - 对不起 什么
- Hi. William Rosewood, DDO-JSIOC.  - I beg your pardon?

417
00:40:44,350 --> 00:40:47,330
是我 谢谢
This is me. Thank you.

418
00:40:50,790 --> 00:40:53,090
这鬼东西有什么用
Now, what you gonna do with this shit?

419
00:40:55,560 --> 00:41:00,430
我真不敢相信 阿克威尔
No way. I don't believe this! Ackwell!

420
00:41:01,260 --> 00:41:05,310
阿克威尔 福利 阿克威尔 福利 你这疯子
Ackwell Folee! Ackwell Folee, you crazy thing.

421
00:41:05,480 --> 00:41:06,890
你来干吗
What you doing here?

422
00:41:09,370 --> 00:41:11,260
- 瑟奇  - 是瑟奇
- "Serge."  - Serge.

423
00:41:13,440 --> 00:41:16,030
看你的头发头发好看呀
Look at your head! I love it short!

424
00:41:16,190 --> 00:41:19,320
- 是啊 瑟奇  - 转过身 转过身
- Yeah, Serge.  - Turn around. Turn around.

425
00:41:19,820 --> 00:41:21,870
你这身打扮简直完美
I don't believe how perfect you look!

426
00:41:22,030 --> 00:41:24,450
我最喜欢的狗仔牌黑皮鞋
And then finally you have black Hush Poopies,

427
00:41:24,620 --> 00:41:28,330
你真懂得穿衣服
which are totally retro, which I love. You put a really good package together.

428
00:41:29,370 --> 00:41:33,710
- 你记得比利 罗斯伍德吗  - 比利 比利 我记得你
- You remember Billy Rosewood.  - Billy! Billy, I remember you.

429
00:41:33,880 --> 00:41:35,840
- 你记得我吗  - 当然
- Do you remember?  - Of course.

430
00:41:36,120 --> 00:41:39,840
我给你冲了咖啡 就在画廊 还有一片柠檬皮
I made you an espresso at the art gallery with a lemon twist?

431
00:41:41,260 --> 00:41:43,050
那是我最后一杯了
It was the last one I ever made.

432
00:41:43,360 --> 00:41:45,880
浓咖啡不好喝 你知道为什么吗
It's terrible to drink espresso. You know why?

433
00:41:46,600 --> 00:41:49,100
令你的牙生迹 我不会给你看我的
It stain your teeth. I'm not going to show you mine,

434
00:41:49,270 --> 00:41:50,350
但让我看看你的牙齿
but let me see your teeth.

435
00:41:52,020 --> 00:41:54,480
好漂亮 看看你的可以吗
They're so pretty. Can I see your teeth?

436
00:41:55,690 --> 00:41:57,610
你的牙肉很健康
Look, and you got healthy gums.

437
00:41:57,780 --> 00:41:59,530
- 你有用清肠剂吗  - 什么
- Do you do colonics?  - Excuse me?

438
00:41:59,700 --> 00:42:01,410
- 你有用清肠剂吗  - 没有
- Do you do colonics?  - No. Never...

439
00:42:01,570 --> 00:42:03,910
- 是我的新欢  - 清肠剂
- It's my new favourite thing!  - You dig colonics?

440
00:42:04,080 --> 00:42:08,120
我告诉你他们把管子插进去
I can't tell you what it's like, because they stick a hose up inside you...

441
00:42:08,290 --> 00:42:10,500
- 我知道  - 不 你得明白
- I know...  - No, you've got to understand.

442
00:42:10,670 --> 00:42:14,630
你五岁时吃的粮也放出来
Out comes a candy bar from when you were five!

443
00:42:16,250 --> 00:42:18,050
你的画廊怎么了
What happened to your art gallery that you had?

444
00:42:18,210 --> 00:42:20,970
画廊破产了
The art gallery is completely bankrupt.

445
00:42:21,130 --> 00:42:23,050
丢到厕所去了 为什么
In the toilet. Why?

446
00:42:23,220 --> 00:42:27,060
因为老板又蠢又顿又无知
Because we had an owner who was obstinate and stupid and ignorant.

447
00:42:27,220 --> 00:42:29,930
- 是你开枪射他的 记得吗  - 噢 对了 是我开的枪
- You shot him, remember?  - Oh, right, yes. I shot him.

448
00:42:30,100 --> 00:42:32,730
- 你现在干哪行  - 卖枪 过来看看
- What are you doing now?  - I'm doing guns. Come and look!

449
00:42:37,190 --> 00:42:39,860
这是我的摊位 生存精品店
This is my booth. The Survival Boutique.

450
00:42:40,120 --> 00:42:45,740
我卖武器和其他保安设施
We are doing weapons and protective devices and products for survival

451
00:42:45,910 --> 00:42:48,240
世界不好嘛 疯癫兼暴力
in the helter-skelter world of today.

452
00:42:48,410 --> 00:42:50,540
好了 现在 有一件事是非常重要的
OK, now, one thing's very important.

453
00:42:50,710 --> 00:42:54,580
生存精品店有一套哲学
At the Survival Boutique, I feel that it's my personality,

454
00:42:54,750 --> 00:42:58,380
跟我的性格息息相关 凡事必须符合
my philosophy that everything must conform to the three P's, OK,

455
00:42:58,440 --> 00:43:01,920
兼重保护 地位和美貌
which is protection, prestige and pretty.

456
00:43:03,890 --> 00:43:06,550
生存和美貌没有矛盾
I mean, why you should look ugly if you're just trying to survive?

457
00:43:06,720 --> 00:43:09,680
安全和保持自己的风格
You should be able to maintain your personal sense of style

458
00:43:09,850 --> 00:43:11,100
同样重要
and be safe as well.

459
00:43:11,270 --> 00:43:12,770
好 你觉得怎样
OK, what do you think this is?

460
00:43:14,020 --> 00:43:16,810
看上去像锁匙扣 其实不简单
Is look like a key chain, but it's so much more.

461
00:43:16,980 --> 00:43:20,400
叫“震死你”是一个前海豹队员设计的
This is called a Stunner. It is designed by an ex-Navy SEAL.

462
00:43:20,570 --> 00:43:23,950
是吗 他很认真 我从没见他笑过
OK? Very serious individual, I never see him smile.

463
00:43:24,110 --> 00:43:26,950
我也从没见他穿过一条合适的裤子
Also, I never see him in a pair of pants that fit.

464
00:43:29,690 --> 00:43:32,120
就说你遇到偷车贼
Someone comes up to you who is a carjacker.

465
00:43:33,000 --> 00:43:36,040
你不会为你的丰田车送命吧
Do you want to die for your Camry? I don't think so, right?

466
00:43:36,490 --> 00:43:39,130
那么你可以说 撒一点点的谎
So you say... a little bit of deception...

467
00:43:39,680 --> 00:43:42,090
我要把家里的钥匙从车钥匙上拿下来 好吗
"I want to separate the house from my car keys, OK?

468
00:43:42,260 --> 00:43:46,260
我就是按一下这个键 好吗 然后他说 好的
I'm just going to push this button, OK?" And he says, "OK."

469
00:43:46,430 --> 00:43:49,890
于是你按键 开动机关
And then you push this button, and out it comes from the mechanism,

470
00:43:50,120 --> 00:43:53,980
爆发出前所未见的耀眼光芒
the brightest, blinding light ever that you seeing.

471
00:43:54,140 --> 00:43:56,650
他什么都看不见了 就像这个样子
He cannot see. He's like this.

472
00:43:56,810 --> 00:43:58,770
你成功保家卫族
Everyone is come running to help you.

473
00:43:58,940 --> 00:44:02,150
而且非常威风
And once again, you have survived with style.

474
00:44:02,320 --> 00:44:04,400
哗 劲
Wow. That's cool.

475
00:44:04,570 --> 00:44:08,620
比利 我送一个给你 好吗
Billy, I want to give you one for a present, OK?

476
00:44:09,440 --> 00:44:11,490
- 多谢  - 还有你 阿克威尔
- Thank you.  - And Ackwell...

477
00:44:11,660 --> 00:44:14,200
也送一个给你 因为我担心你
I want to give you one because I worry about you.

478
00:44:14,720 --> 00:44:18,250
- 我想你安全  - 谢谢
- I want you to be safe.  - Thanks.

479
00:44:18,420 --> 00:44:19,580
现在要给看的
Now I'm going to show you something

480
00:44:19,750 --> 00:44:22,340
让你们大开眼界
that is going to totally blow your rocks off.

481
00:44:22,510 --> 00:44:26,800
绝对是我最骄人的杰作
It's absolutely orgasmic and my most thing that I'm proud of.

482
00:44:26,970 --> 00:44:31,890
最适合今日世界的自卫工具
It's the most up-to-date, the ultimate survival tool for today.

483
00:44:33,850 --> 00:44:37,190
新一代豪华武器隆重面世
The dawn of a new generation in luxury personal weaponry,

484
00:44:37,560 --> 00:44:40,380
“歼灭者2000”是美国顶级自卫装置
the Annihilator 2000 is America's premier

485
00:44:40,460 --> 00:44:43,820
家居旅行皆宜的安全武器
survival, home and travel total security unit.

486
00:44:43,990 --> 00:44:47,200
“歼灭者2000”是一个轻巧 性能卓越的武器
The Annihilator 2000 is a lightweight, high-performance weapon

487
00:44:47,360 --> 00:44:49,360
能满足新一代的
that meets the demands of the new generation

488
00:44:49,530 --> 00:44:51,870
高收入群体的一切要求
of upper-income urban survivalists.

489
00:44:52,700 --> 00:44:54,700
“歼灭者”配有手提电话
The Annihilator 2000 has the conveniences

490
00:44:54,870 --> 00:44:58,500
传真机和微波炉
of a cellular telephone with fax machine and a microwave oven.

491
00:45:00,790 --> 00:45:03,380
夜视镜 微电脑
Night-vision goggles, microprocessor,

492
00:45:03,550 --> 00:45:08,130
人声警报系统 CD播放机 数码收音机
verbal alarm systems, a compact disc player, digital AM/FM radio,

493
00:45:08,300 --> 00:45:11,340
摄影机和回放功能 以上仅是
video camera and playback functions are just a few of the features

494
00:45:11,510 --> 00:45:14,470
歼灭者的部份功能
of the extraordinary Annihilator 2000.

495
00:45:14,640 --> 00:45:16,100
你说是真的吗
You think those are real?

496
00:45:16,270 --> 00:45:20,150
“歼灭者”制敌易如反掌
Stopping power is a matter of convenience with your Annihilator 2000.

497
00:45:22,360 --> 00:45:24,400
那是杜蒂 我的训练员
That's Dodi, my personal trainer.

498
00:45:25,940 --> 00:45:28,150
她可以举二百磅
She can bench-press 200 pounds.

499
00:45:29,240 --> 00:45:32,240
她在帮我减磅 但这很困难
She's working on reducing my body fat, but it's really difficult,

500
00:45:32,410 --> 00:45:35,540
因我太喜欢吃羊奶芝士
because I keep sneaking away to have a goat cheese.

501
00:45:35,630 --> 00:45:37,660
我才不管 横竖我有西装蔽体
I don't care. I wear suits.

502
00:45:37,830 --> 00:45:41,540
“歼灭者2000”以轻合金制成
The Annihilator 2000 is constructed of a lightweight aluminium alloy,

503
00:45:41,710 --> 00:45:43,540
配合新科技
combined with a new polymer technology,

504
00:45:43,710 --> 00:45:46,250
永不磨损
making it totally resistant to corrosion.

505
00:45:48,670 --> 00:45:51,800
新一代豪华武器隆重面世
The dawn of a new generation in luxury personal weaponry,

506
00:45:51,970 --> 00:45:54,600
“歼灭者2000”是美国顶级自卫装置
the Annihilator 2000 is America's premier

507
00:45:54,760 --> 00:45:58,430
家居旅行皆宜的安全武器
survival, home and travel total security unit.

508
00:45:58,600 --> 00:46:00,310
谁会买这鬼东西
Now, who's the hell is gonna buy that shit?

509
00:46:00,840 --> 00:46:02,150
你在开玩笑
Are you joking?

510
00:46:02,310 --> 00:46:05,070
这是洛杉矶 我卖了几百套 而且供不应求
This is LA. I'm selling hundreds of these. It's on back order.

511
00:46:05,230 --> 00:46:07,730
- 别胡扯  - 不 我可没有
- Get the fuck outta here!  - No, I cannot!

512
00:46:07,900 --> 00:46:09,990
我跟你讲 我卖了十枝
I am trying to tell you, I sell ten of these

513
00:46:10,150 --> 00:46:12,070
给成龙和史泰龙
to Jackie Stallone for stocking stuffers.

514
00:46:12,240 --> 00:46:15,410
- 胡扯  - 史泰龙买了十四枝
- Get the fuck outta here.  - Sly come in and bought 14.

515
00:46:15,580 --> 00:46:17,740
莎莎·嘉宝买了一枝
Zsa Zsa Gabor has one...

516
00:46:17,910 --> 00:46:20,540
- 我们得走了 瑟奇  - 谢谢
- We gotta go, Serge.  - Thanks.

517
00:46:20,710 --> 00:46:23,460
阿克威尔 我的名字其实很易发音
Ackwell, try to say Serge. It's not so difficult.

518
00:46:23,630 --> 00:46:26,590
瑟奇 就像去污粉的牌子
"Serge" sounds like a detergent.

519
00:46:37,970 --> 00:46:39,560
阿克塞尔 你怎打算
What are you gonna do, Axel?

520
00:46:39,730 --> 00:46:42,690
没怎样 我只想听他发言
I'm not gonna do nothing. I just wanna hear the man speak.

521
00:46:43,910 --> 00:46:46,080
今时今日为“奇妙世界”做保安
To keep a park like Wonder World

522
00:46:46,510 --> 00:46:51,380
让全家老幼可安全地游玩
a safe, wholesome, family environment

523
00:46:51,550 --> 00:46:57,310
实是艰巨的工作
in difficult times like these is an enormous challenge.

524
00:46:58,590 --> 00:47:02,600
但我的朋友迪艾利成功了
But my friend Ellis DeWald has done just that.

525
00:47:06,940 --> 00:47:11,400
他还为不幸的小朋友谋福利
Couple that with Ellis' work with underprivileged kids,

526
00:47:11,570 --> 00:47:16,110
他们今日也有出席
some of whom are seated at the head table right now with Ellis...

527
00:47:29,790 --> 00:47:33,380
艾利得奖是实至名归
...and you can understand why he's our award winner.

528
00:47:33,550 --> 00:47:34,750
有请迪艾利
So let's bring him up here.

529
00:47:34,920 --> 00:47:37,660
各位来宾“奇妙世界”的保安主管
Ladies and gentlemen, the head of security at Wonder World

530
00:47:37,900 --> 00:47:41,140
私家保安年奖的得主
and Private Law Enforcement's Man of the Year award winner,

531
00:47:41,300 --> 00:47:43,760
我的好朋友 迪艾利
my dear friend, Ellis DeWald.

532
00:47:57,240 --> 00:47:59,990
- 恭喜你  - 谢谢 奥伦
- Congratulations. You deserve it.  - Thank you, Orrin.

533
00:48:01,410 --> 00:48:03,530
- 恭喜  - 谢谢 米克
- Congratulations.  - Thanks, Mike.

534
00:48:19,590 --> 00:48:22,340
阿克塞尔 我知你一定会搅事
You're not gonna do nothing, Axel. You never do nothing.

535
00:48:22,510 --> 00:48:24,470
多谢 多谢
Thank you very much.

536
00:48:24,640 --> 00:48:27,180
在“奇妙世界”工作
You know, a lot of nice things happen

537
00:48:27,350 --> 00:48:30,690
当然好事自然来
when you work at a nice place like Wonder World,

538
00:48:30,850 --> 00:48:34,520
尤其是老板好人如
especially when your bosses are people like Orrin Sanderson

539
00:48:35,120 --> 00:48:36,780
辛奥伦和戴夫叔叔
and Uncle Dave Thornton.

540
00:48:36,860 --> 00:48:40,280
如果我说得奖大美妙了
And I don't think that Uncle Dave would mind

541
00:48:40,450 --> 00:48:46,030
我想戴夫叔叔是不会介意的
if I said that this is the nicest thing yet.

542
00:48:46,200 --> 00:48:48,080
多谢大家
Thank you very much.

543
00:48:52,120 --> 00:48:55,590
阿克塞尔 别胡来 求求你
Please don't do this, Axel. Please don't do it. Don't do it.

544
00:48:55,750 --> 00:48:57,920
- 哇噢  - 别 别
- Bravo!  - Don't do it. Don't do it.

545
00:48:58,090 --> 00:49:01,880
迪艾利 好 好
Bravo, Ellis DeWald! Ellis DeWald!

546
00:49:02,840 --> 00:49:04,890
好
Bravo!

547
00:49:05,640 --> 00:49:08,220
噢 哦 迪艾利
Bravo! Bravo, Ellis!

548
00:49:08,390 --> 00:49:10,600
各位来宾 迪艾利先生
Ellis DeWald, ladies and gentlemen!

549
00:49:11,890 --> 00:49:14,230
请大家为迪艾利热烈鼓掌
Ellis DeWald! Y'all keep it going!

550
00:49:14,400 --> 00:49:16,230
大家大力拍手呀 来 过来
Keep it going for Ellis DeWald! Come on, it's Ellis!

551
00:49:16,400 --> 00:49:17,900
是迪艾利呀
Ellis DeWald, y'all!

552
00:49:19,650 --> 00:49:22,070
掌声不够 这是迪艾利
You're not clapping loud enough! This is Ellis DeWald!

553
00:49:22,240 --> 00:49:23,660
今晚盛会的贵宾 对了
It's this man's night! Yes!

554
00:49:26,280 --> 00:49:30,040
各位 我从密芝根州底特律市赶来
Ladies and gentlemen, I travelled all the way from Detroit, Michigan

555
00:49:30,200 --> 00:49:33,000
就是来恭喜他的
to be with this man tonight, to honour this man tonight.

556
00:49:33,790 --> 00:49:36,380
我叫阿克塞尔 福里 是底特律警察
My name is Axel Foley. I'm a Detroit police officer.

557
00:49:36,540 --> 00:49:39,210
对他来说 我现在站在他身边
It is a tremendous surprise for Mr. DeWald

558
00:49:39,380 --> 00:49:41,130
实在大出他意料之外
to have me standing right next to him right now.

559
00:49:41,300 --> 00:49:43,550
我感到他觉得兴奋莫名
I can feel his body tingling!

560
00:49:43,720 --> 00:49:46,010
我也想大家知道
But, ladies and gentlemen, I want you to know,

561
00:49:46,180 --> 00:49:48,050
不止是一晚
there's not a night that goes by

562
00:49:48,220 --> 00:49:51,980
我每晚都想起迪艾利
that I don't think about what I owe Ellis DeWald.

563
00:49:52,140 --> 00:49:55,440
我每一晚都想
There's not a night that passes that I don't think about

564
00:49:55,600 --> 00:49:59,980
底特律欠迪艾利太多了
what the people of Detroit owe Ellis DeWald!

565
00:50:00,150 --> 00:50:04,570
我坐在下面看见大家给他颁奖
And I'd just like to say, when I see y'all give him this award for...

566
00:50:04,740 --> 00:50:06,490
这是什么 太美丽了
What's this here? Ah, that's beautiful.

567
00:50:06,660 --> 00:50:08,830
“感谢你对社会的贡献”
"With gratitude for community service."

568
00:50:09,910 --> 00:50:12,330
我也准备对社会作出一点贡献
And I'm going to do the community a service

569
00:50:12,500 --> 00:50:15,830
我们欠迪艾利的
because I'm going to pay back Ellis DeWald

570
00:50:16,000 --> 00:50:18,960
我们连本带利归还
everything we owe him with interest!

571
00:50:20,960 --> 00:50:24,300
迪艾利 迪艾利
Ellis DeWald! Ellis DeWald!

572
00:50:27,720 --> 00:50:30,560
艾利 微笑 再没什么机会了
Go on, smile, Ellis. Get them last few smiles in.

573
00:50:31,430 --> 00:50:33,560
什么事呀 福里
What's the matter, Foley?

574
00:50:33,730 --> 00:50:36,350
你恨我杀死你的男朋友
You mad at me for shooting your boyfriend?

575
00:50:46,990 --> 00:50:48,740
找到他了 就是他 就是他
I got him! I got him! I got him!

576
00:50:54,830 --> 00:50:57,580
你和比利扰乱治安 不是吧
You and Billy disturbing the peace? No!

577
00:50:59,040 --> 00:51:01,000
快去打那个该死的电话
Do me a favour. Just make your fucking phone call

578
00:51:01,170 --> 00:51:02,170
把我们放出来 懂吗
and get us out of here, all right?

579
00:51:02,340 --> 00:51:06,340
好 我看看那儿我认识谁
Sure. Let's see, now who do I know down there? Let's see.

580
00:51:06,510 --> 00:51:08,470
喂 别烦我
Hey, don't fuck with me right now.

581
00:51:08,640 --> 00:51:11,510
你放心我会救你们出来
All right, keep your shirt on. I'll get you guys out.

582
00:51:11,680 --> 00:51:14,350
顺带一提 我找到那部货车了
Oh, incidentally, I think we found that truck you were looking for.

583
00:51:15,640 --> 00:51:18,440
- 在哪儿  - 桑塔莫妮卡码头的海滩旁
- Where?  - By the Santa Monica Pier at the beach.

584
00:51:18,600 --> 00:51:20,690
我先来接你们再过去
I'm headed there now and I'll pick you guys up on the way.

585
00:51:20,860 --> 00:51:23,860
还有 你别去冲花洒
And Axel, in the meantime, don't take any showers.

586
00:51:35,080 --> 00:51:37,910
我累死了 今匀大件事了
I'm all washed-up. Dead in the water.

587
00:51:38,270 --> 00:51:41,380
别担心 亚蓬来接我们走
Will you stop worrying? I talked to Flint, he's gonna get us out of here.

588
00:51:41,640 --> 00:51:44,130
我真的很喜欢那办公室
I really liked that office.

589
00:51:44,300 --> 00:51:48,470
- 福里 你可以走了  - 果然快手
- Foley! You're out of here.  - That was quick.

590
00:51:50,220 --> 00:51:52,100
他留下 你出来
Not him, just you.

591
00:51:57,770 --> 00:51:59,520
进来
Come in.

592
00:52:11,880 --> 00:52:13,340
谢谢
Thank you, officer.

593
00:52:17,410 --> 00:52:19,460
我查过你了 福里
I ran a check on you, Foley.

594
00:52:21,710 --> 00:52:25,480
你是个好警察 但喜欢自把自为
You're a hell of a detective, but something of a maverick.

595
00:52:28,880 --> 00:52:31,840
我知你想怎样
I know what you're doing. I know the drill.

596
00:52:32,930 --> 00:52:36,310
你去烦迪艾利 令他惊慌
You hassle DeWald, you get him to panic,

597
00:52:36,470 --> 00:52:37,810
希望他出错
make a rash move...

598
00:52:38,810 --> 00:52:43,100
福里 但我不想打草惊蛇
But God damn it, Foley, we do not want to panic this man.

599
00:52:43,270 --> 00:52:47,440
我们想他继续做他的坏事
We want him doing business as fucking usual.

600
00:52:48,240 --> 00:52:50,070
你明白吗 福里
Do you copy me, Foley?

601
00:52:56,740 --> 00:53:01,500
这是去底特律的头等机票 联邦政府送的
Ticket to Detroit, first class, courtesy of the federal government.

602
00:53:01,670 --> 00:53:04,040
还有 我的名片
Also, my card.

603
00:53:04,210 --> 00:53:09,130
你对迪艾利还有别的想法 交我处理好了
Should you have any more thoughts about DeWald, let us handle it.

604
00:53:16,720 --> 00:53:19,890
我发誓我会上飞机的
I give you my word as a gentleman I'll be on that plane.

605
00:53:28,820 --> 00:53:32,150
货车是位洛杉矶交通警察发现的
Truck was spotted by an LAPD traffic control officer in Santa Monica.

606
00:53:32,320 --> 00:53:34,950
颜色变了 但牌子和型号相同
It's a different colour, but the same make and model as yours.

607
00:53:35,740 --> 00:53:39,790
收到了 这是海滩队长
Read you. Out. Beach leader, over?

608
00:53:39,950 --> 00:53:42,540
飞虎队 等我们到步才行动
Negatory, SWAT, hold for our arrival.

609
00:53:42,710 --> 00:53:46,000
估计十一分钟后到达
ETA...11 minutes. Out.

610
00:53:47,880 --> 00:53:49,880
比利 你跟谁通话
Billy, who were you talking to?

611
00:53:50,050 --> 00:53:52,470
货车在郡的绿线之内发现
Truck was discovered inside the county green line,

612
00:53:52,630 --> 00:53:55,380
我要调配洛杉矶 桑塔莫妮卡
so I co-ordinated with the SMPD, BHPD,

613
00:53:55,550 --> 00:53:59,760
比佛利警方 还有洛杉矶郡警 公园管理局
LAPD, sheriff of Los Angeles County, Supervisor of Parks and Recreation,

614
00:53:59,930 --> 00:54:02,350
加州公路警察 地方检察官
California State Highway Patrol, district attorney's office

615
00:54:02,430 --> 00:54:04,350
和海岸巡逻队
and United States Naval Shore Patrol.

616
00:54:16,490 --> 00:54:18,870
第一队 开始行动
Beach leader to team one. Proceed.

617
00:54:44,890 --> 00:54:46,810
所有队伍准备就绪
All teams standing ready.

618
00:54:48,730 --> 00:54:50,570
上 上 上
Go! Go! Go!

619
00:54:59,910 --> 00:55:01,450
安全
Area secured.

620
00:55:10,920 --> 00:55:14,840
实验室说纤维跟货车座位一样
Lab says these are the same fibres as the truck upholstery.

621
00:55:15,010 --> 00:55:16,590
没什么用
No help there.

622
00:55:16,760 --> 00:55:19,470
还有海沙 是风吹来的吧
There's some beach sand, probably blew in after it was abandoned.

623
00:55:24,270 --> 00:55:27,100
我刚给上司骂了一顿
I just had a very unpleasant conversation with my superiors.

624
00:55:27,270 --> 00:55:29,810
- 因你被捕  - 不
- What, about being busted?  - No.

625
00:55:29,980 --> 00:55:34,610
说我的货车行动用了太多人
There was some objection to my use of manpower in Operation: Truck Siege.

626
00:55:39,570 --> 00:55:42,330
- 这是什么  - 有五十元钞票吗
- What is it?  - You got a 50-dollar bill?

627
00:55:42,490 --> 00:55:45,750
我要养家 十二年没见过了
I've got a wife and three kids. I haven't seen a 50 in 12 years.

628
00:55:46,460 --> 00:55:49,210
- 比利 你呢  - 几时还
- Billy, you got a 50-dollar bill?  - When do I get it back?

629
00:55:49,370 --> 00:55:51,210
拿来呀
Man, give me 50 dollars!

630
00:55:56,380 --> 00:55:58,130
是我全副身家了
It's all I got.

631
00:56:05,350 --> 00:56:09,060
这是五十元钞票的一角 跟比利的新钞票一样有密码
This is corner of a 50-dollar bill, like Billy's new one with the hidden barcode.

632
00:56:09,940 --> 00:56:12,360
钞票的一角 有什么特别
So the corner tore off a bill. Happens all the time.

633
00:56:12,520 --> 00:56:14,480
你看条形密码
No, the barcode's going up and down,

634
00:56:14,650 --> 00:56:16,480
该是钞票的这一角
which means it comes off this corner of the bill.

635
00:56:16,650 --> 00:56:19,240
照理应该有油墨
If it comes off this corner it should have some ink on it.

636
00:56:19,400 --> 00:56:21,860
但没有 这空白的一角太大了
This doesn't. This is too big to be blank.

637
00:56:50,480 --> 00:56:53,770
看 是大笨象
Look! It's Oki-Doki!

638
00:56:58,400 --> 00:57:00,490
你看着弟弟 别让他跑掉
Go after your brother. And don't let him get away.

639
00:57:00,650 --> 00:57:02,530
我要装胶卷
I got to load my camera.

640
00:57:02,700 --> 00:57:04,570
大笨象
Oki-Doki!

641
00:57:04,740 --> 00:57:08,490
小朋友 乖你们好吗 很高兴见到你
Hey, nice little kid. How you doing? Good to see you.

642
00:57:08,660 --> 00:57:12,120
大笨象 我爱你
I love you, Oki-Doki!

643
00:57:12,290 --> 00:57:15,000
大笨象 你扭来看看
Hey, Oki, do the Oki Shuffle.

644
00:57:19,550 --> 00:57:22,130
你做错了 这样才对
That's not right! It's like this.

645
00:57:24,180 --> 00:57:26,720
我喜欢改变扭法
Hey, listen, kid. I'm Oki-Doki and I changed the steps.

646
00:57:26,890 --> 00:57:27,890
你有什么不满
You got a problem with that?

647
00:57:29,310 --> 00:57:32,180
总之你不可以虾我
You're supposed to be nice to me no matter what I do!

648
00:57:32,680 --> 00:57:35,690
我踢你屁股
You little motherfucker, I'll kick your ass.

649
00:57:37,150 --> 00:57:38,570
是吗
Oh, yeah?

650
00:57:44,450 --> 00:57:48,080
奶奶 奶奶 大笨象推我
Grandma! Grandma! Oki-Doki pushed me!

651
00:57:54,750 --> 00:57:56,420
你拿了牌吗
You take it already.

652
00:57:57,420 --> 00:57:59,590
喂 你究竟玩不玩
Come on, Sheldon. You playing or what?

653
00:57:59,760 --> 00:58:01,920
等等 谁吃过蒜头
Who the hell ate garlic?

654
00:58:02,090 --> 00:58:05,050
午餐我要香草牛肉三文治
Yeah, when's lunch? I want a pastrami sandwich on rye.

655
00:58:05,220 --> 00:58:07,720
你们看到那个新的兔子了吗
You guys see that new Rufus Rabbit?

656
00:58:09,800 --> 00:58:11,560
- 阿克塞尔  - 什么事
- Axel?  - What?

657
00:58:11,920 --> 00:58:15,230
咖啡 你要咖啡吗
Coffee. Would you like some coffee?

658
00:58:16,220 --> 00:58:17,690
路易斯 你好吗
Hey, Louis, how's it going?

659
00:58:17,860 --> 00:58:20,230
- 好啊 好  - 替我问候艾连
- Fine, fine.  - Say hi to Irene for me.

660
00:58:20,400 --> 00:58:23,110
- 没问题  - 路易斯
- Will do.  - Louis?

661
00:58:25,450 --> 00:58:27,110
跟我来
Follow me.

662
00:58:27,280 --> 00:58:30,030
我不介意给她留个小信息
I wouldn't mind giving her a little massage.

663
00:58:30,870 --> 00:58:34,160
迪艾利上任后
When DeWald took over he stuck me down here

664
00:58:34,330 --> 00:58:36,290
调我来管这个什么监察网
on what he calls park safety watch.

665
00:58:37,080 --> 00:58:40,590
他以为调开了我 但只要我有部电脑
He thinks he took me out of the loop, but as long as I have a computer,

666
00:58:41,080 --> 00:58:45,670
我一样可以拿到大部份资料
I can still access most of what's in the mainframe.

667
00:58:45,840 --> 00:58:48,800
- 这是隧道系统  - 对
- OK, is this the tunnel system?  - Yes.

668
00:58:48,970 --> 00:58:52,770
有没有隧道是通往一个地方
Do any of these tunnels lead to a place where it's like limited access

669
00:58:52,930 --> 00:58:54,480
只有亚迪一伙才有权进入的地方
and only DeWald's boys can go there?

670
00:58:54,640 --> 00:58:58,560
没有 游乐场没禁区
No. All park accesses are unrestricted to park personnel.

671
00:58:59,520 --> 00:59:02,820
除了快活林 因装修关了门
Well, except for the Happy Forest. That's closed while it's being redone.

672
00:59:02,910 --> 00:59:04,860
快活林在哪
Show me the Happy Forest.

673
00:59:05,030 --> 00:59:09,120
就在这儿 B走廊的尽头
That would be right here at the end of Corridor B.

674
00:59:09,280 --> 00:59:15,040
就在
It's right after...

675
00:59:16,250 --> 00:59:19,750
- 快活林关了多久  - 太久了
- How long's it been closed?  - Too long.

676
00:59:22,750 --> 00:59:24,880
我是问快活林关了多长时间
I'm talking about the Happy Forest ride?

677
00:59:28,390 --> 00:59:32,760
快活林 噢 是的 大约两星期
The Forest. Yes, about a couple of weeks.

678
00:59:32,930 --> 00:59:34,010
因为不受欢迎
It wasn't a very popular ride,

679
00:59:34,090 --> 00:59:35,980
他们要搞一些新的东西
so they're trying to come up with some new ideas.

680
00:59:36,140 --> 00:59:37,390
我想他们找到了
I think they found a new idea.

681
00:59:37,560 --> 00:59:40,560
我可以拿去吗 你要从我这儿偷
Can I have this piece of thing here? Can you rip that off for me?

682
00:59:40,730 --> 00:59:42,940
- 当然  - 谢谢
- Sure.  - Thanks.

683
00:59:47,150 --> 00:59:49,110
拿去
There you go.

684
00:59:49,280 --> 00:59:54,030
你知道 这件事完结后
You know... when this thing is over...

685
00:59:59,080 --> 01:00:02,880
我们去吃晚餐好吗
Would you like to get together and have some dinner or something?

686
01:00:04,210 --> 01:00:06,670
- 好  - 帮我放入去好吗
- That would be nice.  - Can you put that in here?

687
01:00:06,840 --> 01:00:09,800
行了 可以走了
Sure. There you go.

688
01:00:09,970 --> 01:00:11,680
- 约定你了  - 定了
- We have a date.  - A date.

689
01:00:11,850 --> 01:00:14,140
- 帮我穿上这东西好吗  - 好的
- All right. Can you help me with this thing?  - Sure

690
01:00:16,680 --> 01:00:18,180
行了
There you go.

691
01:00:19,640 --> 01:00:23,080
- 记住 大笨象好记性  - 我会
- Remember, an elephant never forgets.  - All right.

692
01:00:23,600 --> 01:00:26,000
[请保持通道畅通]

693
01:00:32,740 --> 01:00:35,370
- 路易斯 你好  - 不错 很高兴见到你
- Hey, Louis, how goes it?  - Fine. Nice to see you.

694
01:00:35,480 --> 01:00:37,830
- 问候艾莲  - 再见
- Say hello to Irene.  - You bet. See you around.

695
01:02:19,850 --> 01:02:21,220
一切准时
Everything on schedule?

696
01:02:21,390 --> 01:02:23,140
我要给影像做点工夫
Yeah, I had to tweak the image a little bit.

697
01:02:23,310 --> 01:02:25,980
真麻烦 但我处理好了
The bleeding problem. But it's under control now.

698
01:02:35,030 --> 01:02:36,700
福里上楼了
Foley's upstairs.

699
01:03:13,530 --> 01:03:14,740
捉住他
Get him!

700
01:04:08,830 --> 01:04:12,330
亚迪一族请来“小城风光”
Will the DeWald family please come to Tiny Town?

701
01:04:12,500 --> 01:04:14,210
亚迪一族请来“小城风光”
The DeWald family to Tiny Town.

702
01:04:23,300 --> 01:04:26,220
快活林不开呀
But, honey, the Happy Forest is closed.

703
01:04:27,390 --> 01:04:31,150
好 五点钟大门见
OK, I'll meet you at the main gate at 5:00.

704
01:04:32,150 --> 01:04:34,980
- 喂 对不起  - 对不起
- Oh, I'm sorry.  - You're sorry?

705
01:04:49,010 --> 01:04:50,720
我是探员阿克塞尔 福里
Hi, this is Detective Axel Foley.

706
01:04:50,890 --> 01:04:52,850
我找傅探员 快
I'd like to speak with Agent Fulbright, please.

707
01:04:53,600 --> 01:04:56,230
替我接他的无线电 是紧要事
Could you patch me into his radio? It's an emergency.

708
01:04:59,920 --> 01:05:01,260
亚傅 我是福里
Fulbright, Foley.

709
01:05:04,760 --> 01:05:07,010
我找到你要的东西了
Hey, listen, I found what you're looking for.

710
01:05:07,180 --> 01:05:09,270
对 我在“奇妙世界”
Yeah, I'm at Wonder World.

711
01:05:09,890 --> 01:05:11,600
可恶 你马上来
Fuck, man! Get out here now!

712
01:05:13,420 --> 01:05:14,730
给我警察局
Get me 911.

713
01:05:37,920 --> 01:05:40,420
“奇妙世界”一带的车辆注意
Attention all cars in the vicinity of Wonder World.

714
01:05:40,590 --> 01:05:45,680
立刻出动 一〇-一九 一〇-四五 一二-二二出发了
Proceed there immediately. We have a 10-19, 10-45, and 12-22 in progress.

715
01:05:45,850 --> 01:05:48,260
我为什么不觉得惊奇呢
Why am I not surprised?

716
01:06:33,850 --> 01:06:37,310
不要开枪 我放下枪
All right, don't shoot! I'll put my gun down.

717
01:06:38,190 --> 01:06:42,650
放在地下 我没有武器 别开枪
I put my gun on the ground, and I'm unarmed. Don't shoot.

718
01:06:45,660 --> 01:06:47,110
太好了
This is great.

719
01:06:48,800 --> 01:06:52,950
你捉到他了 好 他闯入禁区
You caught him. Good. He broke into a security area.

720
01:06:54,710 --> 01:06:57,830
喂 放松点 你等坐牢吧
Relax. Save that shit for new talent night at San Quentin.

721
01:06:57,880 --> 01:07:00,840
- 我要揭发你的罪行  - 我的罪行
- I'm on to your operation.  - My operation?

722
01:07:03,000 --> 01:07:05,510
阿克塞尔 你搞什么鬼
God damn it, Axel, what the hell have you done now?

723
01:07:05,680 --> 01:07:08,760
他疯了 在游乐场开枪
He went berserk. He was firing a weapon in the park.

724
01:07:08,840 --> 01:07:11,810
那儿有成千上万 天真无邪的孩子
My God, there are hundreds of small, innocent children around.

725
01:07:11,970 --> 01:07:14,220
监狱是不颁金像奖的
You know they don't give out Oscars in prison, right?

726
01:07:14,850 --> 01:07:16,270
操你
Fuck you!

727
01:07:19,230 --> 01:07:22,150
辛先生 有人
Mr. Sanderson, there's someone here from...

728
01:07:22,540 --> 01:07:24,740
我姓傅 是特工
Fulbright, Secret Service.

729
01:07:26,750 --> 01:07:28,110
福里
Foley...

730
01:07:32,740 --> 01:07:34,660
我还以为你上飞机回底特律了
I thought I put you on a plane to Detroit.

731
01:07:35,390 --> 01:07:37,080
幸好我留下来
You're gonna be really glad that I stayed.

732
01:07:37,180 --> 01:07:39,040
你要调查的 我查到了
Like I said, I know what you're investigating.

733
01:07:39,100 --> 01:07:40,580
你要找的就在这儿
What you're looking for is right here.

734
01:07:41,170 --> 01:07:43,210
是吗 我调查什么
Yeah? And what am I investigating?

735
01:07:43,380 --> 01:07:44,920
纸 美国质量
Paper, US Mint quality.

736
01:07:45,090 --> 01:07:47,150
在底特律被劫走的银纸
That's what was in that hijacked truck back in Detroit.

737
01:07:47,230 --> 01:07:49,310
你跟踪货车回洛杉矶
You wanted to follow the truck back to LA

738
01:07:49,390 --> 01:07:51,870
就可以跟踪亚迪 找到他的印刷厂
so you could track DeWald, find out where his fucking print shop is.

739
01:07:52,030 --> 01:07:53,600
就在“奇妙世界”
Well, it's here in Wonder World.

740
01:07:53,690 --> 01:07:55,770
这个疯子说什么
What on Earth is this maniac raving about?

741
01:07:55,930 --> 01:07:59,100
- 他疯了 如假包换的疯了  - 在“奇妙世界”
- He's insane! He's proved that.  - In Wonder World?

742
01:07:59,270 --> 01:08:03,020
这地方是太空署和任天堂的结晶
This place is as high-tech as NASA and Nintendo combined.

743
01:08:03,190 --> 01:08:05,400
他们这儿有个秘密房间
They got a hidden room under this closed ride.

744
01:08:05,570 --> 01:08:07,490
他们就在里面干活 我去过了
And they do all this shit in there, and I was in there,

745
01:08:07,560 --> 01:08:09,360
所以他们追我
and that's why they were chasing me.

746
01:08:09,530 --> 01:08:11,070
我们追福里先生
My men were pursuing Mr. Foley

747
01:08:11,240 --> 01:08:14,950
因他神智不清 极可能是危险人物
because he's obviously delusionary and potentially dangerous.

748
01:08:15,120 --> 01:08:17,040
那秘密房间 究竟有没有
This hidden room, delusionary also?

749
01:08:18,560 --> 01:08:21,630
没有 我们关闭了一个游戏
No. There is a closed ride, which we use to...

750
01:08:21,790 --> 01:08:26,460
- 我还是去看看吧  - 对 我们大家去看看吧
- I'd better take a look at it.  - Yes, maybe we'd better look at it.

751
01:08:26,500 --> 01:08:30,500
[快活林]
[仅限维修人员]

752
01:08:33,980 --> 01:08:37,220
就是这部机器 印假银纸
Right here. Counterfeit bills, right out of this machine.

753
01:08:38,230 --> 01:08:41,400
- 是真的吗  - 恐怕是真的
- Is this true?  - 'Fraid so, officer.

754
01:08:42,300 --> 01:08:44,560
艾利 我们人脏并获了
'Fraid we've been caught red-handed, right, Ellis?

755
01:08:45,050 --> 01:08:46,780
大概是吧
'Fraid so.

756
01:08:48,570 --> 01:08:50,780
想看看吗 是高挡货
Would you like to see them? They're first quality.

757
01:08:51,450 --> 01:08:52,820
当奴 开机
Make a run, Donald.

758
01:09:08,720 --> 01:09:11,090
我们叫它们是“奇妙世界”钞票
We're calling them Wonder World dollars.

759
01:09:12,140 --> 01:09:14,890
可以用来入场 玩游戏和购物
Redeemable for admission, rides, souvenirs.

760
01:09:15,050 --> 01:09:17,220
是圣诞节的宣传计划
It's our big Christmas promotion.

761
01:09:17,390 --> 01:09:21,350
我们打算送给全国各地的小学
We're giving it away to elementary schools all across the country.

762
01:09:22,520 --> 01:09:24,520
原来你也是他们一伙的
You must be in on this shit, is that what it is?

763
01:09:24,690 --> 01:09:26,860
你出机器 他出纸 对吗
You supply the equipment, he supplies the paper, right?

764
01:09:27,030 --> 01:09:29,030
他们换走了印真钱的软件
They changed the visual matrix from the real money

765
01:09:29,190 --> 01:09:31,280
就在我离开后换的 当我们一离开
to this shit the minute that I left, and as soon as we leave,

766
01:09:31,450 --> 01:09:34,280
- 他们会换回来  - 这是什么纸
- they'll put it back.  - What's this paper?

767
01:09:36,830 --> 01:09:39,240
- 普通纸  - 他们换走了
- Ordinary rag.  - Then they switched it.

768
01:09:39,410 --> 01:09:42,160
我没兴趣再被人无理指责
I am tired of these accusations.

769
01:09:42,330 --> 01:09:45,790
我要警方逮捕他 告他扰乱公共次序
Officers, I want this man arrested for public endangerment.

770
01:09:47,710 --> 01:09:49,760
我可以跟你谈谈吗
Could I speak with you a moment?

771
01:09:51,420 --> 01:09:52,800
该死的 福里
God damn it, Foley!

772
01:09:52,970 --> 01:09:55,970
我花了一年时间跟迪艾利
We spent a fucking year with our noses up DeWald's ass!

773
01:09:56,140 --> 01:09:58,600
眼看就要大功告成
We are this close to locking this thing up,

774
01:09:58,770 --> 01:10:01,480
你 给你搞砸了
and you... you piss all over us!

775
01:10:01,890 --> 01:10:03,270
我们的工作付诸东流
Our case is blown.

776
01:10:04,810 --> 01:10:07,310
你回底特律去 我要告诉你
You're going back to Detroit, and I'll tell you something else,

777
01:10:07,480 --> 01:10:08,980
你若不是警察
if you weren't a cop,

778
01:10:09,150 --> 01:10:11,740
我就弄死你 叫你终身监禁
I'd have you doing dead time in Leavenworth for life.

779
01:10:13,240 --> 01:10:15,780
亚蓬 他是你的了
Detective Flint, he's yours.

780
01:10:19,120 --> 01:10:20,370
阿克塞尔 我们走吧
Let's go, Axel.

781
01:10:27,880 --> 01:10:29,840
不要让他上飞机
Make sure he doesn't get on the plane.

782
01:10:30,420 --> 01:10:32,840
该死的 阿克塞尔 我的退休金
God damn it, Axel, I got a wife, three kids, a mortgage

783
01:10:33,010 --> 01:10:34,670
不够养老婆和三个孩子
and a pension that won't cut it.

784
01:10:34,840 --> 01:10:36,720
我需要“奇妙世界”那份工
I need that job at Wonder World.

785
01:10:36,800 --> 01:10:37,850
那是我的退休大计 阿克塞尔
It's my retirement plan, Axel.

786
01:10:41,180 --> 01:10:42,470
我们被跟踪
We're being followed.

787
01:10:45,100 --> 01:10:47,480
看来是“奇妙世界”的护卫
Looks like the security guards at Wonder World.

788
01:10:47,650 --> 01:10:49,860
大概他们要看着你上飞机
They probably want to make sure you get on that plane.

789
01:10:52,320 --> 01:10:54,030
多得你 我的前途一片暗淡
Because of you, my future is now in jeopardy.

790
01:10:54,200 --> 01:10:56,200
真的是很暗淡
I mean, real fucking jeopardy.

791
01:10:56,360 --> 01:10:59,870
亚迪很不高兴 亚辛也不会怎样信任我
DeWald is pissed. Sanderson doesn't think too highly of me.

792
01:11:00,030 --> 01:11:01,660
有人打劫 停车
Hold up! Stop the car!

793
01:11:03,000 --> 01:11:04,870
- 那边的酒 停车  - 什么
- That liquor store. Stop the car!  - What?

794
01:11:06,370 --> 01:11:08,920
- 可恶 老天  - 等一下
- Oh, shit!  - Wait!

795
01:11:15,550 --> 01:11:17,070
别担心 我去捉他好了
It's all right. Don't worry. Take it easy.

796
01:11:17,130 --> 01:11:20,600
捉到他之后 我杀死他
I'll get him. I'll get him. When I do, I'll kill him!

797
01:11:30,150 --> 01:11:33,570
阿克塞尔 我接电话后便赶来 你没事吧
Axel, I left as soon as I got your call. Are you all right?

798
01:11:33,730 --> 01:11:37,320
没事 但是戴夫 我要你好好的想想
I'm fine, but Dave, listen, I want you to think back real hard

799
01:11:37,490 --> 01:11:40,910
罗渣失踪那晚有什么事 有什么忘了告诉我
to the night that Fry first disappeared. Maybe you forgot to tell me something.

800
01:11:42,030 --> 01:11:43,790
没有 为什么
No. Why would you think that?

801
01:11:43,950 --> 01:11:46,410
因为这字条本身
Because this note by itself...

802
01:11:48,210 --> 01:11:49,580
根本没什么意思
It just don't make no sense.

803
01:11:49,750 --> 01:11:52,090
“这非常重要 生死由关”
"This is important. Life and death. Roger."

804
01:11:52,250 --> 01:11:53,300
他干吗要给你这个呢
Why would he send that?

805
01:11:54,840 --> 01:11:56,720
干吗不说“救命”不说有事和你商量呢
It don't say "Help". He don't say, "I need to talk to you".

806
01:11:56,800 --> 01:11:58,880
什么都没有 就是这些
Nothing. It's just this.

807
01:12:16,860 --> 01:12:18,700
对了
Oh, shit.

808
01:12:19,910 --> 01:12:21,820
他一定发现了纸的样本
Fry must have found some sample paper.

809
01:12:21,990 --> 01:12:23,870
他知道会被杀 所以送来你处
He knew they would kill him so he sent you it.

810
01:12:24,010 --> 01:12:26,750
- 上面有条形密码  - 什么意思
- Look, there's a barcode on it.  - What does that mean?

811
01:12:27,000 --> 01:12:29,410
即是说这是政府公物
That means that this paper used to belong to Uncle Sam.

812
01:12:29,580 --> 01:12:30,580
我们有证据
Now we got some evidence.

813
01:12:30,750 --> 01:12:33,380
我们可以把亚迪和亚辛送进监狱
We can put Sanderson and DeWald's ass in jail. That's what it means.

814
01:12:33,470 --> 01:12:35,000
我看未必
I don't think so.

815
01:12:36,460 --> 01:12:40,090
我早知你会找戴夫叔叔
I figured you'd call Uncle Dave here, so we followed him.

816
01:12:42,970 --> 01:12:45,180
我以前也当过差
I actually was a real cop once,

817
01:12:45,720 --> 01:12:47,560
我了解你们怎样思想
so I know how you assholes think,

818
01:12:47,840 --> 01:12:50,980
是缓慢地
which is to say, slowly.

819
01:12:52,060 --> 01:12:53,810
非常缓慢地
Very slowly.

820
01:12:56,760 --> 01:12:58,320
你是一直把那件证物
So you were carrying around the evidence

821
01:12:58,490 --> 01:13:02,280
放在口袋里的吧 福尔摩斯
in your pocket the whole time, huh, Sherlock?

822
01:13:02,450 --> 01:13:05,520
我给你说故事的真正结局
Well, here's how the real ending of the story goes.

823
01:13:05,690 --> 01:13:07,680
看你喜不喜欢
Let's see if you like it.

824
01:13:07,930 --> 01:13:10,120
我们知道你跑了
We, at Wonder World, heard you were on the loose.

825
01:13:10,200 --> 01:13:11,830
也明白你不妥“奇妙世界”
You had a grudge against the park.

826
01:13:12,960 --> 01:13:17,000
更恐怕你会伤害戴夫叔叔
I feared you might try to harm our beloved Uncle Dave,

827
01:13:17,290 --> 01:13:21,930
于是我尽快赶来 我想阻止你
so I raced over here as fast as I could to try and stop you,

828
01:13:22,990 --> 01:13:26,510
但 可惜 一切都太迟了
but alas, it was too late.

829
01:13:31,940 --> 01:13:34,190
把他放进车子里去
Get him in the car. All the way in the car.

830
01:13:43,530 --> 01:13:46,200
拿着 拿着
Take it. Take it.

831
01:13:47,160 --> 01:13:49,540
你担心有指模吗 福里
What's the matter, you worried about fingerprints, Foley?

832
01:13:49,700 --> 01:13:52,370
不用了 这是你的枪 看到吗
Forget it. Take a look at the gun. It's yours.

833
01:13:54,540 --> 01:13:56,460
把你的枪给我
Give me your weapon.

834
01:14:04,950 --> 01:14:06,490
拾起枪 仍到街上去
Pick up that gun and throw it in the street!

835
01:14:10,290 --> 01:14:11,670
把门关上 然后过去
Close the door and get over there!

836
01:14:45,870 --> 01:14:48,250
戴夫叔叔 振作点 可恶
Hold on, Uncle Dave. Damn it!

837
01:14:53,790 --> 01:14:55,790
喂 别死呀
Don't you die on me, man.

838
01:15:07,640 --> 01:15:11,730
有人受枪伤 快来呀
Hey! I got an emergency out here. It's a gut shot. Hey, come on!

839
01:15:16,020 --> 01:15:17,980
是戴夫叔叔呀
Hey, that was Uncle Dave.

840
01:15:25,570 --> 01:15:27,950
- 血压怎样  - 九十的四十 在跌
- What's his pressure?  - Ninety over 40 and dropping.

841
01:15:28,120 --> 01:15:30,620
要升高他的血压 来吧
All right, I got to get his pressure up. Let's go, guys.

842
01:15:30,790 --> 01:15:32,330
四个单位
Four units.

843
01:15:32,500 --> 01:15:35,710
我需要氧气 来吧 我数三声 一 二 三
I need oxygen. Let's go. On three. One, two, three.

844
01:15:35,880 --> 01:15:38,630
在他的动脉上插管
Get an arterial line in him. Any medical history?

845
01:15:38,800 --> 01:15:41,710
我也受过枪伤 没什么大不了
I've been shot before, but it's no big deal.

846
01:15:41,820 --> 01:15:44,090
- 咖啡机在哪  - 前面就是
- Hey, man, where's the coffee machine?  - Down the hall.

847
01:15:44,260 --> 01:15:45,550
谢谢
Thanks.

848
01:15:45,720 --> 01:15:49,390
注意 全市戒备 有疑犯在福顿区开枪
Attention, this is an all-city alert for a suspect in the Thornton shooting.

849
01:15:49,560 --> 01:15:52,060
疑犯是黑人 约三十岁
Suspect is an African-American male in his 30s...

850
01:16:08,120 --> 01:16:09,910
你有听说有个黑人枪伤了戴夫叔叔
You hear some black guy shot Uncle Dave?

851
01:16:10,080 --> 01:16:12,870
- 我没听过  - 我们走吧
- No.  - Come on, let's get out of here.

852
01:16:38,170 --> 01:16:40,770
你听见了吗 戴夫叔叔受了枪伤
Did you hear? Somebody shot Dave Thornton.

853
01:16:40,940 --> 01:16:44,280
- 有人向戴夫叔叔开枪  - 有电视吗
- Somebody shot Uncle Dave?  - Is there a TV here?

854
01:16:44,450 --> 01:16:46,280
当然有
Yes, of course.

855
01:16:49,240 --> 01:16:52,450
当局相信福里袭击戴夫叔叔
Authorities believe that Foley may have decided to attack Uncle Dave

856
01:16:52,620 --> 01:16:55,660
是基于私人理由而报复
in retaliation for some personal rejection.

857
01:16:55,830 --> 01:16:57,620
受人爱戴的戴夫叔叔
The much-loved Uncle Dave Thornton

858
01:16:57,790 --> 01:17:00,500
目前正在医院接受急救
is undergoing emergency surgery at this moment.

859
01:17:00,670 --> 01:17:04,090
根据医院消息 情况并不乐观
According to hospital sources, the prognosis is bleak.

860
01:17:04,260 --> 01:17:07,010
那癫人良心怎过得去
How does a psycho like that live with himself?

861
01:17:08,140 --> 01:17:10,050
快走 你见过字条
Janice, Axel. Get out of the park right now.

862
01:17:10,220 --> 01:17:12,010
他们会杀了所有知道字条的人
They're going to kill whoever knows about Roger Fry's note.

863
01:17:12,180 --> 01:17:13,720
字条我会交给联邦当局
I got the note and I'm taking it to the feds.

864
01:17:13,890 --> 01:17:17,080
你必需去找亚珍 她现在不方便听电话
You must be looking for Janice. She can't come to the phone right now.

865
01:17:17,240 --> 01:17:18,350
我可以留口讯吗
Can I take a message?

866
01:17:18,520 --> 01:17:21,110
- 你敢动她  - 那会是你的错
- If you do anything to her...  - It'll be your fault.

867
01:17:21,820 --> 01:17:24,190
你半小时内到“奇妙世界”
I want you at Wonder World within the hour.

868
01:17:24,360 --> 01:17:26,650
单独来 到主入口 不许带武器
Come to the main gate alone and unarmed.

869
01:17:26,820 --> 01:17:30,160
- 记得带那张银纸  - 然后你就放我们走
- And bring the piece of mint paper.  - Oh, then you let us both go?

870
01:17:30,590 --> 01:17:31,990
你半小时内不出现
You don't show up here in a half-hour,

871
01:17:32,160 --> 01:17:36,290
或是带了警察和武器 我就杀你朋友
alone and unarmed, and with no cops, I kill your friend.

872
01:17:36,460 --> 01:17:39,540
我杀过你的朋友 记得吗 福里
And it wouldn't be the first time, would it, Foley?

873
01:17:45,130 --> 01:17:47,010
有位观众拍下了
I've just been informed that we have an amateur video

874
01:17:47,170 --> 01:17:48,840
今天下午的事件
of the incident this afternoon

875
01:17:49,010 --> 01:17:52,050
是关于枪击戴夫叔叔的疑犯阿克塞尔 福里
involving Uncle Dave's suspected assassin, Axel Foley.

876
01:17:54,220 --> 01:17:58,180
别开枪 我现在就放下枪
All right, don't shoot. I'm putting my gun down.

877
01:17:58,680 --> 01:18:02,810
我趴下了 我没有武器 别开枪
I'm putting it on the ground. I'm not armed. Don't shoot.

878
01:18:04,730 --> 01:18:08,820
那是一位游客在午间拍下的
That was an amateur video shot earlier today by a tourist.

879
01:18:21,880 --> 01:18:24,380
小心照顾我的汽车
Would you please take special care of my car?

880
01:18:24,550 --> 01:18:26,000
- 当然  - 谢谢
- Yes, sir.  - Thank you.

881
01:18:43,860 --> 01:18:46,190
- 可恶  - 阿克威尔
- Shit!  - Ackwell...

882
01:18:46,360 --> 01:18:48,610
- 又是你  - 瑟奇 我需要武器
- Again!  - Serge, I need a weapon.

883
01:18:48,940 --> 01:18:51,610
我没有呀 都送回精品店了
I don't have any weapon. I take all back to the boutique.

884
01:18:51,780 --> 01:18:54,740
- 这件呢  - 这是陈列品
- What about this?  - This is the floor model.

885
01:18:54,910 --> 01:18:58,620
人们向他喷气 咳嗽 很脏的嘛
People been breathing on it, coughing on it, touching it...

886
01:18:58,790 --> 01:19:01,710
瑟奇 我需要一件武器
Serge, I need a weapon now.

887
01:19:02,750 --> 01:19:06,920
当尼 阿克威尔时间
Donny. Donny, Ackwell in some kind of rush, OK?

888
01:19:07,090 --> 01:19:09,460
拿“歼灭者”去吧
So take the Annihilator

889
01:19:09,630 --> 01:19:12,340
用古龙水给他清洁一下
and wash it off with some swab of cologne or something

890
01:19:12,510 --> 01:19:15,760
记得用盒装好 要好好的
and take the case and make sure it's nice and pretty, OK?

891
01:19:17,310 --> 01:19:18,520
是哥伦皮做的
It's Corinthian leather.

892
01:19:19,850 --> 01:19:22,100
比利 罗斯伍德警官 阿克塞尔 福里的电话
Detective Billy Rosewood. Axel Foley calling.

893
01:19:23,100 --> 01:19:26,440
阿克塞尔 听着 我是你的朋友吗 我是你的朋友
Axel, listen. Am I your friend? I am your friend.

894
01:19:26,610 --> 01:19:29,070
我相信你能解释清楚 或许你不能
I'm sure you can explain everything, or maybe you can't explain anything,

895
01:19:29,240 --> 01:19:30,570
但首先你得去自首
but you've got to turn yourself in, man!

896
01:19:30,740 --> 01:19:35,280
- 我去“奇妙世界”  - 不 等我 阿克塞尔
- I'm going to Wonder World.  - No! Wait for me! Axel!

897
01:20:11,360 --> 01:20:13,320
举高双手 搜身
Put your arms out and hold for a pat-down.

898
01:20:21,200 --> 01:20:22,700
福里到了 先生
Foley just arrived, sir.

899
01:20:23,710 --> 01:20:26,000
带他来控制室 福里到了
Take him to control. We have Foley.

900
01:20:27,540 --> 01:20:28,960
进来
Come on.

901
01:20:29,130 --> 01:20:32,380
- 你想印多少  - 全部
- How much do you want run?  - All of it.

902
01:20:33,380 --> 01:20:35,590
- 阿克塞尔  - 你没事吧
- Axel!  - Are you OK?

903
01:20:35,760 --> 01:20:37,510
拿那张纸来
Let's have it. The mint paper.

904
01:20:37,870 --> 01:20:40,050
嘿 前门那里有部保时捷
Hey, there's a Porsche parked out by the front gate.

905
01:20:40,220 --> 01:20:41,810
车里有电话
There's a phone inside.

906
01:20:42,160 --> 01:20:44,230
她打电话来 我就给你银制
When she calls back here, I'll give you the mint paper.

907
01:20:44,570 --> 01:20:47,850
- 没商量  - 那谈判破裂了
- I don't think so.  - Then we got a stalemate.

908
01:20:48,220 --> 01:20:49,900
未致奥伦
Not quite. Orrin...

909
01:20:50,750 --> 01:20:54,030
只要杀死你们 那纸就是废纸
We kill you both. The paper don't mean jack shit.

910
01:20:54,190 --> 01:20:56,030
你怎知我没有把纸寄给政府
How you know I didn't mail the paper to the Secret Service

911
01:20:56,200 --> 01:20:57,530
还附带一个小字条
with a little note attached to it?

912
01:20:57,850 --> 01:21:01,240
- 他吹牛  - 是吗 试试看
- He's bluffing.  - You think so? Call me.

913
01:21:01,410 --> 01:21:05,660
我知道警察怎么想的 纸在车里 对吗
Orrin, I know how cops think. The note is in the car, right?

914
01:21:09,590 --> 01:21:11,040
拿车匙来 福里
The keys, Foley.

915
01:21:13,840 --> 01:21:16,010
把该死的车匙拿来
Give me the fucking keys.

916
01:21:30,360 --> 01:21:33,780
- 放下枪  - 再来一次
- Drop that fucking gun!  - Again?

917
01:21:33,940 --> 01:21:34,980
放下枪
Drop it!

918
01:21:38,570 --> 01:21:40,280
阿克塞尔 你在这儿搞什么鬼
Axel, what the hell are you doing here?

919
01:22:27,580 --> 01:22:31,370
- 发生什么事  - 是冷却保安系统
- What the hell happened?  - It's the coolant safety system.

920
01:22:31,540 --> 01:22:34,000
火警是保护主脑的
Protects the mainframe in case of fire.

921
01:22:34,170 --> 01:22:37,760
- 怎么打开  - 在里面没法开
- How do we get it open?  - We can't. Not from this side.

922
01:23:33,020 --> 01:23:36,440
他想用外面的线 去处理呀
He's trying to use an outside line. Do something!

923
01:23:37,730 --> 01:23:38,780
喂 警察局
Hello, police?

924
01:23:41,070 --> 01:23:42,280
可恶
Shit!

925
01:23:42,450 --> 01:23:44,240
福里走了 他在游乐场
Foley's loose in the park!

926
01:23:44,410 --> 01:23:48,080
重复 福里在游乐场 去抓他
I repeat... Foley's loose in the park! Get him!

927
01:23:52,370 --> 01:23:53,620
迪先生
Mr. DeWald!

928
01:23:54,880 --> 01:23:57,210
我们得想办法 叫救兵呀
We gotta do something. Call for help!

929
01:23:57,380 --> 01:24:00,630
这儿没电话 只有电脑的传真线
There's no phone in here, just the modem line for the computers.

930
01:24:02,220 --> 01:24:04,680
得了 让电脑拨电话
I got it! Just let the computer dial...

931
01:24:04,840 --> 01:24:07,760
但对方电话只会不停响
The phone would just ring and ring on the other end, and that's it.

932
01:24:07,930 --> 01:24:09,560
有什么用
What good would that be?

933
01:24:11,230 --> 01:24:14,730
非常有用 拨亚蓬的传呼机
A lot of good. We can call Flint's pager.

934
01:24:25,240 --> 01:24:30,830
福里在“故乡广场” 重复 福里在“故乡广场”
Foley is in Hometown Square. Repeat, Foley is in Hometown Square.

935
01:26:12,800 --> 01:26:14,970
福里就要去“外星人袭地球”
Foley is heading for Alien Attack.

936
01:26:31,240 --> 01:26:33,740
注意 注意 这是红色警报
Attention. Attention. This is a red alert.

937
01:26:33,910 --> 01:26:36,410
外星人太空船正侵袭本市
Alien spacecraft are invading the city.

938
01:26:36,580 --> 01:26:40,290
入侵开始 登上地铁
Board the subway trains for immediate evacuation.

939
01:27:38,100 --> 01:27:39,680
他上那些梯级去了
He ran up those stairs!

940
01:27:57,660 --> 01:27:59,450
跟他讲我马上就要
Tell him I need that right away!

941
01:28:00,790 --> 01:28:03,460
可恶 别再来了 对不起
Damn it. Not again. Excuse me.

942
01:28:07,130 --> 01:28:08,790
总部 我是亚蓬
Dispatch, this is Flint.

943
01:28:08,960 --> 01:28:12,470
替我查查五五五-四〇八五
Trace that number that keeps calling me. 555-4085.

944
01:28:12,630 --> 01:28:16,180
号码来自“奇妙世界”的电脑线路
Trace just came in. It's a computer line at the Wonder World theme park.

945
01:28:16,970 --> 01:28:19,810
“奇妙世界”跟他们讲 他们的电脑疯了
Wonder World? Call 'em back. Tell them their computer's on the blink.

946
01:28:19,970 --> 01:28:22,730
我们试过了 但所有的语音线路都坏了
We tried that, but all the voice lines at Wonder World seem to be down.

947
01:28:22,890 --> 01:28:25,310
一定跟戴夫叔叔枪伤有关
Must have something to do with that Uncle Dave shooting.

948
01:28:26,650 --> 01:28:30,780
- 他受了枪伤  - 疑凶叫阿克塞尔 福里
- Jesus! Somebody shot Uncle Dave?  - Some fool named Axel Foley.

949
01:28:39,160 --> 01:28:41,790
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey... Hey, hey, hey, hey.

950
01:28:59,890 --> 01:29:01,470
他在什么鬼地方
Where the fuck is he?

951
01:30:53,540 --> 01:30:56,630
去报警 我去找阿克塞尔
Get to a phone and call the police. I'll try and find Axel.

952
01:30:56,800 --> 01:30:58,010
好的
All right!

953
01:31:10,800 --> 01:31:13,000
吻我屁股

954
01:31:16,650 --> 01:31:18,150
原来是你 福里
There you are. Foley's...

955
01:32:02,650 --> 01:32:06,240
我是野人 比尔 罗斯伍德 本镇的警长
Name's Wild Bill Rosewood. I'm the sheriff of this town.

956
01:32:26,970 --> 01:32:29,390
这里搞什么鬼
What the hell happened here?

957
01:32:40,320 --> 01:32:41,400
妈的
Shit!

958
01:32:43,990 --> 01:32:45,070
该死
Damn it!

959
01:32:58,170 --> 01:33:00,460
快关掉那鬼东西
Turn that fucking song off!

960
01:34:24,590 --> 01:34:27,340
福里 你没事吧
Foley? You all right?

961
01:34:28,260 --> 01:34:32,590
- 亚傅  - 你伤得重吗
- Hello, Fulbright.  - You hurt bad?

962
01:34:35,850 --> 01:34:39,350
福里 我该向你道歉
Look, Foley, I guess I owe you an apology.

963
01:34:40,100 --> 01:34:41,270
你说得对
You were right.

964
01:34:41,440 --> 01:34:45,110
我把亚辛锁在车上了 他是同党 对吗
I got Sanderson handcuffed in the car. He was in on it, right?

965
01:34:46,530 --> 01:34:49,610
我也发现了另一个同党
I found out about another partner that was in on it.

966
01:34:52,530 --> 01:34:53,820
福里 永别了
So long, Foley.

967
01:34:55,450 --> 01:34:56,450
阿克塞尔
Axel!

968
01:35:14,220 --> 01:35:15,430
你没事吧
You OK?

969
01:35:17,890 --> 01:35:20,390
搞什么鬼
Any chance you can explain any of this to me?

970
01:35:22,690 --> 01:35:24,610
干嘛有人向我开枪
Like why the fuck am I shot?

971
01:35:31,280 --> 01:35:33,360
你们没事吧
You guys OK?

972
01:35:37,700 --> 01:35:41,410
- 没事 你呢  - 我很好
- Are you OK?  - I'm fine.

973
01:35:45,750 --> 01:35:48,380
游乐场不知几时开门
I wonder what time the park opens.

974
01:36:01,730 --> 01:36:04,560
他需要接受治疗
He needs medical attention.

975
01:36:09,400 --> 01:36:11,240
- 痛吗  - 别碰呀
- Does this hurt?  - Don't touch it.

976
01:36:19,410 --> 01:36:21,120
我实在非常 非常开心
I am so very, very happy

977
01:36:21,290 --> 01:36:26,750
我要给大家介绍“奇妙世界”的一个新角色
to introduce to you our new character in Wonder World,

978
01:36:26,920 --> 01:36:32,130
没有他 我今日不会在这里
named after a man who's most responsible for my being here today.

979
01:36:36,180 --> 01:36:38,260
“阿克塞尔 狐狸”
Axel Fox!

980
01:37:02,410 --> 01:37:06,330
阿克塞尔 你玩过“爱情隧道”没有
Hey, I don't think you've seen the Tunnel of Love ride, have you, Axel?

981
01:37:08,380 --> 01:37:12,300
我不知道“奇妙世界”有“爱情隧道”
I didn't know y'all had a Tunnel of Love ride at Wonder World.

982
01:37:12,460 --> 01:37:14,340
很快就有了
There will be shortly.

