1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 修正制作
最新最快的HR-HDTV请登陆 www.YYeTs.com

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
后期｜鱼子酱

3
00:00:15,000 --> 00:00:20,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

4
00:01:15,600 --> 00:01:16,960
在三十年代初
ln the early '30s,

5
00:01:16,960 --> 00:01:21,080
阿道夫希特勒和他的核心集团着迷于超自然的神秘学
Adolf Hitler and his inner circle became obsessed with the occult,

6
00:01:21,080 --> 00:01:23,050
认为魔法对于他们统治世界
believing that the black arts were key

7
00:01:23,050 --> 00:01:25,240
的计划极其重要
to their plan for world domination.

8
00:01:25,320 --> 00:01:26,910
纳粹间谍游走于全世界
Nazi agents traveled the globe

9
00:01:26,990 --> 00:01:30,650
寻找被称为魔文石的古代日耳曼民族的圣物
in search of ancient Nordic relics known as rune stones.

10
00:01:30,720 --> 00:01:33,720
他们相信如果他们驾驭了这些石头的力量
They believed if they harnessed the power of these stones,

11
00:01:33,790 --> 00:01:36,160
那么没什么可以阻止他们成为主宰民族的步伐
nothing could stop the march of the Master Race.

12
00:01:37,460 --> 00:01:39,900
这些石头上的符号据说是
The symbols inscribed in these stones were said to

13
00:01:39,900 --> 00:01:40,920
用来描述通往…
describe the path...

14
00:01:43,970 --> 00:01:46,060
不朽的道路
to immortality.

15
00:02:43,200 --> 00:02:46,500
复仇之溪

16
00:02:47,170 --> 00:02:49,360
“亲爱的沃尔纳先生
"Dear Mr. Wollner,

17
00:02:49,440 --> 00:02:53,500
我代表德国遗产北美研究
l write you on behalf of a society of scholars

18
00:02:53,570 --> 00:02:57,910
社团的学者们向你写信
researching Germany's heritage throughout North America.

19
00:02:59,650 --> 00:03:03,240
我们谨慎地选择了你们家庭 沃尔纳先生
We chose your family with care, Mr. Wollner.

20
00:03:05,290 --> 00:03:10,420
我们邀请你考虑招待将在你们的地区进行工作
We ask you to consider hosting Herr Richard Wirth

21
00:03:10,490 --> 00:03:13,020
的理查德·沃思先生
as he conducts work in your region.

22
00:03:13,090 --> 00:03:15,560
他只要求有一间私人的房间
He requires only a private room

23
00:03:15,630 --> 00:03:18,720
以及简朴的住宿条件
and modest accommodations within your home.

24
00:03:18,800 --> 00:03:23,030
每个月我们将会提供一笔酬金酬谢你的辛劳
A gratuity will be provided each month for your pains.

25
00:03:23,100 --> 00:03:26,540
现随信附上酬金的预付款
Find enclosed an advance of this amount.

26
00:03:27,200 --> 00:03:29,200
一百五十美元”
$150."

27
00:03:29,200 --> 00:03:33,180
我觉得我们应该讨论一下
l think we should discuss.

28
00:03:35,980 --> 00:03:38,640
一百五十美元 妈妈
$150, Mama.

29
00:04:25,500 --> 00:04:27,160
莉泽！
Liese

30
00:04:54,990 --> 00:04:56,390
谁在那？
Who's there?

31
00:05:19,920 --> 00:05:23,050
莉泽 我们现在收收桌子吧
Liese, we will clear the table now.

32
00:05:38,870 --> 00:05:40,460
安娜·莉泽
Annaliese

33
00:05:40,540 --> 00:05:42,170
是的
Yes.

34
00:05:42,240 --> 00:05:43,770
她必须去学校上学
She goes to school where she must.

35
00:05:43,840 --> 00:05:45,610
我们所有人都在练习
All of us practice.

36
00:05:45,680 --> 00:05:47,650
为了去城里做买卖
And for in town when we go to sell.

37
00:05:49,650 --> 00:05:51,120
当然
Naturally.

38
00:05:51,180 --> 00:05:52,950
原谅我
Forgive me.

39
00:05:53,020 --> 00:05:54,650
我现在过时了
l'm old-fashioned now.

40
00:05:54,720 --> 00:05:56,920
无论如何 我不必劳神
At any rate, l needn't bother.

41
00:05:56,990 --> 00:05:59,480
大概几年内全世界都将会使用德语
The whole world will speak German in a matter of years.

42
00:05:59,560 --> 00:06:03,220
我们听说你是一个历史学家
We were told you were a historian.

43
00:06:03,300 --> 00:06:04,850
是的
Yes.

44
00:06:06,530 --> 00:06:08,120
你们知道…
Did you know...

45
00:06:08,200 --> 00:06:09,900
是我们的维京老祖宗
our Viking ancestors

46
00:06:09,970 --> 00:06:11,400
发现了这块大陆吗
discovered this land?

47
00:06:12,840 --> 00:06:14,640
理所当然 哥伦布是一个骗子
Columbus was, of course, a fraud.

48
00:06:16,010 --> 00:06:18,840
是芬兰人发现了这片河流地域
Finlandic parties scouted up these rivers

49
00:06:18,910 --> 00:06:21,070
早在西班牙人到达的三百年前
300 years before the Spanish arrived.

50
00:06:21,150 --> 00:06:22,770
他们被印第安人驱逐了
They were repelled by lndians,

51
00:06:22,850 --> 00:06:24,820
但是他们留下了魔文石
but they left their rune stones behind.

52
00:06:26,320 --> 00:06:30,150
就像你们修建这农场的时候挖掘出的古老石头
Like the ancient stone you dug up when you built this farm.

53
00:06:31,890 --> 00:06:33,320
你怎么知道那个
How did you know that?

54
00:06:36,460 --> 00:06:38,260
这石头变成什么样呢
What became of the stone?

55
00:06:38,330 --> 00:06:40,930
我们建谷仓的时候用它来做地基了
We used it in the foundation when we built the barn.

56
00:06:41,000 --> 00:06:42,370
它在地窖地下
lt's in the root cellar.

57
00:06:42,440 --> 00:06:44,730
我们把它的正面朝内了 你仍然可以看到它
We faced it inward. You can still see it.

58
00:06:46,710 --> 00:06:48,300
你真有远见
How forward-thinking of you.

59
00:06:49,810 --> 00:06:52,400
我们本应该多问一些问题
We should have asked more questions.

60
00:06:52,480 --> 00:06:54,380
我们可以早上去问
We can ask in the morning.

61
00:06:56,080 --> 00:06:57,980
我是说 几星期前
l mean, weeks ago.

62
00:07:57,640 --> 00:07:59,580
给我看看石头
Show me the stone.

63
00:08:22,000 --> 00:08:23,830
他们在这
They were here.

64
00:08:25,140 --> 00:08:26,900
北欧之神
The Nordic gods.

65
00:08:26,970 --> 00:08:29,070
我们的祖先
Our ancestors.

66
00:08:30,780 --> 00:08:32,330
不要哭
Don't cry.

67
00:08:32,410 --> 00:08:33,710
把她拿到这儿来给我
Bring her here to me.

68
00:08:34,950 --> 00:08:37,140
他们说你在上学
They tell me you're in school.

69
00:08:37,220 --> 00:08:39,480
那么你喜欢学习
You like to study, then.

70
00:08:39,550 --> 00:08:41,040
找寻东西
Find things.

71
00:08:41,120 --> 00:08:42,140
挑战你的思想
Challenge your mind.

72
00:08:42,220 --> 00:08:44,350
学习这个
Study this.

73
00:09:19,390 --> 00:09:21,450
现在看你的小鸟
Look at your birdie now.

74
00:09:24,930 --> 00:09:27,400
看到了吗 她在向你眨眼
See? She's winking at you.

75
00:09:29,200 --> 00:09:31,360
如果勤加练习
And with practice,

76
00:09:31,440 --> 00:09:34,240
我会让她活得更久
l will be able to make her live even longer.

77
00:09:37,140 --> 00:09:39,510
这就是我现在力所能及的了
That's all l can do for now.

78
00:09:41,580 --> 00:09:43,740
但是我有自己的计划
But l have my books.

79
00:09:43,820 --> 00:09:45,810
我有时间
l have time.

80
00:09:45,890 --> 00:09:47,880
我有这石头
l have this stone.

81
00:09:56,000 --> 00:09:59,830
那些掌控于鲜血之上的人
Those who came before rule the blood.

82
00:10:00,850 --> 00:10:04,410
一旦你掌控着鲜血 死亡就不再意味着是结束
And when you rule the blood, death is no longer the end.

83
00:10:06,520 --> 00:10:08,050
你爱你的家人 对吗
You love your family, yes?

84
00:10:09,890 --> 00:10:12,380
你得为他们做点什么
You'd do anything for them.

85
00:10:12,460 --> 00:10:15,300
不要让他们像你的小鸟一样死去 你会吗
Don't want them to end up like your little birdie, do you?

86
00:10:20,870 --> 00:10:22,930
你会成为一个好的小帮手
You'll be a good little helper.

87
00:10:26,640 --> 00:10:30,770
你的身体每次只会受一点点伤
Your part will hurt only a little bit each time.

88
00:10:41,960 --> 00:10:44,260
呼吸道畅通 输点氧气进去
Airways are clear. Get that oxygen over here.

89
00:10:44,330 --> 00:10:46,800
- 你能听见我吗  - 让他们所有人都后退
- Can you hear me?  - Get them to all stand back!

90
00:10:46,860 --> 00:10:47,760
先生 你能听见我吗
Sir, can you hear me?

91
00:10:47,830 --> 00:10:49,300
看着我 先生
Look at me, sir.

92
00:10:49,370 --> 00:10:50,860
- 把枪放下  - 能别这么做吗 女士
- Put the gun down.  - How about not do that, ma'am?

93
00:10:50,930 --> 00:10:52,770
先生 你能听见我吗
Sir, can you hear me?

94
00:10:52,840 --> 00:10:54,030
你能听见我吗 先生？
Can you hear me, sir?

95
00:10:54,100 --> 00:10:56,100
不要睡觉 现在看着我 先生
Don't go to sleep. Watch me now, sir.

96
00:10:57,270 --> 00:10:58,210
- 冷静下来  - 不要那样做 女士
- Calm down.  - Don't do that, ma'am.

97
00:10:58,270 --> 00:10:59,330
把你的枪放到地上
Put your gun on the ground.

98
00:10:59,410 --> 00:11:01,170
把你的枪放到地上 女士
Put your gun on the ground, ma'am.

99
00:11:01,240 --> 00:11:02,230
冠状动脉
Coronary!

100
00:11:02,310 --> 00:11:04,110
这儿 看着我 女士
Here, look at me, ma'am.

101
00:11:04,180 --> 00:11:05,910
把你的枪放到地上
Put your gun on the ground.

102
00:11:05,980 --> 00:11:07,920
- 拉里 打开敷布  - 退后
- Larry, open that compress.  - Stand back.

103
00:11:09,020 --> 00:11:10,210
拉里 来吧 打开它
Larry! Come on, get it open!

104
00:11:11,690 --> 00:11:12,880
拉里 压住那里
Larry, put pressure on that.

105
00:11:14,490 --> 00:11:16,580
把你的枪放到地上
Put your gun on the ground!

106
00:11:16,660 --> 00:11:18,750
先生 看着我
Sir, look at me.

107
00:11:18,830 --> 00:11:20,060
他快不行了
We're losing him.

108
00:11:21,300 --> 00:11:22,360
听我说 女士
Look here, ma'am.

109
00:11:22,430 --> 00:11:23,830
没人会伤害你 看着我
Nobody will hurt you. Look at me.

110
00:11:23,900 --> 00:11:24,830
拉里 他不行了
Larry, we lost him.

111
00:11:24,900 --> 00:11:26,230
把枪放下
Just put the gun down.

112
00:11:26,300 --> 00:11:27,790
把枪放下
Put it down.

113
00:11:28,910 --> 00:11:31,470
看着我 女士
Look at me, ma'am.

114
00:11:31,540 --> 00:11:33,740
他们在里面制作甲安菲他明[一种兴奋剂] 趴下
They're cooking meth in here! Get down!

115
00:11:38,420 --> 00:11:39,400
大家都还好吧
ls everyone okay?

116
00:12:26,730 --> 00:12:28,130
水槽关掉了吗
ls that tank turned off?

117
00:12:29,670 --> 00:12:31,160
我知道你是谁
l know who you are.

118
00:12:32,300 --> 00:12:33,600
有人在外面院子里
Somebody out in the yard?

119
00:12:33,670 --> 00:12:35,700
我听到有人声
l heard somebody.

120
00:12:35,770 --> 00:12:37,400
你把孩子们带来了吗
You bring the boys over?

121
00:12:37,470 --> 00:12:39,440
孩子们在家里和芭芭拉待在一起
The boys are at home with Barb.

122
00:12:39,510 --> 00:12:40,440
你在干什么
What are you doing?

123
00:12:40,510 --> 00:12:41,880
只是试着帮忙 爸爸
Just trying to help, Dad.

124
00:12:41,950 --> 00:12:43,470
如果你想帮忙 清理一下院子
lf you want to help, rake the yard.

125
00:12:43,550 --> 00:12:44,540
那里看起来真糟糕
lt looks like shit.

126
00:12:44,610 --> 00:12:46,980
刚值完十五小时的班 爸爸
Just finished a 15-hour shift, Dad.

127
00:12:47,050 --> 00:12:48,750
不要着急
Don't worry.

128
00:12:48,820 --> 00:12:50,840
你的兄弟会去做的 他跟你在一起吗
Your brother will do it. ls he with you?

129
00:12:50,920 --> 00:12:53,580
爸爸 他已经走了两年了
Dad? He's been gone two years.

130
00:12:53,660 --> 00:12:55,520
他从伊拉克回来了 我看见他了
He's back from lraq. l saw him.

131
00:12:58,160 --> 00:12:59,590
这不是很容易的
lt ain't easy.

132
00:12:59,660 --> 00:13:01,190
我知道 爸爸
l know, Dad.

133
00:13:02,670 --> 00:13:05,460
你知道什么 你不在那儿
What do you know? You weren't there.

134
00:13:05,540 --> 00:13:07,660
你的兄弟不得不去那并杀了那些狗娘养的
Your brother had to go and kill the sons of bitches.

135
00:13:07,740 --> 00:13:09,800
你没有在伊拉克 你在吗
You weren't in lraq, were you?

136
00:13:09,870 --> 00:13:11,360
他作为英雄回家了
He comes home a hero.

137
00:13:11,440 --> 00:13:13,470
你带他到唐恩溪钓鱼
You take him fishing up near Town Creek,

138
00:13:13,540 --> 00:13:15,440
他的家人再也没有看到他了
his family never sees him again.

139
00:13:15,510 --> 00:13:17,570
你为什么不救你的兄弟
Why didn't you save your brother?

140
00:13:21,680 --> 00:13:23,350
- 我要给你做晚餐  - 为什么你不告诉我
- l'll make your dinner.  - Why didn't you tell me

141
00:13:23,420 --> 00:13:25,280
你给他在公墓立了墓碑
you put up a stone for him at the cemetery?

142
00:13:25,360 --> 00:13:26,690
我有告诉你 爸爸
I did tell you, Dad.

143
00:13:26,690 --> 00:13:28,720
我不得不读这该死的报纸才知道
I had to read it in the goddamn paper.

144
00:13:30,290 --> 00:13:31,660
我本应该在那的
l should have been there for that.

145
00:13:33,000 --> 00:13:35,290
我们所有人都应该在那的
We all should have been there for that.

146
00:13:35,370 --> 00:13:36,490
你究竟在想什么
What the hell do you think

147
00:13:36,570 --> 00:13:38,120
我在这无所事事 你呢
l'm hanging around here for, you?

148
00:13:38,200 --> 00:13:39,760
你什么都不告诉你的父亲
You don't tell your father shit.

149
00:13:41,840 --> 00:13:43,360
我亲自带你去了葬礼
l took you to the ceremony myself.

150
00:14:16,470 --> 00:14:17,380
- 是的  - 我想去玩不给糖就捣蛋[指万圣节风俗]
- Yeah.  - I want to go trick-or-treating.

151
00:14:17,380 --> 00:14:18,540
埃文叔叔 你忘记了
Uncle Evan, you forgot.

152
00:14:18,540 --> 00:14:20,440
你说过会带我们去玩不给糖就捣蛋
You were gonna take us trick-or-treating.

153
00:14:20,510 --> 00:14:22,140
现在已经完全天黑了
lt's almost dark out.

154
00:14:22,210 --> 00:14:24,740
- 你答应过的  - 我爱爸爸
- You promised.  - l love Daddy.

155
00:14:24,810 --> 00:14:26,010
嘿
Hey.

156
00:14:26,080 --> 00:14:28,050
你觉得我忘记了？
So you think I forgot?

157
00:14:28,120 --> 00:14:29,810
好吧 我在路上的
Well, l'm on my way.

158
00:14:41,730 --> 00:14:44,000
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat!

159
00:14:44,070 --> 00:14:45,590
谢谢
Thank you!

160
00:15:19,740 --> 00:15:21,470
孩子们 快走
Guys, come on.

161
00:15:22,810 --> 00:15:24,530
没有计划在内 芭芭拉 我们无处可去了
Didn't plan on it, Barb. We just ended up there.

162
00:15:24,610 --> 00:15:26,730
你知道我怎么想的吗
You know how I feel about it.

163
00:15:26,810 --> 00:15:29,040
我只是想孩子们有个安身之处
I just thought the boys needed a place to go.

164
00:15:29,110 --> 00:15:30,940
但他不在这 他失踪了
But he's not there. He's missing.

165
00:15:31,010 --> 00:15:33,640
你为什么一定要安葬他 我真想不通
Why do you keep trying to bury him? l don't understand.

166
00:15:33,720 --> 00:15:36,240
看来是时候做出一些决定了
lt just seemed like it was time to make some kind of decision.

167
00:15:36,320 --> 00:15:37,950
这不是你能决定的
lt's not yours to make.

168
00:15:42,500 --> 00:15:43,870
对不起
l'm sorry.

169
00:15:47,780 --> 00:15:49,300
别让孩子们失望
Don't make these boys give up hope.

170
00:15:49,380 --> 00:15:51,710
这是他们应该拥有的
lt's all they have.

171
00:15:51,780 --> 00:15:53,250
太痛苦了 对吗
lt's cruel, okay?

172
00:15:54,580 --> 00:15:56,350
我们都靠希望和信念而活着
We're all just living on hope and faith.

173
00:15:56,420 --> 00:15:59,850
如果我能回来的话会给他换个地方的
lf l could go back there and switch places with him,

174
00:15:59,920 --> 00:16:01,320
我只有一分钟时间了
l would in a minute.

175
00:16:02,490 --> 00:16:03,750
我需要你的谅解
l need you to know that.

176
00:16:03,830 --> 00:16:05,990
我知道
l know.

177
00:16:09,530 --> 00:16:10,430
晚安
Good night.

178
00:16:16,770 --> 00:16:18,100
…杰弗逊县
... and Jefferson County

179
00:16:18,170 --> 00:16:20,660
气温低至五十五度左右[摄氏12～13度]
with temperatures in the low to mid-50s.

180
00:16:20,740 --> 00:16:22,770
尽管只是多云 潮湿天气要到星期六早晨
The wet weather should ease off by Saturday morning,

181
00:16:22,850 --> 00:16:24,470
才能缓和
despite cloudy conditions.

182
00:16:24,550 --> 00:16:26,910
明天晚上弗吉尼亚西部是市民将会得到上天的款待
West Virginians may be in store for a treat tomorrow night...

183
00:16:26,980 --> 00:16:29,850
看到今年第一个月蚀
the first lunar eclipse of the year.

184
00:16:29,920 --> 00:16:31,650
所以明晚可以去郡天文台
So step outside tomorrow night

185
00:16:31,720 --> 00:16:33,920
进行观赏
and head down to the county observatory

186
00:16:33,990 --> 00:16:35,720
那里将会举行一个公众的观星活动
which will be holding a public star party

187
00:16:35,790 --> 00:16:37,120
地点在格林伍德小学的草地上…
on the grounds of Greenwood Elementary...

188
00:16:55,080 --> 00:16:56,910
埃文 醒来
Evan, wake up.

189
00:16:56,980 --> 00:16:58,310
埃文
Evan

190
00:16:58,380 --> 00:16:59,440
埃文 快醒来
Evan, wake up.

191
00:16:59,520 --> 00:17:00,640
埃文
Evan

192
00:17:00,720 --> 00:17:01,880
埃文 快醒来
Evan, wake up.

193
00:17:01,950 --> 00:17:03,710
埃文 快醒来
Evan, wake up!

194
00:17:06,060 --> 00:17:07,960
埃文！
Evan

195
00:17:08,020 --> 00:17:09,790
帮帮我
Help me!

196
00:17:09,860 --> 00:17:11,090
维克托 你在哪里
Vic, where are you?

197
00:17:11,160 --> 00:17:12,350
埃文！
Evan

198
00:17:12,430 --> 00:17:14,520
他像一个英雄一样回家
He comes home a hero.

199
00:17:14,600 --> 00:17:16,330
你带他到唐恩溪钓鱼
You take him fishing up near Town Creek,

200
00:17:16,400 --> 00:17:18,530
他的家人再也没见过他了
his family never sees him again.

201
00:17:18,600 --> 00:17:20,360
你为什么不救你的兄弟
Why didn't you save your brother?

202
00:17:20,440 --> 00:17:22,300
埃文 救救我
Evan, help me!

203
00:17:22,370 --> 00:17:23,460
维克托！
Vic

204
00:17:23,540 --> 00:17:25,870
维克托 你在哪
Victor, l can't find you!

205
00:17:25,940 --> 00:17:28,070
帮帮我 埃文
Help me, Evan!

206
00:17:29,380 --> 00:17:30,610
埃文！
Evan

207
00:17:35,820 --> 00:17:37,010
埃文 快醒醒
Evan, wake up.

208
00:17:37,090 --> 00:17:38,050
醒醒啊
Wake up.

209
00:17:38,120 --> 00:17:39,250
埃文 快醒醒
Evan, wake up.

210
00:17:40,520 --> 00:17:41,320
是我啊 醒醒
lt's me. Wake up.

211
00:17:41,390 --> 00:17:42,720
埃文 快醒醒
Evan, wake up.

212
00:17:43,990 --> 00:17:45,360
是我 维克托
lt's me, Victor.

213
00:17:47,930 --> 00:17:49,690
是我 是我呀
lt's me. lt's me.

214
00:17:53,470 --> 00:17:54,460
谁
Who?

215
00:18:00,580 --> 00:18:01,800
我今晚需要的你帮助
l need your help tonight.

216
00:18:01,880 --> 00:18:03,170
我需要你的帮助 别多问
l need your help. No questions.

217
00:18:04,590 --> 00:18:05,720
把小船放到卡车上
Load the boat on the truck

218
00:18:05,790 --> 00:18:07,230
准备够两天后用的装备
and bring enough gear for two days out.

219
00:18:07,290 --> 00:18:08,660
带上枪和大量的弹药
Bring the guns and plenty of ammo.

220
00:18:08,730 --> 00:18:10,220
- 为什么  - 别告诉你父亲
- Why?  - Don't tell Dad.

221
00:18:10,300 --> 00:18:12,660
办完这件事之前不要让任何人知道我回来了
No one's to know l'm back till this is done.

222
00:18:12,730 --> 00:18:14,360
- 芭芭拉和这些孩子们…  - 我…
- Barbara and the boys...  - l...

223
00:18:14,430 --> 00:18:16,030
任何人都不能
l said no one.

224
00:18:16,100 --> 00:18:17,090
现在快点
Now hurry.

225
00:18:18,170 --> 00:18:19,470
等下 不 让我看看你
Wait. No. Let me check you out.

226
00:18:19,540 --> 00:18:20,470
- 走  - 你受伤了吗
- Go.  - Are you hurt?

227
00:18:20,540 --> 00:18:21,670
快走
Go.

228
00:18:21,740 --> 00:18:23,210
他们知道我现在走了
They know l've gone by now.

229
00:18:23,280 --> 00:18:24,710
谁 维克 谁知道你要走了
Who? Vic, who knows you're gone?

230
00:18:24,780 --> 00:18:26,510
快走
Go.

231
00:18:29,450 --> 00:18:30,940
快点
Just hurry.

232
00:19:38,500 --> 00:19:39,630
埃文 什么事 兄弟
Evan, what's up, buddy?

233
00:19:39,700 --> 00:19:41,160
我要外出 我需要你马上过来
l need you to come over right now and

234
00:19:41,160 --> 00:19:42,500
照顾下父亲 我就要走了
look after my dad while l'm gone.

235
00:19:42,570 --> 00:19:43,700
好的
Sure.

236
00:19:43,770 --> 00:19:45,000
多久
For how long?

237
00:19:55,380 --> 00:19:56,820
我们走
Let's go.

238
00:20:02,860 --> 00:20:04,790
去唐恩溪 我们在那下
Head to Town Creek. We'll put in there.

239
00:20:06,090 --> 00:20:07,490
我们在追踪谁吗
Are we going after somebody?

240
00:20:11,300 --> 00:20:12,770
要射杀他吗
To shoot?

241
00:20:25,850 --> 00:20:27,010
如果你不想干
You want out of this,

242
00:20:27,080 --> 00:20:28,950
现在现在告诉我还来得及
you tell me now before it's too late.

243
00:20:30,190 --> 00:20:32,590
你和我做了这件事就无法挽回了
You do this with me, nothing will ever be the same.

244
00:20:32,650 --> 00:20:35,520
你就永远不能回头了 你应该知道的
You'll never be the same. You ought to know that.

245
00:20:35,590 --> 00:20:38,690
如果我不告诉你就是我不对了
lt wouldn't be right if l didn't tell you that.

246
00:20:38,760 --> 00:20:39,990
你自己决定
lt's your call.

247
00:20:47,470 --> 00:20:48,460
开始吧
Let's go.

248
00:21:59,980 --> 00:22:01,030
自从我和巴婆的警官一起
l haven't been here

249
00:22:01,110 --> 00:22:03,410
回来这寻找线索 我再也没回过这里来
since l came back with the sheriff in Paw Paw.

250
00:22:03,480 --> 00:22:04,910
这是你消失的地方吗
This where you ended up?

251
00:22:05,950 --> 00:22:07,470
那个晚上你什么都看到了吗
That night, you see anything?

252
00:22:07,550 --> 00:22:09,740
我不知道你在我前面还是后面
l didn't know if you were ahead of me or behind me.

253
00:22:09,820 --> 00:22:10,880
我大声叫喊着
l did call it out.

254
00:22:10,950 --> 00:22:12,110
没关系
Doesn't matter.

255
00:22:12,190 --> 00:22:14,250
不 我想你知道我有努力要救你
No. l want you to know l tried.

256
00:22:14,320 --> 00:22:16,380
到溪谷还要一两个小时脚程
We got an hour or two on foot up Creek Valley.

257
00:22:17,760 --> 00:22:20,280
我们方圆十里地都找遍了
We searched every inch of ground within 10 miles of here.

258
00:22:20,360 --> 00:22:21,620
嗯 你没找到我
Well, you missed me.

259
00:22:49,690 --> 00:22:52,290
好的 保持安静 有一只狗
Okay. Keep it quiet. There's a dog.

260
00:23:35,770 --> 00:23:39,070
父亲离开了 天黑之后他才打算回来
The father is leaving. He's not going to be back until after dark.

261
00:23:39,140 --> 00:23:40,700
你决定做这件事了吗
Are you ready to do this?

262
00:23:42,680 --> 00:23:44,440
你也没提及过那是一家人
You didn't say anything about a family.

263
00:23:44,510 --> 00:23:46,110
你要担心那一家人
You want to worry about a family,

264
00:23:46,180 --> 00:23:48,050
还是担心我们
worry about ours.

265
00:23:48,120 --> 00:23:49,810
你给我一些好的理由
You got to give me some kind of reason.

266
00:23:56,890 --> 00:23:58,360
我就是这个理由
l'm the reason.

267
00:24:30,930 --> 00:24:31,890
你还好吗
You okay?

268
00:24:31,960 --> 00:24:33,590
很好 我们准备进去
All right, l'm going in.

269
00:24:33,660 --> 00:24:35,490
他们发现我们就惨了
The minute they see me, all hell's gonna break loose.

270
00:24:35,560 --> 00:24:37,360
你守着后门
l want you to cover the back porch.

271
00:24:37,430 --> 00:24:39,460
嗯 知道吗
Okay? You got it?

272
00:24:39,530 --> 00:24:41,300
好的 走吧
All right. Come on.

273
00:26:29,480 --> 00:26:30,470
他在哪
Where is he?

274
00:27:06,500 --> 00:27:07,840
埃文 开枪
Evan, shoot!

275
00:27:27,300 --> 00:27:28,630
- 维克  - 在这呢
- Vic!  - ln here.

276
00:27:30,400 --> 00:27:31,760
看着她
Watch her.

277
00:27:31,830 --> 00:27:33,460
楼上有个姑娘
There's a girl upstairs.

278
00:27:33,540 --> 00:27:34,730
莉泽 快跑
Liese, run!

279
00:27:34,800 --> 00:27:36,270
快跑 莉泽
Run, Liese!

280
00:27:36,340 --> 00:27:37,830
莉泽 快跑
Liese, run!

281
00:28:39,270 --> 00:28:42,130
好了 不要害怕
lt's okay. Don't be scared.

282
00:28:42,200 --> 00:28:43,260
躲起来
Just hide.

283
00:28:44,810 --> 00:28:46,070
从前面出去
Out front!

284
00:29:04,060 --> 00:29:05,120
他在哪
Where is he?

285
00:29:05,190 --> 00:29:06,660
妈的 维克 放下枪
Fuck! Vic, put the gun down!

286
00:29:06,730 --> 00:29:08,320
他在哪
Where is he?

287
00:29:11,170 --> 00:29:12,290
前面出去
Out front!

288
00:29:14,040 --> 00:29:15,530
快跑 莉泽 快跑
Run, Liese! Run!

289
00:29:21,610 --> 00:29:23,310
开枪
Do it!

290
00:29:23,380 --> 00:29:25,350
拉她进来
Get her inside.

291
00:29:25,410 --> 00:29:26,900
他在哪
Where is he?

292
00:29:33,920 --> 00:29:35,650
- 卡尔  - 别看
- Karl!  - Don't look.

293
00:29:35,720 --> 00:29:37,420
你要杀他就杀吧
lf you're going to kill him, then kill him.

294
00:29:37,490 --> 00:29:39,080
安静点
Try to be quiet now.

295
00:29:39,160 --> 00:29:40,220
去死吧
Go to hell.

296
00:31:05,450 --> 00:31:07,110
你为什么要来这
Why did you come here?

297
00:31:08,680 --> 00:31:10,480
我们都要为这付出代价了
We're all going to pay for this now.

298
00:31:13,420 --> 00:31:15,620
你看到这一切发生 却什么都没做
You saw everything, and you did nothing.

299
00:31:15,690 --> 00:31:17,180
不要碰她
Don't you touch her.

300
00:31:17,260 --> 00:31:18,560
叫她闭嘴
Shut her up!

301
00:31:21,860 --> 00:31:23,190
每当你都站在这个水槽里
Every time you stood at this sink

302
00:31:23,260 --> 00:31:25,560
看着那个黑乎乎的容器
and looked out at that black container,

303
00:31:25,630 --> 00:31:27,730
你知道发生什么事 但你什么都不做
you knew, and you did nothing!

304
00:31:29,100 --> 00:31:30,400
- 什么也不做  - 我不知道你说什么
- Nothing!  - l don't understand.

305
00:31:30,470 --> 00:31:31,940
为什么这些人把你留在这
Why would these people keep you here?

306
00:31:32,010 --> 00:31:34,000
吃晚饭了 莉泽
Dinner time, Liese.

307
00:31:36,040 --> 00:31:37,880
他会奇怪为什么这没人来的
He'll wonder why no one comes.

308
00:31:42,220 --> 00:31:43,650
他在哪
Where is he?

309
00:31:44,720 --> 00:31:47,310
天啊 维克 住手
Jesus! Vic! Stop it!

310
00:31:47,390 --> 00:31:48,910
这是我的家人
This is my family.

311
00:31:48,990 --> 00:31:50,890
我的兄弟
My brother.

312
00:31:50,960 --> 00:31:53,760
你根本不知道你在干什么
You have no idea what you've started.

313
00:31:55,130 --> 00:31:57,390
今晚我们同样会看到他哭泣
Tonight we'll see him weeping, too.

314
00:31:59,730 --> 00:32:01,570
把他们绑起来
Tie them up.

315
00:32:01,640 --> 00:32:02,660
容器里的是什么
What's in the container?

316
00:32:02,740 --> 00:32:03,670
叫你把他们绑起来
Just tie them up!

317
00:32:03,740 --> 00:32:06,540
少他妈命令我 告诉我到底是怎么回事
Stop ordering me around and tell me what the hell is going on!

318
00:32:06,610 --> 00:32:09,480
这些人花掉了我两年的生命
These people took two years of my life.

319
00:32:09,540 --> 00:32:10,530
我的生命
My life.

320
00:32:15,050 --> 00:32:16,540
你想要博取同情吗 埃文
You want to get sympathetic, Evan?

321
00:32:16,620 --> 00:32:18,020
别朝人的肚子射击
Don't shoot someone in the stomach.

322
00:32:18,090 --> 00:32:19,750
那会很痛 让你生不如死
lt hurts like hell, and it takes too long to die.

323
00:32:21,420 --> 00:32:22,750
去把他们绑起来
Go tie them up.

324
00:33:14,000 --> 00:33:15,470
那个黑色容器里面的是什么
What is in that black container?

325
00:33:20,640 --> 00:33:22,900
听着 我不是要伤害你
Look, l'm not here to hurt you.

326
00:33:22,970 --> 00:33:24,130
我会弄明白的
l'll figure this out.

327
00:33:59,410 --> 00:34:00,810
这是他干的
This is his doing.

328
00:34:05,150 --> 00:34:06,620
时间让我们老去
Time doesn't touch us.

329
00:34:11,890 --> 00:34:12,980
你在说谎
You're lying.

330
00:34:19,400 --> 00:34:22,530
我十七岁的时间 比你活着还要长得多
l've been 17 longer than you've been alive.

331
00:34:31,340 --> 00:34:32,810
那容器里的是什么
What's in that container?

332
00:34:42,920 --> 00:34:44,350
今天有什么收获 沃尔纳先生
What you got today, Mr. Wollner?

333
00:34:44,420 --> 00:34:45,550
五辆旧汽车
Five crates.

334
00:34:45,620 --> 00:34:46,990
好啊 我们可以这么做
Yeah, we can do that.

335
00:34:48,530 --> 00:34:50,190
用来换现金还是用来卖
Cash or trade?

336
00:34:50,260 --> 00:34:51,250
用来卖
Trade.

337
00:34:54,500 --> 00:34:58,490
我不知道你怎么保持它运行的 但是它的确很漂亮
l don't know how you keep it running, but she sure is pretty.

338
00:35:02,740 --> 00:35:04,230
它什么时候生产的 一九二九
What's she, about 1929?

339
00:35:06,940 --> 00:35:08,040
一九三〇吧 也许
1930, maybe?

340
00:35:51,020 --> 00:35:52,990
埃文！埃文！
Evan Evan

341
00:35:53,060 --> 00:35:55,080
你没有理由进去看
You got no reason to look in there.

342
00:35:57,330 --> 00:35:58,890
我想你就是那个理由
l thought you were the reason.

343
00:36:00,300 --> 00:36:01,890
别
Don't.

344
00:36:40,570 --> 00:36:42,700
好了 我不是跟他们一伙的
lt's okay. l'm not with them.

345
00:36:42,770 --> 00:36:44,240
我来带你出去 没事了
l'm getting you out of here. lt's okay.

346
00:36:45,680 --> 00:36:47,580
我叫埃文·马什 我是个救护员
My name is Evan Marsh. l'm a paramedic.

347
00:36:47,650 --> 00:36:48,700
瞧 伙计 他们…
Look, man, they...

348
00:36:50,750 --> 00:36:53,220
大概一个星期前 他们在深林里袭击我
they jumped me in the woods about a week ago.

349
00:36:53,280 --> 00:36:55,650
我想我在森林里见过你的老婆和孩子
l think l saw your wife and kids look for you in the woods.

350
00:36:55,720 --> 00:36:57,710
没事了 我现在在救你
lt's okay. l got you now.

351
00:36:57,790 --> 00:36:58,810
尽管做吧
Just do it.

352
00:36:58,890 --> 00:37:00,520
看 我徒手弄不开
Look, l can't do it with my hands.

353
00:37:00,590 --> 00:37:02,490
- 我马上回来  - 别
- Be right back.  - No!

354
00:37:02,560 --> 00:37:03,620
快点
Hurry.

355
00:37:06,200 --> 00:37:07,260
快点
Hurry.

356
00:37:24,580 --> 00:37:25,740
把他带去巴婆的河
Take him down the river to Paw Paw.

357
00:37:25,820 --> 00:37:26,840
叫个救护车
Call an ambulance from there.

358
00:37:26,920 --> 00:37:28,390
我们完成我们的目标后 可以带上他走
We can take him with us when we're done.

359
00:37:28,450 --> 00:37:30,610
- 我们现在就走了  - 我们还没有完成
- We're going now.  - We ain't finished yet!

360
00:37:30,690 --> 00:37:32,120
我们不能让他一个人吊在那
We ain't gonna leave him strung up in there.

361
00:37:32,190 --> 00:37:33,850
我们可以这样做 设一个埋伏
We could do this. Set up an ambush...

362
00:37:33,930 --> 00:37:35,220
你在里面 我在院子里
You inside, me in the yard.

363
00:37:35,290 --> 00:37:36,450
他不需要被卷入这件事
He doesn't need to be involved in that.

364
00:37:36,530 --> 00:37:37,860
这是个有家庭的男人
That man's got family somewhere.

365
00:37:37,930 --> 00:37:39,730
你在那段时间一直问我我在战争时期做了什么…
All those times you asked me what l did in the war...

366
00:37:39,800 --> 00:37:40,820
真相就是…
what it was like...

367
00:37:40,900 --> 00:37:42,630
不要对我说那该死的战争
Don't throw that goddamn war at me.

368
00:37:42,700 --> 00:37:44,790
我曾经说过我要去当兵 你却背着我跟人签了入伍合同
l said l was gonna enlist. You signed up behind my back.

369
00:37:44,870 --> 00:37:46,770
所以我不得不留在这儿每天照顾父亲
And l had to stay here and take care of Dad every day

370
00:37:46,840 --> 00:37:48,470
而且还要听他说你是他该死的英雄
and have him tell me how you're his fucking hero.

371
00:37:48,540 --> 00:37:50,840
我去当兵是因为我认为我可以活着回来
l signed up because l thought l could make it back alive!

372
00:37:51,840 --> 00:37:52,810
难道我不行吗
And l couldn't?

373
00:37:52,880 --> 00:37:55,180
你在这杀害老人和女孩
You here are killing old women and girls.

374
00:37:55,250 --> 00:37:57,440
噢 是的 吃屎的大英雄
Oh, yeah, big fucking war hero.

375
00:37:59,080 --> 00:38:01,050
你能不能停下来想象如果这件事发生在你身上
You ever stop to think how this could have been you?

376
00:38:03,090 --> 00:38:04,780
我想得够多了
That's all l ever think about!

377
00:38:04,860 --> 00:38:06,520
那就是我在这儿的原因
That's why l'm here!

378
00:38:06,590 --> 00:38:08,350
现在我们去给那个可怜虫松绑
Now we're gonna cut that poor bastard loose,

379
00:38:08,430 --> 00:38:09,830
把他带进屋子里
take him in the house out of the way,

380
00:38:09,890 --> 00:38:11,360
然后处理这件事
and take care of this!

381
00:38:12,360 --> 00:38:14,390
然后让你回到你儿子身边
Then take you back to your boys.

382
00:38:18,100 --> 00:38:19,630
别忘了你的孩子们 维克
Don't forget about your boys, Vic.

383
00:39:53,560 --> 00:39:54,720
有人来了
Someone's coming!

384
00:40:05,380 --> 00:40:07,210
快点 我们得快点
Hurry. We got to hurry.

385
00:40:07,280 --> 00:40:09,340
- 他来了  - 尽量撑住
- He's coming.  - Just try to hold steady.

386
00:40:34,840 --> 00:40:35,900
把他带进去
Put him inside.

387
00:41:30,630 --> 00:41:31,620
起来
Get up!

388
00:41:33,230 --> 00:41:34,320
他在哪
Where the hell is he?

389
00:41:35,770 --> 00:41:37,600
在哪
Where is he?

390
00:41:37,670 --> 00:41:39,230
他在哪
Where is he?

391
00:41:39,300 --> 00:41:41,830
你对我儿子做了什么
What have you done to my son?

392
00:41:41,910 --> 00:41:43,310
我其他的家人在哪
Where's the rest of my family?

393
00:41:43,370 --> 00:41:45,170
他到底他妈的在哪
Where the hell is he?

394
00:41:47,110 --> 00:41:48,310
你不知道你到底做了什么
You don't know what you've done.

395
00:41:48,380 --> 00:41:49,570
你得离开这
You must go!

396
00:41:49,650 --> 00:41:51,710
马上 趁现在还有时间
Go now, while there's still time!

397
00:42:13,540 --> 00:42:15,330
你的子弹伤不了他
Your bullets won't hurt him!

398
00:42:15,410 --> 00:42:16,530
跑啊
Run!

399
00:42:18,810 --> 00:42:21,400
他不能进到屋子里面 他是被禁止的
He can't come into the house! He's barred!

400
00:42:23,450 --> 00:42:24,570
他出来了
He's out!

401
00:43:07,890 --> 00:43:09,150
那到底是什么
Where the hell is it?

402
00:43:09,230 --> 00:43:11,420
他进不来的
He can't come in!

403
00:43:14,060 --> 00:43:15,960
我要去把他绑起来…
l'm going to keep him tied...

404
00:43:54,940 --> 00:43:56,270
他进不来这房子的
He can't come into the house.

405
00:43:56,340 --> 00:43:57,500
他是被禁止的
He's barred.

406
00:43:57,580 --> 00:43:58,740
你说的禁止是什么意思
What do you mean, barred?

407
00:43:58,810 --> 00:44:00,300
他进不来
He can't come in.

408
00:44:00,380 --> 00:44:02,400
门上的画还有窗户使他进不来
The painting on the doors and the windows keep him out.

409
00:44:34,250 --> 00:44:35,680
那外面的是什么
What is that out there?

410
00:44:35,750 --> 00:44:39,510
沃思…理查德·沃思
Wirth... Richard Wirth

411
00:45:38,410 --> 00:45:40,900
门 把门关上
The door! Get the door!

412
00:45:48,420 --> 00:45:49,980
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?

413
00:45:50,050 --> 00:45:52,450
窗户
The window.

414
00:45:52,520 --> 00:45:55,120
他可以从窗户进来
He can come in through the window.

415
00:45:55,190 --> 00:45:56,250
快点
Come on.

416
00:45:58,230 --> 00:46:01,390
这种咒文是他没有杀死我们全部人的唯一理由
This rune is the only reason he has not killed us all!

417
00:46:15,680 --> 00:46:16,740
快点
Come on!

418
00:46:20,780 --> 00:46:22,010
- 好了吗  - 好了
- You got it?  - Yeah.

419
00:46:24,960 --> 00:46:25,850
该死
Fuck!

420
00:46:31,130 --> 00:46:32,960
他能被控制的
He can be controlled.

421
00:46:34,700 --> 00:46:36,790
就某种程度来说
Somewhat.

422
00:46:36,870 --> 00:46:39,530
我们知道了一些事
We know some things.

423
00:46:39,600 --> 00:46:41,470
也许已经够了
Maybe enough.

424
00:47:07,300 --> 00:47:08,560
是纳粹把他弄过来的
The Nazis sent him.

425
00:47:09,900 --> 00:47:12,130
那是一九三六年
lt was 1936.

426
00:47:12,210 --> 00:47:15,840
我们以为沃思是一位学者
We thought Wirth was a scholar,

427
00:47:15,910 --> 00:47:18,140
但是他来这儿实践超自然能力
but he was here to practice the occult.

428
00:47:18,210 --> 00:47:19,870
魔文石
Rune stones.

429
00:47:19,950 --> 00:47:22,210
血祭仪式
Blood rituals.

430
00:47:22,280 --> 00:47:24,340
我们都不知道
We didn't know.

431
00:47:24,420 --> 00:47:27,850
然后战争开始了 他们不能唤回他
And then the war started, and they couldn't retrieve him.

432
00:47:27,920 --> 00:47:29,550
所以我们监禁了他
So we imprisoned him.

433
00:47:29,620 --> 00:47:30,850
莉泽做的
Liese did.

434
00:47:30,930 --> 00:47:32,860
她把咒文贴满了院子
She put runes around the yard.

435
00:47:32,930 --> 00:47:34,390
围栏上的咒文
The symbols on the fences

436
00:47:34,460 --> 00:47:36,490
让他在农场里进不来屋子
keep him on the farm and out of the house.

437
00:47:36,560 --> 00:47:38,050
她那时只有十二岁
She was only 12 at the time.

438
00:47:38,130 --> 00:47:40,430
五年过去了
Five years passed.

439
00:47:40,500 --> 00:47:43,870
但是那之前 我们是他的囚徒
But by then, we were his prisoners.

440
00:47:43,940 --> 00:47:46,430
告诉我怎么才能杀死他
Just tell me how to kill him.

441
00:47:46,510 --> 00:47:48,410
带上你的兄弟现在离开这儿
Take your brother and leave now.

442
00:47:48,480 --> 00:47:51,070
如果你能够及时到达围栏外边 你就可以出去
lf you can make it outside the fences, you can get out.

443
00:47:52,380 --> 00:47:53,710
我们带你一起走
We'll take you with us.

444
00:47:53,780 --> 00:47:56,980
不 我们得留下来
No. We have to stay.

445
00:47:57,050 --> 00:47:59,380
我们让他进入了我们的生命
We let him into our lives.

446
00:47:59,450 --> 00:48:00,920
我们不能离开这儿
We can't leave here.

447
00:48:50,500 --> 00:48:51,490
埃文！
Evan

448
00:50:07,370 --> 00:50:09,140
不
No.

449
00:52:08,300 --> 00:52:09,670
我的父亲呢 卡尔呢
Where's my father? Where's Karl?

450
00:52:09,740 --> 00:52:11,330
他们死了
They're dead.

451
00:52:11,410 --> 00:52:12,770
他们很幸运
They're lucky.

452
00:52:12,840 --> 00:52:14,030
他们现在自由了
They're free now.

453
00:52:16,240 --> 00:52:17,470
她呼吸困难
She's having trouble breathing.

454
00:52:17,540 --> 00:52:18,810
她有心脏病药吗
Does she take any medicine for her heart?

455
00:52:18,880 --> 00:52:20,900
- 你有阿司匹林吗  - 没有
- Do you have any aspirin?  - No.

456
00:52:26,850 --> 00:52:28,480
- 你他妈要去干什么  - 我要去拿我的包
- What the fuck are you doing?  - l gotta get my bag.

457
00:52:28,560 --> 00:52:31,020
- 这个女人现在需要帮助  - 这些人不可信
- That woman needs help now.  - These people can't be trusted.

458
00:52:57,050 --> 00:52:57,880
快跑
Run!

459
00:53:18,010 --> 00:53:19,800
来 嚼这个 会有帮助的
Here, chew these. lt'll help.

460
00:53:33,590 --> 00:53:35,110
他毁灭了发动机
He's killed the generator.

461
00:53:35,190 --> 00:53:36,210
枪
Guns.

462
00:53:39,760 --> 00:53:41,350
- 我怎样才能杀了他  - 维克托 够了
- How do l kill him?  - Victor, enough.

463
00:53:41,430 --> 00:53:43,020
- 我正在救我们的命  - 我也是
- l'm trying to save our lives.  - So am l.

464
00:53:43,100 --> 00:53:44,720
那样的话 我们都将死亡
Either way, we all die.

465
00:53:46,430 --> 00:53:48,030
并不是只有你一个人遭受着痛苦
You're not the only one who's suffered.

466
00:53:57,380 --> 00:53:59,470
他是从我就开始的
He started with me.

467
00:54:19,330 --> 00:54:21,270
他来我们农场时我十二岁
l was 12 when he came to our farm.

468
00:54:21,340 --> 00:54:23,060
那是他第一次吃我的身体
That's when he first fed on me.

469
00:54:23,140 --> 00:54:25,470
当我哥哥看到他的行为
When my brother saw what he'd done to me,

470
00:54:25,540 --> 00:54:28,600
他试着去杀死沃思 但太迟了
he tried to kill Wirth, but it was too late.

471
00:54:28,680 --> 00:54:31,700
他已经很强壮了
He was already too strong.

472
00:54:31,780 --> 00:54:34,750
他能做的 只是代替我而已
All he could do was take my place.

473
00:54:34,820 --> 00:54:37,780
他暂时用了自己的血
He gave his own blood for a while.

474
00:54:37,850 --> 00:54:39,940
沃思 他差点杀了我们
Wirth, he almost killed us,

475
00:54:40,020 --> 00:54:41,490
他需要我们的帮忙
but he needed our help,

476
00:54:41,560 --> 00:54:43,280
所以他就像这样把我们封锁在时间里
so he froze us in time like this.

477
00:54:43,360 --> 00:54:45,880
我想那是第五年了
l think it was the fifth year.

478
00:54:45,960 --> 00:54:48,990
一个流浪汉到这儿来找工作
A vagrant who came here looking for work.

479
00:54:49,060 --> 00:54:50,930
我们把他吊在在了拖车上
We'd put him up in the trailer.

480
00:54:51,000 --> 00:54:52,430
他是第一个牺牲者吗
First victim?

481
00:54:52,500 --> 00:54:54,330
我们都是牺牲受害者
We were also victims.

482
00:54:58,140 --> 00:55:00,470
很多年过去了 我去偷了许多他的书和日志
Over the years, l've stolen many of his books and journals.

483
00:55:00,540 --> 00:55:03,200
从这边 我了解到许多东西
Everything l've learned, l've learned from these.

484
00:55:06,550 --> 00:55:09,850
起初 我父亲认为它是个没有危害的迷信行为
At first, my father thought it was a harmless superstition.

485
00:55:09,920 --> 00:55:12,040
但我看见了他所能够做的
But l've seen what he can do.

486
00:55:12,120 --> 00:55:14,520
一开始 他复活了些小东西
At first, he raised small things.

487
00:55:14,590 --> 00:55:17,390
我的鸟 猪 狗
My bird, the pigs, dogs.

488
00:55:17,460 --> 00:55:18,860
杀了它们之后 他把它们带了回去
He'd kill them and bring them back.

489
00:55:18,930 --> 00:55:20,720
然而那个仪式需要用血祭
But he needed blood for the ritual.

490
00:55:20,790 --> 00:55:22,730
人血
Human blood.

491
00:55:22,800 --> 00:55:25,230
活体的血
Blood of the living.

492
00:55:25,300 --> 00:55:29,200
你在拖车里吊着的那些可怜虫怎样了
What happened to the poor fucks you strung up in the trailer?

493
00:55:29,270 --> 00:55:30,900
他们发生了什么事
What happened to them?

494
00:55:30,970 --> 00:55:34,240
没错 一些确实已经死了
A few have died, yes.

495
00:55:34,310 --> 00:55:36,000
但这样等于救了多少人
But to save how many?

496
00:55:36,080 --> 00:55:37,510
你都知道他能做些什么
You've seen what he can do.

497
00:55:37,580 --> 00:55:39,510
你能想像如果他到外面去了会怎样
Can you imagine if he got out?

498
00:55:39,580 --> 00:55:41,880
直到你来之前 他都被我们关着
We had him contained until you came here.

499
00:55:43,620 --> 00:55:46,000
如果他再大开杀戒 那这就是你该受良心谴责
The next time he kills, it'll be on your conscience,

500
00:55:46,000 --> 00:55:47,380
跟我无关
not mine.

501
00:55:47,450 --> 00:55:48,290
他已经被挡在房子外了
He's barred from the house.

502
00:55:48,290 --> 00:55:49,580
我们只要躲在这里 让他饿死
We'll just hole up here and starve him out.

503
00:55:49,660 --> 00:55:52,090
我们在他饿死之前可能先会饿死
We'll starve well before he will.

504
00:55:57,960 --> 00:56:00,590
他正在回到他的地方去了 我们也该行动了
He's going back to his pit. Let's go.

505
00:56:00,670 --> 00:56:02,500
等等 他好像要回到石头里
Wait. He's going back to the stone.

506
00:56:02,570 --> 00:56:03,760
它给予他更多力量
lt gives him more strength.

507
00:56:52,190 --> 00:56:54,090
你说曾把他困住 怎么办到的
You said you contained him. How?

508
00:56:54,150 --> 00:56:56,880
神秘的咒文 像窗户上那些
The runes. Like the windows.

509
00:56:56,960 --> 00:56:59,020
我们在篱笆上画了一圈这些咒文
We painted barring runes on the perimeter fence.

510
00:56:59,090 --> 00:57:01,030
好 那这些咒文是什么呢
Okay, now, what are the runes?

511
00:57:01,090 --> 00:57:02,720
远古北欧的字母
Ancient Nordic alphabet.

512
00:57:02,800 --> 00:57:05,200
他认为他是维京人的后代
He believes he's descended from the Vikings.

513
00:57:05,270 --> 00:57:09,670
我们给了他一点血 但不够他完成仪式
We gave him blood, but just not enough to finish the ritual.

514
00:57:09,740 --> 00:57:13,170
仪式一旦结束了 那就没人能够控制他了
Once it ends, no one will be able to contain him.

515
00:57:13,240 --> 00:57:15,610
- 怎么结束的  - 我知道的只是从
- How does it end?  - All l have to go on

516
00:57:15,680 --> 00:57:17,940
这本书上的一些图画中得来
are a few drawings in this book.

517
00:57:18,010 --> 00:57:20,310
但我知道这是他的最终目的
But l do know this is his ultimate goal.

518
00:57:20,380 --> 00:57:22,080
就是这个 在这边的图画
This. This drawing right here.

519
00:57:22,150 --> 00:57:24,850
- 这就是他追求的东西  - 他妈的这到底是什么
- This is what he's after.  - What the hell is it?

520
00:57:24,920 --> 00:57:26,720
第三只眼
A third eye.

521
00:57:26,790 --> 00:57:29,090
是希特勒协会里的成员把他送到这来的
The members of Hitler's society who sent him here

522
00:57:29,160 --> 00:57:32,060
认为你能够在这之上继续发展
thought you could develop one over time.

523
00:57:32,130 --> 00:57:33,820
月食时它就会被释放
lt's released during a lunar eclipse,

524
00:57:33,890 --> 00:57:35,660
使你变得强大有力
making you all powerful.

525
00:57:35,730 --> 00:57:38,530
我不知道他确切会变成什么样
l don't know what it will be exactly,

526
00:57:38,600 --> 00:57:42,130
但我知道他需要血 大量的血
but l do know he needs blood, a lot of it.

527
00:57:42,200 --> 00:57:44,430
只要不是他自己的 那会是他中毒
Just not his own. That would be poison to him.

528
00:57:44,500 --> 00:57:47,740
一旦他的第三只眼被释放出来 他就会变身
Once his third eye is released, he'll cross over.

529
00:57:47,810 --> 00:57:49,400
那时没有任何东西可以控制他
Nothing will be able to contain him,

530
00:57:49,480 --> 00:57:51,340
甚至连那些咒文也不可以
not even the runes.

531
00:57:51,410 --> 00:57:53,000
你如何不让他变身
How do you stop him from crossing over?

532
00:57:53,080 --> 00:57:54,480
应该有方法的
There has to be a way.

533
00:57:54,550 --> 00:57:56,110
骨头
The bones.

534
00:58:02,420 --> 00:58:04,250
骨头
The bones.

535
00:58:08,530 --> 00:58:10,000
可能吧
Maybe.

536
00:58:14,400 --> 00:58:17,030
但是有人必须到外面去
But someone will have to go outside.

537
00:58:32,200 --> 00:58:34,400
他从德国拿到了他祖先的骨头
He brought his ancestors'bones from Germany

538
00:58:34,470 --> 00:58:36,340
把它们放在盔甲里
and made them into a kind of armor.

539
00:58:36,410 --> 00:58:38,200
他会在仪式上穿 然后直到我偷了它
He wore it at rituals until l stole it.

540
00:58:38,270 --> 00:58:40,300
是啊 我看见过 他在车棚的后面
Yeah, l've seen it. lt's in the back of the barn.

541
00:58:40,380 --> 00:58:42,610
他家族的血液就在这些骨头里
ln those bones is the blood of his family.

542
00:58:42,680 --> 00:58:44,270
有骨头在 他就不能追捕
He can't trace or hunt against them.

543
00:58:44,350 --> 00:58:45,970
那在我穿上之后呢
And after l put it on?

544
00:58:46,050 --> 00:58:48,480
你必须将他的鲜血和灵魂之间的联系消除
You need to break the link between his blood and his mind.

545
00:58:48,550 --> 00:58:50,710
如果你能使他不再吸取鲜血
lf you can keep him from getting any more blood,

546
00:58:50,790 --> 00:58:52,690
可能你就能够阻止他变身
maybe you can stop him from crossing over.

547
00:58:52,760 --> 00:58:54,420
把他弄到前院来
Just get him in the front yard.

548
00:59:28,760 --> 00:59:30,280
嘿 沃思 你的书
Hey, Wirth, your books!

549
00:59:40,100 --> 00:59:42,770
来啊 妈的
Come on, you fuck!

550
01:00:20,710 --> 01:00:22,470
快跑
Run!

551
01:00:49,640 --> 01:00:51,500
- 快开枪射他  - 子弹对他不起作用
- Shoot him!  - Bullets don't work.

552
01:00:51,570 --> 01:00:54,600
不是沃思 他不能吃死人
Not Wirth. He can't feed off the dead.

553
01:00:59,150 --> 01:01:00,620
快开枪 不然我来
Do it, or l'll do it!

554
01:01:18,170 --> 01:01:19,860
现在你像我们一样了
Now you're like us.

555
01:02:18,630 --> 01:02:20,100
要开始了
lt's begun.

556
01:03:09,310 --> 01:03:10,640
卢克
Luke?

557
01:03:25,800 --> 01:03:27,790
我需要你的帮助
l need you to help me.

558
01:03:33,640 --> 01:03:35,630
你能行吗
Can you do that?

559
01:03:37,310 --> 01:03:40,040
我要你把我弄到
l need you to put me somewhere...

560
01:03:41,040 --> 01:03:43,140
我不能伤害你的地方
where l can't hurt you.

561
01:03:49,250 --> 01:03:51,240
快点
Just do it.

562
01:04:00,730 --> 01:04:02,960
我的家人 我的孩子们
My family, my children.

563
01:04:03,030 --> 01:04:06,300
我的家人们 他们准备要来看我 接我回家
My family, they're gonna come and get me, bring me home, right?

564
01:04:06,370 --> 01:04:07,960
他们会的 是吗
They will, won't they?

565
01:04:16,380 --> 01:04:19,280
埃文 快开门
Evan, open the door!

566
01:04:28,420 --> 01:04:30,190
那是我的
That's mine.

567
01:04:30,260 --> 01:04:32,060
我要杀了你
l'm gonna kill you.

568
01:04:32,130 --> 01:04:33,720
不
No.

569
01:04:33,800 --> 01:04:35,920
我要吃掉你
You're going to feed me.

570
01:04:39,240 --> 01:04:42,570
我非常了解像你这样的男人
l've known men like you all my life.

571
01:04:42,640 --> 01:04:45,510
小身躯 小抱负
Tiny men with your tiny ambitions.

572
01:04:45,580 --> 01:04:49,380
去杀死敌人
Kill the enemy.

573
01:04:49,450 --> 01:04:51,850
你们结果都是一样的
You all end up the same...

574
01:04:51,910 --> 01:04:55,780
自己制造死亡 还叫别人妖怪
making death with your own hands and calling others monsters.

575
01:08:03,800 --> 01:08:07,330
埃文 这是骨头
Evan, get the bones!

576
01:08:50,100 --> 01:08:52,160
你说沃思不喝自己的血的 是吗
You said Wirth can't drink his own blood, right?

577
01:08:52,240 --> 01:08:53,500
当然
Yes.

578
01:08:53,570 --> 01:08:56,040
把你的围巾给我 告诉我你每晚是怎样喂他的
Give me your scarf. Tell me how you fed him every night.

579
01:08:56,110 --> 01:08:59,980
夜深了之后 我们就要准备给在拖车里的
After dark, we'd prepare who was in the trailer,

580
01:09:00,050 --> 01:09:01,770
东西弄一个切口
make the incision,

581
01:09:01,850 --> 01:09:03,440
然后我就摇铃
then l'd ring the bell.

582
01:09:03,520 --> 01:09:05,750
我父亲就会把骨甲披上
My father would put on the bone tunic,

583
01:09:05,820 --> 01:09:07,620
打开地下室 放他出来
open the cellar, and let him out.

584
01:09:07,690 --> 01:09:10,550
谁来弄这个切口
Who made the incisions?

585
01:09:10,620 --> 01:09:13,650
他们要以特定的方式用特定的刀来完成
They had to be done a certain way with a certain knife.

586
01:09:14,400 --> 01:09:16,000
你做过吗
You did it.

587
01:09:20,870 --> 01:09:23,460
你今晚要对我做相同的事情
You're gonna have to do the same thing to me tonight.

588
01:09:26,140 --> 01:09:27,900
求求你 不要 我不能
Please, no. l can't.

589
01:09:28,000 --> 01:09:30,090
不 你一定要
Yes, you can.

590
01:09:32,820 --> 01:09:34,340
我们来做这个
We do this.

591
01:09:34,420 --> 01:09:36,940
我们他家族的血液里让他中毒
We poison him with the blood of his own family.

592
01:09:41,300 --> 01:09:42,860
来吧 快点 走
Come on. Let's go.

593
01:09:44,500 --> 01:09:46,490
不要
Don't go.

594
01:09:49,100 --> 01:09:51,040
我爱你
Love you.

595
01:10:31,880 --> 01:10:35,400
你是不是想知道如何才能逃离这边
You ever wonder how you managed to escape?

596
01:10:39,590 --> 01:10:42,420
这些年以来唯一的一个
The only one after all these years.

597
01:10:45,290 --> 01:10:47,220
非常简单
Very simple.

598
01:10:47,290 --> 01:10:49,190
我成全你
l let you.

599
01:10:50,230 --> 01:10:52,090
我能够让你憎恨我
l could feel your hatred.

600
01:10:52,160 --> 01:10:54,660
我知道你会回来的
l knew you'd come back.

601
01:10:57,780 --> 01:11:01,300
今晚 我就将一切变成可能
Tonight, we'll make this possible.

602
01:11:01,380 --> 01:11:04,320
你把我从我家里释放了出来
You released me from the family.

603
01:11:27,870 --> 01:11:30,400
血就是血 对吗 他是属于他自己家族里的
Blood is blood, right? He is his family.

604
01:11:32,250 --> 01:11:34,510
快开始吧
Do it.

605
01:11:37,880 --> 01:11:38,980
差不多了
Finish it.

606
01:11:49,400 --> 01:11:51,390
马上去敲铃 然后回到屋子里去吧
Now ring the bell. Go back in the house.

607
01:11:51,460 --> 01:11:52,830
还没结束了
lt's not finished.

608
01:11:58,600 --> 01:12:00,570
它会保护你的
lt will protect you.

609
01:12:00,640 --> 01:12:03,670
否则他会马上吃干你的
Otherwise he'd bleed you dry in no time.

610
01:12:03,740 --> 01:12:05,940
快走
Go.

611
01:12:07,550 --> 01:12:09,410
快走
Go.

612
01:14:09,400 --> 01:14:11,520
沃思！
Wirth

613
01:14:19,540 --> 01:14:22,270
你帮我的奖赏
Your reward for helping me...

614
01:14:22,340 --> 01:14:24,240
你将会看到你兄弟的死去
you get to see your brother die.

615
01:14:24,310 --> 01:14:26,330
我在等着你 沃思
l'm waiting for you, Wirth!

616
01:14:35,190 --> 01:14:36,250
埃文
Evan

617
01:14:37,360 --> 01:14:38,760
埃文
Evan

618
01:14:57,040 --> 01:14:59,980
埃文！埃文！
Evan Evan

619
01:16:48,790 --> 01:16:50,650
你要毒死我
You poisoned me!

620
01:17:00,630 --> 01:17:02,570
应该轮到我们了
This is our time.

621
01:17:03,800 --> 01:17:06,460
这本应该很早就发生了
Should have happened long ago.

622
01:17:07,870 --> 01:17:10,710
当沃思先生进来的时候
When Mr. Wirth come in now.

623
01:17:51,480 --> 01:17:54,420
沃思！
Wirth

624
01:18:05,460 --> 01:18:08,260
沃思！
Wirth

625
01:19:23,640 --> 01:19:25,200
莉泽！
Liese

626
01:19:44,300 --> 01:19:45,460
莉泽！
Liese

627
01:19:58,900 --> 01:20:00,000
莉泽？
Liese

628
01:20:39,940 --> 01:20:43,350
希姆莱把其它八个像沃思的
Himmler sent eight others like Wirth

629
01:20:43,410 --> 01:20:47,440
送到了另外一些家里 农场
to other families, other farms

630
01:20:47,520 --> 01:20:51,320
在那些地方也找到了古魔文石
where ancient rune stones had been found.

631
01:21:03,230 --> 01:21:05,900
那是我一直期待的
l was expecting this.

632
01:21:08,670 --> 01:21:10,900
这些年
All those years,

633
01:21:10,980 --> 01:21:14,670
一切都瞬间倾泻 像雪崩一样
all at once, like an avalanche.

634
01:21:15,850 --> 01:21:18,410
哎 我能做些什么
Well, what can l do?

635
01:21:18,480 --> 01:21:21,450
一直陪在我身边到最后
Stay with me until it's over.

636
01:21:34,010 --> 01:21:36,100
不要恨我们
Don't hate us.

637
01:22:35,230 --> 01:22:37,830
来吧 这里有更多的圆面包
Okay, here are more buns.

638
01:22:37,900 --> 01:22:39,840
这是芥末酱
Here's the mustard.

639
01:22:39,910 --> 01:22:41,170
芥末酱
Mustard?

640
01:22:52,200 --> 01:22:53,670
嗨 宝贝
Hey, baby.

641
01:22:53,740 --> 01:22:55,430
你还好吗
You okay?

642
01:22:55,510 --> 01:22:58,030
当然
Yeah.

643
01:22:58,110 --> 01:23:00,200
我马上就过来
l'll be right there.

644
01:23:07,750 --> 01:23:11,090
希姆莱把八个其它像沃思的东西
Himmler sent eight others like Wirth

645
01:23:11,160 --> 01:23:14,820
送到另外的家庭 农场
to other families, other farms

646
01:23:14,890 --> 01:23:18,330
那边也找到了古魔文石
where ancient rune stones had been found.

647
01:24:22,860 --> 01:24:23,950
在三十年代初
ln the early '30s,

648
01:24:24,030 --> 01:24:28,120
阿道夫希特勒和他的核心集团着迷于超自然的神秘学
Adolf Hitler and his inner circle became obsessed with the occult,

649
01:24:28,200 --> 01:24:31,010
认为魔法对于他们统治
believing that the black arts were key to

650
01:24:31,020 --> 01:24:33,160
世界的计划极其重要
their plan for world domination.

651
01:24:33,240 --> 01:24:35,570
纳粹间谍游走于全世界
Nazi agents traveled the globe in search

652
01:24:35,640 --> 01:24:39,740
寻找被称为魔文石的古代日耳曼民族的圣物
of ancient Nordic relics known as rune stones.

653
01:24:39,810 --> 01:24:43,650
他们相信如果他们驾驭了这些石头的力量
They believed if they harnessed the power of these stones,

654
01:24:43,720 --> 01:24:47,850
那么没什么可以阻止他们成为主宰民族的步伐
nothing could stop the march of the Master Race.

655
01:24:47,920 --> 01:24:49,850
这些石头上的符号据说是
The symbols inscribed in these stones

656
01:24:49,920 --> 01:24:54,690
用来描述通往不朽的道路
were said to describe the path to immortality.

