1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
-= THE LAST FANTASY 荣誉出品 =-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
-= TLF字幕组 =-
翻译&校对｜arwencat

3
00:00:15,000 --> 00:00:20,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

4
00:01:41,800 --> 00:01:44,000
二十个问题，开始
Twenty questions. Go.

5
00:01:46,960 --> 00:01:49,450
是个男人，是政治人物吗？
You're a man. Are you in politics?

6
00:01:54,040 --> 00:01:56,280
热啤酒，跟喝尿没两样
Warm beer. Tastes like piss.

7
00:01:57,100 --> 00:01:59,400
[马路勇士]

8
00:02:05,330 --> 00:02:07,160
轮到你问问题了，亲爱的
It's your turn, babe.

9
00:02:07,660 --> 00:02:09,120
活着的还是死了？
Dead or alive?

10
00:02:09,910 --> 00:02:13,620
你不觉得现在问这个问题很白痴吗？
Don't you think that's a really stupid question these days?

11
00:02:15,450 --> 00:02:17,370
知道吗，他就是个混蛋
You know, he's kind of an asshole,

12
00:02:17,450 --> 00:02:19,290
如果你想让我教训他，乐意效劳
but if you need me to take care of him, I will.

13
00:02:19,330 --> 00:02:20,360
我可听见了
I can hear you.

14
00:02:20,440 --> 00:02:23,110
他才是他们家动脑子的那个
He's the one in the family with all the brains.

15
00:02:23,160 --> 00:02:24,660
是吗？
Is that right?

16
00:02:32,370 --> 00:02:34,530
好吧，州际公路就在前面，我们怎么办？
All right, the interstate's coming up. What do we do?

17
00:02:34,610 --> 00:02:36,990
别上州际，就在这条小路上继续开
Don't get on it. Stay on this back road.

18
00:02:37,030 --> 00:02:38,520
怎么每次你这么说
How come every time you say that,

19
00:02:38,620 --> 00:02:41,530
我们就要在不知名的鬼地方逛上好几个小时
we end up in a three-hour scenic tour in the middle of nowhere?

20
00:02:41,610 --> 00:02:43,200
听着，我们都同意要遵守规矩，不是吗？
Look, we agreed on the rules, didn't we?

21
00:02:43,280 --> 00:02:45,360
但是上州际公路，我们就破坏了规矩不是吗？
And by taking it, we're breaking what?

22
00:02:45,440 --> 00:02:48,020
规矩是我们不应该走州际高速
The rule that says we shouldn't take the interstate.

23
00:02:48,110 --> 00:02:52,270
“我猜我们不想打破任何规矩”，照他说的
"I guess we wouldn't want to break any rules," he said,

24
00:02:52,310 --> 00:02:54,770
一边喝着啤酒，一边开着偷来的奔驰车
drinking his beer as he drove the stolen Mercedes

25
00:02:54,820 --> 00:02:58,480
严重超速，还有呢，瞧啊，双手脱把！
ridiculously over the speed limit, and, look, no hands!

26
00:02:58,650 --> 00:03:00,360
- 宝贝儿，别这样！ - 别这样！
- Babe, don't!  - Stop!

27
00:03:01,190 --> 00:03:03,110
- 住手，你这白痴！ - 别！
- Stop it, you moron!  - Don't!

28
00:03:10,230 --> 00:03:15,360
- 好吧，聪明仔，我来看地图  - 就你？这上面可都是有字的
- All right, smartass, I'll read the map.  - Can you? It has actual writing on it.

29
00:03:16,360 --> 00:03:17,720
好笑吗
Very funny.

30
00:03:20,690 --> 00:03:22,440
嘿，嘿，嘿！
Hey, hey, hey, hey!

31
00:03:31,100 --> 00:03:32,430
喂，伙计
Hey, guys.

32
00:03:33,390 --> 00:03:35,640
好吧，大家关窗户
All right, windows, everybody.

33
00:03:38,850 --> 00:03:41,140
这家伙想干什么？
What the hell is this guy doing?

34
00:03:42,340 --> 00:03:44,970
我女儿和我，我们的车没油了
My daughter and I, we ran out of gas.

35
00:03:46,930 --> 00:03:49,890
先生，请你把车挪到路边
All right, sir, please move your car out of the road.

36
00:03:49,970 --> 00:03:54,300
我们昨天早上从丹弗出发，最后一次加油是在科罗拉多斯普林斯
We left Denver yesterday morning. Last gas we got was Colorado Springs.

37
00:03:54,920 --> 00:03:57,510
很抱歉，我们帮不了你，请把车挪开！
I'm sorry, we can't help you. Now move your car!

38
00:03:57,590 --> 00:03:59,140
求你了，我们只是需要一点汽油
Look, all we need is just a little bit of gas.

39
00:03:59,180 --> 00:04:00,800
是吗，我想也是，谁都需要
Yeah, I'm sure you do. You and everybody else.

40
00:04:00,880 --> 00:04:02,630
站在那别动！
Stay where you are!

41
00:04:02,720 --> 00:04:05,800
我们可以做交易，我们有食物和水
We can trade you for it. We got food and water.

42
00:04:05,850 --> 00:04:08,880
- 布莱恩，我们的食物很充足  - 充足…你怎么敢肯定？
- Brian, we have more than enough.  - More than... How do you know that?

43
00:04:08,970 --> 00:04:12,180
- 我说了别再走近！ - 布莱恩，他看上去没事
- I said do not get any closer!  - Brian, he looks clean.

44
00:04:12,260 --> 00:04:14,250
他可能处于潜伏期，想想看…
Or he could be incubating. Think about it for a second...

45
00:04:14,340 --> 00:04:16,380
伙计们！那孩子得病了
Guys! She's got it.

46
00:04:16,840 --> 00:04:17,970
见鬼！
Shit!

47
00:04:19,420 --> 00:04:21,630
快点，快点，快走…
Come on, come on, come on...

48
00:04:38,790 --> 00:04:40,670
他们会死的
They'll die out there.

49
00:04:41,670 --> 00:04:43,170
是人都会死
Everyone dies.

50
00:04:50,910 --> 00:04:54,750
规矩很简单，至少，在我哥哥看来是的
The rules are simple. At least, that's how my brother sees it.

51
00:04:56,000 --> 00:04:59,080
一，不惜一切代价避免感染
One, avoid the infected at all costs.

52
00:04:59,540 --> 00:05:02,000
病毒通过呼吸传播，具有高致病性
Their breath is highly contagious.

53
00:05:02,710 --> 00:05:06,830
二，对患者在过去24小时内接触过的物品全面消毒
Two, disinfect anything they've touched in the last 24 hours.

54
00:05:07,660 --> 00:05:13,120
[末日病毒]
三，已被感染的人和死人无异拯救他们是徒劳的
Three, the sick are already dead. They can't be saved.

55
00:05:13,120 --> 00:05:15,700
[末日病毒]
不守规矩，就会死
You break the rules, you die.

56
00:05:15,700 --> 00:05:19,120
[末日病毒]
遵守这些，才能活命
You follow them, you live.

57
00:05:19,120 --> 00:05:21,200
[末日病毒]
只是也许
Maybe.

58
00:05:41,610 --> 00:05:43,490
嘿，看我找到了什么
Hey. Look what I found.

59
00:05:45,950 --> 00:05:47,060
真是好极了
Great.

60
00:05:47,150 --> 00:05:51,400
嘿，如果你凑巧能找到一个全新的油盘，那可谢天谢地了
Hey, if you happen to find a brand-new factory-issued oil pan, holler.

61
00:05:57,320 --> 00:06:01,150
- 你确定你修不好它吗？ - 它爆缸了，高材生
- Are you sure you can't fix it?  - It's blown, lvy Boy.

62
00:06:09,940 --> 00:06:11,780
- 布莱恩  - 怎么？
- Brian.  - What?

63
00:06:15,020 --> 00:06:17,150
刚才那辆车只是没油了
All that car needed was gas.

64
00:06:18,030 --> 00:06:21,440
等等，什么？不，不，绝对不行
Wait, what? No. No, no, no way.

65
00:06:22,270 --> 00:06:25,470
- 如果我们呆在这，就是等死  - 我们回去还不是一样吗？
- Lf we sit here, we're just gonna die.  - We won't if we go back?

66
00:06:25,560 --> 00:06:28,980
你看见那女孩了，那些血迹还有疹子
You saw the girl. You saw the blood, the rashes.

67
00:06:30,310 --> 00:06:32,140
芭比，你说呢，你也看到了
Bobby, come on, you saw her.

68
00:06:32,180 --> 00:06:34,480
- 难道就我这么想吗？ - 凯特，我们别无选择…
- Am I the only one here?  - Kate, we do not have a lot of options...

69
00:06:34,560 --> 00:06:35,810
那些规矩可是你定的！
They're your rules!

70
00:06:35,850 --> 00:06:38,010
丹尼，告诉你女朋友冷静点儿
Danny, tell your girlfriend to get her shit together.

71
00:06:38,100 --> 00:06:41,310
- 我不是他女朋友  - 她不是我女朋友
- I'm not his girlfriend.  - She's not my girlfriend.

72
00:06:42,850 --> 00:06:46,510
是吗，那跟我说说，为什么她现在在这儿？
All right, then tell me, tell me. Why the hell is she here?

73
00:06:48,480 --> 00:06:50,840
而不是留在她的公馆里
Why didn't we let her sit tight in her McMansion,

74
00:06:50,890 --> 00:06:52,300
- 坐等强盗洗劫？ - 够了
- waiting for the looters?  - Okay.

75
00:06:52,350 --> 00:06:56,590
我们能不能都冷静一下，把眼前的问题想清楚？好吗
Could we just calm down and try and think this thing through? Please.

76
00:06:57,630 --> 00:07:00,300
- 好吧  - 那么车的事怎么样？
- Yeah.  - So what about the car?

77
00:07:02,670 --> 00:07:04,220
我不知道，丹尼，我正在想
I don't know, Danny. I'm trying to think.

78
00:07:04,300 --> 00:07:06,970
- 可是，我们需要那车…  - 我知道！
- Well, we need that car...  - I know that!

79
00:07:10,920 --> 00:07:12,010
见鬼！
Shit!

80
00:07:27,920 --> 00:07:30,420
好的，大家带上口罩
All right, put your masks on, guys.

81
00:07:44,840 --> 00:07:46,330
弗兰克·赫雷维
Frank Holloway.

82
00:07:50,250 --> 00:07:52,290
我们需要你的车
We're gonna need your car.

83
00:07:55,580 --> 00:07:57,580
哦，我想也是
Yeah, I figured as much.

84
00:08:00,910 --> 00:08:03,830
你们真想要这么一辆车？
Do you really want to splatter your brand-new vehicle

85
00:08:03,880 --> 00:08:08,290
你知道的，这车里有个染病患者
with the insides of someone who, for all you know, may be infected?

86
00:08:09,250 --> 00:08:11,160
我们有足够的消毒剂
We got loads of Clorox.

87
00:08:12,370 --> 00:08:14,330
- 消毒不是我最关心的问题  - 布莱恩，可以了
- Cleanup is not my chief concern.  - Brian, that's all right.

88
00:08:14,410 --> 00:08:16,660
- 别太靠近  - 我上周收听到一则广播
- That's close enough.  - I picked up a radio transmission

89
00:08:16,750 --> 00:08:19,740
是从法明顿市郊的一个学校播出的
from a school outside of Farmington last week.

90
00:08:19,990 --> 00:08:22,200
各处的人们都涌向那里
People from all over the state are traveling there.

91
00:08:22,290 --> 00:08:23,540
为什么？
For what?

92
00:08:23,950 --> 00:08:26,660
是疾病控制中心，他们设立了一个应急中心
The CDC, they set up some kind of emergency response center.

93
00:08:26,740 --> 00:08:28,700
他们拥有一种新抗毒血清
They've got a new serum.

94
00:08:28,910 --> 00:08:31,990
是个不错的故事，伙计，我还没听说过呢
That's one hell of a story, man. I don't think I've heard that one yet.

95
00:08:32,070 --> 00:08:33,200
有什么结果吗？
Are they getting results?

96
00:08:33,280 --> 00:08:35,200
不，他们才不会有什么结果，凯特
No, they're not getting any results, Kate.

97
00:08:35,240 --> 00:08:39,320
他们有新的治疗方法，我要这车带我女儿去那里
They've got a new treatment, and I am taking my daughter there in this car.

98
00:08:39,360 --> 00:08:42,570
那么，如果你们同意，万事大吉，如果不同意…
Now, if you're onboard with that, great. If not...

99
00:08:43,030 --> 00:08:45,610
这只是哄小孩的把戏，他很清楚
This is a fairytale, and he knows it.

100
00:08:46,700 --> 00:08:48,280
就像是巴尔的摩疫苗事件的重演
It's the Baltimore vaccine all over again.

101
00:08:48,370 --> 00:08:49,980
那些玩意儿没一个管用的
It's a bunch of retrovirals that don't work for shit.

102
00:08:50,030 --> 00:08:51,820
那你动手啊，布莱恩，朝他脑袋开枪啊
So go ahead, Brian. Shoot him in the head.

103
00:08:51,860 --> 00:08:53,360
等等！嘿
Wait! Hey.

104
00:08:57,070 --> 00:08:58,570
我有个主意
I got an idea.

105
00:09:26,770 --> 00:09:27,810
嘿
Hey.

106
00:09:29,060 --> 00:09:32,020
想知道个秘密吗？关于男生的？
Want to know a secret? About boys?

107
00:09:33,390 --> 00:09:35,940
会叫的狗不咬人
Their bark is worse than their bite.

108
00:09:36,310 --> 00:09:38,310
- 懂我的意思吗？ - 不
- You know what I mean?  - No.

109
00:09:38,400 --> 00:09:41,100
- 没关系的  - 别听她的，孩子
- It's okay.  - Don't listen to her, kiddo.

110
00:09:41,430 --> 00:09:45,470
- 相信我，她很喜欢我咬她的  - 那你干嘛不吃了我，布莱恩？
- Trust me, she loves it when I bite.  - Why don't you eat me, Brian?

111
00:09:45,550 --> 00:09:49,520
- 这事我们可以排上日程  - 老天，布莱恩！她才八岁
- I think we can arrange that.  - Jesus, Brian! She's, like, eight.

112
00:09:49,980 --> 00:09:52,340
是吗，就精神年龄来说，他也八岁
Yeah, well, mentally, so is he.

113
00:10:22,010 --> 00:10:25,590
永别了，马路勇士，你这破烂玩意
Adiós, Road Warrior. You crap piece of shit.

114
00:10:29,630 --> 00:10:31,840
宣扬无神论的政府覆灭了
But Godless governments have fallen,

115
00:10:31,880 --> 00:10:34,090
上帝亲手毁灭了人类…
and the armies of man have perished by his hand...

116
00:10:34,180 --> 00:10:35,540
你拍一，我拍一…
Pattycake, pattycake...

117
00:10:35,630 --> 00:10:40,800
…这场瘟疫是上帝的惩罚，世界变成了他的打谷场
... for this pandemic is the flail of God and the world his threshing floor,

118
00:10:40,880 --> 00:10:43,880
我们无法逃避，上帝要抽打他的稻谷
and, implacably, he will thresh out his harvest

119
00:10:43,960 --> 00:10:48,500
直至麦粒和草茎脱离，也即是正义脱离邪恶
until the wheat is separated from the chaff, the righteous from the sinner.

120
00:10:48,790 --> 00:10:53,250
无需怀疑，草茎必定多过麦粒
And make no mistake about it, there shall be far more chaff than wheat.

121
00:10:54,130 --> 00:10:55,120
只有少数能被选中…
Few chosen...

122
00:10:55,210 --> 00:10:58,960
[暗讽牧师说到的草茎]
话说到这儿，最近大麻还真是不多见了
Come to think of it, I haven't seen much weed around lately.

123
00:11:00,550 --> 00:11:03,330
- 真好笑啊  - 怎么了？
- Very funny.  - What?

124
00:11:06,040 --> 00:11:07,950
你该对此心存敬畏
Just show some respect.

125
00:11:08,040 --> 00:11:10,830
为什么呢？因为上帝连我的女儿也要惩罚？
For what? That God's punishing my daughter?

126
00:11:11,670 --> 00:11:14,080
那他又在奖励谁呢？谁呢，你吗？
Who's he rewarding? Who, you?

127
00:11:14,790 --> 00:11:17,540
- 我不是这个意思  - 那你的意思是？
- That's not what I'm saying.  - What are you saying?

128
00:11:17,620 --> 00:11:19,780
有些人将自己与世隔绝，囤积食物
Some people locked themselves away, piled up food,

129
00:11:19,870 --> 00:11:23,160
甚至连电话也不接，但是没过一周他们就死了
didn't even pick up the phone. They were dead in a week.

130
00:11:23,200 --> 00:11:25,250
而我，在一个体育场工作，为他人掘墓…
Me, I worked at the stadium, digging those mass graves for 400...

131
00:11:25,330 --> 00:11:27,990
- 日薪四百美元！ - 一点没错
- 400 bucks a day!  - That's exactly right.

132
00:11:28,530 --> 00:11:31,160
随便你们怎么笑话我，我对上帝的确心存敬畏
You can laugh all you want, but I was up to my knees in that shit,

133
00:11:31,250 --> 00:11:32,400
而现在我还活着
and here I am.

134
00:11:32,490 --> 00:11:36,080
那么说你是有免疫，或者被选中还是什么？
So you're immune or chosen or something?

135
00:11:36,870 --> 00:11:38,860
起码我活着，他们没有
I'm here and they're not.

136
00:11:40,160 --> 00:11:42,490
那么，我想你也不介意替我给我女儿一个晚安吻吧
So, then, I guess you won't mind kissing my daughter good night for me,

137
00:11:42,530 --> 00:11:43,910
嗯，布莱恩？
huh, Brian?

138
00:11:46,200 --> 00:11:47,820
我想你不愿意
I didn't think so.

139
00:11:52,530 --> 00:11:54,780
看来被选中的也没几个嘛，嗯？
So much for being chosen, huh?

140
00:11:55,910 --> 00:11:58,400
[美国知名大学联盟，此处指代优等生]
你倒挺高兴的嘛，嗯，常青藤联盟？
That's hysterical, huh, lvy League?

141
00:12:01,450 --> 00:12:03,160
你去的哪个学校，丹尼？
Where'd you go to school, Danny?

142
00:12:03,200 --> 00:12:06,030
- 他拿到了去哈弗的奖学金  - 耶鲁
- He got a scholarship to go to Harvard.  - Yale.

143
00:12:06,110 --> 00:12:09,200
- 事实上，是耶鲁  - 现在是哪还有什么关系吗？
- It was Yale, actually.  - It doesn't really matter, does it?

144
00:12:09,280 --> 00:12:13,400
他还没来得及入学，学校就因为这点小事被关闭了
A little something shut the place down before freshman orientation.

145
00:12:14,190 --> 00:12:17,560
- 说话注意点，布莱恩  - 这难道不是很好笑吗？
- Watch it, Brian.  - How's that for a knee-slapper?

146
00:12:18,060 --> 00:12:20,860
- 为什么你非得这么讨人厌？ - 住手！
- Why do you have to be such a dick?  - Come on!

147
00:12:20,940 --> 00:12:22,730
当心！当心！
Watch out! Watch out!

148
00:12:37,850 --> 00:12:39,900
你！你给我老实呆在后面，听见没有？
You! You stay in the back, you hear me?

149
00:12:39,980 --> 00:12:42,720
嘿，如果你能好好开车我会的！
Hey, I will if you keep your eyes on the goddamn road!

150
00:12:42,810 --> 00:12:45,520
嘿，你随时都可以下车！你现在就可以滚下去！
Hey, you can get out anytime! You can get out right now!

151
00:12:45,560 --> 00:12:50,220
- 好了，好了  - 凯特！凯特！
- Okay. Okay. Okay.  - Kate! Kate!

152
00:12:51,350 --> 00:12:54,430
那里有胶带粘着，你不用担心
The tape held. You don't have to worry about it.

153
00:12:55,890 --> 00:12:59,230
你还好吧？在看什么？
Are you okay? What is it?

154
00:13:06,060 --> 00:13:08,890
倒霉，她好像把我一颗牙给打松了
Damn it. I think she knocked a filling loose.

155
00:13:08,970 --> 00:13:10,470
我真替你难过
I weep for you.

156
00:13:15,550 --> 00:13:16,930
锁上了
It's locked.

157
00:13:25,800 --> 00:13:27,470
丹尼，当心
Danny, be careful.

158
00:13:28,680 --> 00:13:30,010
没事
It's okay.

159
00:13:40,340 --> 00:13:41,420
见鬼
Shit.

160
00:14:00,160 --> 00:14:02,460
嘿，你没事吧？丹尼！
Hey, are you all right? Danny!

161
00:14:03,500 --> 00:14:04,660
怎么回事？
What happened?

162
00:14:09,180 --> 00:14:10,300
上帝！
Jesus!

163
00:14:11,500 --> 00:14:13,710
弄到汽油就离开这儿
Just get the gas and let's go.

164
00:14:29,000 --> 00:14:31,830
嘿，孩子们，我们二十分钟后回来
Hey, kids, we'll be back in 20.

165
00:14:32,370 --> 00:14:35,090
是吗，其实也就五分钟就能回来了
Yeah, we'll be back in more like five.

166
00:14:36,370 --> 00:14:37,450
靠
Shit.

167
00:14:38,330 --> 00:14:40,370
芭比！宝贝儿？
Bobby! Baby?

168
00:14:41,500 --> 00:14:44,500
- 那是什么？ - 那个？
- What's that?  - That?

169
00:14:46,000 --> 00:14:48,990
嗯，是布莱恩和我
Well, Brian and I,

170
00:14:49,990 --> 00:14:53,370
我们也曾有爸爸，像你爸爸一样
we had a dad, too. He was just like yours.

171
00:14:54,450 --> 00:14:58,620
我们小时候，每个夏天，他会带我们去这个地方
And every summer, when we were little, he would take us to this place.

172
00:14:58,660 --> 00:15:00,330
叫海龟滩
It's Turtle Beach.

173
00:15:00,710 --> 00:15:06,160
我们在那里游泳冲浪，还有钓鱼
And we could swim and surf, and we'd fish

174
00:15:06,990 --> 00:15:11,240
吃软壳蟹三明治蘸蛋黄酱
and eat these soft-shell crab sandwiches that were soaked in mayo.

175
00:15:14,820 --> 00:15:16,910
那里有很多的海龟吗？
Were there lots of turtles?

176
00:15:16,990 --> 00:15:21,030
很多？老天，那里有好几千只海龟，到处都是
Lots? God, there were thousands of them! They were everywhere.

177
00:15:21,490 --> 00:15:25,690
你在水里几乎没办法不踩到它们
I mean, you could barely put your foot in the water without stepping on one.

178
00:15:25,780 --> 00:15:29,070
有时它们甚至会叠罗汉
Sometimes they'd be stacked up on top of each other.

179
00:15:29,280 --> 00:15:32,520
- 不可能的！ - 是真的
- That's impossible!  - It is possible.

180
00:15:33,480 --> 00:15:37,450
- 它们到处都是  - 我们能跟他们一起去海龟滩吗？
- They were everywhere.  - Can we go to Turtle Beach with them?

181
00:15:38,860 --> 00:15:40,320
该睡觉了
Time to sleep.

182
00:15:42,190 --> 00:15:45,270
你凭什么觉得那里就安全呢？
What makes you think you're gonna be safe there?

183
00:15:46,770 --> 00:15:48,480
那有一家老汽车旅馆
It's an old motel.

184
00:15:49,490 --> 00:15:53,650
那地方已经荒废了很多年，我们会对那里进行全面消毒
The place has been abandoned for years. We'll go on scavenging trips

185
00:15:53,690 --> 00:15:57,180
每次出门回来都进行隔离检疫
and quarantine ourselves every single time we get back,

186
00:15:57,600 --> 00:16:00,230
- 然后等待  - 直到有人来救我们
- and wait.  - Until they come for us.

187
00:16:01,360 --> 00:16:04,220
直到…直到瘟疫消失
Until... Until the disease dies off.

188
00:16:05,350 --> 00:16:07,400
你是指瘟疫还是指人？
The disease or the people?

189
00:16:09,970 --> 00:16:12,100
都是一回事，其实
It's the same thing, really.

190
00:16:15,310 --> 00:16:16,970
芭比，我爱你
Bobby, I love you,

191
00:16:17,260 --> 00:16:20,440
你也知道有时候，我确实很惹人厌…
and you know what a dipshit I can be sometimes...

192
00:16:21,940 --> 00:16:23,680
有什么大不了的嘛？
What's the big deal?

193
00:16:26,770 --> 00:16:29,260
我觉得我们应该开始和别的人约会
I think we should see other people.

194
00:16:32,720 --> 00:16:34,800
如果你真这么想
If that's the way you feel.

195
00:16:35,840 --> 00:16:37,640
我就是这么想
It is the way I feel.

196
00:16:44,470 --> 00:16:47,460
- 你有时候真的太讨厌了  - 我知道！
- You can be such a dipshit sometimes.  - I know!

197
00:16:48,050 --> 00:16:51,140
就现在来说，可能是世界上最惹人讨厌的
Probably the biggest in the world at this point.

198
00:17:13,080 --> 00:17:15,130
你有想过耶鲁吗？
Do you ever think of Yale?

199
00:17:18,180 --> 00:17:20,170
当然想
Yeah. Sure.

200
00:17:22,300 --> 00:17:26,330
还有那些，你觉得将来打算要做的事情
That, and all those things you think you'll get to do someday.

201
00:17:33,250 --> 00:17:34,420
天啊！
Jesus!

202
00:17:35,340 --> 00:17:38,580
- 快灭火！快灭火！ - 快，快，快！
- Put it out! Put the fire out!  - Go, go, go, go, go!

203
00:17:40,540 --> 00:17:43,130
你以为你能跑的掉吗，小子？
Where do you think you're going, boy?

204
00:17:43,540 --> 00:17:44,950
- 快点  - 快
- Hurry up.  - Hurry.

205
00:17:45,040 --> 00:17:47,910
快躲起来，把火灭了
Just keep it down. Keep it down. Put it out.

206
00:18:25,750 --> 00:18:31,860
[中国佬带来了病毒]

207
00:18:31,860 --> 00:18:39,000
[疫区]
[为避免疫情爆发，请立]
[即向公共卫生部门通报]

208
00:19:12,900 --> 00:19:18,350
生物危害 - 尸体

209
00:19:38,500 --> 00:19:42,600
海兰高中
急救中心

210
00:19:52,180 --> 00:19:54,560
- 听话，我很快就回来  - 爸爸
- Okay, I'll be right back.  - Daddy.

211
00:19:54,680 --> 00:19:56,470
宝贝，我就进去一下…
Honey, I'm just going in there

212
00:19:56,510 --> 00:19:58,180
好确定你的床下面没有怪兽
to make sure there are no monsters under the bed.

213
00:19:58,260 --> 00:20:01,010
如果那里有怪兽，你更不能去
If there are monsters, you shouldn't go.

214
00:20:01,140 --> 00:20:04,720
乖，听爸爸话，没什么好担心的，好吗？
Okay, now listen to me. There's no reason to worry. All right?

215
00:20:04,800 --> 00:20:06,510
在你会说“法泽斯沃德船长”之前，我就会回来的
I'll be back before you can say Captain Feathersword.

216
00:20:06,550 --> 00:20:08,340
法泽斯沃德船长
Captain Feathersword.

217
00:20:09,630 --> 00:20:11,760
你真是个小鬼灵精，知道吗？
You're too smart for me, you know that?

218
00:20:11,840 --> 00:20:13,550
我留下来陪她
I'll stay with her.

219
00:20:14,840 --> 00:20:16,000
芭比
Bobby.

220
00:20:16,710 --> 00:20:18,670
听着，现在不是做这个的时候，好吗？
Look, now is not the time, okay?

221
00:20:18,720 --> 00:20:21,920
女孩儿们需要单独相处的机会聊聊男生
The girls need some alone time to talk about boys.

222
00:20:26,220 --> 00:20:29,000
我说真的，别太接近那女孩儿
I am serious. Do not get too close to her.

223
00:20:29,210 --> 00:20:33,580
我也说真的，你快去吧，我没事的
I'm serious. Just go. It's gonna be fine.

224
00:20:36,790 --> 00:20:40,000
知道吗，你做事老是随心所欲
You know, you are always doing whatever the hell you want.

225
00:20:40,080 --> 00:20:42,000
所以你才爱我啊！
That's why you love me!

226
00:21:00,040 --> 00:21:01,200
有人吗？
Hello?

227
00:21:05,160 --> 00:21:06,330
有人在吗？
Hello?

228
00:21:44,490 --> 00:21:47,780
看起来你的医院很缺病人啊，弗兰克
Looks like your hospital ran out of patients, Frank.

229
00:21:51,440 --> 00:21:53,740
来吧，咱们走
Come on. Let's get out of here.

230
00:21:58,690 --> 00:22:00,150
凯特去哪了？
Where's Kate?

231
00:22:04,610 --> 00:22:06,610
- 她在干什么？ - 凯特？
- What is she doing?  - Kate?

232
00:22:07,560 --> 00:22:10,190
- 咱们该走了，这里什么也没有  - 你怎么知道
- We have to go. There's nothing here.  - You don't know that.

233
00:22:10,270 --> 00:22:12,070
凯特，他们失败了，咱们走吧
Kate, they failed. Let's go.

234
00:22:12,150 --> 00:22:15,020
那一侧我们都还没有检查过
There's a whole wing we haven't checked yet.

235
00:22:16,400 --> 00:22:18,690
看到没？这里还有人呢
You see? There are people here.

236
00:22:19,360 --> 00:22:20,430
等等！
Wait!

237
00:22:39,760 --> 00:22:41,180
不会吧
No way.

238
00:22:42,640 --> 00:22:44,590
哦，我的上帝，他们成功了
Oh, my God. They did it.

239
00:22:59,720 --> 00:23:02,470
- 先生，先生！ - 什么事？
- Sir. Sir!  - Yes?

240
00:23:05,050 --> 00:23:09,430
- 您是这里的主管吗？ - 不，林德斯医生才是
- Are you in charge here?  - No, you want Dr. Lindus.

241
00:23:09,760 --> 00:23:13,050
他的办公室在老数理楼的二层
His office is on the second floor of the old math building.

242
00:23:13,130 --> 00:23:16,340
不过你在那里找不到他，他在周四死了
But you won't find him there. He died on Thursday.

243
00:23:17,630 --> 00:23:19,050
医生，我们从科罗拉多一路赶到这里
Doctor, we've come all the way from Colorado.

244
00:23:19,130 --> 00:23:20,340
我们听说你们这里有一种抗毒血清
We heard that you had a serum here.

245
00:23:20,430 --> 00:23:24,170
我的女儿，她…我女儿她病的很重
It's my daughter, she's... My daughter is very sick.

246
00:23:27,220 --> 00:23:29,500
- 多久了？ - 一周多一点
- How long?  - A little over a week.

247
00:23:30,460 --> 00:23:33,210
- 她有耳部出血吗？ - 没有
- Is she bleeding from her ears yet?  - No.

248
00:23:35,050 --> 00:23:38,040
那么，带她来吧
Well, bring her in.

249
00:23:39,590 --> 00:23:43,580
好了，孩子们，这些好人会带你们去找爸爸妈妈
Okay, kids, these nice people are gonna take you to your parents,

250
00:23:44,250 --> 00:23:46,340
他们就在外面等着
who are all waiting outside.

251
00:23:46,420 --> 00:23:50,710
所以，等你们乖乖吃完药，一切都会变好的
So, as soon as we finish our medicine, we'll all be right as rain.

252
00:23:50,790 --> 00:23:55,910
你要对这些孩子做什么？那是什么东西？抗毒血清在哪？
What are you doing to these kids? What's that? Where's the serum?

253
00:23:57,040 --> 00:24:00,370
血清？是啊，是有种血清
The serum? Yes, we had a serum.

254
00:24:01,450 --> 00:24:05,580
它使患者病情稳定了三天，有些人甚至开始好转
For three days it stabilized the patients. A few actually improved.

255
00:24:06,080 --> 00:24:09,040
三天，就是我们的极限了
Three days. That's the best that we could do,

256
00:24:09,700 --> 00:24:12,700
就我所知，这也是全世界能力的极限
or anyone else in the world as far as I know.

257
00:24:13,240 --> 00:24:14,950
把病情恶化的时间推迟了三天
Staved off the virus for three days.

258
00:24:15,040 --> 00:24:17,750
也延长了患者七十二小时的病痛折磨
Prolonged sickness and pain for 72 hours.

259
00:24:17,830 --> 00:24:20,490
所以，我不要再继续延长了
Well, I'm not prolonging it anymore.

260
00:24:21,580 --> 00:24:24,080
- 那里是什么？ - 氰化钾
- What's in the punch?  - Potassium.

261
00:24:25,210 --> 00:24:27,280
很多的氰化钾
Lots and lots of potassium.

262
00:24:29,950 --> 00:24:31,940
现在，请原谅
Now, if you'll excuse us.

263
00:24:36,580 --> 00:24:39,150
不！不，住手！你不能这样做！
No! No, stop! You can't do this!

264
00:24:39,240 --> 00:24:41,820
凯特，他们已经感染了，和死人一样，咱们走
Kate, they're sick. They're already dead. Let's go.

265
00:24:41,910 --> 00:24:44,070
- 布莱恩，他们还是孩子  - 说谁死了？我女儿还活着！
- Brian, they are kids.  - Who's dead? My daughter's alive!

266
00:24:44,150 --> 00:24:45,320
她没有死！
She's not dead!

267
00:24:45,360 --> 00:24:47,320
- 还有其他地方…  - 别再拉这该死的帘子！
- There are other places...  - Stop pulling the goddamn curtain!

268
00:24:47,360 --> 00:24:49,620
求你！求你了
Please! Please.

269
00:24:52,280 --> 00:24:55,700
- 把枪给我  - 弗兰克，呆在那里别动！
- Give me your gun.  - Frank, stay where you are!

270
00:24:56,530 --> 00:24:59,480
- 把枪给我，布莱恩  - 弗兰克，你知道我不能
- Give me your gun, Brian.  - Frank, you know I can't do that.

271
00:24:59,530 --> 00:25:01,150
给我枪！
Give me the gun!

272
00:25:03,980 --> 00:25:05,150
丹尼！
Danny!

273
00:25:06,110 --> 00:25:10,650
住手！住手，见鬼！给我住手！现在！
Stop. Stop! Stop, goddamn you! Stop it! Now!

274
00:25:13,690 --> 00:25:15,140
松手
Put that down.

275
00:25:15,480 --> 00:25:17,690
- 松手！ - 看看你的四周
- Put it down!  - Look around you.

276
00:25:18,560 --> 00:25:20,690
我们两周前就断电了
We lost power two weeks ago.

277
00:25:21,070 --> 00:25:24,480
我们搜集镇上所有的汽油来发电
We sucked the town dry of gas just to run the generators.

278
00:25:24,560 --> 00:25:26,360
现在什么都没有了
There's nothing left.

279
00:25:34,390 --> 00:25:38,020
不要这样，求求你
Don't. Please don't.

280
00:25:40,440 --> 00:25:44,890
有的时候选择生存，只是选择了一种更加痛苦的死亡
Sometimes choosing life is just choosing a more painful form of death.

281
00:26:34,800 --> 00:26:38,210
你是说你最喜欢的卡通是“圆衬衫拖把脸”？
You're telling me your favorite cartoon's name is Mop-Face Circle-Shirt?

282
00:26:38,250 --> 00:26:40,880
- 不是！ - “脏仔裤刷子比尔”？
- No!  - Brush-Bill Soup-Jeans?

283
00:26:40,960 --> 00:26:45,000
[海绵宝宝]
不对！是“方型裤子海绵鲍勃”！
No! SpongeBob SquarePants!

284
00:26:46,340 --> 00:26:48,630
勺子嘴唇拳击短裤！
Spoon-Lips Boxer-Shorts!

285
00:27:02,050 --> 00:27:03,870
弗兰克！弗兰克！
Frank! Frank!

286
00:27:08,790 --> 00:27:11,290
好吧，你会没事的，只要…
Okay. You're gonna be okay, just...

287
00:27:13,370 --> 00:27:15,450
好吧，听着，慢慢呼吸
Okay, listen. Breathe slow.

288
00:27:21,820 --> 00:27:23,200
好吧，好吧
Okay, okay.

289
00:28:16,070 --> 00:28:17,190
我们离开这儿
We're getting out of here.

290
00:28:25,310 --> 00:28:26,480
出什么事了？
What happened?

291
00:28:26,560 --> 00:28:30,390
没什么，她把氧气瓶拿下来，她好像有点呼吸困难，我想
Nothing. She took it off. She had problems breathing, I think.

292
00:28:32,640 --> 00:28:37,430
- 过来  - 爸爸？我想上厕所
- Come here.  - Daddy? I have to go.

293
00:28:40,440 --> 00:28:43,220
[一号指小便，二号指大便]
- 一号还是二号？ - 二号
- Number one or number two?  - Number two.

294
00:28:45,430 --> 00:28:47,020
你能憋住吗？
Can you hold it?

295
00:28:49,970 --> 00:28:53,770
如果我给你拿一个痰盂之类的东西，你能用那个上吗？
Well, how about if I get you, like, a potty or something, can you do it here then?

296
00:28:53,850 --> 00:28:55,340
不行
No.

297
00:28:58,680 --> 00:29:02,720
好吧，我要你表现的像个大孩子
All right, now. I need you to be a very big girl for me right now.

298
00:29:03,430 --> 00:29:05,970
好吗？你得非常勇敢
Okay? I need you to be really brave.

299
00:29:06,560 --> 00:29:09,340
你看到那边那些蓝色小屋子了吗？
You see those little blue huts over there?

300
00:29:10,010 --> 00:29:11,680
你自己走过去
I need you to go over there by yourself,

301
00:29:11,760 --> 00:29:14,720
爸爸就在这里等你，好吗？
and I'll be waiting right here for you, okay?

302
00:29:15,050 --> 00:29:17,390
- 你能试试看吗？ - 好的
- Can you try that for me?  - Okay.

303
00:29:18,550 --> 00:29:22,010
- 好孩子，准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Good girl. You ready?  - Ready.

304
00:29:23,220 --> 00:29:24,470
来吧
Come on.

305
00:29:28,050 --> 00:29:30,880
爸爸就在这里等你，知道吗？
I'll be waiting right here for you, okay?

306
00:29:47,630 --> 00:29:49,920
- 没事的，宝贝，没关系  - 爸爸
- Okay, honey. It's okay.  - Daddy.

307
00:29:50,010 --> 00:29:52,000
- 对不起  - 不，该我对不起
- I'm sorry.  - No, I'm sorry.

308
00:29:53,880 --> 00:29:58,210
你做的很好，我为你感到骄傲，现在爸爸带你去，好吗？
You did great. I'm very proud of you. Now Daddy will take you, okay?

309
00:30:03,210 --> 00:30:05,710
你是个好人，丹尼尔
You strike me as a good man, Daniel.

310
00:30:10,870 --> 00:30:15,540
我们很快就回来，来吧，宝贝儿
We'll be back in a minute. Come on, honey.

311
00:30:28,870 --> 00:30:30,030
上车
Get in.

312
00:30:36,740 --> 00:30:41,530
- 快…快上车！ - 我们不能把他们留在这，这不行
- Get... Get in the car!  - We can't leave them here. Not here.

313
00:30:41,620 --> 00:30:43,360
听着，我们带他们到了这里，当初就说好的
Look, we brought them here. That was the deal.

314
00:30:43,410 --> 00:30:46,200
现在，该忘掉童话回归现实了
Now, it's time to drop the fairytales and move on.

315
00:30:46,240 --> 00:30:50,570
你也听见那医生说的，这里什么都没有，什么都没有！
You heard what that doctor said. There's nothing here. There's nothing!

316
00:30:52,370 --> 00:30:54,480
你已经害我们身陷危险过
You already put us in danger once back there.

317
00:30:54,570 --> 00:30:57,650
芭比？芭比，说点什么
Bobby? Bobby, say something.

318
00:31:17,110 --> 00:31:20,150
嘿，叫什么呢…那首史蒂文森小姐教你的歌
Hey, what was that song... What was that song Miss Stevens taught you

319
00:31:20,230 --> 00:31:23,020
- 你原来总是唱的？ - 小小蜘蛛
- that you used to sing all the time?  - Itsy Bitsy Spider.

320
00:31:23,070 --> 00:31:25,140
小小蜘蛛，对啊你还记得怎么唱吗？
The ltsy Bitsy Spider, yeah. Do you remember how to sing that?

321
00:31:25,240 --> 00:31:30,690
小小蜘蛛爬上排水槽
Ltsy bitsy spider went up the waterspout

322
00:31:31,400 --> 00:31:36,560
雨下来了冲走了它
Down came the rain and washed the spider out

323
00:31:37,730 --> 00:31:42,650
太阳出来晒干了雨水
Out came the sun and dried up all the rain

324
00:31:43,110 --> 00:31:48,980
小小蜘蛛又爬出来啦
And the itsy bitsy spider went up the spout again

325
00:32:18,180 --> 00:32:20,470
离海滩还有多远，丹尼？
How long till the beach, Danny?

326
00:32:23,760 --> 00:32:26,970
至少还要两天路程，怎么？
At least two days. Why?

327
00:32:34,430 --> 00:32:36,210
有人想打十八洞吗？
Anyone for 18 holes?

328
00:32:40,760 --> 00:32:45,050
[旅馆：前方出口两英里]
如果我们得找地方过夜，最好找个高级住所
If we're gonna stop somewhere for the night, might as well be high-end.

329
00:32:45,130 --> 00:32:46,300
对吧？
Right?

330
00:32:46,760 --> 00:32:50,590
- 你说呢，芭比？ - 随便你了，布莱恩
- What do you say, Bobby?  - Do whatever you want, Brian.

331
00:33:40,200 --> 00:33:41,370
有人吗！
Hello!

332
00:33:43,460 --> 00:33:44,610
有没有人！
Hello!

333
00:33:49,860 --> 00:33:52,030
这地方的服务真差劲
The service here is for shit.

334
00:34:03,360 --> 00:34:04,400
嘿
Hey.

335
00:34:06,660 --> 00:34:07,700
嘿
Hey.

336
00:34:14,200 --> 00:34:16,940
- 你还好吗？ - 还好
- You all right?  - Yeah.

337
00:34:24,280 --> 00:34:25,360
嘿
Hey.

338
00:34:32,150 --> 00:34:34,350
你看，之前的事情…
Look, what happened back there...

339
00:34:39,230 --> 00:34:42,140
我只是想把大家平安的带到海滩
I'm just trying to get us to the beach alive.

340
00:34:44,060 --> 00:34:47,230
- 你明白的，对吗？ - 嗯，我知道
- You know that, right?  - Yeah, I know.

341
00:34:51,110 --> 00:34:53,180
我们都同意遵守规矩
We all agreed on the rules.

342
00:34:54,310 --> 00:34:58,230
那些得病的人，已经死了，我们做什么也救不了他们
And the sick, they're dead. There's nothing we can do for them.

343
00:34:59,260 --> 00:35:00,430
是的
Right.

344
00:35:02,100 --> 00:35:05,050
- 就这样，我得去后面查看一下  - 好的
- All right, I should go check the back.  - Okay.

345
00:35:23,390 --> 00:35:26,090
好吧，别想了，你不会有事的
Okay. Knock it off, stupid, you're fine.

346
00:35:32,880 --> 00:35:35,510
嘿，丹尼！我找到了游泳池！
Hey, Danny! I found the pool!

347
00:35:47,090 --> 00:35:49,210
你想模仿马可波罗吗？
You want to play Marco Polo?

348
00:36:02,960 --> 00:36:04,420
- 糟了！ - 救我！
- Shit!  - Help!

349
00:36:06,260 --> 00:36:07,340
救我！
Help!

350
00:36:09,420 --> 00:36:12,550
哦，我的上帝！丹尼！
Oh, Jesus Christ! Danny!

351
00:36:40,950 --> 00:36:42,160
我们来打高尔夫吧
Let's play some golf.

352
00:36:52,570 --> 00:36:56,410
天啊！耶！
Jesus! Yeah!

353
00:37:15,000 --> 00:37:16,670
嘿，你没事吧？
Hey, are you okay?

354
00:37:17,000 --> 00:37:19,410
我一直以为高尔夫是老年乐呢
I thought golf was for old people.

355
00:37:21,790 --> 00:37:23,570
- 靠  - 白痴！
- Fuck.  - Jerk!

356
00:37:31,870 --> 00:37:33,870
过来，宝贝
Come on down here, baby.

357
00:37:34,870 --> 00:37:37,660
- 干嘛？ - 拉我一把嘛
- What?  - Help me out of here.

358
00:37:40,200 --> 00:37:44,110
来吧，就像咱们闯进橡树森林那次一样
Come on, it'll be just like the time we broke into Forest Oaks.

359
00:37:45,620 --> 00:37:47,990
还记得看林人怎么把咱们踢出来的吗？
Remember how the groundskeeper booted us out?

360
00:37:48,080 --> 00:37:49,150
是啊
Yeah.

361
00:37:49,700 --> 00:37:53,240
不过，这次我们联手，没人动的了咱们
Well, this time we're members. They can't touch us.

362
00:37:55,690 --> 00:37:57,450
这里软绵绵的很舒服哦
It's nice and soft.

363
00:37:59,990 --> 00:38:04,780
从里面出来吧，快点
Just come out of there. Come on.

364
00:38:06,200 --> 00:38:07,940
就拉我一下
Just give me a hand.

365
00:38:22,940 --> 00:38:26,140
- 下来吧！给我过来！ - 布莱恩！别闹！
- Come over here! Get over here!  - Brian! Stop it!

366
00:38:26,230 --> 00:38:28,560
别闹了！不要！
Come on! Don't!

367
00:38:31,190 --> 00:38:32,310
怎么了？
What?

368
00:38:32,980 --> 00:38:35,900
- 我身上都弄脏了！ - 只是些沙子！
- I'm gonna get all dirty!  - It's sand!

369
00:38:36,400 --> 00:38:38,510
是啊，沙子就很脏，混蛋！
Yeah, sand is dirt, asshole!

370
00:38:51,680 --> 00:38:53,560
好吧，女士们先生们
Okay, ladies and gentlemen,

371
00:38:53,640 --> 00:38:57,470
这是第十八洞比赛，年轻的布莱恩·格林正要开球
it's the 18th hole, and young Brian Green steps up to the tee.

372
00:38:57,850 --> 00:39:00,850
他必须一杆进洞才能赢得大师杯
He needs a hole in one here to get to the Masters,

373
00:39:00,890 --> 00:39:05,180
但他真正担心的却是别人发现他其实是同性恋！
but what he's really worried about is people finding out that he's gay!

374
00:39:05,260 --> 00:39:06,680
见鬼！
God damn it!

375
00:39:08,770 --> 00:39:12,550
伙计，我对你的建议是放下球杆，休息十分钟
Dude, my advice to you is put the club down, wait 10 minutes,

376
00:39:12,850 --> 00:39:15,180
然后再也别打高尔夫了
and just never pick it up again.

377
00:39:16,720 --> 00:39:19,430
如果你觉得好笑，不如你来给我们露一手
If it's so funny, show us what you got.

378
00:39:19,800 --> 00:39:22,800
谢谢，不过我想我还是要用根真正的远杆
Thanks, but I think I'll use an actual driver.

379
00:39:28,510 --> 00:39:30,210
就要到最后时刻了，朋友们
It's getting down to the wire, folks.

380
00:39:30,300 --> 00:39:33,470
- 凯蒂，凯特，姓什么不知道…  - 闭嘴！
- Katie, Kate, whatever her last name...  - Shut up!

381
00:39:34,720 --> 00:39:36,050
- 好吧！ - 厉害
- All right!  - Nice.

382
00:39:42,040 --> 00:39:44,550
哇噻，这姑娘打的真不错！
Shit, the girl can swing!

383
00:39:44,710 --> 00:39:48,000
菲尔菲德乡村俱乐部，少年锦标赛冠军，连续三届
Fairfield Country Club Junior Champion three years in a row,

384
00:39:48,080 --> 00:39:51,710
非常感谢，老虎伍兹也不是我的对手
thank you very much. Tiger Woods can kiss my ass.

385
00:39:53,760 --> 00:39:54,870
耶！
Yeah!

386
00:40:02,290 --> 00:40:03,790
哦，牛
Oh, shit.

387
00:40:13,830 --> 00:40:14,870
好耶！
Yeah!

388
00:40:32,740 --> 00:40:33,910
拉瑞？
Larry?

389
00:40:34,870 --> 00:40:36,410
拉瑞，回答
Larry, come in.

390
00:40:39,240 --> 00:40:40,830
你听到了吗？
Can you hear me?

391
00:40:43,160 --> 00:40:45,110
听到请回答
If you're there, pick up.

392
00:40:48,200 --> 00:40:52,360
我们正在回来的路上，听到了吗？我们正在回来的路上
We're coming back. Do you hear me? We're coming back.

393
00:41:05,820 --> 00:41:07,530
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?

394
00:41:08,820 --> 00:41:10,940
你到底在干嘛？
What the hell are you doing?

395
00:41:11,360 --> 00:41:15,810
每一天，每一部电话！通讯都断了
All day long, every single phone! The phones are dead.

396
00:41:17,020 --> 00:41:21,240
怎么了，我只是希望能联系到我的父母
So, I just gotta try and get in touch with my parents.

397
00:41:21,360 --> 00:41:23,020
他们都死了
They're dead, too.

398
00:41:25,320 --> 00:41:28,390
- 你怎么知道  - 我不知道？那他们在哪呢？
- You don't know that.  - I don't? Where were they?

399
00:41:28,850 --> 00:41:31,730
他们的游轮在比雷埃夫斯靠岸隔离检疫
Their cruise ship was quarantined in Piraeus.

400
00:41:31,820 --> 00:41:34,770
- 那么他们就是死了  - 你怎么就能这么说？
- Then they're dead.  - How do you know?

401
00:41:36,400 --> 00:41:40,070
- 你连比雷埃夫斯在哪都不知道！ - 这和它在哪一点关系都没有！
- You don't even know where Piraeus is!  - It doesn't matter where Piraeus is!

402
00:41:40,150 --> 00:41:44,310
任何地方的任何人，都死了，你的父母，我的父母
Everyone, everywhere, is dead, your parents, my parents.

403
00:41:44,610 --> 00:41:47,010
很快你我也都会死
Soon you and I will be dead, too.

404
00:41:57,350 --> 00:41:59,150
凯特，出什么事了？
Kate, what happened?

405
00:41:59,550 --> 00:42:01,520
- 别管我  - 别这样
- Leave me alone.  - Please.

406
00:42:02,140 --> 00:42:04,100
她对你说什么了？
What did she say to you?

407
00:42:06,140 --> 00:42:07,300
布莱恩？
Brian?

408
00:42:09,890 --> 00:42:11,730
- 那不是布莱恩  - 不好
- That's not Brian.  - No.

409
00:42:18,630 --> 00:42:19,840
- 糟糕！ - 发现他们了！
- Shit!  - We got them!

410
00:42:19,890 --> 00:42:21,640
走这边！
This way!

411
00:44:43,310 --> 00:44:46,310
到二楼这来！这里一团糟！
Up on the second floor! It's a mess up here!

412
00:45:07,890 --> 00:45:11,180
你们是谁，你们到底来这想干什么？
Who are you, and what the hell are you doing here?

413
00:45:11,270 --> 00:45:12,690
你是什么人？
Who are you?

414
00:45:13,480 --> 00:45:15,260
也许把这个拿掉，我们能说话方便点
Maybe we'll be able to talk once we get rid of this.

415
00:45:15,350 --> 00:45:18,180
不要！别碰我！求你，别碰我！
No! Don't touch me! Please, don't touch me!

416
00:45:20,470 --> 00:45:24,060
我们几天前外出搜寻物资给养！刚刚才回来！
We've been out a couple of days scouting for supplies! We just got back!

417
00:45:24,140 --> 00:45:25,520
放开他！
Let him go!

418
00:45:27,800 --> 00:45:28,840
现在
Now.

419
00:45:35,720 --> 00:45:37,350
所有人都抓到了吗？
We got everybody?

420
00:45:37,560 --> 00:45:39,550
- 我想是的  - 没有其他人了
- I think so.  - There's nobody else.

421
00:45:39,630 --> 00:45:40,670
汤姆！
Tom!

422
00:45:41,630 --> 00:45:43,260
- 我的防护服  - 怎么了？
- My space.  - What?

423
00:45:44,260 --> 00:45:46,630
被他们撕破了，已经不安全了
They breached it. It's not safe.

424
00:45:47,510 --> 00:45:49,760
我没…不安全了！
I can't... It's not safe!

425
00:45:53,460 --> 00:45:56,550
你们看起来就像罩着个安全套过活
That's what you get for living in a condom, man.

426
00:45:57,140 --> 00:45:58,460
- 你们…  - 去你的
- You get...  - Screw you.

427
00:45:59,880 --> 00:46:03,710
嘿，别碰他！我们只是想在这里过一夜！
Hey, leave him alone! We just wanted to spend the night here!

428
00:46:04,710 --> 00:46:08,000
你们这帮混蛋，你们把拉瑞怎么了？
You sons of bitches. What have you done with Larry?

429
00:46:15,880 --> 00:46:18,000
我们怎么知道，伙计？
How the hell do I know, man?

430
00:46:18,540 --> 00:46:20,080
[暗讽他们穿的防护服]
也许他跟浴帘打了一架
Maybe he got in a fight with a shower curtain

431
00:46:20,170 --> 00:46:22,170
就像你们一样
like the rest of you guys.

432
00:46:26,080 --> 00:46:28,500
拉瑞，他应该守在这儿的
Larry. He was guarding the place.

433
00:46:35,410 --> 00:46:36,790
他们把他杀了
They killed him.

434
00:46:36,870 --> 00:46:39,910
- 我们来的时候他就已经死了  - 是吗
- He was like that when we got here.  - Yeah, right.

435
00:46:40,000 --> 00:46:42,200
你以为我们会相信？
You expect us to believe that?

436
00:46:42,410 --> 00:46:44,330
你们干嘛不下去
Why don't you go in the pool,

437
00:46:44,370 --> 00:46:47,210
自己去查他的死因？
check out the cause of death for yourself?

438
00:46:49,580 --> 00:46:51,660
- 怎么，没人愿意吗？ - 闭嘴
- What, no volunteers?  - Shut up.

439
00:46:51,750 --> 00:46:56,240
汤姆，他肯定是在我们离开时发病了，但他没告诉我们
Tom, he must have been sick when we left and didn't say anything.

440
00:46:56,580 --> 00:46:58,490
不可能的，你知道那不可能
That's impossible. You know that's impossible.

441
00:46:58,540 --> 00:47:00,040
我们的防疫体系很完善
The system is perfect.

442
00:47:00,080 --> 00:47:03,450
- 为什么？就因为这是你想出来的？ - 他的防护服没有密封好
- Why? Because you thought of it?  - He didn't seal up his suit properly.

443
00:47:03,530 --> 00:47:06,490
是他自己的错，他没有遵循程序
He made a mistake. He didn't follow procedure.

444
00:47:06,750 --> 00:47:08,320
只要能安心睡觉，随你怎么想
Whatever gets you through the night.

445
00:47:11,450 --> 00:47:15,320
听着，虽然才刚见面，但我已经很讨厌你了
You know, I just met you and I'm already sick of you.

446
00:47:15,700 --> 00:47:19,230
- 我是有这个能耐  - 布莱恩，别说了！天啊！
- I have that effect on people.  - Brian, cut it out! Jesus!

447
00:47:22,450 --> 00:47:25,020
我要你们马上离开这里，现在
I want all of you out of here. Now.

448
00:47:34,150 --> 00:47:35,190
嘿！
Hey!

449
00:47:35,360 --> 00:47:37,700
- 拜托，我们需要那个  - 我们也是
- Please, we need that.  - So do we.

450
00:47:38,600 --> 00:47:39,810
进去
Get in.

451
00:47:40,770 --> 00:47:43,900
- 不是你  - 什么？丹尼
- Not you.  - What? Danny.

452
00:47:45,560 --> 00:47:48,480
你们要干什么？放了那女孩
What the hell are you doing? Let the girl go.

453
00:47:49,650 --> 00:47:51,390
- 女孩要留下来  - 不！
- The girls stay.  - No!

454
00:47:51,940 --> 00:47:54,020
- 没错，她们得留下  - 把你的手拿开！
- Yeah, they stay.  - Get your hands off me!

455
00:47:54,060 --> 00:47:57,520
- 不许你碰他，你这混蛋！ - 不许动！
- Don't you touch her, you son of a bitch!  - Don't move!

456
00:47:58,230 --> 00:47:59,480
退后！
Get back!

457
00:48:01,650 --> 00:48:03,510
如果我们把女孩留下
If we keep the girls,

458
00:48:03,560 --> 00:48:06,640
这两个男人你打算怎么办？杀了他们？
what are you gonna do with the guys? Kill them?

459
00:48:06,730 --> 00:48:08,940
我们不是那种人
We're not that kind of people.

460
00:48:09,190 --> 00:48:10,260
对吗？
Yeah?

461
00:48:10,890 --> 00:48:15,640
那我们是哪种人？坐着等死的人吗？
And what kind of people are we? The kind that just sits and waits to die?

462
00:48:17,680 --> 00:48:18,770
等等
Wait.

463
00:48:20,350 --> 00:48:24,390
去你的，汤姆！这可不是在工厂，你还以为你说话算数
Screw you, Tom! This isn't the mill. You're not in charge anymore.

464
00:48:25,470 --> 00:48:27,100
放了那些女孩
Let the girls go.

465
00:48:41,500 --> 00:48:44,510
我们得检查一下，确定她们没有感染
We have to check them out. Make sure they're clean.

466
00:48:44,590 --> 00:48:45,760
没错
Right.

467
00:48:52,300 --> 00:48:53,460
脱衣服
Strip.

468
00:48:54,250 --> 00:48:56,420
- 不要，求你  - 我说了脱衣服！
- Please, no.  - I said strip!

469
00:49:17,550 --> 00:49:19,200
见鬼，见鬼，见鬼！
Shit, shit, shit, shit!

470
00:49:19,290 --> 00:49:21,620
- 怎么回事？ - 哦，我的天那！退后！退后！
- What's going on?  - Oh, my God! Back off! Back off!

471
00:49:21,710 --> 00:49:24,620
- 谁能告诉我到底怎么回事！ - 离她远一点！
- Somebody tell me what's going on!  - Stay away from her!

472
00:49:24,700 --> 00:49:27,330
- 到底怎么了？ - 快撤！
★- What the hell is going on?  - I said go!

473
00:49:30,830 --> 00:49:31,920
见鬼！
Shit!

474
00:49:37,000 --> 00:49:41,490
我们赶快离开这！赶快！
Get the hell out of here right now! I said, right now!

475
00:50:51,000 --> 00:50:57,850
麦克死了，去爸爸那里找我

476
00:51:15,500 --> 00:51:17,130
这个锁上了
This one's locked.

477
00:51:17,300 --> 00:51:20,370
- 我去看看里面  - 我去后面看一下
- I'm gonna look inside.  - I'll go check the back.

478
00:51:33,260 --> 00:51:34,420
丹尼？
Danny?

479
00:51:59,560 --> 00:52:01,890
你想落得和他们一样下场吗？
Do you want to end up like them?

480
00:52:07,560 --> 00:52:09,350
如果她在我们就会
We will if she stays.

481
00:52:13,610 --> 00:52:15,020
去跟他谈谈
Talk to him.

482
00:52:20,600 --> 00:52:22,860
- 布莱恩？ - 来搭把手，好吗？
- Brian?  - Help me out, will you?

483
00:52:24,740 --> 00:52:26,290
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.

484
00:52:26,370 --> 00:52:29,370
油泵的钥匙肯定在这里什么地方
The key to the pump has to be here somewhere.

485
00:52:29,450 --> 00:52:33,190
- 布莱恩，这事我们得…  - 这见鬼的钥匙在哪？
- Brian, we need to deal with...  - Where the hell is that key?

486
00:52:51,080 --> 00:52:52,620
上车去
Get in the car.

487
00:53:04,580 --> 00:53:05,750
上车
Get in.

488
00:53:16,850 --> 00:53:18,090
有什么发现吗？
Any luck?

489
00:53:40,100 --> 00:53:41,200
布莱恩
Brian.

490
00:53:41,200 --> 00:53:43,700
[钮维尔]
[２英里]

491
00:53:51,230 --> 00:53:52,440
下车
Get out.

492
00:53:57,700 --> 00:53:59,240
我说下车
I said get out.

493
00:54:08,070 --> 00:54:11,120
- 我会坐到后面  - 我不是那么说的
- I'll get in the back.  - That's not what I said.

494
00:54:27,040 --> 00:54:29,090
布莱恩，求你让我留下
Brian, please let me stay.

495
00:54:32,050 --> 00:54:34,330
布莱恩，不要！
Brian, please don't!

496
00:54:35,920 --> 00:54:37,800
布莱恩，别丢下我！
Brian, do not do this!

497
00:54:37,960 --> 00:54:40,750
- 沿着路走能到一个小镇  - 这个只是瘀伤
- There's a town down that road.  - These are just bruises.

498
00:54:40,840 --> 00:54:42,300
我这几天坐在后面
I've been bouncing around in the back of that

499
00:54:42,390 --> 00:54:44,340
- 车很颠簸  - 镇上应该有足够的水
- stupid car for days.  - I'm sure there's plenty of water in town,

500
00:54:44,430 --> 00:54:48,640
- 但先给你半加仑  - 所以我才有瘀伤，但我没有感染！
- but here's half a gallon.  - Of course I have bruises, but I am fine!

501
00:54:48,930 --> 00:54:51,300
- 如果你省着点用…  - 我爱你
- Lf you ration it...  - I love you.

502
00:54:51,840 --> 00:54:53,470
- …应该能撑个几天  - 你爱我，不是吗？
- ...it should last a few days.  - You love me, don't you?

503
00:54:53,550 --> 00:54:58,060
- 食物也是一样  - 布莱恩，我会带口罩，我没想到
- The same goes for the food.  - Brian, I'll wear a mask. I didn't know.

504
00:54:58,140 --> 00:55:00,140
别说你不知道！
Like hell you didn't know!

505
00:55:01,140 --> 00:55:03,470
- 我…  - 你怎么能这么对我！
- I...  - Don't you do that!

506
00:55:04,100 --> 00:55:05,850
你怎么可以对我撒谎！
Don't you lie to me!

507
00:55:06,260 --> 00:55:07,770
我不确定
I wasn't sure.

508
00:55:09,940 --> 00:55:14,480
请不要丢下我！求你？
Please don't leave me here! Please, won't you help me?

509
00:55:22,770 --> 00:55:26,950
等你到了镇上，找一个舒服的地方
When you get to town, you find a comfortable place,

510
00:55:27,030 --> 00:55:28,650
明白吗，找张舒服的床
you know, with a good bed.

511
00:55:31,860 --> 00:55:35,020
还有毯子，尽管现在天气还很热
And get yourself a blanket, even if it feels hot now.

512
00:55:37,280 --> 00:55:38,950
还有很多的水
And lots of water.

513
00:55:40,960 --> 00:55:43,160
要赶在你太虚弱之前
Do it before you're too weak.

514
00:55:46,500 --> 00:55:48,740
布莱恩，布莱恩！
Brian. Brian!

515
00:55:49,580 --> 00:55:51,700
我警告过你当心那女孩
I warned you about the girl.

516
00:55:52,710 --> 00:55:54,450
- 你…  - 我告诉过你离她远一点
- You...  - I told you to stay away from her.

517
00:55:54,540 --> 00:55:57,500
为什么你就不能听我的？
Why the hell couldn't you have listened to me?

518
00:55:59,760 --> 00:56:02,370
她噎住了，她当时无法呼吸
She was choking. She couldn't breathe.

519
00:56:40,900 --> 00:56:43,520
- 布莱恩  - 嘿，把啤酒递给我，好吗？
- Brian.  - Hey, hand me a beer, will you?

520
00:57:00,400 --> 00:57:01,740
热啤酒
Warm beer.

521
00:57:03,520 --> 00:57:05,150
像喝尿一样
Tastes like piss.

522
00:57:15,610 --> 00:57:17,530
- 我们接下来怎么办？ - 我不知道
- What are we gonna do?  - I don't know.

523
00:57:17,620 --> 00:57:19,910
- 快没油了  - 我知道！
- It's almost gone.  - I know that!

524
00:57:25,130 --> 00:57:26,210
有车
Car.

525
00:57:27,300 --> 00:57:28,700
- 我看见了  - 我们得让它停车
- I see it.  - We gotta make them stop.

526
00:57:28,790 --> 00:57:31,080
好的，咱们要礼貌的挥手并请求帮助
Yeah, we'll just wave politely and ask for help.

527
00:57:31,170 --> 00:57:33,210
布莱恩，布莱恩！
Brian. Brian!

528
00:57:47,880 --> 00:57:51,260
嘿！我来处理
Hey! I'll deal with this.

529
00:57:58,640 --> 00:58:01,010
- 呆在那别过来！ - 别再走过来！
- Stay where you are!  - Don't come any closer!

530
00:58:01,090 --> 00:58:05,430
我就站在这里，我们需要一些汽油
I'm gonna stay right here. We just need some gas.

531
00:58:06,630 --> 00:58:11,570
- 抱歉，我们也没有多余的  - 我知道，我理解
- Sorry. We don't have any to spare.  - I know. I understand.

532
00:58:15,310 --> 00:58:18,350
但是我想我们同为基督教友
But I was just hoping that maybe as a fellow Christian,

533
00:58:18,430 --> 00:58:21,810
- 你也许可以帮助我们  - 请别说了
- you might be able to help us.  - Please don't do that.

534
00:58:22,900 --> 00:58:26,020
你看，我妻子在车上，她怀孕了
You see, my wife in the car, she's pregnant.

535
00:58:26,940 --> 00:58:30,320
我们只是想找一个安静的地方生下孩子
We're just looking for a cool place to have the baby,

536
00:58:30,660 --> 00:58:34,400
- 度过这场危机  - 挂倒档，我们走，走
- see this thing through.  - Go in reverse. Let's go. Let's go.

537
00:58:34,570 --> 00:58:35,900
祝你好运
Good luck.

538
00:58:36,570 --> 00:58:38,100
- 快，快  - 女士
- Go, go, go.  - Ma'am.

539
00:58:38,150 --> 00:58:40,030
- 不，不行  - 求你
- No, I can't.  - Please.

540
00:58:40,120 --> 00:58:41,700
我恳求你！
I'm begging you!

541
00:58:44,610 --> 00:58:45,950
不，布莱恩！
No, Brian!

542
00:58:50,610 --> 00:58:51,820
下车！
Get out!

543
00:58:54,000 --> 00:58:55,210
下车！
Get out!

544
00:59:31,890 --> 00:59:33,260
去弄汽油
Get the gas.

545
00:59:35,310 --> 00:59:36,390
哦，上帝
Oh, God.

546
00:59:48,600 --> 00:59:50,300
你要干什么？
What are you doing?

547
00:59:50,380 --> 00:59:53,100
油可没长腿，丹尼
They weren't gonna give it to us, Danny.

548
00:59:53,890 --> 00:59:55,390
去帮她
Help her out.

549
00:59:58,720 --> 01:00:03,010
你别再跟我说话，你听见没？你无权对我发号施令！
You don't talk to me. You hear me? You don't tell me what to do!

550
01:00:04,260 --> 01:00:08,220
别想走开，你这王八蛋！我跟你说话呢！
Don't walk away from me, you son of a bitch! I'm talking to you!

551
01:00:09,050 --> 01:00:11,550
- 他妈…  - 是我在跟你说话
- What the...  - I am talking to you,

552
01:00:11,720 --> 01:00:15,210
是我在告诉你该做什么，你这自以为是的白痴！
and I'm telling you what to do, you self-righteous shit!

553
01:00:15,710 --> 01:00:18,340
当你哥哥冲锋在前给你扫除障碍的时候
It must be nice sitting on the sidelines

554
01:00:18,420 --> 01:00:20,380
你在旁边看着感觉很爽吧
while your dumb brother wades in shit for you.

555
01:00:20,470 --> 01:00:22,670
- 不是，我没有…  - 总有人要做那些事的
- No, I don't...  - Somebody had to do it.

556
01:00:22,750 --> 01:00:24,420
- 你能做到吗，丹尼？ - 你没必要…
- Was it gonna be you, Danny?  - You didn't have to...

557
01:00:24,510 --> 01:00:27,180
你还记得…还记得在家的最后一天吗？
You remember... You remember our last day at home?

558
01:00:27,590 --> 01:00:31,170
不是你去爸妈的卧室里拿枪吧，对吗？
It wasn't you who went up to Mom and Dad's room to get his gun, was it?

559
01:00:31,210 --> 01:00:34,920
不是你！也不是你要上楼去撒谎
It wasn't you! It wasn't you who had to go up there and lie

560
01:00:35,000 --> 01:00:38,550
跟他们说不用担心，说我们很快就会回来
and tell them not to worry, that you'd be back real soon.

561
01:00:38,880 --> 01:00:42,290
- 他们还活着？那时还活着？ - 你自己清楚
- They were alive? Alive?  - You knew they were.

562
01:00:42,880 --> 01:00:46,580
他们活着？你…你跟我说…
They were? You... You told me...

563
01:00:46,660 --> 01:00:51,920
- 我说了你想听的  - 你这混蛋！混蛋！
- What you wanted to hear.  - You asshole! Asshole!

564
01:00:54,540 --> 01:00:57,040
你给我过来，老实点，我当混蛋是为了什么？
Come here. Come here. I'm an asshole for what?

565
01:00:57,130 --> 01:00:58,750
告诉我，丹尼，是为了什么？
Tell me, Danny, asshole for what?

566
01:00:58,880 --> 01:01:00,120
为了什么？
For what?

567
01:01:00,370 --> 01:01:03,500
不就为了让你走的问心无愧吗？
For letting you walk by with a clean conscience?

568
01:01:05,380 --> 01:01:07,830
你不就是这样的人吗，丹尼
Well, that's what you like, Danny.

569
01:01:09,830 --> 01:01:11,320
记得芭比吗？
Remember Bobby?

570
01:01:13,780 --> 01:01:15,540
你还记得她吗？
You remember Bobby?

571
01:01:16,120 --> 01:01:18,160
难道不是我把她拖下车的
I was the one that had to drag her out of the car

572
01:01:18,240 --> 01:01:21,700
而你就只是坐在那看着！
while you just sat there watching me do it!

573
01:01:30,290 --> 01:01:31,860
芭比是对的
Bobby was right.

574
01:01:34,950 --> 01:01:36,860
你才是家里动脑子的那个
You got all the brains.

575
01:03:14,640 --> 01:03:15,800
丹尼
Danny.

576
01:03:23,500 --> 01:03:25,500
嘿，布莱恩
Hey. Brian.

577
01:03:30,670 --> 01:03:32,000
停车
Stop here.

578
01:03:34,590 --> 01:03:36,170
布莱恩，布莱恩
Brian. Brian.

579
01:03:36,920 --> 01:03:38,040
我们在这房子这停一下，好吗？
We're gonna stop at this house, okay?

580
01:03:38,130 --> 01:03:41,420
我们得找些东西来包扎伤口
We're gonna find something to dress your wound with.

581
01:03:41,550 --> 01:03:43,420
随你怎么说了，医生
Whatever you say, Doc.

582
01:04:13,000 --> 01:04:15,700
丹尼，那里
Danny. There.

583
01:04:26,200 --> 01:04:28,080
再靠近一点
A little closer.

584
01:04:29,080 --> 01:04:31,000
再来一点，好了，停
Keep going. Okay, stop.

585
01:05:08,000 --> 01:05:09,160
有人吗？
Hello?

586
01:05:28,980 --> 01:05:30,150
有人吗！
Hello!

587
01:05:33,910 --> 01:05:37,120
如果你能听见，我们只是需要一些医疗用品
If you can hear me, we just need medical supplies.

588
01:05:40,920 --> 01:05:42,460
有人受伤了
Someone's hurt.

589
01:05:47,220 --> 01:05:48,880
我们没有感染
We're not infected,

590
01:05:51,350 --> 01:05:53,680
我们也无意伤害谁
and we don't mean you any harm.

591
01:05:54,810 --> 01:05:56,020
我们…
We're...

592
01:05:57,060 --> 01:06:01,110
我们只是拿一些需要的东西，然后就离开
We're just gonna take what we need, and we'll leave.

593
01:07:30,500 --> 01:07:33,300
出什么事了？哦，见鬼！你身上是什么？
What happened? Oh, shit! What's on you?

594
01:07:40,230 --> 01:07:43,100
这没有传染性，不是人血
It's not contagious. It's not human blood.

595
01:07:45,690 --> 01:07:47,230
是狗血
It's dog blood.

596
01:07:50,610 --> 01:07:53,740
- 我正担心你呢，弟弟  - 对不起
- You had me worried, little brother.  - I'm sorry.

597
01:07:56,290 --> 01:07:57,290
抱歉
Sorry.

598
01:08:03,210 --> 01:08:08,430
嘿，你可别误会，你能把裤子脱下来吗？
Hey, don't take this the wrong way. Can you pull down your pants?

599
01:08:38,260 --> 01:08:41,060
嘿，被选中的人还真不少，嗯？
Hey, so much for being chosen, huh?

600
01:08:45,860 --> 01:08:47,190
对不起
I'm sorry.

601
01:09:18,780 --> 01:09:20,740
他感染了，对吗？
He's got it, doesn't he?

602
01:09:26,620 --> 01:09:27,700
倒霉！
Shit!

603
01:09:32,400 --> 01:09:36,140
我不知道有没有人能听到
I don't know if there's anybody listening,

604
01:09:37,440 --> 01:09:39,680
我的发电机快停了
but my generator is dying.

605
01:09:40,640 --> 01:09:45,190
因此，如果有人在听，这是我放的最后一首歌
So, if there is someone out there, this is my last song.

606
01:09:46,230 --> 01:09:50,230
我是劳拉·梅金，德州科珀斯克里斯蒂市最后的幸存者
This is Laura Merkin, last survivor of Corpus Christi, Texas,

607
01:09:50,890 --> 01:09:53,150
在此告别
saying goodbye.

608
01:10:09,350 --> 01:10:10,930
能让我看看吗？
Can I see those?

609
01:10:35,900 --> 01:10:39,720
芭比曾有个疯狂的念头
Bobby had this crazy idea.

610
01:10:43,020 --> 01:10:44,890
她想当妈妈
She wanted to be a mom.

611
01:10:49,230 --> 01:10:51,050
你能相信吗？
Can you believe that?

612
01:10:53,220 --> 01:10:54,430
为什么不呢？
Why not?

613
01:10:57,060 --> 01:10:58,300
她和我？
With me?

614
01:11:02,390 --> 01:11:05,470
这可不是什么我擅长的事情，伙计
There are some things I'm just not good at, man.

615
01:11:09,350 --> 01:11:11,100
她怎么想的…
Where did she get...

616
01:11:13,350 --> 01:11:14,550
孩子？
A baby?

617
01:11:21,760 --> 01:11:24,770
谁知道呢？也许我会做的很好呢
Who knows? Maybe I would have been good at it.

618
01:12:30,480 --> 01:12:32,130
嘿，丹尼，丹尼？
Hey, Danny. Danny?

619
01:12:35,310 --> 01:12:38,630
我要告诉你些事，是秘密
I gotta tell you something. It's a secret.

620
01:12:40,470 --> 01:12:42,510
你想听个秘密吗？
You want to hear a secret?

621
01:12:45,130 --> 01:12:47,090
- 当然  - 在体育场里
- Sure.  - At the stadium,

622
01:12:52,470 --> 01:12:54,930
还有一些人，他们那时…
some of those people, they were...

623
01:12:57,260 --> 01:12:59,420
那时还活着，丹尼
They were still alive, Danny.

624
01:13:02,140 --> 01:13:05,220
我们却把他们丢进坟墓，然后…
We were gonna dump them in the grave and then...

625
01:13:06,840 --> 01:13:08,800
他们中有些还在动
Some of them would move.

626
01:13:11,720 --> 01:13:13,710
我看着上司
I'd look at the supervisor,

627
01:13:15,760 --> 01:13:17,890
他就假装没看到，所以…
and he'd pretend not to see, so...

628
01:13:20,510 --> 01:13:22,840
所以我们也假装没看到
So we'd pretend not to see them,

629
01:13:25,180 --> 01:13:26,560
但其实我们看到了
but we did.

630
01:13:28,260 --> 01:13:30,640
看到了，但我们还是把他们埋葬了
We did, and we'd bury them anyway.

631
01:13:32,300 --> 01:13:35,590
- 那里有好多的尸体，丹尼  - 我知道
- There were so many bodies, Danny.  - I know.

632
01:13:36,430 --> 01:13:38,680
- 真的好多  - 我知道
- So many.  - I know.

633
01:13:41,720 --> 01:13:43,930
我们怎么落到今天这步田地？
How the hell did we get here?

634
01:13:47,510 --> 01:13:51,010
- 我不知道，布莱恩  - 你知道的
- I don't know, Brian.  - You know.

635
01:13:53,680 --> 01:13:55,140
我们都知道
We both know.

636
01:13:57,090 --> 01:13:58,590
我们都知道
We both know.

637
01:14:01,180 --> 01:14:02,630
我们都知道
We both know.

638
01:14:04,300 --> 01:14:06,220
我们都…
We both...

639
01:14:48,550 --> 01:14:50,470
你要去哪，丹尼？
Where you going, Danny?

640
01:14:57,180 --> 01:14:58,970
你要去哪，伙计？
Where you going, man?

641
01:15:00,210 --> 01:15:02,010
我们要走了，布莱恩
We're leaving, Brian.

642
01:15:13,970 --> 01:15:16,960
- 快点  - 快点，快啊，快！
- Come on.  - Come on, come on, come on, come on!

643
01:15:20,590 --> 01:15:23,250
- 糟糕！ - 哦，天啊
- Shit!  - Oh, my God.

644
01:16:00,320 --> 01:16:02,320
我需要那钥匙，布莱恩
I need those keys, Brian.

645
01:16:03,360 --> 01:16:04,490
是啊
Sure.

646
01:16:06,700 --> 01:16:08,370
那我需要搭一程
And I need a ride.

647
01:16:11,080 --> 01:16:14,130
- 你知道我不能  - 想想吧，丹尼
- You know I can't.  - Come on, Danny.

648
01:16:16,550 --> 01:16:20,590
大海，你和我，再一次
The ocean, you and me, one more time.

649
01:16:22,430 --> 01:16:24,430
你记得那些情景的
You remember how it was.

650
01:16:25,810 --> 01:16:29,400
追赶海浪，嬉笑打闹
Hitting those waves before everything turned to shit.

651
01:16:30,940 --> 01:16:32,820
把钥匙给我
Just give me the keys.

652
01:16:34,650 --> 01:16:36,160
你想要吗？
You want them?

653
01:16:37,320 --> 01:16:41,160
杀了我或者带我走
Shoot me or take me with you.

654
01:16:44,920 --> 01:16:48,800
- 布莱恩，别逼我  - 我不要像他们一样，丹尼
- Brian, don't do it.  - I'm not gonna end up like them, Danny.

655
01:16:51,260 --> 01:16:53,640
独自活生生的腐烂
Rotting alive, alone.

656
01:16:55,600 --> 01:16:58,390
无法分辨是死是活
You can't tell whether they're alive or dead.

657
01:16:58,480 --> 01:17:00,940
求你了，布莱恩，别这样
Please, Brian. Don't.

658
01:17:04,360 --> 01:17:07,110
- 我们约定好的  - 我就要死了，丹尼！
- It's what we decided.  - I'm dying, Danny!

659
01:17:10,240 --> 01:17:12,790
我才不在乎什么他妈的规矩
I don't give a fuck about the rules.

660
01:17:16,550 --> 01:17:18,050
是你定的规矩
You made them.

661
01:17:20,590 --> 01:17:22,260
我的小弟弟
My little brother.

662
01:17:24,390 --> 01:17:26,810
我教会了他所有的本领
I taught him everything he knows.

663
01:18:22,550 --> 01:18:26,520
我开着车，等待着暴雨降临
I drive and wait for a storm to come

664
01:18:28,270 --> 01:18:30,060
把我们统统冲走
and wash us all away,

665
01:18:32,190 --> 01:18:33,730
但是它没有
but it doesn't.

666
01:18:39,120 --> 01:18:40,910
这是美丽的一天
It's a beautiful day.

667
01:18:42,620 --> 01:18:45,120
但它不应该是美丽的
And it shouldn't be a beautiful day.

668
01:18:48,590 --> 01:18:49,800
我等待
I wait,

669
01:18:52,340 --> 01:18:54,390
但什么都没有发生
but nothing happens to me.

670
01:18:57,980 --> 01:19:02,860
第一次，我感到我在世上孤身一人
And for the first time, I feel like I am alone in the world.

671
01:19:18,380 --> 01:19:22,510
我们终于到了两个无话可说的陌生人
We made it. Two strangers with nothing left to say.

672
01:19:28,060 --> 01:19:30,560
布莱恩和我曾经很爱这个地方
Brian and I used to love this place,

673
01:19:31,940 --> 01:19:34,400
旅馆，沙滩
the hotel, the beach.

674
01:19:39,240 --> 01:19:44,080
看起来同以往一样，但已了无生气
They still look exactly the same, but they're just places now.

675
01:19:55,430 --> 01:19:57,520
布莱恩！丹尼！快过来！
Brian! Danny! Come on!

676
01:19:57,600 --> 01:19:59,980
我不知道将会发生什么
I don't know what'll happen next.

677
01:20:01,060 --> 01:20:03,400
我不知道还能活多久
I don't know how long I'll live.

678
01:20:13,000 --> 01:20:15,080
但我知道我将孤身一人
But I know I will be alone.

679
01:20:25,000 --> 01:20:30,000
TLF中文字幕站｜http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net

680
01:20:30,000 --> 01:20:35,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

