1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
翻译｜大风　2017.5

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

3
00:00:37,240 --> 00:00:42,040
堕落天使

4
00:00:45,480 --> 00:00:49,120
在有光明之前，就有天使
Before there was light, there were angels.

5
00:00:49,560 --> 00:00:51,320
闪过片刻的黑暗
One moment darkness

6
00:00:51,440 --> 00:00:55,920
紧接着，天堂里充满了光明和高贵的众生
the next, heaven was bright with glorious beings.

7
00:00:56,240 --> 00:00:57,760
一切都很完美
It was perfect.

8
00:00:58,280 --> 00:00:59,880
但这不是结局
It did not last.

9
00:01:00,120 --> 00:01:03,150
路西法反叛上帝
Lucifer revolted against God.

10
00:01:03,160 --> 00:01:05,400
天堂里划分了阵营
A line was drawn in paradise.

11
00:01:05,480 --> 00:01:06,840
战争开始了
A war began.

12
00:01:06,960 --> 00:01:09,480
每一个天使被迫去选择
Every angel was forced to choose

13
00:01:09,800 --> 00:01:14,440
圣洁的天堂里或者混乱的天堂外
the holiness of heaven or the chaos that roiled outside.

14
00:01:14,880 --> 00:01:17,040
有一个天使拒绝了
One angel refused

15
00:01:17,080 --> 00:01:20,310
他相信唯一值得去奋斗的是
believing the only thing worth fighting for

16
00:01:20,320 --> 00:01:23,210
我们现在称之为“爱”的力量
was a force we now call love.

17
00:01:23,920 --> 00:01:25,410
他被逐出天堂
Cast out of heaven

18
00:01:25,480 --> 00:01:28,560
这个天使不是唯一堕落的
this angel did not fall alone.

19
00:01:28,680 --> 00:01:31,680
所有没有做出选择的天使
Every angel who had yet to choose

20
00:01:31,760 --> 00:01:35,520
在上帝之的愤怒中堕落
fell in a flash of almighty fury.

21
00:01:37,040 --> 00:01:39,200
这些就是堕落天使
These are the Fallen.

22
00:01:39,560 --> 00:01:41,520
从天堂被放逐
Exiled from heaven

23
00:01:41,840 --> 00:01:43,520
他们徘徊在人间
they wander the earth

24
00:01:43,600 --> 00:01:45,920
被流放，直到那反抗天使
banished until the rebel angel

25
00:01:46,040 --> 00:01:49,640
放弃爱，选择一个阵营
abandons love and takes a side.

26
00:01:55,160 --> 00:01:56,520
那是当时
That was then.

27
00:01:57,440 --> 00:01:59,040
这是现在
This is now.

28
00:02:27,720 --> 00:02:28,640
是这里？
Is that it?

29
00:02:28,720 --> 00:02:29,720
肯定是的
Must be.

30
00:03:10,400 --> 00:03:11,400
爱你
Love you.

31
00:03:14,760 --> 00:03:15,760
我的宝贝
My baby.

32
00:03:16,280 --> 00:03:18,280
我只希望我知道怎么能帮你
I just wish I knew how to help you.

33
00:03:18,640 --> 00:03:19,840
我会好好的
I'll be fine.

34
00:03:20,600 --> 00:03:21,600
看这里
Look here.

35
00:03:22,080 --> 00:03:23,080
它很小
It's small.

36
00:03:24,480 --> 00:03:27,130
我想你在生日时有礼物可以打开
I wanted you to have something to open on your birthday.

37
00:03:28,480 --> 00:03:29,480
谢谢
Thank you.

38
00:03:33,000 --> 00:03:34,000
我爱你
I love you.

39
00:03:37,560 --> 00:03:38,560
再见，爸爸
Bye, Dad.

40
00:04:25,020 --> 00:04:26,920
[创始人]
[科林·亨利·班克鲁]

41
00:04:29,400 --> 00:04:32,050
欢迎来到剑十字学院
Welcome to Sword and Cross Academy.

42
00:04:32,120 --> 00:04:35,310
这里已经为问题少年们服务超过了七十五年
For over 75 years we have served adolescents

43
00:04:35,320 --> 00:04:39,400
这些少年们因为社交和情感缺陷不能面对
who because of social and-or emotional challenges that they face

44
00:04:40,680 --> 00:04:44,840
正常传统的教育环境
have been unable to thrive in a traditional academic environment.

45
00:04:45,320 --> 00:04:49,320
在剑十字学院，我们结合了大学预科教育
At Sword and Cross we combine college preparatory education

46
00:04:49,800 --> 00:04:51,760
最先进的实践技能
cutting edge clinical services

47
00:04:52,000 --> 00:04:54,810
还有各种加强的教育方案
and diverse enrichment programs that focus on

48
00:04:54,960 --> 00:04:56,530
有助于个人成长
personal growth.

49
00:04:56,840 --> 00:04:58,120
这次你想怎么处理他？
Where do you want him this time?

50
00:04:58,280 --> 00:04:59,280
去那边
Through there.

51
00:04:59,520 --> 00:05:00,880
我马上过来
I'll be right with you.

52
00:05:11,360 --> 00:05:12,480
包括
Including

53
00:05:13,400 --> 00:05:15,150
击剑、游泳
fencing, swimming

54
00:05:15,160 --> 00:05:18,280
还有世界著名的富勒图书馆
and the use of our world renowned Fowler Library.

55
00:05:18,640 --> 00:05:24,240
我们创始人的理念是基于核心道义…
Our founder's philosophy is based upon the core principles...

56
00:05:26,920 --> 00:05:28,410
现在放下你的危险品
Now dump your hazards.

57
00:05:29,440 --> 00:05:30,160
危险品？
Hazards?

58
00:05:30,240 --> 00:05:33,400
酒精、毒品、任何类型的武器
Alcohol. Drugs. Weapons of any type.

59
00:05:33,680 --> 00:05:36,120
与帮派有关的物品和服饰
Gang related items or clothing.

60
00:05:36,360 --> 00:05:40,250
音乐播放器、平板、游戏机、笔记本电脑等
Music players, tablets, gaming systems, laptops.

61
00:05:43,360 --> 00:05:44,360
手机
Cell phones.

62
00:05:44,800 --> 00:05:45,960
不，不，不，我需要手机
No no no, I need my phone.

63
00:05:45,960 --> 00:05:48,530
每周有一次十分钟的通话特权
You get ten minutes of phone privileges once a week.

64
00:05:48,560 --> 00:05:50,320
- 你真搞笑  - 这是什么？
- You're kidding.  - What's this?

65
00:05:50,920 --> 00:05:52,720
- 我不知道，这是个礼…  - 危险品
- I don't know, it's a present...  - Hazard.

66
00:05:53,160 --> 00:05:54,650
别搞这么久，兰迪
Haven't got all day, Randy.

67
00:05:54,720 --> 00:05:55,850
我马上过来，阿瑞娜！
I'll be right there. Arriane!

68
00:05:55,880 --> 00:05:59,280
你能带露西达去宿舍吗？
Could you show Lucinda to the dorms?

69
00:06:00,080 --> 00:06:01,200
当然可以
Sure, I got it.

70
00:06:01,640 --> 00:06:03,840
午饭后，你可以拿回你的包
You can pick your bag up after lunch.

71
00:06:06,640 --> 00:06:09,320
现在跟我说说你的周未，卡马，我洗耳恭听
So tell me about your weekend, Cam. I'm all ears.

72
00:06:09,720 --> 00:06:11,440
- 阿瑞娜  - 露西
- Arriane.  - Luce.

73
00:06:13,160 --> 00:06:15,160
我们得用狗链拴住他
We're going to keep him on a very short leash.

74
00:06:15,240 --> 00:06:17,320
现在没必要控诉，比尔
There's no need to press charges this time, Bill.

75
00:06:17,360 --> 00:06:19,160
你知道我们可以搞定
You know we've got this covered.

76
00:06:19,320 --> 00:06:20,600
我们继续盯紧他
We'll keep a good eye on him.

77
00:06:21,480 --> 00:06:24,080
- 你最好离卡马远点  - 嗯，为什么？
- You're going to want to stay away from Cam.  - Yeah, why's that?

78
00:06:24,560 --> 00:06:25,800
他是个麻烦
He's trouble.

79
00:06:25,880 --> 00:06:27,240
非善类
Not the good kind.

80
00:06:31,720 --> 00:06:33,440
让我看看你的课程表
Let me see your schedule.

81
00:06:34,800 --> 00:06:36,680
很好，你和我们一个班
Good, you're with us.

82
00:06:37,160 --> 00:06:38,490
- 我们？ - 预科班
- Us?  - Prep-track.

83
00:06:38,560 --> 00:06:39,800
我们喜欢一起上大课
We tend to stick together.

84
00:06:40,360 --> 00:06:42,560
这里大多数孩子的心理有问题
Most kids here are psych referrals.

85
00:06:43,040 --> 00:06:45,240
他们很幸运地熬过一天而没有弄湿自己
They're lucky to get through the day without wetting themselves

86
00:06:45,240 --> 00:06:48,920
或者因为他们的铅笔没有削圆去攻击老师
or attacking a teacher because their pencils are unevenly sharpened.

87
00:06:49,480 --> 00:06:51,800
不过，别害怕，他们被隔离了
Don't be spooked, though. They keep them separate.

88
00:06:51,800 --> 00:06:55,240
所有严重心理缺陷的全部都在三楼
All the serious mental defectives are up on the third floor.

89
00:06:55,760 --> 00:06:58,680
这就是一个大疯人院
It's one big pharmapalooza.

90
00:06:59,360 --> 00:07:00,640
这是我的房间，二〇八
This is me. 208.

91
00:07:00,720 --> 00:07:01,720
你是哪间？
Where are you?

92
00:07:02,480 --> 00:07:03,480
三一三
313

93
00:07:04,000 --> 00:07:05,240
你在逗我，对吗？
You're messing with me, right?

94
00:07:07,680 --> 00:07:08,760
你是神经…
You're a psy...

95
00:07:11,880 --> 00:07:13,040
是的
Okay.

96
00:07:14,280 --> 00:07:15,280
嘿
Hey.

97
00:07:15,720 --> 00:07:16,760
抱歉
Sorry.

98
00:08:22,200 --> 00:08:25,640
跟我说说你的幻觉，你对它们怎么看？
Tell me about your hallucinations. What do you call them?

99
00:08:26,040 --> 00:08:27,040
幽灵
Shadows.

100
00:08:27,240 --> 00:08:28,240
幽灵
Shadows.

101
00:08:29,600 --> 00:08:31,880
什么时候开始的？
And they started when?

102
00:08:34,200 --> 00:08:35,530
在我小的时候
When I was little.

103
00:08:35,680 --> 00:08:37,880
五或六岁，我记不太清了
Five or six. I can't remember exactly.

104
00:08:41,240 --> 00:08:42,840
你一直能看到它们？
And you still see them?

105
00:08:44,000 --> 00:08:46,360
不，有一阵子没看见了
No. I haven't for a while.

106
00:09:15,240 --> 00:09:17,240
跟我说，露西达
Tell me, Lucinda.

107
00:09:18,040 --> 00:09:19,640
你认为你为什么在这里？
Why do you think you're here

108
00:09:20,160 --> 00:09:21,600
在剑十字学院？
at Sword and Cross'?

109
00:09:22,440 --> 00:09:23,770
那得问法官
Ask the judge.

110
00:09:24,160 --> 00:09:26,480
我看过你的档案，我知道法官的想法
I've read your file. I know what the judge thinks.

111
00:09:27,160 --> 00:09:29,000
我不明白的是你自己的决定
What I don't understand is your decision.

112
00:09:29,080 --> 00:09:31,840
西格尔大夫说只要按时吃药，你就很稳定
Doctor Segal says that on medication, you're stable.

113
00:09:32,000 --> 00:09:35,800
没有幻觉，没有妄想，没有噩梦
No hallucinations. No paranoia. No nightmares.

114
00:09:36,360 --> 00:09:37,850
我没有疯，你知道的
I'm not crazy, you know.

115
00:09:38,520 --> 00:09:40,920
不，没有人说你是疯子
No. Nobody's saying you're crazy.

116
00:09:41,400 --> 00:09:42,840
大家都说我是疯子
Everybody's saying that.

117
00:09:43,120 --> 00:09:47,170
你明白吗，如果你拿上处方药，你就可以离开
Do you understand, that if you take your prescribed medication you can leave.

118
00:09:48,280 --> 00:09:51,390
回家，回到你原来的学校里去
Go home. Go back to your old school.

119
00:09:51,400 --> 00:09:52,890
和你的朋友们在一起
Be with your friends.

120
00:09:53,360 --> 00:09:55,120
我不喜欢他们给我的感觉
I don't like the way they make me feel.

121
00:09:55,120 --> 00:09:59,760
但如果你拒绝，你就得呆在这里
But if you refuse, you need to be here

122
00:10:00,680 --> 00:10:04,080
就得在法院监督之下进行法定治疗
in a court sanctioned treatment facility, under supervision.

123
00:10:08,440 --> 00:10:10,040
即便这意味着被监禁
Even if it means being locked up

124
00:10:10,120 --> 00:10:13,920
我也愿意，总比我假装融入群体中要强
I'd rather be me than pretend to be something I'm not just to fit in.

125
00:10:16,680 --> 00:10:18,880
你有机会过上正常的生活
You have a chance at a normal life.

126
00:10:26,040 --> 00:10:28,690
可怜虫，她还不知道她现在的处境
Poor thing. She has no idea what she's in for.

127
00:10:28,720 --> 00:10:30,210
也许这次会不一样
Maybe it'll be different this time.

128
00:10:30,240 --> 00:10:31,240
你知道一些我不知道的事？
You know something I don't?

129
00:10:31,240 --> 00:10:33,040
有改变就是好事，就这样
It'd just be nice for a change, that's all.

130
00:10:33,040 --> 00:10:34,450
好子，我们搞有点意思的
Alright, let's make it interesting.

131
00:10:34,520 --> 00:10:36,990
我赌二十倍，露西会死于火灾，跟以往一样
Twenty to one Luce goes down in flames, just like always.

132
00:10:37,000 --> 00:10:37,920
我押一百
I'm in for a hundred.

133
00:10:37,920 --> 00:10:38,920
- 阿瑞娜！ - 什么？
- Arriane!  - What?

134
00:10:39,000 --> 00:10:40,000
- 盖比哪？ - 太残酷了
- Gabbe?  - It's cruel.

135
00:10:40,000 --> 00:10:41,330
这不是游戏，罗兰
This isn't a game, Roland.

136
00:10:41,400 --> 00:10:42,400
也许就是游戏
Maybe it is.

137
00:10:44,160 --> 00:10:45,240
又要开始了
Here we go again.

138
00:10:58,000 --> 00:11:01,970
心灵就是能让自己
The mind is its own place and in itself

139
00:11:02,040 --> 00:11:04,800
从天堂变成地狱的地方
can make a Hell of Heaven.

140
00:11:05,720 --> 00:11:06,560
这是什么？
What's that?

141
00:11:06,680 --> 00:11:08,600
弥尔顿，《失乐园》
Milton. Paradise Lost.

142
00:11:08,800 --> 00:11:10,720
- 你是露西达·派瑞司？ - 是我
- You're Lucinda Price?  - Yeah.

143
00:11:10,720 --> 00:11:14,040
我是索菲亚，你选了我的宗教哲学课程
I'm Miss Sophia. You're in my Philosophy of Religion class.

144
00:11:14,240 --> 00:11:16,360
- 你来拿你的课本？ - 是的
- Did you come for your books?  - Mm-hmm.

145
00:11:16,680 --> 00:11:20,600
预计算，英国文学，化学，宗教和历史
Pre-calc, English lit, Chemistry, Religion and History.

146
00:11:21,080 --> 00:11:23,080
噢，还差一本
Oh, still missing one.

147
00:11:23,960 --> 00:11:26,690
你介不介意？那是特殊收藏品
Would you mind? It's in special collections.

148
00:11:26,840 --> 00:11:27,840
当然
Sure.

149
00:11:31,360 --> 00:11:34,760
噢，很高兴见到你，露西
Ah, it's a pleasure to meet you, Luce.

150
00:11:36,320 --> 00:11:37,320
谢谢
Thanks.

151
00:12:27,360 --> 00:12:28,360
嘿
Hi.

152
00:12:37,320 --> 00:12:38,520
嘿，等等
Hey, wait.

153
00:12:42,720 --> 00:12:43,920
你把这个落下了
You dropped this.

154
00:13:36,080 --> 00:13:37,080
该死！
Shit!

155
00:13:37,640 --> 00:13:38,920
你吓到我了
You scared me.

156
00:13:43,600 --> 00:13:44,600
好了
Alright.

157
00:13:52,600 --> 00:13:53,960
你个可怜虫
You poor thing.

158
00:13:54,440 --> 00:13:56,760
- 天哪  - 噢，你摔倒了？
- Jeez.  - Oh, did you fall?

159
00:13:57,080 --> 00:13:58,080
你受伤了吗？
Are you hurt?

160
00:13:58,800 --> 00:14:00,240
- 我没事  - 不，你有事
- I'm fine.  - No you're not.

161
00:14:00,320 --> 00:14:03,320
你从来就一个令人作呕的存在
You've never been less fine in your whole nauseating existence.

162
00:14:03,440 --> 00:14:05,160
来这里是个错误选择
Coming here was a bad choice.

163
00:14:05,480 --> 00:14:07,960
听着，如果是我做了什么让你不安的话，我很抱歉…
Listen, if I did something to upset you, I'm sorry...

164
00:14:08,000 --> 00:14:09,570
你让我恶心
You make me sick.

165
00:14:10,000 --> 00:14:10,840
你不是东西
You're nothing.

166
00:14:10,880 --> 00:14:13,920
你眨动睫毛，摆动你的头发就想让这个世界停下来
You bat your lashes and flick your hair and expect the whole world to come to a stop.

167
00:14:13,930 --> 00:14:15,120
你根本就不认识我
You don't even know me.

168
00:14:15,200 --> 00:14:17,360
我知道你是一个杀人小疯子
I know you're a murdering little psycho.

169
00:14:27,880 --> 00:14:29,190
嘿！住手！
Hey! Break it up!

170
00:14:29,200 --> 00:14:31,240
疯婊子，你应当带上警告标签
Psycho bitch. You should come with a warning label.

171
00:14:31,520 --> 00:14:32,760
太快了吧
That was quick.

172
00:14:34,200 --> 00:14:36,800
- 她…  - 别跟我说是她先动手的
- She...  - Don't tell me she started it.

173
00:14:36,800 --> 00:14:38,150
我确信是她做的
I'm sure she did.

174
00:14:38,160 --> 00:14:40,240
不过那并不意味着我会上当
But that doesn't mean you have to take the bait.

175
00:14:41,440 --> 00:14:42,720
你是对的，我很抱歉
You're right. I'm sorry.

176
00:14:42,920 --> 00:14:45,160
打架是要被开除的
Fighting is grounds for expulsion.

177
00:14:45,520 --> 00:14:48,680
对你来说，那就是被转到州立精神病医院
Which for you would mean a transfer to the state psych hospital.

178
00:14:49,080 --> 00:14:50,410
那是你想去的地方吗？
Is that what you want?

179
00:14:51,280 --> 00:14:52,280
不是
No.

180
00:14:53,680 --> 00:14:57,600
既然今天是你的第一天，我估计你还没有看过学生守则
Since today is your first day and I'm guessing you've yet to read the code of conduct

181
00:14:58,840 --> 00:15:00,600
我罚你去打扫院子
I'll just give you yard duty.

182
00:15:02,400 --> 00:15:04,720
至于你？你跟我来
And you? You come with me.

183
00:15:25,760 --> 00:15:28,330
你知道吗，没有通行证不能进到这里来
You know you're not supposed to be in here without a pass.

184
00:15:29,920 --> 00:15:30,800
我只是，啊…
 I just, ah...

185
00:15:30,840 --> 00:15:33,040
噢，不，不，不，只是开个玩笑
Oh no no no, that was a joke.

186
00:15:33,480 --> 00:15:35,800
- 噢  - 抱歉
- Oh.  - I'm sorry.

187
00:15:36,200 --> 00:15:37,200
噢，完蛋了
Oh gosh.

188
00:15:37,720 --> 00:15:39,920
啊，不好笑吗？
Oh. Not funny?

189
00:15:40,240 --> 00:15:42,400
我这第一天可真不好过
It's just been a really rough day.

190
00:15:42,560 --> 00:15:45,290
是啊，欢迎来到剑十字学院
Yeah. Welcome to Sword and Cross.

191
00:15:46,400 --> 00:15:48,240
- 这个地方真…  - 疯狂
- This place is...  - Crazy.

192
00:15:48,600 --> 00:15:51,410
我是佩尼沃舍·凡·斯凯乐·洛克伍德，你可以叫我佩尼
I'm Pennyweather Van Syckle-Lockwood. You can call me Penn.

193
00:15:52,240 --> 00:15:53,040
好的
Okay.

194
00:15:53,120 --> 00:15:56,760
你是露西达·派瑞斯，不过大家都叫你露西
And you are Lucinda Price, but everyone calls you Luce.

195
00:15:56,840 --> 00:15:58,760
从多佛四点二高分转过来的
Transferred here from Dover with a 4.2.

196
00:15:58,920 --> 00:15:59,920
很引人注目
Impressive.

197
00:16:00,840 --> 00:16:02,040
你怎么知道的？
How did you know that?

198
00:16:02,600 --> 00:16:04,720
该死，是不是像狗仔队？
Shoot. Was that stalkery?

199
00:16:05,320 --> 00:16:06,680
是的，有一点
A little bit, yeah.

200
00:16:06,960 --> 00:16:07,880
抱歉
Sorry.

201
00:16:07,880 --> 00:16:10,810
是这样的，这是个很小的学校，真的，非常小
See the thing is, this is a really small school. Like really, really small.

202
00:16:10,840 --> 00:16:13,070
就像是无穷小，而且在这里也没什么大事
Like infinitesimally small, and not a lot happens here.

203
00:16:13,080 --> 00:16:15,680
这里不象多佛，而你是新来的女孩，还这么聪明漂亮
It's not like Dover, and you're the new girl and you're smart and you're pretty

204
00:16:15,680 --> 00:16:18,450
所以我猜你可能会是吸引大量关注的目标，
so I'm guessing that you're going to be the centre of a lot of attention

205
00:16:18,480 --> 00:16:20,160
包括正反两方面
both positive and negative.

206
00:16:21,480 --> 00:16:22,480
很好
Great.

207
00:16:24,640 --> 00:16:25,640
跟你说吧
Tell you what.

208
00:16:26,040 --> 00:16:28,240
我这就走，你忙你的
I'm gonna go, let you do your thing

209
00:16:28,280 --> 00:16:31,270
接下来如果你感觉松心点，你就能…
and then maybe if you're feeling forgiving you can...

210
00:16:31,280 --> 00:16:34,040
忘记我在厕所搭讪你的整个过程的大部分记忆
forget the whole me accosting you in the bathroom with too much information

211
00:16:34,040 --> 00:16:36,210
这时你就想你是就一个人，然后去散步
when you just want to be alone and then rambling on and on

212
00:16:36,240 --> 00:16:37,360
因为我不知道要如何才能自己停下来
because I don't know know how to stop myself

213
00:16:37,360 --> 00:16:38,810
就现在的谈话状态
from talking situation that's happening right now

214
00:16:38,840 --> 00:16:39,920
能否再给我个机会？
and give me another chance?

215
00:16:40,240 --> 00:16:41,320
我现在就走
I'll go now.

216
00:16:41,800 --> 00:16:43,480
- 嘿，佩尼？ - 嗯？
- Hey Penn?  - Yeah?

217
00:16:44,160 --> 00:16:47,560
你介意带我回宿舍吗？我有点迷路了
Do you mind showing me back to the dorms? I'm a little bit lost.

218
00:16:47,880 --> 00:16:48,880
乐意奉陪
Sure.

219
00:16:49,440 --> 00:16:50,480
谢谢
Thanks.

220
00:17:32,320 --> 00:17:36,840
如果天使真的就行走在我们之中，那在哪里呢？
What if angels actually walked among us right now, here on earth?

221
00:17:37,520 --> 00:17:39,920
这就是堕落天使的故事
That's the story of The Fallen.

222
00:17:40,200 --> 00:17:41,800
被赶出天堂的天使
Angels cast out of heaven

223
00:17:41,880 --> 00:17:45,320
注定要和我们凡人一起生活
condemned to live their lives alongside us mere mortals.

224
00:17:45,800 --> 00:17:48,530
放逐，因为他们没有选择阵营
Banished, because they failed to pick a side

225
00:17:48,530 --> 00:17:51,000
在路西法对抗天堂的战争中
In Lucifer's war against Heaven.

226
00:17:51,360 --> 00:17:53,960
谁能告诉我天堂的战争意味着什么？
Who can tell me what the war in Heaven was about?

227
00:17:54,080 --> 00:17:55,080
托德？
Todd?

228
00:17:56,280 --> 00:17:57,610
善良与邪恶的对抗？
Good versus evil?

229
00:17:57,880 --> 00:18:00,040
不，这太简单了
No, that's too simplistic.

230
00:18:00,200 --> 00:18:02,470
路西法是上帝的宠儿
Lucifer was God's favourite.

231
00:18:02,480 --> 00:18:03,920
他的光辉是最明亮的
His brightest light.

232
00:18:04,200 --> 00:18:07,010
是什么导致他对抗上帝？
What caused him to turn from God?

233
00:18:07,080 --> 00:18:08,070
有人回答吗？
Anyone?

234
00:18:08,080 --> 00:18:09,730
因为他的女友抛弃了他
'Cause his girlfriend dumped him.

235
00:18:10,680 --> 00:18:12,170
其它的天使怎么样了呢？
What happened to the other angels?

236
00:18:16,600 --> 00:18:20,080
那些与撒旦一起的被放逐到地狱
Those that sided with Satan were banished to Hell.

237
00:18:20,600 --> 00:18:22,600
只有忠诚的信徒留在了天堂
Only the faithful remained in heaven.

238
00:18:23,320 --> 00:18:27,530
而那些没有选择阵营的天使，他们被赶出了天堂
The angels that didn't choose, they were cast out.

239
00:18:27,600 --> 00:18:29,170
他们就是堕落天使
They are the Fallen.

240
00:18:30,680 --> 00:18:32,440
被迫行走人间
Forced to walk the earth

241
00:18:33,680 --> 00:18:37,320
一些堕落天使还保留了他们的天使特性
some of the Fallen retained their angelic nature

242
00:18:37,400 --> 00:18:41,290
忏悔并等待回到天堂的机会
repented and wait for the chance to return to Heaven.

243
00:18:41,560 --> 00:18:44,230
还有一些与路西法结盟
Others aligned themselves with Lucifer

244
00:18:44,240 --> 00:18:46,810
在混乱深渊里寻欢作乐
finding pleasure in mischief and chaos.

245
00:18:48,520 --> 00:18:50,840
但这两种都不能离开这个世界
But neither group can leave this world

246
00:18:51,240 --> 00:18:53,200
因为他们中有一个
because of one of their own.

247
00:18:53,920 --> 00:18:55,720
叛逆天使
The rebel angel.

248
00:18:56,000 --> 00:18:58,440
他拒绝了战争双方
He rejected both sides of the war

249
00:18:58,680 --> 00:19:00,710
上帝和路西法一样
God and Lucifer alike

250
00:19:00,720 --> 00:19:04,480
都在追寻人类的爱
all in his pursuit of human love.

251
00:19:04,920 --> 00:19:06,410
其它的堕落天使
The other fallen angels

252
00:19:06,410 --> 00:19:08,200
必须留在地球上
must remain here on earth

253
00:19:08,280 --> 00:19:13,200
直到他选择在那场唯一的战争中选择其中的一方
until he chooses a side in the only war that has ever been waged.

254
00:19:13,720 --> 00:19:17,800
而战争仍然在我们周边，每天都在持续着
The war we still see every day raging all around us.

255
00:19:18,200 --> 00:19:20,930
不过，你肯定在教堂学校里学过这些？
But surely you learned some of this in Sunday school?

256
00:19:21,240 --> 00:19:23,080
没有，我从小到大没去过教堂
No, I didn't go to church growing up.

257
00:19:23,400 --> 00:19:24,400
真的？
Really?

258
00:19:25,120 --> 00:19:27,000
是的，我父母不是信徒
Yeah, my parents aren't really religious.

259
00:19:27,640 --> 00:19:30,000
那么说来，你没有受洗过？
So, you were never baptized?

260
00:19:30,520 --> 00:19:32,170
嗯，没有
Um, no.

261
00:19:33,920 --> 00:19:36,200
那战争应该结束了吧？
Is it supposed to be over, the war?

262
00:19:36,720 --> 00:19:39,430
我是说，从神学上来说
I mean, theologically speaking

263
00:19:39,440 --> 00:19:41,000
如果魔鬼还存在
if the Devil is still alive

264
00:19:41,000 --> 00:19:43,040
是什么阻止他再次尝试呢？
What's to stop him trying from trying again?

265
00:19:43,080 --> 00:19:44,920
很好的问题
Excellent question.

266
00:20:03,040 --> 00:20:05,080
那么，还有更多的赌注吗？
So, any more takers on that bet?

267
00:20:05,200 --> 00:20:05,880
是的
Yep.

268
00:20:05,880 --> 00:20:07,450
让他们继续，罗兰
Keep them rolling, Roland.

269
00:21:01,720 --> 00:21:02,840
露西，你这个可怜虫
Luce, you poor thing.

270
00:21:03,040 --> 00:21:04,320
你还好吗？
Are you okay?

271
00:21:12,320 --> 00:21:14,840
这里怎么了？有人受伤吗？
What is going on here? Is anyone hurt?

272
00:21:17,360 --> 00:21:18,800
不，我没事
No really, I'm fine.

273
00:21:20,680 --> 00:21:22,040
吃得很好
The food is fine.

274
00:21:24,320 --> 00:21:26,760
- 一切？ - 一切，宝贝
- Anything?  - Anything, sweetie.

275
00:21:28,160 --> 00:21:31,840
一定要有肉桂煎饼和香蕉奶油，那声音…
Definitely your orange cinnamon pancakes with whipped cream with bananas. That sounds...

276
00:21:31,920 --> 00:21:32,920
嘿！
Hey!

277
00:21:34,120 --> 00:21:35,640
你说得太久了，快点
What's taking so long? Come on.

278
00:21:36,120 --> 00:21:37,120
我也要用电话
I need it.

279
00:21:39,200 --> 00:21:41,830
妈妈？妈妈？
Mom? Mom?

280
00:21:41,840 --> 00:21:45,480
定额时间结束，定额时间结束
Allocated time completed. Allocated time completed.

281
00:21:52,280 --> 00:21:54,930
我真不敢相信等了一个礼拜就说了这些东西
I just can't believe I have to wait a whole week to talk to them.

282
00:21:55,160 --> 00:21:57,090
你看，我甚至没机会说再见
You know, I didn't even get a chance to say goodbye.

283
00:21:57,120 --> 00:21:59,040
你可以在周二用我的时间打电话
You can have my time on Tuesday.

284
00:21:59,440 --> 00:22:00,040
不用
No.

285
00:22:00,040 --> 00:22:01,400
没事，我不打电话
Yeah, I'm not gonna use it.

286
00:22:01,560 --> 00:22:03,880
我在这里六年了，我认识这里的所有人
I've been here six years. Everyone I know is here

287
00:22:03,920 --> 00:22:06,440
还有，我有兴趣说话的人都是在这个房间里
and everyone I'm interested in talking to is in this room.

288
00:22:08,880 --> 00:22:10,120
那你父母呢？
What about your parents?

289
00:22:12,240 --> 00:22:13,650
我一直想问
I've been meaning to ask.

290
00:22:14,880 --> 00:22:16,560
我为什么会在这里？
How I ended up here?

291
00:22:17,640 --> 00:22:20,210
你不必告诉我，这不是什么大事
You don't have to tell me. It's not a big deal.

292
00:22:21,920 --> 00:22:24,760
嗯，在我父母离婚后
Well after my parents got divorced

293
00:22:25,120 --> 00:22:27,320
他们都不想要我，所以
neither of them really wanted me around so

294
00:22:27,320 --> 00:22:29,720
他们认为寄宿学校对我比较好
they decided that boarding school was in my best interest.

295
00:22:30,160 --> 00:22:32,480
而当我妈妈一看到宣传手册
And as soon as my Mom saw that brochure

296
00:22:32,560 --> 00:22:35,560
上面有孩子骑马、游泳之类
the one with the kids riding horses and swimming and stuff

297
00:22:36,840 --> 00:22:37,760
就这样
that was it.

298
00:22:37,760 --> 00:22:41,360
找学校的过程就结束了，我被录取了，然后我就在这里了
The search was over, I was enrolled and here I am.

299
00:22:41,960 --> 00:22:46,240
所以你不是盗窃癖，躁郁症，厌食者了？
So you're not a kleptomaniac, manic depressive, anorexic cutter?

300
00:22:46,320 --> 00:22:47,480
不是
No.

301
00:22:48,400 --> 00:22:50,440
我的诊断更糟糕
My diagnosis is much worse

302
00:22:50,520 --> 00:22:53,520
而且，我恐怕，无法治愈
and, I'm afraid, untreatable.

303
00:22:54,960 --> 00:22:56,720
我是TDP
I have TDP.

304
00:22:57,840 --> 00:22:58,960
TDP？
TDP?

305
00:23:00,040 --> 00:23:01,840
悲惨的被冷漠双亲遗弃者
Tragically Disinterested Parents.

306
00:23:03,720 --> 00:23:06,640
是的，我父母真烂
Yeah, my parents suck.

307
00:23:08,680 --> 00:23:10,250
不过这里有乐土
But there's a pool.

308
00:23:10,560 --> 00:23:12,320
不过这里有乐土
But there is a pool.

309
00:23:47,760 --> 00:23:49,480
你在和我开玩笑吧
You've gotta be kidding me.

310
00:23:54,640 --> 00:23:56,130
别告诉我
Don't tell me.

311
00:23:56,640 --> 00:23:58,320
卡马在恋爱？
Is Cam in love?

312
00:24:01,400 --> 00:24:03,240
这可会给你制造麻烦
That could make things difficult for you.

313
00:24:03,680 --> 00:24:05,680
别忘记你是给谁工作的
Just don't forget who you work for.

314
00:24:09,360 --> 00:24:10,800
丹尼尔
Daniel.

315
00:24:11,000 --> 00:24:12,880
我昨天没机会对你说谢谢
I didn't get a chance to say thanks yesterday.

316
00:24:13,400 --> 00:24:14,400
别客气
Don't mention it.

317
00:24:15,760 --> 00:24:17,480
总之，无论如何要谢谢你
Well thank you anyway.

318
00:24:18,840 --> 00:24:21,370
还有一件事，我有点不好意思问，可是…
There's one more thing I'm a little embarrassed to even ask but...

319
00:24:21,400 --> 00:24:22,600
那就别问
Well then don't.

320
00:24:23,200 --> 00:24:25,400
嗯，我现在很肯定，我一定要搞清楚
Well I've committed now. I'm just going to go for it.

321
00:24:25,400 --> 00:24:27,360
就是你看起来很面熟
It's just you seem really familiar to me.

322
00:24:27,840 --> 00:24:29,560
就好像我在哪里见过你
Like I know you from somewhere.

323
00:24:29,880 --> 00:24:31,400
- 有可能吗？ - 不可能
- Is that possible?  - No.

324
00:24:33,120 --> 00:24:34,480
我会记得你
I'd remember you.

325
00:24:34,880 --> 00:24:36,560
因为我一直在想…
Because I keep thinking that...

326
00:24:36,600 --> 00:24:38,560
我得走了，好吗？回头见
I've gotta go, alright? I'll see you later.

327
00:24:54,080 --> 00:24:55,080
谢谢你
Thank you.

328
00:24:56,160 --> 00:24:58,840
嗨，新来的同学，刚来的头几天就很不平凡啊
Hey new girl. Pretty eventful first few days.

329
00:24:59,160 --> 00:25:00,650
是不是已经开始计划逃离了？
Already planning your escape?

330
00:25:00,720 --> 00:25:02,680
嗯，正在考虑
Yeah, considering it.

331
00:25:03,960 --> 00:25:06,200
你啊，你想来点早餐吗？
You ah, you want some breakfast?

332
00:25:07,440 --> 00:25:10,320
很诱人，不过我上课快要迟到了
That's tempting, but I'm actually running late to class.

333
00:25:10,320 --> 00:25:12,040
迟到总比不上强
It's better never than late.

334
00:25:25,280 --> 00:25:26,560
这真不错
This is really good.

335
00:25:28,080 --> 00:25:29,160
哪里搞来的？
Where's it from?

336
00:25:30,320 --> 00:25:32,560
我从教师休息室里偷来的
I stole it from the faculty lounge.

337
00:25:33,040 --> 00:25:35,080
那里有个非常不错的咖啡机
They have a pretty decent espresso machine.

338
00:25:37,560 --> 00:25:38,920
你真无可救药
You're incorrigible.

339
00:25:39,680 --> 00:25:40,840
他们也这么说我
That's what they tell me.

340
00:25:41,080 --> 00:25:42,240
你不同意吗？
You don't agree?

341
00:25:44,400 --> 00:25:45,680
我知道我喜欢什么
I just know what I like.

342
00:25:46,560 --> 00:25:48,760
而且你还不择手段
And you don't mind breaking the rules to get it.

343
00:25:49,560 --> 00:25:50,560
很好
Well

344
00:25:51,240 --> 00:25:53,360
如果冒险是值得奖励的
if the risk is worth the reward

345
00:25:58,080 --> 00:25:59,360
我不明白为什么不做呢？
I don't see why not.

346
00:26:01,760 --> 00:26:02,950
你怎么样？
What about you?

347
00:26:02,960 --> 00:26:05,560
在剑十字学院，你不会一直遵规守纪的
You don't end up at Sword and Cross by following the rules.

348
00:26:05,720 --> 00:26:07,080
你内心有点小叛逆？
You got a little rebel in you?

349
00:26:09,680 --> 00:26:11,200
我只是有点被误解了
I'm just misunderstood.

350
00:26:11,960 --> 00:26:13,080
不，我看出来了
No, I see it.

351
00:26:15,160 --> 00:26:16,320
你很引人注目
You got a spark.

352
00:26:17,040 --> 00:26:18,040
你说什么？
What do you mean?

353
00:26:19,000 --> 00:26:22,890
我是说，你是那种宁愿做自己认为对的事，而不是只听话的那种人
Means you're the kind of person who'd rather do what's right than what you're told.

354
00:26:24,720 --> 00:26:25,960
换句话说，你是个麻烦人物
It means you're trouble.

355
00:26:27,840 --> 00:26:29,680
你觉得你很了解我，嗯哼？
You think you know me, huh?

356
00:26:31,280 --> 00:26:32,800
我知道我喜欢什么
I know what I like.

357
00:26:46,120 --> 00:26:47,120
时间到了
Time's up.

358
00:26:52,280 --> 00:26:54,240
罗兰在这周五要举办个舞会
Roland's having a party this Friday.

359
00:26:54,240 --> 00:26:55,470
- 是吗？ - 是非正式的
- Yeah?  - It's just casual.

360
00:26:55,480 --> 00:26:57,050
- 你可以带个朋友来  - 好的
- You can bring a friend.  - Okay.

361
00:26:57,120 --> 00:27:00,160
我们在周末聚在一起，放松一下压力
Bunch of us get together at the end of the week to blow off some steam.

362
00:27:00,520 --> 00:27:01,520
谢谢
Thanks.

363
00:27:04,440 --> 00:27:05,850
你不上课吗？
Aren't you in this class?

364
00:27:06,120 --> 00:27:07,960
哦，我以前已经听过了
Oh, I've heard it all before.

365
00:27:17,920 --> 00:27:19,680
准备！开始！
En garde! Allez!

366
00:27:24,520 --> 00:27:26,240
他们怎么会想搞这个课程的呢？
How well did they think this through?

367
00:27:26,800 --> 00:27:29,120
你想啊，给重症问题少年一个武器
You know, giving weapons to heavily medicated teenagers

368
00:27:29,120 --> 00:27:31,080
是很难道控制冲动和愤怒的
with poor impulse control and anger issues.

369
00:27:34,280 --> 00:27:35,280
停！
Halt!

370
00:27:35,480 --> 00:27:37,960
好了，换对手，斯帕克斯，你上
Alright, change partners. Sparks, you're up.

371
00:27:38,840 --> 00:27:41,680
派瑞斯，让我们看看你有没有认真听课
Price, let's see if you've been paying attention.

372
00:27:45,600 --> 00:27:46,930
记住我刚才的示范了吗？
Remember what I showed you?

373
00:27:47,440 --> 00:27:48,520
记得不太全
Not really.

374
00:27:51,880 --> 00:27:53,040
预备！
En garde!

375
00:27:56,240 --> 00:27:57,240
开始！
Allez!

376
00:28:05,800 --> 00:28:07,080
不算很差嘛
That wasn't terrible

377
00:28:07,160 --> 00:28:09,080
考虑到你只是第一次上课
considering it was just your first time.

378
00:28:09,480 --> 00:28:10,480
好了
Alright.

379
00:28:10,760 --> 00:28:11,800
交换对手
Switch partners.

380
00:28:12,320 --> 00:28:14,000
格里戈里，快点
Grigori. Come on over.

381
00:28:18,480 --> 00:28:19,480
准备！
En garde!

382
00:28:20,240 --> 00:28:21,240
开始！
Allez!

383
00:29:09,600 --> 00:29:10,600
非常好
Very good.

384
00:29:10,680 --> 00:29:12,170
再来一次，准备
One more. En garde.

385
00:29:16,680 --> 00:29:17,680
开始！
Allez!

386
00:29:26,800 --> 00:29:28,000
格里戈里，停下
Grigori, halt.

387
00:29:29,040 --> 00:29:30,040
停！
Halt!

388
00:29:31,080 --> 00:29:32,080
停！
Halt!

389
00:29:34,840 --> 00:29:36,200
你们两个，停下！
Both of you, halt!

390
00:30:04,880 --> 00:30:06,370
我花了一礼拜搞这个
I give it a week.

391
00:30:06,440 --> 00:30:08,720
是关于整个洗礼的事吗？对她有影响吗？
What about the whole baptism thing? Could that affect her?

392
00:30:08,920 --> 00:30:10,080
细节并不重要
The details don't matter.

393
00:30:10,080 --> 00:30:14,400
格里戈里总是能找一些事让自己入迷，不过那根本没什么用
Grigori always finds something to obsess over but it never makes a difference.

394
00:30:14,480 --> 00:30:17,880
现在你只需要放松，然后接受露西要死了的现实
Now y'all just need to relax and accept that Luce is gonna die

395
00:30:18,000 --> 00:30:21,160
而且无论你、丹尼尔、索菲亚小姐做什么都不能阻止
and there's nothing you or Daniel or Miss Sophia can do to stop it.

396
00:30:21,640 --> 00:30:23,210
我以为你以前从来没有击过剑呢
I thought you'd never done this before?

397
00:30:23,400 --> 00:30:24,480
我是没有
I haven't.

398
00:30:24,800 --> 00:30:26,680
我的身体好像被接管了
My body just took over.

399
00:30:27,360 --> 00:30:28,850
就好像自己知道该怎么做一样
Like I knew exactly what to do.

400
00:30:28,920 --> 00:30:29,920
嗯
Huh.

401
00:30:30,000 --> 00:30:31,360
这很诡异，你以前有没有这种感觉？
It was weird. Have you ever felt that?

402
00:30:31,360 --> 00:30:33,800
有，就像我做三角函数一样
Yeah, I was kinda like that with trigonometry.

403
00:30:34,080 --> 00:30:36,160
所有题目都豁然开朗了，一开始我还以为
It all just fell into place so at first I was like

404
00:30:36,520 --> 00:30:38,230
“哇，我是天才，”
'wow, I'm a genius.'

405
00:30:38,240 --> 00:30:42,400
不过紧接着我就想起来，去年已经复习过了，所以我想那不过是我没记住而已
But then I remembered that we covered it last year so I guess that's not as impressive.

406
00:30:44,960 --> 00:30:46,450
你爱上他了，嗯？
You got it bad, huh?

407
00:30:48,320 --> 00:30:49,600
不，不是这样的
No, it's not like that.

408
00:30:50,400 --> 00:30:51,680
嗯，也许吧
Well, maybe it is.

409
00:30:52,240 --> 00:30:54,080
只是我对丹尼尔有一些感觉
It's just I have these feelings about Daniel.

410
00:30:54,160 --> 00:30:55,490
好像我认识他
Like I know him.

411
00:30:55,640 --> 00:30:57,600
就像我认识他好长时间了一样
Like I've known him for a really long time.

412
00:30:57,720 --> 00:31:00,450
好吧，也许你们一起上过幼儿园之类的
Yeah, maybe you guys went to preschool together or something.

413
00:31:00,800 --> 00:31:03,320
我问过他以前是否见过面，他说没有
Well I asked him if we'd met before and he said no

414
00:31:03,320 --> 00:31:05,400
而且他基本上立刻就跑开了，这很奇怪
and he basically ran away. It was strange.

415
00:31:05,480 --> 00:31:06,480
是啊
Yeah.

416
00:31:07,120 --> 00:31:11,010
有些事情的确不寻常…嗯
Something definitely not quite... hmm.

417
00:31:11,520 --> 00:31:12,520
你想说什么？
What do you mean?

418
00:31:15,640 --> 00:31:17,280
你不要跟别人说，要不我会很麻烦的
I can get in a lot of trouble if you tell anybody

419
00:31:17,290 --> 00:31:18,650
我要跟你说一些事，好吗？
what I'm about to say to you, okay?

420
00:31:18,680 --> 00:31:19,680
我不会说的
I won't.

421
00:31:19,840 --> 00:31:21,920
我之所以会在空闲时间在办公室做志愿者
So I volunteer in the office for my free period

422
00:31:21,920 --> 00:31:24,840
这听上去很无聊，但实际上很酷很有意思
which I know sounds totally lame but is actually kind of cool and fun

423
00:31:24,840 --> 00:31:26,560
是我自己的怪癖，有点吧
in its own weird way, sort of.

424
00:31:27,000 --> 00:31:30,840
原来兰迪对电脑根本一窍不通
Turns out Randy is totally useless when it comes to computers.

425
00:31:30,840 --> 00:31:33,730
所以他会问你一些最基本的知识，比如
So he asks yours truly to do the most basic tasks like

426
00:31:33,760 --> 00:31:37,520
找桌面上的文件，找一些喷嚏刺猬之类视频
find files on his desktop and search for videos of sneezing hedgehogs or whatever.

427
00:31:37,680 --> 00:31:39,010
这意味着
Meaning

428
00:31:40,160 --> 00:31:44,480
我可以全权进入学校每一个人的档案
I have full access to everybody's academic records.

429
00:31:45,640 --> 00:31:47,320
我看了丹尼尔的档案
I've looked at Daniel's file.

430
00:31:48,160 --> 00:31:49,490
是空白的
It's empty-

431
00:31:50,240 --> 00:31:53,840
他没有家庭地址，没有紧急联络人，什么也没有
He's got no home address, no emergency contact, nothing.

432
00:31:53,840 --> 00:31:55,120
- 你喜欢这件吗？ - 喜欢
- Do you like this?  - Yeah.

433
00:31:56,200 --> 00:31:57,920
和那群孩子们一样
It's the same with all those kids.

434
00:31:58,560 --> 00:32:00,810
那一群人总有一些不对劲
There's just something not quite right about that whole group.

435
00:32:00,840 --> 00:32:03,250
你从未听他们说起过家人、原来的学校
You never hear them talk about their families or their old schools.

436
00:32:03,280 --> 00:32:06,720
他们几乎不去上课，而且好像彼此以前都相互认识
They barely ever go to class and it's like they all knew each other from before.

437
00:32:06,800 --> 00:32:07,920
等等，你说的是哪些人？
Wait, who do you mean?

438
00:32:08,000 --> 00:32:09,080
丹尼尔第一个来的
Daniel arrived first.

439
00:32:09,120 --> 00:32:12,270
他是去年年初来的，接着是盖比
He transferred at the beginning of last year and then Gabbe.

440
00:32:12,280 --> 00:32:14,050
是那高个金发女郎，总是跟在他的边上的那个？
The tall blonde that's always hanging around him?

441
00:32:14,080 --> 00:32:16,650
是的，百分之八十五的果糖甜美度
Yep, 85 percent confectionery sugar by volume.

442
00:32:16,720 --> 00:32:17,960
接下来是阿瑞娜
Then Arriane.

443
00:32:18,080 --> 00:32:19,770
噢，是的，第一天就是她带着我转的
Oh yeah, she showed me around my first day.

444
00:32:19,800 --> 00:32:21,560
还有莫莉，严重智障
And Molly. Serious defective.

445
00:32:21,600 --> 00:32:25,200
至于罗兰，我真不知道他是如何通过每周尿检的
And Roland, I have literally no idea how he passes his weekly pee test

446
00:32:25,200 --> 00:32:29,070
而二十五岁的未来先生，卡马，是去年春天转过来的
and then Mr. Future 25 Years to Life, Cam, transferred in last spring.

447
00:32:29,080 --> 00:32:30,080
索菲亚小姐也是其中之一
Miss Sophia, too.

448
00:32:30,080 --> 00:32:33,200
她是今年新来的，除了她喜欢的，根本无视其它人
She's new this year and totally ignores everyone except her favourites.

449
00:32:34,080 --> 00:32:35,130
那你怎么看？
Well what do you make of it?

450
00:32:35,160 --> 00:32:36,730
难住我了
Beats me.

451
00:32:43,240 --> 00:32:45,000
- 我真不敢相信  - 什么事？
- I can't believe it.  - What?

452
00:32:45,080 --> 00:32:47,480
我事实上要去参加一个罗兰的聚会
I'm actually going to one of Roland's parties.

453
00:32:53,240 --> 00:32:55,000
噢，你们俩看上去真可爱
Oh, don't you two look lovely?

454
00:32:55,480 --> 00:32:56,520
谢谢
Thanks.

455
00:32:57,560 --> 00:32:58,970
你也是，一如既往
You do too. As always.

456
00:32:59,640 --> 00:33:00,720
你真可爱
Aren't you sweet.

457
00:33:03,520 --> 00:33:05,120
我有点讨厌她，这是不是有问题？
Is it wrong that I kind of hate her?

458
00:33:05,160 --> 00:33:08,000
为什么，就因为她完美无瑕，蜂蜜香甜，阳光肌肤，
Why, because she's a flawless, honey-scented, spray tanned,

459
00:33:08,000 --> 00:33:10,880
比基尼性感，还总是而带微笑、金发碧眼的大美女
Bikini waxed manicured blond-fembot who's always smiling

460
00:33:10,880 --> 00:33:13,320
而且还在这时亲吻你的暗恋对象？
and is at this moment kissing your crush?

461
00:33:13,960 --> 00:33:15,450
是的，几乎就是这样
Yeah, pretty much that.

462
00:33:16,080 --> 00:33:18,520
也许是错的，不过我完全明白
It might be wrong, but I totally get it.

463
00:33:20,240 --> 00:33:21,760
有人要饮料吗？
Anybody order drinks?

464
00:33:37,160 --> 00:33:39,840
我还在想你怎么会在这里
I'm still trying to figure out how you ended up here.

465
00:33:40,000 --> 00:33:41,600
好吧，是你请的我，记得吗？
Well you invited me, remember.

466
00:33:41,680 --> 00:33:43,200
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.

467
00:33:43,880 --> 00:33:46,000
你想加入我们，对吗？
With the rest of us it's obvious, right?

468
00:33:46,560 --> 00:33:47,560
吸毒者
Drugs.

469
00:33:47,920 --> 00:33:49,080
破坏狂
Vandalism.

470
00:33:49,480 --> 00:33:50,480
抑郁者
Depression.

471
00:33:51,160 --> 00:33:52,400
色情狂
Nymphomania.

472
00:33:55,520 --> 00:33:58,120
那么，你为什么会来这种的地方呢？
So why did you end up at a place like this?

473
00:33:59,080 --> 00:34:01,400
也许我并不像我看上去的那么天真
Maybe I'm not as innocent as I look.

474
00:34:22,200 --> 00:34:23,920
- 你好  - 嗨
- Hello.  - Hi.

475
00:34:24,600 --> 00:34:26,280
这是飞行莲花夹克吗？
Is that a Flying Lotus jacket?

476
00:34:26,520 --> 00:34:27,520
是的
Yeah.

477
00:34:28,080 --> 00:34:30,040
你真够风骚的
You are such a hipster.

478
00:34:31,400 --> 00:34:33,160
我说的是…是褒义词的含义
In... in a good way, I mean.

479
00:34:33,920 --> 00:34:36,040
你知道的，不是你故意去装逼
Like you know, it's not like you're trying to be cool.

480
00:34:36,920 --> 00:34:38,360
你是真的很酷
Like you're actually cool.

481
00:34:39,440 --> 00:34:40,440
哇
Wow.

482
00:34:41,680 --> 00:34:43,800
在我的一生中，被人扣过好多帽子
I've been accused of a lot of things in my life

483
00:34:44,320 --> 00:34:45,520
但从来没人说过我酷
but never that.

484
00:34:54,120 --> 00:34:55,750
- 嘿  - 噢，嘿，谢谢
- Hey.  - Oh, hey. Thank you.

485
00:34:55,760 --> 00:34:56,720
噢，这是给我的吗？
Oh, is that for me?

486
00:34:56,720 --> 00:34:58,840
太神了，非常感谢，谢谢
Amazing. Thank you so much. Thank you.

487
00:34:59,200 --> 00:35:00,200
好吧
Sure.

488
00:35:00,560 --> 00:35:01,560
呃…
Um...

489
00:35:01,760 --> 00:35:02,880
那么…
So...

490
00:35:04,400 --> 00:35:05,920
这是个表演秀，还是…？
Is it from a show, or...?

491
00:35:05,960 --> 00:35:07,560
是的，他会有惊人的现场秀
Yeah. He's amazing live.

492
00:35:07,640 --> 00:35:09,400
我在阿什维尔见过他与蒂伯斯的现场秀
I saw him in Asheville with Teebs.

493
00:35:09,520 --> 00:35:12,400
不可能，蒂伯斯是我最喜欢的超级嘻哈艺人
Get out of it. Teebs is my favourite post-Dilla artist.

494
00:35:12,400 --> 00:35:13,720
哈，霹雳猫乐改变了我的生活
Well Thundercat changed my life.

495
00:35:13,720 --> 00:35:15,880
噢，不，也许不只是霹雳猫乐
Well no, except maybe for Thundercat.

496
00:35:16,000 --> 00:35:17,880
那你听过白昼混音吗？
Have you heard the Daylight remix?

497
00:35:18,240 --> 00:35:19,240
那是贝斯
That bass.

498
00:35:20,040 --> 00:35:21,040
说对了
Exactly.

499
00:35:24,000 --> 00:35:25,040
是
Yes.

500
00:35:35,640 --> 00:35:36,840
可怕的记忆？
Bad memories?

501
00:35:37,920 --> 00:35:39,490
这么说，你还一直在想着他？
So do you still think about him?

502
00:35:39,880 --> 00:35:40,880
谁？
Who?

503
00:35:41,640 --> 00:35:43,840
被你杀掉的那个男孩，特雷弗
The boy you killed. Trevor.

504
00:35:44,840 --> 00:35:47,360
你记得的，高高的个，温柔的眼睛
You know, tall, easy on the eyes.

505
00:35:48,240 --> 00:35:50,720
至少在他勾搭上你之前是这样的
Well at least he was before he hooked up with you.

506
00:35:51,120 --> 00:35:53,080
现在他不会这么看了
Now he's not so much to look at.

507
00:35:53,480 --> 00:35:54,760
你怎么会知道他的？
How do you know about him?

508
00:35:55,080 --> 00:35:57,520
- 我对你非常了解，疯狂的露西  - 离我远点
- I know a lot about you, Crazy Luce.  - Get that away from me.

509
00:35:58,000 --> 00:36:01,240
我敢打赌，我比你自己还要了解你
I'll bet I know you better than you know yourself.

510
00:36:03,840 --> 00:36:06,360
对于不喜欢火某些人来说，确实会喜欢上你
For someone who doesn't like fire, it sure does seem to like you.

511
00:36:06,360 --> 00:36:07,280
够了！
That's enough!

512
00:36:07,280 --> 00:36:10,290
闭嘴，阿瑞，要不我给你脸上加个伤疤，好与你背上的伤疤匹配
Shut up, Arri, before I give you a scar on your face to match the one on your back.

513
00:36:10,320 --> 00:36:11,810
退后，莫莉
Back off, Molly.

514
00:36:12,920 --> 00:36:14,520
- 你还好吗？ - 嗯，我没事
- Are you okay?  - Yeah, I'm fine.

515
00:36:15,000 --> 00:36:15,960
你在做什么？
What are you doing?

516
00:36:16,000 --> 00:36:18,160
我不过在和你的疯女友搞点乐子
Just having some fun with your psycho girlfriend.

517
00:36:18,200 --> 00:36:19,920
离露西远点
Stay away from Luce.

518
00:36:20,440 --> 00:36:21,400
你听到了没？
You hear me?

519
00:36:21,440 --> 00:36:23,120
噢，你已经越轨了，卡马
Oh, you've lost track, Cam.

520
00:36:23,560 --> 00:36:26,210
你总想要你得不到的东西
You always want what you can't have.

521
00:36:31,040 --> 00:36:32,800
这回她是我的
This time she's mine.

522
00:36:33,840 --> 00:36:34,960
放开我！
Lay off me!

523
00:36:39,160 --> 00:36:40,840
外太空肯定有生命
There's definitely life in outer space!

524
00:36:40,920 --> 00:36:42,360
嘿！露西去哪了？
Hey! Where's Luce?

525
00:36:42,440 --> 00:36:44,600
噢，我不知道，我还以为她和你在一起
Um, I don't know. I thought that she was with you.

526
00:36:46,240 --> 00:36:46,920
好的
Okay.

527
00:36:47,000 --> 00:36:48,370
她不需要你的帮助
She doesn't need your kind of help.

528
00:36:48,400 --> 00:36:49,800
谁来保护她，你吗？
Who's gonna protect her, you?

529
00:36:49,800 --> 00:36:53,120
嘿，你们这些爱情鸟需要放松，嗯？现在是派对时间
You know, you lovebirds need to relax, huh? It's a party.

530
00:36:55,160 --> 00:36:57,250
你知道吗，我突然感觉非常累，真的
You know, I'm feeling pretty tired all of a sudden, actually.

531
00:36:57,280 --> 00:36:58,510
我想我应当走了
I think I'm just gonna go.

532
00:36:58,520 --> 00:36:59,680
你需要我陪你一起走吗？
You want me to walk with you?

533
00:36:59,720 --> 00:37:01,290
不用，没事的，你应当留下来
No, it's okay. You should stay.

534
00:37:30,000 --> 00:37:31,000
喂？
Hello?

535
00:37:45,160 --> 00:37:46,160
莫莉
Molly.

536
00:37:48,040 --> 00:37:49,920
莫莉，出来吧，我知道是你
Molly, come on. I know it's you.

537
00:38:58,200 --> 00:38:59,200
特雷弗在哪里？
Where's Trevor?

538
00:38:59,440 --> 00:39:00,600
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

539
00:39:01,240 --> 00:39:02,040
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.

540
00:39:02,040 --> 00:39:04,240
你干了什么，你这个怪物！
What did you do, you freak!

541
00:39:04,480 --> 00:39:05,520
这是我的错
It's my fault.

542
00:39:05,680 --> 00:39:06,800
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

543
00:39:47,600 --> 00:39:49,960
那么同我说说，在剑十字的第一周过得怎么样？
So tell me, how was your first week at Sword and Cross'?

544
00:39:51,200 --> 00:39:52,200
很好
Fine.

545
00:39:59,640 --> 00:40:01,320
没有事情要说？
No incidents to report?

546
00:40:01,600 --> 00:40:03,640
幻觉？噩梦？
Visions? Nightmares?

547
00:40:04,920 --> 00:40:05,920
没有
No.

548
00:40:06,880 --> 00:40:08,290
那你的幽灵怎么样了？
What about your shadows?

549
00:40:15,000 --> 00:40:16,000
好
Good.

550
00:40:17,680 --> 00:40:18,680
很好
Good.

551
00:40:20,880 --> 00:40:21,880
非常好
Good.

552
00:41:42,400 --> 00:41:43,400
你怎么了？
What's wrong?

553
00:41:45,280 --> 00:41:46,280
没事
Nothing.

554
00:41:49,400 --> 00:41:51,120
我还是无法摆脱
I just can't get past it.

555
00:41:52,120 --> 00:41:53,120
什么？
What?

556
00:41:54,640 --> 00:41:56,360
我认识你的那种感觉
This feeling that I know you.

557
00:42:00,400 --> 00:42:01,730
我们之前不是说过了吗？
Haven't we been through this?

558
00:42:03,320 --> 00:42:04,320
是的，可是…
Yeah, but...

559
00:42:07,040 --> 00:42:08,370
我不相信你
I don't believe you.

560
00:42:10,920 --> 00:42:12,640
我们之间有某种关联
There is something between us.

561
00:42:13,240 --> 00:42:15,000
而且你也感觉到了，对吗？
And you feel it too, don't you?

562
00:42:15,400 --> 00:42:16,840
好吧，好吧
Alright. Okay.

563
00:42:18,160 --> 00:42:20,200
你说得对，我应当告诉你真相
You're right. I should have just told you the truth.

564
00:42:21,080 --> 00:42:22,200
就是…
It's...

565
00:42:23,440 --> 00:42:26,720
我意识到，我对你没那么热情，还有…
Like I realise I haven't been very warm towards you, and...

566
00:42:26,720 --> 00:42:28,080
你就是个混蛋
You've been a real dick.

567
00:42:28,360 --> 00:42:29,320
我是混蛋，可你要相信我
Yeah, but believe me.

568
00:42:29,320 --> 00:42:31,890
你得知道，这并不是因为你做了什么
You've got to know it's not because of anything you've done.

569
00:42:32,640 --> 00:42:33,750
听着，有个女孩…
See, there's this girl...

570
00:42:33,760 --> 00:42:34,760
是说盖比？
Gabbe?

571
00:42:35,680 --> 00:42:37,170
什么？不是
What? No.

572
00:42:37,280 --> 00:42:40,920
不，不是盖比，不，是另外一个人，另一个女孩
No, not Gabbe. No, just someone else. Another girl.

573
00:42:41,160 --> 00:42:43,810
我想你会说我跟她分手了，但是
I guess you could say I'm not with her anymore, but

574
00:42:44,880 --> 00:42:46,040
我一直爱着她
I still love her.

575
00:42:47,760 --> 00:42:48,850
其实我想说的是…
What I'm trying to say is...

576
00:42:48,880 --> 00:42:51,360
你是个烂仔，我最好离你远点？
You're a mess and I'm better off without you?

577
00:42:53,200 --> 00:42:54,530
差不多这个意思
Something like that.

578
00:42:55,800 --> 00:42:57,080
事情没这么简单
It's not that simple.

579
00:42:58,400 --> 00:43:00,240
你无法跟别人说出你的感受
You can't tell someone how to feel.

580
00:43:00,840 --> 00:43:01,840
是的
Yeah.

581
00:43:02,200 --> 00:43:03,690
我希望情况会有所不同
I wish things could be different.

582
00:43:07,360 --> 00:43:08,690
嗨！别走
Hey! Don't go.

583
00:43:37,760 --> 00:43:39,920
你在这里啊，我很担心你
There you are. I was worried about you.

584
00:43:40,000 --> 00:43:42,120
你没说拜拜就离开了派对
You left the party without saying goodbye.

585
00:43:43,160 --> 00:43:44,160
怎么了？
What's wrong?

586
00:43:45,040 --> 00:43:45,880
露西？
Luce?

587
00:43:45,920 --> 00:43:47,410
站住！告诉我！
Stop! Talk to me!

588
00:43:48,080 --> 00:43:50,280
昨晚我和莫莉有一次有趣的对话
I had an interesting conversation with Molly last night.

589
00:43:50,320 --> 00:43:51,320
好吧
Okay.

590
00:43:51,480 --> 00:43:53,130
她知道我的一些事情
She knew things about me.

591
00:43:53,400 --> 00:43:55,050
而那些事情我从来没同别人说过
Things I haven't shared with anyone.

592
00:43:55,050 --> 00:43:56,240
那然后…？
And...?

593
00:43:56,320 --> 00:43:58,280
是有人告诉她的
Someone's been talking to her.

594
00:43:58,480 --> 00:44:00,080
那人看过我的档案
Someone who's read my file.

595
00:44:01,360 --> 00:44:03,720
噢，好吧，因为这样才说得通
Oh right, 'cause that makes perfect sense.

596
00:44:03,720 --> 00:44:07,000
我背叛你的信任，成了一个无情的、没有灵魂的、没有想象力的傻逼
I betrayed your trust to a ruthless, soulless, unimaginative bully

597
00:44:07,000 --> 00:44:09,890
去和那不讲卫生，说话智联的家伙告密，图的是什么？
with suspect hygiene and poor language skills in exchange for what?

598
00:44:10,000 --> 00:44:13,360
噢，就为了穿两个免费耳洞和画那囚犯纹身？
Oh, two free body piercings and a prison tattoo.

599
00:44:13,440 --> 00:44:16,480
而且我还得确保能脱离干系，但是你却轻易发现了我
I was sure I'd get away with it, but you caught me.

600
00:44:17,640 --> 00:44:20,480
好吧，至少你是足够实诚能承认
Well, at least you're big enough to admit it.

601
00:44:21,080 --> 00:44:22,920
怎么了？真的？
What's wrong? Really?

602
00:44:26,080 --> 00:44:27,650
你看过我的档案，对吗？
You have read my file, haven't you?

603
00:44:27,720 --> 00:44:28,800
当然
Of course.

604
00:44:29,400 --> 00:44:30,680
所以你知道…
So then you know about...

605
00:44:30,960 --> 00:44:32,370
你的幽灵？
Your shadows?

606
00:44:33,320 --> 00:44:34,320
你一直还能看到幽灵吗？
Do you still see them?

607
00:44:34,440 --> 00:44:35,440
是的
Yeah.

608
00:44:37,360 --> 00:44:38,520
那你现在看到了吗？
Do you see them right now?

609
00:44:38,600 --> 00:44:42,000
没有，但我来这里后，幻觉变得更糟糕了
No. But since I've been here they've gotten a lot worse.

610
00:44:42,720 --> 00:44:44,210
让我很害怕
And I'm scared.

611
00:44:44,480 --> 00:44:46,050
我害怕会让别人受伤
I'm scared somebody's going to get hurt.

612
00:44:46,050 --> 00:44:47,450
不，别傻了
No, don't be ridiculous.

613
00:44:47,480 --> 00:44:48,520
我没有
I'm not.

614
00:44:50,160 --> 00:44:51,760
特雷弗就站在那里
Trevor was just standing there.

615
00:44:52,960 --> 00:44:54,480
他就站在那里
He was just standing there

616
00:44:54,480 --> 00:44:57,920
- 我们…  - 告诉我…告诉我到底发生了什么
- and we...  - Okay. Tell me... tell me exactly what happened.

617
00:44:57,960 --> 00:45:00,000
特雷弗一整年假装不理我
Trevor acted like I didn't exist all year

618
00:45:00,000 --> 00:45:02,360
可突然在派对上对我调情
and then suddenly at this party he was flirting with me.

619
00:45:02,440 --> 00:45:04,120
来吧，跟我去小屋
Come up to the cabin with me.

620
00:45:06,280 --> 00:45:08,640
就这次我感觉
Just one time I wanted to feel

621
00:45:09,440 --> 00:45:10,640
正常
normal.

622
00:45:11,200 --> 00:45:13,280
- 你来一杯吗？ - 好的
- You want a drink?  - Sure.

623
00:45:26,800 --> 00:45:27,800
你听到了没有？
Did you hear that?

624
00:45:28,960 --> 00:45:30,760
特雷弗，你确定这里就我们俩吗？
Trevor, are you sure that we're alone?

625
00:45:31,120 --> 00:45:32,120
露西
Luce.

626
00:45:33,200 --> 00:45:34,200
放松
Relax.

627
00:45:51,480 --> 00:45:52,480
不
No.

628
00:45:52,560 --> 00:45:54,210
停下，停下，出去，出去
Stop. Stop. Get off. Get off!

629
00:45:55,240 --> 00:45:56,600
- 到底怎么了？ - 请离开这里
- What the hell?  - Please, get out of here.

630
00:45:56,600 --> 00:45:57,600
怎么了？
What's going on?

631
00:45:59,400 --> 00:46:00,400
不，不！
No. No!

632
00:46:01,080 --> 00:46:02,080
露西？
Luce?

633
00:46:02,360 --> 00:46:04,010
幽灵比以前的更大了
The shadows were bigger than ever.

634
00:46:06,960 --> 00:46:09,440
紧接着突然就爆炸了
And then suddenly everything exploded.

635
00:46:09,480 --> 00:46:12,630
我根本没明白过来，我就在屋外了，而特雷弗还在里面
And I don't know how but I was outside and Trevor didn't make it.

636
00:46:12,640 --> 00:46:13,640
特雷弗！
Trevor!

637
00:46:27,480 --> 00:46:29,320
特雷费在哪里？告诉我
Where's Trevor? Tell me.

638
00:46:30,120 --> 00:46:31,200
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

639
00:46:31,880 --> 00:46:32,640
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

640
00:46:32,640 --> 00:46:34,880
你做了什么，你这个怪物？
What did you do, you freak?

641
00:46:35,040 --> 00:46:37,320
是我的错，我很抱歉
It's my fault. I'm so sorry.

642
00:46:37,880 --> 00:46:38,920
特雷弗！
Trevor!

643
00:46:39,760 --> 00:46:42,280
他的死是因为我有问题
And he's dead because there's something wrong with me.

644
00:46:43,440 --> 00:46:45,280
我很高兴你想和我成为朋友
And I'm really glad you want to be my friend

645
00:46:45,280 --> 00:46:48,600
但你应当离开我，因为我很危险
but you should stay away from me because I'm dangerous.

646
00:46:49,320 --> 00:46:51,080
你希望他死吗？
Did you want him to die?

647
00:46:52,160 --> 00:46:52,840
没有
No.

648
00:46:52,920 --> 00:46:54,440
你想过伤害他吗？
Did you try to hurt him?

649
00:46:57,280 --> 00:46:58,120
没有
No.

650
00:46:58,120 --> 00:47:00,320
好了，那就不是你的错
Well then it's not your fault.

651
00:47:01,280 --> 00:47:04,480
你不必孤独一人，露西，你需要一个朋友
You don't need to be alone, Luce. You need a friend.

652
00:47:07,800 --> 00:47:09,160
让我来帮你
Let me help you.

653
00:47:10,480 --> 00:47:11,480
为什么？
Why?

654
00:47:12,200 --> 00:47:14,120
因为那是朋友该做的
Because that's what friends do.

655
00:47:26,360 --> 00:47:31,200
上次我们讨论到路西法的自大是怎么导致了堕落的
Last time we were discussing how it was Lucifer's pride that led to the fall.

656
00:47:32,960 --> 00:47:33,960
是的
Yes.

657
00:47:34,600 --> 00:47:36,360
现在，谁能来翻译一下？
So who can translate?

658
00:47:36,880 --> 00:47:39,200
尤米力特斯 忽米涅斯 圣蒂斯
Humilitas homines sanctis

659
00:47:39,560 --> 00:47:42,160
安杰利斯 西米利斯 法西特
angelis similes facit

660
00:47:42,400 --> 00:47:46,560
依特 斯派里亚 依克斯 安杰利斯 戴蒙斯 法西特
et superbia ex angelis demones facit.

661
00:47:46,680 --> 00:47:47,840
哪一位来？
Anyone?

662
00:47:50,080 --> 00:47:52,280
就是骄傲把天使变成了魔鬼
It was pride that turned angels into devils.

663
00:47:52,280 --> 00:47:54,000
是什么，露西？
What was that, Luce?

664
00:47:55,280 --> 00:47:57,200
谦逊让人如天使一样
It is humility that makes men as angels.

665
00:47:57,240 --> 00:47:59,560
骄傲把天使变成恶魔
It was pride that turned angels into devils.

666
00:48:03,040 --> 00:48:05,560
我们当中有了一个拉丁语学者
We have a Latin scholar in our midst.

667
00:48:06,720 --> 00:48:08,130
不，我从来没有…
No, I've never...

668
00:48:09,560 --> 00:48:10,890
我只是猜的
It was just a guess.

669
00:48:15,880 --> 00:48:18,720
那么，这和叛逆天使有什么关联呢？
So how does that relate to the rebel angel?

670
00:48:19,440 --> 00:48:23,410
是不是他的自傲，他固执得追求爱超过了上帝
Wasn't it his pride, his stubborn pursuit of love over God

671
00:48:23,480 --> 00:48:26,240
导致了他的堕落，困在人间？
that led to the Fallen being trapped on earth?

672
00:48:26,960 --> 00:48:28,040
阿瑞娜？
Arriane?

673
00:48:29,200 --> 00:48:33,280
我听腻了你歪曲这些宗教寓言，用来满足你自己的信仰
I'm tired of listening to you twist these religious fables to fit your own beliefs.

674
00:48:33,360 --> 00:48:36,360
你说这个故事不就是想说，爱不过是一种选择
You tell this story of yours as is love was a choice.

675
00:48:37,720 --> 00:48:39,400
我不喜欢你说话的语气
I don't care for your tone.

676
00:48:40,360 --> 00:48:43,600
也许你只是生气叛逆天使选错了女孩
Maybe you're just pissed the rebel angel chose the wrong girl.

677
00:48:43,680 --> 00:48:44,960
出去
Get out.

678
00:48:45,040 --> 00:48:46,530
我很乐意
Gladly.

679
00:48:47,360 --> 00:48:49,680
我宁愿永世在地狱里
I'd rather burn in hell for all eternity

680
00:48:49,680 --> 00:48:54,360
也不想再听一秒钟你那伪善的、自鸣得意的胡说八道
than have to listen to one more second of your pious self-satisfied ravings.

681
00:49:00,560 --> 00:49:01,790
刚才还真精彩
That was kind of awesome.

682
00:49:01,800 --> 00:49:02,760
是的
Yeah.

683
00:49:02,760 --> 00:49:04,200
你觉得她会被留级吗？
Do you think she'll get suspended?

684
00:49:04,280 --> 00:49:05,960
我甚至怀疑她会被关禁闭
I doubt she even gets detention.

685
00:49:05,960 --> 00:49:07,680
那些孩子们根本啥也不在乎
Those kids get away with everything.

686
00:49:08,840 --> 00:49:11,390
嘿，我把毛衣给忘了，一会我来找你们
Hey, I forgot my sweater. I'll catch up with you guys.

687
00:49:11,400 --> 00:49:12,400
好的
Okay.

688
00:49:15,280 --> 00:49:18,120
听我说，你必须盯住卡马
Listen to me. You've got to keep your eye on Cam.

689
00:49:18,680 --> 00:49:19,800
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?

690
00:49:19,880 --> 00:49:23,670
我不相信那雕塑是个意外，她有危险
I don't believe the statue was an accident. She's in danger.

691
00:49:23,680 --> 00:49:26,120
事故发生前，我看到他在顶楼
I saw him on the upper floor just before it happened.

692
00:49:26,240 --> 00:49:27,480
他为什么这么做？
Why would he do that?

693
00:49:27,640 --> 00:49:29,560
你听到过的，她没有受洗礼
You heard. She isn't baptized.

694
00:49:29,600 --> 00:49:31,480
她需要我们的保护，她是…
She needs our protection. She's...

695
00:49:34,120 --> 00:49:36,120
对不起，我只是…我忘记拿毛衣了
Sorry, I just... l forgot my sweater.

696
00:49:38,200 --> 00:49:39,720
我去和她谈谈
I'll go talk to her.

697
00:50:18,560 --> 00:50:19,640
嘿，露西！
Hey Luce!

698
00:50:20,200 --> 00:50:21,200
等等
Wait.

699
00:50:22,920 --> 00:50:23,920
什么事？
What?

700
00:50:24,040 --> 00:50:25,040
- 你想干什么？ - 没什么
- What do you want?  - Nothing.

701
00:50:25,040 --> 00:50:27,000
我只是想，也许我们可以一起走走
I just thought maybe we could walk together.

702
00:50:27,680 --> 00:50:28,680
哦
Oh.

703
00:50:29,680 --> 00:50:30,800
好吧
Sure.

704
00:50:34,760 --> 00:50:36,720
今天你在课堂里一直在画什么？
What were you working on in class today?

705
00:50:37,880 --> 00:50:39,320
没什么，只是一个…
Nothing. It's ah...

706
00:50:40,080 --> 00:50:42,240
一本漫画小说
sort of a graphic novel.

707
00:50:43,000 --> 00:50:44,240
什么类型的故事？
What kind of story?

708
00:50:45,680 --> 00:50:47,480
我想，你可以叫它“浪漫爱情”
I guess you could call it a romance.

709
00:50:47,760 --> 00:50:49,360
是大团圆的结局吗？
Does it have a happy ending?

710
00:50:49,760 --> 00:50:50,640
我不知道
I don't know.

711
00:50:50,640 --> 00:50:51,970
你不知道它是怎么结局的？
You don't know how it ends?

712
00:50:52,040 --> 00:50:53,640
不，还没到结局
No, not yet.

713
00:50:55,320 --> 00:50:56,840
说实话，我有点卡住了
I'm sort of stuck, to be honest.

714
00:50:58,720 --> 00:51:01,320
嗯，说来听听，跟我说说你的小说
Well let's hear it. Tell me your story.

715
00:51:01,360 --> 00:51:03,440
不，不，我觉得这不是个好主意
No. No, I don't think that's a good idea.

716
00:51:03,680 --> 00:51:04,680
为什么？
No'?

717
00:51:05,880 --> 00:51:07,600
或许我可以帮你完成结尾
Maybe I could help you with the ending.

718
00:51:13,040 --> 00:51:14,040
好吧
Okay.

719
00:51:15,280 --> 00:51:16,960
是讲一个男孩和一个女孩
It's about this boy and this girl

720
00:51:17,480 --> 00:51:19,320
他们彼此深受对方
and they love each other more than anything

721
00:51:20,280 --> 00:51:21,880
但是他们不能在一起
but they can never be together.

722
00:51:23,640 --> 00:51:24,480
为什么？
Why?

723
00:51:24,480 --> 00:51:25,970
因为有个诅咒
Because there's this curse.

724
00:51:27,680 --> 00:51:29,800
每隔十七年，他们相遇
Every seventeen years they meet

725
00:51:30,360 --> 00:51:31,880
接着坠入爱河
and they fall in love

726
00:51:34,080 --> 00:51:37,520
而当他们正处于最幸福的时刻，女孩死了
and then just when they're happiest, the girl dies.

727
00:51:39,280 --> 00:51:40,560
所以这是个悲剧？
So it's a tragedy?

728
00:51:45,680 --> 00:51:47,170
那男孩怎么样了呢？
What happens to the boy?

729
00:51:51,040 --> 00:51:52,040
他等待
He waits.

730
00:51:52,320 --> 00:51:54,240
他年龄不变，相貌不变
He doesn't age or change.

731
00:51:55,720 --> 00:51:57,290
他深陷于爱的回忆中
He remains in love.

732
00:51:59,200 --> 00:52:01,440
岁月流逝，而那女孩终于又回来了
Years pass, and eventually she returns.

733
00:52:02,200 --> 00:52:03,200
同一个女孩？
The same girl?

734
00:52:06,440 --> 00:52:07,560
她改变了
She's changed.

735
00:52:09,000 --> 00:52:11,120
她有了新的名字，新有家庭
She has a new name, new family.

736
00:52:12,560 --> 00:52:14,000
没有关于男孩的记忆
She has no memory of him

737
00:52:14,320 --> 00:52:15,810
但男孩知道是女孩
but he knows it's her.

738
00:52:17,440 --> 00:52:18,440
她的灵魂
It's her soul

739
00:52:19,280 --> 00:52:20,480
转世了
reincarnated.

740
00:52:20,840 --> 00:52:22,560
接着他们再坠入爱河
And they fall in love.

741
00:52:26,760 --> 00:52:27,800
每次都是
Always.

742
00:52:31,160 --> 00:52:33,040
我是说，每一次都略有不同
I mean, each time it's slightly different.

743
00:52:34,200 --> 00:52:37,280
有无限的版本，但最终结局都是一样
There are infinite versions but the end is always the same.

744
00:52:38,160 --> 00:52:40,120
一切都只是一个吻
But then all it takes is a kiss

745
00:52:41,040 --> 00:52:42,400
然后女孩就消失了
and she's gone.

746
00:52:44,560 --> 00:52:46,000
是谁在诅咒他们？
Who put the curse on them?

747
00:52:47,400 --> 00:52:49,000
是魔鬼本身
It was the devil himself.

748
00:52:49,760 --> 00:52:52,160
他妒忌他们的爱，所以他试图破坏它
He was jealous of their love, so he tried to break it.

749
00:52:54,480 --> 00:52:56,720
他们一定得做点什么才行，对吗？
There has to be something they can do, right?

750
00:52:57,200 --> 00:52:58,640
他试过了所有的办法
He's tried everything.

751
00:53:00,280 --> 00:53:01,560
他尝试过提前找到她
He tries looking for her

752
00:53:03,240 --> 00:53:04,730
还尝试过避开她
then tries to avoid her.

753
00:53:06,000 --> 00:53:08,520
试图避开那心碎的一刻
Tries to run away from the inevitable heartbreak.

754
00:53:08,760 --> 00:53:11,490
可无论如何，诅咒总是降临
But the curse always finds a way, no matter what.

755
00:53:12,320 --> 00:53:13,810
你故事里的女孩
The girl in your story.

756
00:53:15,280 --> 00:53:17,600
就是你在泳池里提到的那个女孩？
Is she the one you mentioned at the pool?

757
00:53:17,960 --> 00:53:19,400
你一直深爱着的女孩？
The girl you're still in love with?

758
00:53:20,480 --> 00:53:22,520
她是故事的灵感，是的
She's the inspiration, yeah.

759
00:53:26,200 --> 00:53:27,320
这个女孩？
This girl?

760
00:53:30,560 --> 00:53:32,320
好吧，你明白我的意思，就是，呃…
Alright, you got me. It's um...

761
00:53:33,040 --> 00:53:35,240
我把你当作她现在的化身
I was using you for her current incarnation.

762
00:53:35,640 --> 00:53:37,240
这画的是在巴黎
This is meant to be Paris.

763
00:53:38,960 --> 00:53:41,200
在一七二三年
In 1723.

764
00:53:41,240 --> 00:53:42,730
很愚蠢
It's stupid.

765
00:53:43,520 --> 00:53:44,600
为什么是我？
Why me?

766
00:53:46,080 --> 00:53:47,600
因为你是最美丽的
Because you're beautiful.

767
00:53:52,840 --> 00:53:54,520
可惜我画错了眼睛
But I messed up the eyes.

768
00:53:57,120 --> 00:53:59,440
在你的眼神深处有一些东西
There's always been something about your eyes.

769
00:54:13,880 --> 00:54:14,880
是什么？
What's wrong?

770
00:54:15,280 --> 00:54:16,280
没什么？
Nothing.

771
00:54:19,080 --> 00:54:21,360
跟我说说这个地方，你以前在那呆过？
Tell me about this place. Have you been there before?

772
00:54:22,400 --> 00:54:23,400
这有关系吗？
Does it matter?

773
00:54:23,880 --> 00:54:25,290
- 有  - 为什么？
- Yes.  - Why?

774
00:54:26,080 --> 00:54:28,200
我以前从来没有出过门
I've never travelled before.

775
00:54:28,400 --> 00:54:30,480
也从没离开过这个国家
I've never even left the country.

776
00:54:32,160 --> 00:54:34,800
但是我知道在画的右边有一个咖啡馆
But I know that there's a café just off to the right

777
00:54:34,800 --> 00:54:37,440
而且我还知道在雨后那里有茉莉花香
And I know it smells like jasmine after it rains.

778
00:54:37,440 --> 00:54:41,720
还有那开咖啡馆的老头对他的狗很好，却虐待自己的妻子
And I know that the old man that runs the café is kind to his dog and he's cruel to his wife

779
00:54:41,760 --> 00:54:44,240
我知道这些，是因为我在那里生活过
and I know these things because I've been there.

780
00:54:47,400 --> 00:54:49,160
是和你一起在那里
And I've been there with you.

781
00:54:49,280 --> 00:54:50,850
噢，露西，算了吧
Oh, Luce, come on.

782
00:54:51,280 --> 00:54:52,280
别这样
Don't.

783
00:54:53,280 --> 00:54:55,120
不要告诉我疯了
Don't tell me that I'm crazy.

784
00:54:55,720 --> 00:54:57,320
露西，这只是漫画，好吗？
Luce, its' a drawing, alright?

785
00:54:57,400 --> 00:54:59,240
一切都只是个故事
It's a story, that's all.

786
00:55:01,600 --> 00:55:02,600
你说谎
You're lying.

787
00:55:07,240 --> 00:55:09,520
我希望我能告诉你想知道的
I wish I could tell you what you want to hear.

788
00:55:10,800 --> 00:55:11,800
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

789
00:55:40,120 --> 00:55:41,120
吹口气
Blow.

790
00:55:45,800 --> 00:55:47,210
生日快乐，露西
Happy birthday, Luce.

791
00:55:48,080 --> 00:55:49,160
你怎么知道的？
How'd you know?

792
00:55:49,760 --> 00:55:51,090
你不许个愿吗？
Did you make a wish?

793
00:55:52,840 --> 00:55:54,600
我不能说出来，那就不能实现了
I can't tell you. It won't come true.

794
00:55:54,640 --> 00:55:56,290
噢，没错
Oh, that's okay.

795
00:55:56,800 --> 00:55:58,480
我已经知道你许得什么愿了
I already know what you wished for.

796
00:55:58,640 --> 00:55:59,640
噢，是吗？
Oh yeah?

797
00:56:00,800 --> 00:56:02,080
我许了什么愿？
What'd I wish for?

798
00:56:02,240 --> 00:56:03,240
答案
Answers.

799
00:56:04,080 --> 00:56:05,490
你想要真相
You want the truth.

800
00:56:07,000 --> 00:56:09,600
八点到拱门那见我，我会告诉你一切
Meet me at the arches at eight and I'll tell you everything.

801
00:56:11,880 --> 00:56:12,880
还有，露西
And Luce?

802
00:56:14,200 --> 00:56:15,530
穿漂亮一点
Wear something nice.

803
00:56:16,440 --> 00:56:17,800
是派对时间
It's party time.

804
00:57:01,840 --> 00:57:03,000
看看你
Look at you.

805
00:57:04,080 --> 00:57:05,080
噢，哇
Oh, wow.

806
00:57:06,560 --> 00:57:07,600
这是你的车？
Is it yours?

807
00:57:08,080 --> 00:57:09,080
今晚是的
For tonight.

808
00:57:10,320 --> 00:57:11,760
你是怎么搞到的？
How'd you manage that?

809
00:57:12,480 --> 00:57:14,320
是罗兰的特殊技能
It's Roland's special talent.

810
00:57:14,400 --> 00:57:16,720
你想要什么，他都能搞到
Anything you want, he can get it for you.

811
00:57:16,960 --> 00:57:18,450
我这样会后悔吗？
Am I going to regret this?

812
00:57:19,440 --> 00:57:21,360
只有一个办法可以知道
There's only one way to find out.

813
00:57:26,320 --> 00:57:28,280
- 来吧  - 不，我来开
- Come on.  - No way, I drive.

814
00:57:28,360 --> 00:57:31,090
你真的想在夜晚的一开始就对女孩说“不”吗？
You really want to start the night by saying no to the girl?

815
00:57:32,680 --> 00:57:33,680
好吧
Okay.

816
00:58:17,880 --> 00:58:19,370
我和你在这里做什么？
What am I doing here with you?

817
00:58:19,880 --> 00:58:20,880
庆祝
Celebrating.

818
00:58:21,120 --> 00:58:22,160
你很擅长这样
You're good at that.

819
00:58:22,560 --> 00:58:24,160
每次我问你问题
Every time I ask you a question

820
00:58:24,160 --> 00:58:26,640
你总有很机灵地闪开答案
you have some clever way of avoiding the answer.

821
00:58:26,960 --> 00:58:28,200
那不是实话
That's not true.

822
00:58:28,600 --> 00:58:31,000
那就举个例子，你在哪里长大的？
Here's an example. Where did you grow up?

823
00:58:35,600 --> 00:58:36,360
是吧？
See?

824
00:58:36,440 --> 00:58:38,840
你怎么不跟我说说你自己的事情呢？
How come you won't tell me anything about yourself?

825
00:58:38,920 --> 00:58:41,650
因为我正在享受美好时光，我不想破坏它
Because I'm having a nice time and I don't want to ruin it.

826
00:58:42,800 --> 00:58:44,290
那就是不太好的，对吗？
It's that bad, huh?

827
00:58:45,080 --> 00:58:46,240
我喜欢这样
I prefer this.

828
00:58:50,800 --> 00:58:52,290
你答应过告诉我答案的
You promised answers.

829
00:58:54,880 --> 00:58:57,040
来吧，露西，今天是你生日
Come on, Luce. It's your birthday.

830
00:58:58,440 --> 00:59:00,640
我在想，这里有你更想要的东西
I'm thinking there's something else you might want.

831
00:59:18,880 --> 00:59:20,000
你在做什么？
What are you doing?

832
00:59:20,240 --> 00:59:22,230
- 住手！ - 我告诉过你别靠近她的
- Stop!  - I told you to stay away from her.

833
00:59:22,240 --> 00:59:23,230
丹尼尔，你在做什么？
Daniel, what are you doing?

834
00:59:23,240 --> 00:59:25,120
- 为什么，因为你很在乎她吗？ - 住手！
- Why, because you care so much about her?  - Stop it!

835
00:59:25,130 --> 00:59:27,400
- 住手！ - 不，因为我知道你会搞鬼
- Stop!  - No, because I know what you're capable of.

836
00:59:27,400 --> 00:59:29,280
你是路西法那边的，承认吧！
You're still with Lucifer. Admit it!

837
00:59:29,360 --> 00:59:31,560
为什么你不告诉她，丹尼尔？告诉她真相
Why don't you tell her, Daniel? Tell her everything.

838
00:59:31,640 --> 00:59:32,600
- 她想要真相  - 住手！
- She wants the truth.  - Stop it!

839
00:59:32,600 --> 00:59:33,640
离她远点！
Just stay away from her!

840
00:59:33,640 --> 00:59:35,160
你不能说出来
You don't have a say in it.

841
00:59:35,520 --> 00:59:38,280
我不知道这里是怎么回事，但是这些都与我无关
I don't know what's going on here but it has nothing to do with me.

842
00:59:53,240 --> 00:59:56,360
我从来没有想过，人会注定和某人在一起
I never bought into that idea that there's one person you're meant to be with

843
00:59:56,370 --> 01:00:00,760
可是我的幻觉是如此真实，我的感觉也非常真实
but my visions are so real and my feelings are so real

844
01:00:01,640 --> 01:00:05,280
就象是前世经历，我不明白
it's like past lives or something. I don't know.

845
01:00:05,480 --> 01:00:09,240
一切都莫名地和丹尼尔有关，可他却故意疏远我
And everything's connected to Daniel somehow but he keeps pushing me away.

846
01:00:09,560 --> 01:00:11,560
而且卡马也似乎在隐瞒什么
And Cam's hiding something too.

847
01:00:11,840 --> 01:00:12,840
你有什么看法？
So what do you think?

848
01:00:12,920 --> 01:00:15,010
我认为你是个混球，连你的生日都不告诉我
I think you're a jerk for not telling me it was your birthday

849
01:00:15,040 --> 01:00:18,360
不过我可以忽略你是个混球，因为这荒唐的故事更有意思
but I'm willing to overlook that because this is so ridiculously juicy.

850
01:00:19,960 --> 01:00:21,610
那你相信轮回吗？
Do you believe in reincarnation?

851
01:00:22,320 --> 01:00:24,000
不，根本不信
No. Not at all.

852
01:00:24,400 --> 01:00:26,050
我也不信，可是
I didn't think so either but

853
01:00:27,080 --> 01:00:29,680
这一定得有某种解释能说得通
there has to be some sort of explanation for this.

854
01:00:30,400 --> 01:00:31,400
嗯
Hmm.

855
01:00:33,000 --> 01:00:34,040
也许我能帮忙
Maybe I can help.

856
01:00:45,000 --> 01:00:46,240
你在做什么？
What are you doing?

857
01:00:46,760 --> 01:00:48,360
我们只需要再做一件事
We just need one more thing.

858
01:00:48,480 --> 01:00:49,480
什么事？
What?

859
01:00:56,440 --> 01:00:58,840
你怎么知道托德住这个房间的？
How do you know which room Todd's in?

860
01:01:02,920 --> 01:01:04,250
那具体要怎么做呢？
So how does this work exactly?

861
01:01:04,320 --> 01:01:05,720
你有那些年鉴相片吗？
Have you got those yearbook photos?

862
01:01:05,760 --> 01:01:09,080
托德非常精通这个很牛逼的人脸识别算法
Todd's been working on this really cool facial recognition algorithm.

863
01:01:09,320 --> 01:01:11,000
也不全是我一个人写的代码
It's not all my code.

864
01:01:11,240 --> 01:01:12,840
它是卡内基·梅隆大学搞的
It was developed at Carnegie Mellon,

865
01:01:12,840 --> 01:01:16,000
我不过进行了一些调整
but I've tweaked it a little.

866
01:01:16,280 --> 01:01:17,930
他太谦虚了
He's so modest.

867
01:01:19,920 --> 01:01:20,920
不好意思
Sorry.

868
01:01:22,440 --> 01:01:24,240
这可能得花几分钟
This might take a minute.

869
01:01:39,480 --> 01:01:40,920
正在搜索中
It's just searching.

870
01:01:56,280 --> 01:01:57,800
露西？喂？
Luce? Hello?

871
01:01:58,000 --> 01:01:59,160
我们已经找到了
We've got hits.

872
01:02:08,440 --> 01:02:09,440
哇
Whoa.

873
01:02:10,400 --> 01:02:11,560
看这个名字
Look at the name.

874
01:02:11,640 --> 01:02:13,400
一定是亲戚
It must be a relative.

875
01:02:14,360 --> 01:02:15,850
噢，什么？
Oh, What?

876
01:02:16,360 --> 01:02:18,470
实际上…靠
The actual... Fuck.

877
01:02:25,160 --> 01:02:26,240
打出来
Print it.

878
01:02:27,520 --> 01:02:28,520
我去拿
I'll get it.

879
01:02:40,000 --> 01:02:42,360
托德，我得靠你了，你想想这些要怎么解释
Todd, I'm counting on you having some sort of explanation

880
01:02:42,360 --> 01:02:44,600
因为我真的在站在那里
because I am really struggling here.

881
01:02:46,720 --> 01:02:48,520
我一点也摸不着头脑
I haven't got the faintest idea.

882
01:02:50,000 --> 01:02:51,240
我爱你
I love you.

883
01:02:56,440 --> 01:02:58,560
我们看看还能找到什么
Let's see what else we can find.

884
01:03:33,880 --> 01:03:35,290
又来了
It's happening again.

885
01:03:41,760 --> 01:03:42,760
不
No.

886
01:03:46,240 --> 01:03:47,570
离我远点！
Leave me alone!

887
01:03:48,040 --> 01:03:50,320
露西？你还好吗？
Luce? Everything okay?

888
01:03:54,120 --> 01:03:55,120
露西？
Luce?

889
01:03:58,640 --> 01:03:59,640
佩尼！
Penn!

890
01:04:00,200 --> 01:04:01,850
我得找到佩尼！
I've gotta find Penn!

891
01:04:02,200 --> 01:04:03,200
佩尼！
Penn!

892
01:04:04,040 --> 01:04:05,480
佩尼，你在哪里？
Penn, where are you?

893
01:04:06,560 --> 01:04:07,670
托德！
Todd!

894
01:04:07,680 --> 01:04:09,170
我得找到佩尼！
I've gotta find Penn!

895
01:04:09,280 --> 01:04:10,610
- 不！ - 佩尼！
- No!  - Penn!

896
01:04:10,720 --> 01:04:13,000
托德！
Todd!

897
01:04:18,040 --> 01:04:19,120
托德！
Todd!

898
01:04:23,280 --> 01:04:24,280
不！
No!

899
01:06:19,760 --> 01:06:20,990
在学校医务室
Here at the school infirmary

900
01:06:21,000 --> 01:06:24,120
可以提供给她和医院一样的照顾
we provide the same care she'd receive at the hospital.

901
01:06:24,200 --> 01:06:25,530
我想带她回家
I want to take her home.

902
01:06:25,600 --> 01:06:29,120
医生明确说了，她需要进行临床观察
The doctor's clear. She needs to remain under clinical supervision.

903
01:06:29,600 --> 01:06:30,320
要多久？
For how long?

904
01:06:30,400 --> 01:06:31,600
直到她稳定下来
Until she's stable.

905
01:06:32,240 --> 01:06:33,440
你应该去休息一下
You should get some rest.

906
01:06:34,120 --> 01:06:37,320
一旦露西可能接受谈话了，我就打电话到饭店叫你
We'll call you at the hotel as soon as Luce is able to receive visitors.

907
01:06:41,960 --> 01:06:43,680
现在我们什么也做不了
There was nothing we could have done.

908
01:06:43,800 --> 01:06:45,290
我拒绝接受这个
I refuse to accept that.

909
01:06:45,360 --> 01:06:47,170
我已经警告过她，我已经…
I could have warned her. I could have been there...

910
01:06:47,200 --> 01:06:48,120
以前这样管用过吗？
When has that ever helped?

911
01:06:48,120 --> 01:06:49,830
已经无所谓了，好吗？
It doesn't matter, okay?

912
01:06:49,840 --> 01:06:51,720
她需要我们，而我们让她失望了
She needs us and we let her down.

913
01:06:51,960 --> 01:06:53,680
这是刑事调查吗？
Is this a criminal investigation?

914
01:06:53,760 --> 01:06:54,840
目前还不是
Not at the moment.

915
01:06:55,120 --> 01:06:57,000
火灾是闪电引起的
The fire was caused by lightning.

916
01:06:57,160 --> 01:06:59,000
那只是初步调查报告
That report is preliminary.

917
01:06:59,280 --> 01:07:01,480
考虑到和特雷弗·贝克曼案件的相似处
Given the similarity to the Trevor Beckman case

918
01:07:01,560 --> 01:07:03,430
我们还要问她一些问题
we'll definitely want to question her.

919
01:07:03,440 --> 01:07:05,880
我不想让她在没有律师陪同下和你对话
I don't want you talking to her without her attorney present.

920
01:07:19,560 --> 01:07:21,210
今天我们来到一起
We come together today

921
01:07:21,480 --> 01:07:24,960
哀悼我们失去了一位亲爱的朋友，一个善良和慷慨的…
to mourn the loss of a dear friend, a kind and generous...

922
01:07:25,000 --> 01:07:27,680
他的生命如此短暂，
whose life was far too brief to mourn the loss...

923
01:07:27,760 --> 01:07:31,480
悲剧来临，震惊了我们所有人
whose tragic passing comes as a shock to us all.

924
01:07:31,960 --> 01:07:35,520
我们会永远记住这位善良和慷慨的朋友
We will always remember a kind and generous friend

925
01:07:35,600 --> 01:07:37,920
他的陪伴总是给我们带来欢乐
someone whose company was always a pleasure

926
01:07:38,160 --> 01:07:42,290
虽然今天我们要理解克服悲伤
and although today we are understandably overcome with grief

927
01:07:42,360 --> 01:07:45,760
我请求你们要有信心
I ask you to have faith that in time

928
01:07:46,280 --> 01:07:48,800
要化悲痛为力量
our pain will prove strengthening

929
01:07:49,400 --> 01:07:51,400
并且最终证明
and ultimately a testament

930
01:07:51,960 --> 01:07:54,200
托德非常重要
to how much Todd mattered

931
01:07:54,480 --> 01:07:56,200
一起到永远
and always will.

932
01:07:58,000 --> 01:08:00,520
他不仅是一个可爱的儿子
Not only was he a loving son

933
01:08:00,600 --> 01:08:04,320
他也是一个善良和慷慨的朋友
but he was also a kind and generous friend.

934
01:08:05,880 --> 01:08:10,400
我们必须化悲伤为力量
We must transform our sadness into something strengthening.

935
01:08:10,800 --> 01:08:13,000
来记念他的生命
That's how we celebrate his life

936
01:08:13,600 --> 01:08:16,410
和维护他的遗愿
and ensure his legacy.

937
01:08:18,440 --> 01:08:21,200
你杀了他之后还出现在他的葬礼上？
You show up to his funeral after you get him killed?

938
01:08:21,360 --> 01:08:22,680
我知道你这种人
I know you're the one doing this.

939
01:08:22,720 --> 01:08:23,840
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?

940
01:08:23,840 --> 01:08:26,120
那雕像，图书馆的大火
The statue. The fire in the library.

941
01:08:26,200 --> 01:08:27,400
你想要杀死她
You were trying to kill her.

942
01:08:27,400 --> 01:08:29,120
杀死露西是你的事，丹尼尔
Killing Luce is your thing, Daniel.

943
01:08:29,130 --> 01:08:30,640
你要是敢…
Don't you dare...

944
01:08:30,680 --> 01:08:33,440
怎么了，丹尼尔？你害怕竞争？
What's the matter, Daniel? You afraid of a little competition?

945
01:08:34,240 --> 01:08:35,680
我对露西的感情是真的
What I feel for Luce is real.

946
01:08:35,760 --> 01:08:38,730
这次她不一样了，她应当得到比你能给她的更多
She's different this time. She deserves more than you can give her.

947
01:08:39,040 --> 01:08:40,370
如果你再接近她…
If you come near her...

948
01:08:40,400 --> 01:08:41,400
你要干什么？
You'll What?

949
01:08:42,200 --> 01:08:44,320
多少次你不得不看着她死？
How many times do you have to watch her die?

950
01:09:07,920 --> 01:09:09,330
我爱你
I love you.

951
01:09:37,800 --> 01:09:38,840
露西！
Luce!

952
01:09:40,000 --> 01:09:41,040
噢，佩尼！
Oh, Penn!

953
01:09:42,200 --> 01:09:43,200
露西！
Luce!

954
01:09:47,680 --> 01:09:48,680
托德？
Todd?

955
01:09:55,680 --> 01:09:56,800
对不起
I'm sorry.

956
01:09:58,320 --> 01:10:01,110
我非常，非常抱歉，是我的错
I'm so, so sorry. It's my fault.

957
01:10:01,120 --> 01:10:02,450
噢，别这么说
Oh, don't say that.

958
01:10:05,600 --> 01:10:08,280
是真的，那幽灵是同一个
It's true. The shadows were exactly the same.

959
01:10:08,560 --> 01:10:10,920
- 是同一个幽灵…  - 别说了，好吗？
- It was the exact same...  - Stop it, okay?

960
01:10:13,440 --> 01:10:14,960
不是你导致的
You did not cause this.

961
01:10:16,440 --> 01:10:17,770
我不想听
I won't hear it.

962
01:10:22,400 --> 01:10:23,400
嗯
Okay.

963
01:10:34,200 --> 01:10:35,480
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

964
01:10:48,840 --> 01:10:50,120
你许愿了吗？
Did you make a wish?

965
01:10:50,960 --> 01:10:53,040
过去的生活和命运
Past lives and destinies.

966
01:10:53,120 --> 01:10:54,690
你想要真相
You want the truth.

967
01:10:56,000 --> 01:10:57,890
她根本不了解我，一切只需要一个吻
She doesn't know me at all. All it takes is a kiss.

968
01:10:57,920 --> 01:10:59,000
但是他知道那就是她
But he knows it's her.

969
01:10:59,080 --> 01:11:00,000
露西！不！
Luce! NO!

970
01:11:00,080 --> 01:11:01,960
吻他你就会死
Kiss him and you'll die.

971
01:11:02,760 --> 01:11:04,090
是谁诅咒了他们？
Who put the curse on them?

972
01:11:04,120 --> 01:11:05,200
是恶魔本身
It was the devil himself.

973
01:11:05,200 --> 01:11:07,400
丹尼尔，不！
Daniel, no!

974
01:11:09,800 --> 01:11:11,240
露西，不！
Luce, no.

975
01:11:11,640 --> 01:11:12,840
你会死的
You will die.

976
01:11:13,160 --> 01:11:14,240
你会死的
You will die.

977
01:12:03,000 --> 01:12:04,280
你感觉好点了吗？
You feeling better?

978
01:12:06,960 --> 01:12:09,040
我浑身都疼，不过我还活着
Every part of me hurts, but I'm alive.

979
01:12:11,000 --> 01:12:12,160
这是什么东西？
Well that's something.

980
01:12:14,280 --> 01:12:15,480
我记起来了
I remember.

981
01:12:17,000 --> 01:12:17,680
什么？
What?

982
01:12:18,000 --> 01:12:19,000
一切
Everything.

983
01:12:20,920 --> 01:12:21,920
那火
The fire.

984
01:12:23,680 --> 01:12:24,920
你带给我的
You carrying me.

985
01:12:26,000 --> 01:12:27,570
在你怀里，感觉就像我们是…
Being in your arms, it felt like we were...

986
01:12:27,600 --> 01:12:28,930
你神志不清
Well you were delirious.

987
01:12:33,200 --> 01:12:34,200
也许
Maybe.

988
01:12:36,360 --> 01:12:38,120
但那不是我全部的记忆
But that's not all I remember.

989
01:12:42,200 --> 01:12:43,560
我记得这些
I remember this.

990
01:12:46,520 --> 01:12:48,240
我记得这发生的那一天
I remember the day this was taken.

991
01:12:49,480 --> 01:12:50,480
你什么意思？
What do you mean?

992
01:12:50,960 --> 01:12:51,960
够了！
Enough!

993
01:12:53,360 --> 01:12:54,930
我明白我的内心
I know what I know.

994
01:13:04,080 --> 01:13:06,840
在我生命里，所有人都说我疯了
My whole life people have told me that I'm crazy.

995
01:13:10,040 --> 01:13:10,880
露西
Luce.

996
01:13:10,880 --> 01:13:12,480
那就看看他们是不是对的
Let's see if they're right.

997
01:13:13,520 --> 01:13:15,090
不，露西，从那里下来
No Luce, get down from there.

998
01:13:16,200 --> 01:13:17,240
不，露西
No, Luce.

999
01:13:20,960 --> 01:13:22,080
不！
No.

1000
01:15:06,360 --> 01:15:08,200
永远都是你，露西
It will always be you, Luce.

1001
01:15:08,880 --> 01:15:10,640
正如它永远发生
Just as it always has been.

1002
01:15:20,640 --> 01:15:23,370
现在不是多愁善感的时候
Now is not the time for sentimentality.

1003
01:15:29,200 --> 01:15:30,200
露西？
Luce?

1004
01:15:53,040 --> 01:15:54,480
我给你这个
I gave you this.

1005
01:15:56,280 --> 01:15:57,960
是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.

1006
01:15:59,920 --> 01:16:01,360
这怎么可能？
How is this possible?

1007
01:16:05,360 --> 01:16:07,110
- 没关系  - 不，所有的坏事
- It's okay.  - No, every bad thing

1008
01:16:07,120 --> 01:16:08,690
发生在我身上，是因为这个
that's ever happened to me is because of that.

1009
01:16:08,690 --> 01:16:10,800
不，他们不会伤害你，他们只是在观察
No, they can't hurt you. They just observe.

1010
01:16:10,800 --> 01:16:12,800
那火，他们杀死了特雷弗
The fires. They killed Trevor.

1011
01:16:12,800 --> 01:16:15,690
露西，幽灵不会制造大火，也不是你放的火
Luce, the shadows didn't cause the fire and neither did you.

1012
01:16:15,760 --> 01:16:17,560
他们是观察者
They're called Announcers.

1013
01:16:18,080 --> 01:16:19,080
听着
Look.

1014
01:16:19,960 --> 01:16:22,040
把他们看成一扇能看到过去的窗户
Think of them as windows into the past.

1015
01:16:22,120 --> 01:16:25,200
他们总是被你生命中最重要的时刻吸引
They're attracted to the most important moments in your life.

1016
01:16:34,240 --> 01:16:35,730
我看到了什么？
What am I seeing?

1017
01:16:39,560 --> 01:16:41,240
我们在一起的生活
Our lives together.

1018
01:16:57,280 --> 01:16:59,760
我们已经相爱了几千年
We've been in love for thousands of years.

1019
01:17:01,280 --> 01:17:03,600
露西，你所有的幻觉都是真的
Luce, all your visions are real.

1020
01:17:06,160 --> 01:17:07,730
所以我们在轮回吗？
So we're reincarnated?

1021
01:17:10,280 --> 01:17:11,360
你是
You are.

1022
01:17:12,800 --> 01:17:13,880
我…
I'm...

1023
01:17:14,760 --> 01:17:15,920
是一个天使
An angel.

1024
01:17:20,600 --> 01:17:22,400
我是一个堕落天使
I'm one of the Fallen.

1025
01:17:25,960 --> 01:17:27,160
停下！
Stop!

1026
01:17:27,440 --> 01:17:28,770
别这么做，露西
Don't do it, Luce.

1027
01:17:29,080 --> 01:17:30,490
吻了他，你就会死
Kiss him and you will die.

1028
01:17:32,640 --> 01:17:35,680
这就是为什么我试图避开你的原因，可是我做不到
This is why I tried so hard to push you away but I can't.

1029
01:17:35,760 --> 01:17:37,040
你没有告诉她？
You didn't tell her?

1030
01:17:38,080 --> 01:17:39,080
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.

1031
01:17:39,120 --> 01:17:41,400
难以置信，你难以置信
Unbelievable. You're unbelievable.

1032
01:17:41,760 --> 01:17:43,480
什么？我不明白，为什么？
What? I don't understand, why?

1033
01:17:44,000 --> 01:17:46,920
惩罚我的诅咒并不是因为要选择堕落天使的阵营
The curse is my punishment for not taking a side at the Fall.

1034
01:17:46,920 --> 01:17:48,280
露西，别听他说的
Luce, don't listen to him.

1035
01:17:48,280 --> 01:17:50,560
留下来，露西，我选择了你
Stay, Luce. I chose you.

1036
01:17:51,200 --> 01:17:52,400
我选择了爱情
I chose love.

1037
01:17:52,680 --> 01:17:54,040
别听他说，露西
Don't listen to him, Luce.

1038
01:17:54,040 --> 01:17:56,000
如果你吻了他，你就会死
If you kiss him, you will die.

1039
01:17:56,000 --> 01:17:58,720
- 我已经看过千万次了  - 不，这次不一样
- I've seen it a thousand times.  - No, this time it's different.

1040
01:17:58,720 --> 01:18:00,130
我保证这次不一样
I promise it is different.

1041
01:18:00,130 --> 01:18:01,470
他说谎，露西
He's a liar, Luce.

1042
01:18:01,480 --> 01:18:03,320
如果你选择我，我能保护你
If you stay with me, I can protect you.

1043
01:18:03,320 --> 01:18:04,760
你看过我的真实面目
You've seen me in my true form.

1044
01:18:04,760 --> 01:18:06,030
这是不一样的
This is different.

1045
01:18:06,040 --> 01:18:07,230
我能保护你
I can protect you.

1046
01:18:07,240 --> 01:18:08,480
这可能是我们的机会
This could be our chance.

1047
01:18:10,680 --> 01:18:11,520
求你了
Please.

1048
01:18:11,600 --> 01:18:13,600
露西，我能保证你的将来
Luce, I can offer you a future.

1049
01:18:13,880 --> 01:18:15,120
一个生活
A life.

1050
01:18:18,240 --> 01:18:19,890
我不能再失去你了
I can't lose you again.

1051
01:18:25,960 --> 01:18:27,530
我知道我想要什么
I know what I want.

1052
01:18:37,920 --> 01:18:40,080
不！
No!

1053
01:18:59,360 --> 01:19:00,640
我一直在这里
I'm still here.

1054
01:19:05,000 --> 01:19:06,720
你以为你已经击败了诅咒？
You think you've beaten the curse?

1055
01:19:06,720 --> 01:19:08,960
你根本没意识到她的处境有多危险
You have no idea how much danger she's in.

1056
01:19:09,160 --> 01:19:11,160
路西法知道她没有受洗
Lucifer knows she's not baptized.

1057
01:19:11,160 --> 01:19:12,600
我不明白，告诉我为什么？
I don't understand. Tell me why.

1058
01:19:12,600 --> 01:19:14,840
他为自己解除了诅咒，不是给你
He lifted the curse for himself, not for you.

1059
01:19:14,840 --> 01:19:16,200
他现在来找她了
He'll come for her now.

1060
01:19:16,200 --> 01:19:17,800
丹尼尔保护不了你，露西
Daniel can't protect you, Luce.

1061
01:19:18,280 --> 01:19:19,280
我能！
I can!

1062
01:19:20,600 --> 01:19:22,040
她和我一起是安全的
She's safer with me!

1063
01:19:24,680 --> 01:19:26,800
万物要遵循规律，丹尼尔
There's a natural order to things, Daniel.

1064
01:19:26,840 --> 01:19:28,400
你不能只按自己想法来
You can't just do as you please.

1065
01:19:28,400 --> 01:19:30,160
循环已经被打破了
Well the cycle's been broken.

1066
01:19:30,640 --> 01:19:32,210
罗兰！莫莉！
Roland! Molly!

1067
01:19:37,840 --> 01:19:39,040
露西！
Luce!

1068
01:19:39,280 --> 01:19:40,440
你跟我来！
You're coming with me!

1069
01:19:41,480 --> 01:19:43,440
保护她的安全，我先对付卡马
Keep her safe. I need to deal with Cam.

1070
01:19:43,640 --> 01:19:45,560
我要带她走，我不想让卡马跟着
Where I'm taking her, I don't want him to follow.

1071
01:19:47,120 --> 01:19:48,960
他会把路西法带来的
He'll lead Lucifer right to us.

1072
01:19:49,000 --> 01:19:50,360
他们全是天使
They're all angels.

1073
01:19:51,960 --> 01:19:53,960
我不能让你把她带给路西法！
I won't let you take her to Lucifer!

1074
01:19:54,000 --> 01:19:55,490
我今后不会再回应他了
I don't answer to him anymore.

1075
01:20:32,080 --> 01:20:34,320
是你把他置于危险之中的，丹尼尔
You're the one putting her in danger, Daniel.

1076
01:20:35,200 --> 01:20:37,240
不要假装你关心她！
Don't pretend you even care about her!

1077
01:21:11,240 --> 01:21:12,440
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?

1078
01:21:12,760 --> 01:21:13,990
我能保护她
I can protect her.

1079
01:21:14,000 --> 01:21:15,410
离她远点！
Stay away from her!

1080
01:21:20,840 --> 01:21:21,960
那又如何！
What the heck!

1081
01:21:22,120 --> 01:21:24,280
回到你们的房间里去，关紧门！
Back to your rooms. Shut the door!

1082
01:21:24,360 --> 01:21:25,880
这是一级警戒
This is a lockdown.

1083
01:21:28,320 --> 01:21:29,840
等到一切结束
Wait for the all clear.

1084
01:21:30,040 --> 01:21:31,610
这是一级警戒，关好门
It's a lockdown. Shut the door.

1085
01:21:32,040 --> 01:21:34,120
- 不用害怕  - 我不害怕
- Don't be afraid.  - I'm not.

1086
01:22:00,680 --> 01:22:02,010
我不是你的敌人
I'm not your enemy.

1087
01:22:02,720 --> 01:22:04,320
我没想过要杀她
I'm not trying to kill her.

1088
01:22:04,760 --> 01:22:05,760
那是谁？
Then who?

1089
01:22:06,760 --> 01:22:07,880
露西！等等！
Luce! Wait!

1090
01:22:08,480 --> 01:22:10,400
她在图书馆里放的火，她…
She set the fire in the library. She...

1091
01:22:13,640 --> 01:22:14,640
佩尼？
Penn?

1092
01:22:16,640 --> 01:22:17,640
不！
No!

1093
01:22:19,880 --> 01:22:21,240
不！
No!

1094
01:22:22,640 --> 01:22:23,640
走！
Go!

1095
01:22:24,280 --> 01:22:27,720
露西，你的时间到了，我已经厌倦了等待
Luce, your time has come. I am tired of waiting.

1096
01:22:28,280 --> 01:22:29,720
现在该结束了
This ends now.

1097
01:22:29,800 --> 01:22:33,520
你的每一次出现都阻止了丹尼尔返回天堂
Every breath you take keeps Daniel from his rightful place in heaven!

1098
01:22:33,520 --> 01:22:35,920
- 丹尼尔！ - 你是真正的祸根
- Daniel!  - You are the real curse.

1099
01:22:36,000 --> 01:22:37,360
露西！
Luce!

1100
01:22:38,400 --> 01:22:39,400
露西！
Luce!

1101
01:22:41,160 --> 01:22:42,810
索菲亚，你干了什么？
Sophia, what have you done?

1102
01:22:42,920 --> 01:22:44,400
你自称自己是神的仆人
You claim to be a servant of God.

1103
01:22:44,400 --> 01:22:46,320
我是的，战争还在继续
I am. There's a war going on.

1104
01:22:46,400 --> 01:22:48,430
忠诚的士兵忠于自己的使命
Loyal soldiers do what they must.

1105
01:22:48,440 --> 01:22:49,400
包括谋杀？
Including murder?

1106
01:22:49,440 --> 01:22:51,720
你拒绝从大局着眼
You refuse to see the bigger picture.

1107
01:22:51,800 --> 01:22:53,450
你总是这样
You always have.

1108
01:22:53,960 --> 01:22:57,440
她离开了，你才会被迫做出选择
With her gone you'd have been forced to choose a side

1109
01:22:57,920 --> 01:23:00,440
那样秩序才能恢复
and order would have been restored.

1110
01:23:06,000 --> 01:23:07,240
谢谢
Thank you.

1111
01:23:07,720 --> 01:23:10,040
我不明白她为什么这样做
I don't understand why she'd do that.

1112
01:23:10,800 --> 01:23:12,160
她是个狂热信徒，露西
She's a fanatic, Luce.

1113
01:23:12,400 --> 01:23:14,000
她为上帝战斗，但她走得太远了
She fights for god, but she went too far.

1114
01:23:14,000 --> 01:23:15,600
索菲亚为什么要杀佩尼？
Why would Sophia kill Penn?

1115
01:23:15,680 --> 01:23:17,010
为什么她还想杀我？
Why did she try to kill me?

1116
01:23:17,080 --> 01:23:20,360
你没有受洗礼，如果你死了，就永远死了
You're not baptized. If you die, it'll be forever.

1117
01:23:21,360 --> 01:23:24,120
索菲亚以为只要你消失了，我就没有理由留在人间了
Sophia thought with you gone I'd have no reason to stay on earth

1118
01:23:24,120 --> 01:23:25,690
那我就会返回天堂
and I'd return to heaven.

1119
01:23:25,880 --> 01:23:26,960
但是卡马是对的
But Cam was right.

1120
01:23:27,360 --> 01:23:29,160
路西法会来找你
Lucifer will be coming for you.

1121
01:23:29,560 --> 01:23:31,720
那就是我要带你到一个安全的地方的原因
Which is why I need to get you somewhere safe.

1122
01:23:31,800 --> 01:23:34,450
我知道一个地方，那里有我的朋友，他们可以保护我们
I know a place. I have friends there. They'll protect us.

1123
01:23:34,520 --> 01:23:35,680
我们必须走了
We have to go.

1124
01:23:35,840 --> 01:23:37,920
我现在不能走，我不能丢下佩尼
I can't leave now. I can't leave Penn.

1125
01:23:37,960 --> 01:23:39,200
我们会照顾好她的
We'll take care of her.

1126
01:23:39,320 --> 01:23:40,320
佩尼！
Penn!

1127
01:23:40,480 --> 01:23:43,240
她会跟我们来的，请走吧
She'll come with us. Go. Please.

1128
01:23:46,040 --> 01:23:47,040
露西
Luce.

1129
01:23:47,680 --> 01:23:49,170
他们会把佩尼带来的
They'll take Penn with them.

1130
01:23:50,760 --> 01:23:53,000
没时间了，我们得走了
There's no more time. We have to go.

1131
01:23:53,080 --> 01:23:54,490
等一下，听着
Wait a minute. Listen.

1132
01:23:55,200 --> 01:23:57,600
我的一生都在追寻真相
My whole life I've been searching for the truth.

1133
01:23:57,600 --> 01:23:59,440
我一直想知道我到底是谁
I've been trying to figure out who I am.

1134
01:23:59,920 --> 01:24:02,730
为什么我似乎从来没有能够融入到我本应该有的生活中去
Why I never seem to fit in to the life that was supposed to be mine.

1135
01:24:03,000 --> 01:24:04,490
现在我很害怕
And now I'm terrified.

1136
01:24:05,000 --> 01:24:06,920
我甚至比以前产生了更多的疑问
I have more questions than I ever have before

1137
01:24:06,920 --> 01:24:08,960
可是…就是这样
but... this is it.

1138
01:24:10,120 --> 01:24:11,640
我就是这样
This is who I am.

1139
01:24:12,400 --> 01:24:13,970
这才是我的归宿
This is where I belong.

1140
01:24:14,440 --> 01:24:16,090
就在这里，在你身边
Right here, with you.

1141
01:24:18,160 --> 01:24:19,440
我爱你
I love you.

1142
01:24:20,680 --> 01:24:23,040
我从第一眼看到你时就知道了
I've known it from the first moment I saw you.

1143
01:24:32,120 --> 01:24:33,920
永远都是你，露西
It will always be you, Luce.

1144
01:24:34,200 --> 01:24:35,360
永远
Forever.

1145
01:25:25,500 --> 01:25:33,500
堕落天使

1146
01:25:36,000 --> 01:25:42,000
结局：“叛逆天使”丹尼尔打破了路西法的诅咒，他选择了爱
情，选择了上帝这一边，所有“坠落天使”也都可以重返天堂

1147
01:25:42,000 --> 01:25:48,000
后记：路西法后来因为战败被打落地狱，成了地狱七君王之一，魔名为“撒旦”

