1
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:11,000
翻译：桌面王(Netpilot)

2
00:03:06,500 --> 00:03:09,544
我们得让它受孕
Come on, let´s get her pregnant.

3
00:03:10,795 --> 00:03:12,672
我们还得给伊格纳西奥一家做饭
We´ll cook one for Ignacio´s family.

4
00:03:12,714 --> 00:03:14,591
把门打开
Open the gate.

5
00:03:14,633 --> 00:03:16,051
快点
Quick.

6
00:03:23,224 --> 00:03:24,643
赶快
Come on!

7
00:03:40,534 --> 00:03:42,495
它们不想做
They don´t want to do it!

8
00:03:46,039 --> 00:03:47,832
朗姆酒会让它硬起来的
Rum will make them horny.

9
00:05:31,395 --> 00:05:34,356
以父之名，儿子还有神圣的灵魂
In the name of the Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost.

10
00:05:35,273 --> 00:05:39,110
感谢你们的祝福
Thank you, spirits, for all your blessings.

11
00:05:39,152 --> 00:05:41,405
为我的女儿祝福
Your blessings for my daughter.

12
00:05:41,447 --> 00:05:42,739
嘿
Hey!

13
00:05:43,239 --> 00:05:44,783
集中精力
Concentrate.

14
00:05:48,161 --> 00:05:49,954
和我一起祈祷啊
Pray with me.

15
00:05:55,336 --> 00:06:00,131
感谢大地，风，水还有火山
Thank you, earth, wind, water, volcano.

16
00:06:00,173 --> 00:06:04,512
保佑我女儿能嫁个好人家
Bless my daughter with a good marriage.

17
00:06:05,136 --> 00:06:08,973
我为我的家庭，工作和我的女儿祈祷
I´m praying for my home, my work, my daughter.

18
00:06:09,015 --> 00:06:12,478
这是我需要的，也是我祈祷的
This is what I want, what I pray for.

19
00:06:12,520 --> 00:06:17,816
我希望我的女儿能幸福，并且得到保护
I want my daughter to be happy and protected.

20
00:06:52,643 --> 00:06:54,269
带我走吧
Take me with you.

21
00:06:54,769 --> 00:06:56,271
我为什么要这样做
Why should I?

22
00:06:57,063 --> 00:07:00,191
如果你想和我走，你得让我爽一下
If you want to come, let me taste it.

23
00:07:20,421 --> 00:07:21,963
玛丽亚
Maria!

24
00:07:24,592 --> 00:07:26,259
我父亲会发火的
My father will yell at me.

25
00:07:27,720 --> 00:07:29,430
祝你好运
Lucky for you.

26
00:09:26,630 --> 00:09:28,841
搅拌啊，不然就焦了
Stir it or it will burn!

27
00:10:52,090 --> 00:10:54,927
快点，过来
Come on. Come here.

28
00:10:56,512 --> 00:10:58,179
别插着你的胳膊
Don´t cross your arms!

29
00:10:58,221 --> 00:11:00,432
- 哈喽 - 欢迎
- Hello! - Welcome!

30
00:11:00,474 --> 00:11:03,059
你全家都来了啊
You brought the whole family.

31
00:11:03,394 --> 00:11:05,854
欢迎来我们家
Our house is yours.

32
00:11:08,649 --> 00:11:11,610
你的孩子们也长大了
Your kids have grown!

33
00:11:12,444 --> 00:11:15,196
你带了这么多东西啊
You brought too many things.

34
00:11:17,449 --> 00:11:19,242
谢谢，兄弟
Thank you, brother.

35
00:11:19,283 --> 00:11:21,119
你好
How are you?

36
00:11:21,160 --> 00:11:24,038
感谢来这里做客
Thank you for coming.

37
00:11:24,080 --> 00:11:25,749
感谢到我家来
Welcome to our home.

38
00:11:25,791 --> 00:11:27,543
这太多了
This is too much.

39
00:11:27,584 --> 00:11:31,004
你还带来了鸭子
You even brought a duck!

40
00:11:32,881 --> 00:11:35,258
哦，天啊，谢谢
Oh, God! Thanks.

41
00:11:35,299 --> 00:11:38,261
请去桌子那边坐，多漂亮的孩子啊
Please sit at the table. What a beautiful kid!

42
00:11:40,013 --> 00:11:41,890
很感谢带来的这些东西
Thank you for bringing all this.

43
00:11:41,932 --> 00:11:45,309
谢谢这一篮子东西
Thank you for the basket.

44
00:11:45,352 --> 00:11:47,813
玛丽亚，你真漂亮
Maria, you look beautiful.

45
00:11:47,855 --> 00:11:50,148
去桌子那边坐，你笑笑啊
Sit at the table! Smile at them.

46
00:11:50,774 --> 00:11:54,068
炖猪肉的秘密就是要炖一整夜
The secret is to simmer the pork the night before.

47
00:11:54,110 --> 00:11:56,655
这很好，嘿
It was good, huh?

48
00:11:56,697 --> 00:11:57,781
干杯
Cheers.

49
00:12:00,199 --> 00:12:01,994
非常感谢
Thank you very much.

50
00:12:03,077 --> 00:12:05,664
让我们言归正传
Let´s get to the point.

51
00:12:06,540 --> 00:12:09,042
- 我不是个虚伪的人  - 当然不是了
- I´m not a pretentious man. - Of course not.

52
00:12:09,083 --> 00:12:12,921
- 你了解我的，我很虔诚的 - 是的
- You know me. I´m sincere. - Yes.

53
00:12:12,963 --> 00:12:17,759
我们知道你是个很不错的人，但是我很担心玛丽亚的未来
We know you are a good person, but I care about Maria´s future.

54
00:12:17,801 --> 00:12:19,511
你明白吗？
You understand?

55
00:12:19,553 --> 00:12:23,390
别担心，她可以应有尽有
Don´t worry. She´ll have everything she needs.

56
00:12:25,559 --> 00:12:26,977
这下放心了吧
That´s a relief.

57
00:12:27,019 --> 00:12:30,522
结婚后，我们就是一家人了
After the wedding, we´ll all be the same family.

58
00:12:30,564 --> 00:12:34,401
你可以保留你的房子，你的工作，还有什么需要的吗？
You´ll keep your house, your job. What else would you need?

59
00:12:34,443 --> 00:12:36,403
非常感谢
Thank you very much!

60
00:12:42,493 --> 00:12:43,785
诚心所愿
So be it.

61
00:12:44,953 --> 00:12:47,331
女士们，先生们，我有一个问题
Ma´am? Mister? I have a question.

62
00:12:47,372 --> 00:12:48,916
玛丽亚家务能立如何？
Is Maria a good housewife?

63
00:12:48,957 --> 00:12:51,919
别担心，她很擅长做饭的
Don´t worry, she´s a good cook.

64
00:12:51,960 --> 00:12:55,254
是她帮我做的这顿丰盛的午餐
She helped me cook this.

65
00:12:55,296 --> 00:12:58,174
别担心，她种植了最后那颗咖啡树
Don´t worry. She planted the last coffee trees.

66
00:12:59,051 --> 00:13:01,845
收获季节到了，会有很大的收获的
Best harvest ever. Very good coffee.

67
00:13:02,303 --> 00:13:05,015
她生育能力可以的
She has fertility on her hands!

68
00:13:05,057 --> 00:13:07,059
她很年轻，身体也好
She is young and strong.

69
00:13:07,100 --> 00:13:08,519
为了生孩子
To fertility!

70
00:13:10,938 --> 00:13:12,940
为了未来的孩子
To new babies!

71
00:13:16,443 --> 00:13:19,613
我们的家族将壮大
May our line continue.

72
00:13:19,655 --> 00:13:22,824
我们曾经有很多问题
We´ve had a lot of problems.

73
00:13:22,866 --> 00:13:26,828
胡安娜在怀孕时遇到了很大的问题
Juana had problems getting pregnant.

74
00:13:27,663 --> 00:13:31,249
是教士帮助了我们，我们最终有了个女孩儿
The spiritual guide helped us, but I had a girl.

75
00:13:31,290 --> 00:13:35,045
伊格纳西奥来到这个家庭之后，我最终还能得到一个男孩儿
With Ignacio in the family, I´ll have a boy at last.

76
00:13:35,087 --> 00:13:37,171
干杯
Cheers.

77
00:13:41,552 --> 00:13:45,639
告诉我，伊格纳西奥很好的安葬了他的前妻？
Tell me, did Ignacio mourn his first wife with dignity?

78
00:13:46,014 --> 00:13:51,061
当然了，他是个有礼貌的人，是值得信赖的
Of course. He´s a respectful man. He can be trusted.

79
00:13:51,687 --> 00:13:55,148
我们也没听到伊格纳西奥的任何流言蜚语
We hear no gossip about Ignacio.

80
00:13:55,189 --> 00:13:57,442
尽管有诸多女工人们每天围着他转
With all the female workers around him!

81
00:13:59,069 --> 00:14:03,865
我要确认玛丽亚爱伊格纳西奥
I want to be sure Maria loves Ignacio.

82
00:14:03,907 --> 00:14:07,953
若果不是的话，她不会很好的照顾老公和她的孩子的
If not, she won´t take care of him and his children.

83
00:14:09,663 --> 00:14:12,666
别担心，她很爱他呢
Don´t worry. Of course she loves him.

84
00:14:12,708 --> 00:14:14,042
你怎么想？
Don´t you?

85
00:14:14,585 --> 00:14:17,629
- 你怎么想的？ - 她很爱他的
- Don´t you? - She really loves him!

86
00:14:17,671 --> 00:14:21,257
这很好，这下放心了
Then it´s fine, that´s a relief.

87
00:14:25,971 --> 00:14:30,058
她很害羞，从来没喝过，但是她会喜欢的
She´s shy because she´s never done it. But she´ll enjoy it.

88
00:14:30,100 --> 00:14:33,937
她喝一口，会很喜欢的
When she tastes it, she´ll like it.

89
00:14:34,938 --> 00:14:37,566
怎么会不喜欢呢
How not to enjoy it?

90
00:14:39,401 --> 00:14:40,986
你会看见的
You´ll see.

91
00:14:42,321 --> 00:14:45,866
我们在逗你呢
We´re teasing you! Laugh!

92
00:14:45,907 --> 00:14:48,327
你会表现的很好的
You´ll have to perform very well.

93
00:14:49,328 --> 00:14:51,496
敬未来的新人
To the future couple!

94
00:14:52,998 --> 00:14:54,791
我还有更好的消息
I have more good news.

95
00:14:55,334 --> 00:14:58,378
老板要带我进城
The boss is taking me to the city.

96
00:14:59,212 --> 00:15:01,632
我一回来
As soon as I come back,

97
00:15:02,174 --> 00:15:03,800
就娶玛丽亚
I´ll marry Maria.

98
00:15:04,468 --> 00:15:06,345
谢谢
Thank you.

99
00:15:06,386 --> 00:15:10,641
- 你进城不担心吗？ - 怎么会呢
- Aren´t you scared of going to the city? - Not at all.

100
00:15:12,308 --> 00:15:16,312
无论你去哪里，别忘了你的老家
Wherever you go, don´t forget where you come from.

101
00:15:16,355 --> 00:15:19,066
顺便问问，你进城干些什么呢？
By the way, what will you do in the city?

102
00:15:21,109 --> 00:15:23,737
做买卖，曼纽尔
Business, Manuel. Business.

103
00:15:23,779 --> 00:15:26,907
为了做买卖 - 祝你好运
- To business. - Good luck.

104
00:15:35,874 --> 00:15:37,668
你睡着了吗？
Are you asleep?

105
00:15:38,168 --> 00:15:39,503
你睡着了吗？
Are you asleep?

106
00:15:40,921 --> 00:15:42,381
醒醒
Wake up.

107
00:15:42,923 --> 00:15:44,633
快点，醒醒
Come on, wake up.

108
00:15:44,675 --> 00:15:47,427
- 喜欢吗？ - 到我上面来
- Feel like it? - Get on top of me.

109
00:15:49,930 --> 00:15:51,598
摸我啊
Touch me.

110
00:15:56,395 --> 00:15:59,523
你累了？ 你不想做？
Are you tired? You don´t want to?

111
00:16:03,777 --> 00:16:05,445
等等，硬起来了
Wait, it´s getting hard.

112
00:16:56,455 --> 00:17:00,250
这歌唱的火山都要睡着了
Sing for the volcano to fall asleep.

113
00:17:21,730 --> 00:17:23,815
你干活太慢了
You work too slowly.

114
00:17:35,786 --> 00:17:39,664
- 美国有什么？ - 大房子
- What´s in the United States? - Big houses.

115
00:17:40,540 --> 00:17:42,167
还有花园
With gardens.

116
00:17:42,667 --> 00:17:45,086
人们有汽车
People have cars.

117
00:17:47,547 --> 00:17:49,758
从早到晚都是有电的
The electricity works all the time.

118
00:17:50,425 --> 00:17:52,260
甚至大街上的路灯
Even the streets are lit.

119
00:17:53,136 --> 00:17:55,305
他们销售去皮的水果
They sell the fruit peeled.

120
00:17:55,889 --> 00:17:58,892
所有人都讲英语
And everybody speaks English.

121
00:18:00,435 --> 00:18:03,647
你最好在考虑英语之前
You´d better learn Spanish

122
00:18:03,688 --> 00:18:05,816
学学西班牙语
before thinking about English.

123
00:18:05,857 --> 00:18:08,235
这是因为人们喜欢你
It´s because of people like you

124
00:18:08,735 --> 00:18:10,904
这个国家没前途
this country is stuck.

125
00:18:15,409 --> 00:18:17,744
那里还有什么呢？
And what else is there?

126
00:18:17,786 --> 00:18:20,580
钱，美元
Money. Dollars.

127
00:18:27,796 --> 00:18:31,299
- 那里的空气是什么味道？ - 我不知道
- What does the air smell like there? - I don´t know.

128
00:18:34,428 --> 00:18:39,099
这里的空气除了咖啡味就是火山的味道
Here, the air smells of coffee. And of the volcano.

129
00:18:41,101 --> 00:18:43,103
你不害怕离开这里？
You´re not afraid to leave?

130
00:18:56,491 --> 00:18:59,035
这里的蛇越来越多了
More and more snakes.

131
00:19:02,331 --> 00:19:04,583
你看，这里也变得危险了
There´s danger here too, you see.

132
00:19:08,503 --> 00:19:11,798
它死在这里之前一定走了很长的路
It must have walked a long time before falling here.

133
00:19:28,023 --> 00:19:29,358
我们走吧
Let´s go.

134
00:19:47,834 --> 00:19:50,128
你心里想什么呢？
What do you have in mind?

135
00:22:00,468 --> 00:22:02,886
你认为格里戈在等你
You think the Gringos are waiting for you,

136
00:22:04,012 --> 00:22:06,474
还有工作和住房，嗯？
with a job and a home, huh?

137
00:22:07,223 --> 00:22:10,310
白人不会善待你的
White people will treat you like shit.

138
00:22:10,352 --> 00:22:13,647
不，他们已经有黑人了
No, they have their Negroes for that.

139
00:22:13,688 --> 00:22:16,317
他是印第安人，不是黑人
He is an Indian, not a Negro.

140
00:22:16,358 --> 00:22:18,319
闭嘴，都是胡扯
Shut up, it´s the same shit.

141
00:22:18,360 --> 00:22:20,945
黑人的待遇更糟
The Negroes are treated worse.

142
00:22:21,738 --> 00:22:24,325
派佩是自豪的印第安人
Pepe, proud Indian.

143
00:22:27,077 --> 00:22:30,205
派佩没有钱
Pepe has no money.

144
00:22:30,246 --> 00:22:32,290
他很穷
He is poor.

145
00:22:36,711 --> 00:22:39,423
- 再来一杯 - 喝我的
- Another drink, please. - Take mine!

146
00:22:40,757 --> 00:22:43,636
不要了，太饱了
Not from that one. The good stuff.

147
00:22:45,261 --> 00:22:47,263
她不喝你的
She doesn´t drink your piss.

148
00:22:50,601 --> 00:22:52,394
她是个女士
She´s a lady.

149
00:22:52,727 --> 00:22:54,605
我们能理解
We´ll see.

150
00:22:55,772 --> 00:22:57,857
一边待着去
Sit on this!

151
00:22:59,192 --> 00:23:00,486
教教我
Teach me.

152
00:23:01,487 --> 00:23:03,154
华尼托想要你
Juanito wants to taste you.

153
00:24:11,432 --> 00:24:12,641
嘿
Hey.

154
00:24:13,726 --> 00:24:15,268
给我买杯酒喝
Buy me a drink.

155
00:24:16,520 --> 00:24:19,272
伊格纳西奥不在给我赊账了
Ignacio won´t give me more credit.

156
00:24:22,275 --> 00:24:24,737
我工作不是为了给你买酒喝
I don´t work to pay your drinks.

157
00:24:42,338 --> 00:24:43,838
而且你喝多了
And you are too drunk.

158
00:25:48,570 --> 00:25:49,822
派佩
Pepe.

159
00:25:51,699 --> 00:25:52,991
派佩
Pepe.

160
00:27:10,861 --> 00:27:12,363
别射在里面
Don´t come inside me.

161
00:27:13,237 --> 00:27:14,740
别射在里面
Don´t come inside me.

162
00:27:15,324 --> 00:27:17,826
第一次没事的
The first time, nothing happens.

163
00:27:59,910 --> 00:28:02,955
在火山的后面就是美国
Behind the volcano, it´s the United States.

164
00:28:02,996 --> 00:28:06,417
中间还有个墨西哥
Well, there is Mexico in between.

165
00:28:13,799 --> 00:28:16,385
你真的不害怕？
Really, you´re not afraid?

166
00:28:16,969 --> 00:28:20,389
不，我必须穿越沙漠
No. I have to cross a desert.

167
00:28:21,432 --> 00:28:23,809
我要整日整夜的走
I must walk day and night

168
00:28:23,851 --> 00:28:26,060
逃离米戈
to escape the Migra.

169
00:28:29,022 --> 00:28:31,442
我还得游水
Also, I´ll need to swim

170
00:28:32,443 --> 00:28:36,112
因为我得穿过两条河
because I´ll cross two rivers.

171
00:28:40,492 --> 00:28:42,369
你带我一起去吗？
Are you taking me with you?

172
00:28:44,413 --> 00:28:46,247
也许
Maybe.

173
00:28:46,289 --> 00:28:48,082
如果你对我好的话
If you are nice to me.

174
00:28:59,678 --> 00:29:01,638
我已经对你好了
I´ve already been nice.

175
00:29:09,646 --> 00:29:12,649
可以了，我得把它带回去
Enough. I must take it back.

176
00:29:16,987 --> 00:29:18,530
你都快喝完了
You almost finished it.

177
00:30:38,318 --> 00:30:39,820
告诉我
Tell me,

178
00:30:40,362 --> 00:30:42,698
火山后面有什么？
what´s behind the volcano?

179
00:30:43,323 --> 00:30:44,658
寒冷的天气
Cold weather.

180
00:31:10,767 --> 00:31:12,769
- 就这些？ - 是的，就这些
- That´s all? - Yes, that´s all.

181
00:31:56,855 --> 00:31:58,106
爸爸
Dad!

182
00:31:59,024 --> 00:32:00,192
爸爸
Dad!

183
00:32:03,820 --> 00:32:06,657
- 这里有蛇  - 别动啊
- There are snakes. - Don´t move!

184
00:32:06,698 --> 00:32:08,325
我们来了
We´re coming!

185
00:32:42,818 --> 00:32:46,446
驱蛇剂会有效果吗？
The snake repellent will work this time?

186
00:32:46,488 --> 00:32:47,989
会有效果的
Of course it will.

187
00:32:50,200 --> 00:32:54,121
- 大家可不想在田间和蛇一起工作 - 当然了
- People won´t work in a field with snakes. - Sure.

188
00:32:54,162 --> 00:32:57,124
他们不敢杀蛇，你还要离开
They don´t dare kill them. And you are leaving too.

189
00:33:00,752 --> 00:33:04,506
是的，但是这种产品很有效的
Yes, but this product will work.

190
00:33:05,006 --> 00:33:07,092
是美国生产的
It comes from the United States.

191
00:33:07,134 --> 00:33:09,177
- 那一定不错了 - 当然了
- So it must be good. - Sure.

192
00:33:09,219 --> 00:33:11,304
给你未来的丈夫
Serve your future husband first.

193
00:33:12,013 --> 00:33:13,515
谢谢，玛丽亚
Thank you, Maria.

194
00:33:22,023 --> 00:33:23,900
玛丽亚怎么了？
What´s going on with Maria?

195
00:33:27,237 --> 00:33:31,366
也许是驱蛇剂，味道太浓了
Might be the snake repellent. It smells too strong.

196
00:33:31,408 --> 00:33:32,993
你闻到了吗？
Do you smell it?

197
00:33:33,952 --> 00:33:36,496
我闻到了，感觉不舒服
Me too, it makes me feel sick.

198
00:33:36,538 --> 00:33:39,416
我什么也没闻到
I don´t smell anything.

199
00:33:44,212 --> 00:33:46,131
真的没有
Really nothing.

200
00:33:46,673 --> 00:33:48,091
对你有好处
Good for you.

201
00:34:01,438 --> 00:34:04,441
让我们撒点登革热消毒剂
Let´s spread the anti-dengue

202
00:34:05,025 --> 00:34:06,943
还有其他的池塘
in all the other pools.

203
00:34:27,005 --> 00:34:29,257
我来吧
I´ll do it.

204
00:34:29,299 --> 00:34:31,176
为什么不一起去？
Why not go together?

205
00:34:32,010 --> 00:34:33,887
你得待在这里
You can carry on here.

206
00:34:37,098 --> 00:34:39,559
别在外面待太久
Don´t stay out too late!

207
00:35:18,349 --> 00:35:19,766
一百公斤
A quintal.

208
00:35:27,607 --> 00:35:29,651
你故意把咖啡兑水了
You soaked the coffee on purpose.

209
00:35:30,444 --> 00:35:32,195
你以为我蠢吗？
You think I´m stupid?

210
00:35:33,780 --> 00:35:35,490
我什么也没干啊
I didn´t do anything.

211
00:35:38,118 --> 00:35:40,495
谁来为不足的份量买单？
Who will pay the missing weight?

212
00:35:41,955 --> 00:35:44,333
你为什么和老板作对？
Why do you defend the boss?

213
00:35:46,377 --> 00:35:48,421
玛丽亚，回家去
Maria! Go back to the house!

214
00:35:52,716 --> 00:35:56,052
如果你想得到报酬，去把它晒干
If you want to get paid, dry your bag.

215
00:35:57,512 --> 00:35:59,139
站一边去
Step aside.

216
00:36:44,768 --> 00:36:46,269
你喜欢吗？
Did you like it?

217
00:36:47,938 --> 00:36:49,606
那天晚上
The other night.

218
00:36:51,359 --> 00:36:52,943
都过去了
It´s been a while.

219
00:36:53,652 --> 00:36:55,570
你该回家了
You should have come back.

220
00:36:58,114 --> 00:37:00,116
我不能离家出走
I couldn´t escape from home.

221
00:37:01,952 --> 00:37:03,454
你喜欢吗？
Did you like it?

222
00:37:03,954 --> 00:37:05,373
你呢？
And you?

223
00:37:12,003 --> 00:37:13,506
你受伤了吗？
Did it hurt?

224
00:37:27,561 --> 00:37:29,020
那么
So?

225
00:37:29,813 --> 00:37:31,940
是你的第一次吗？
Was it your first time?

226
00:37:38,364 --> 00:37:39,698
如何
So?

227
00:37:40,408 --> 00:37:41,908
感觉很好
It was good.

228
00:37:44,328 --> 00:37:45,996
今晚来
Come tonight.

229
00:37:48,374 --> 00:37:49,833
我不能
I can´t.

230
00:37:51,292 --> 00:37:53,379
但是我们会很快再来
But we´ll have time, soon.

231
00:37:54,921 --> 00:37:56,256
什么时候？
When?

232
00:37:57,048 --> 00:37:58,675
当我们离开的时候
When we leave.

233
00:38:01,470 --> 00:38:03,680
在咖啡收获季之后
After the coffee harvest,

234
00:38:03,722 --> 00:38:05,682
你拿到薪水
when you get paid.

235
00:38:07,267 --> 00:38:10,604
我会躲在树林里等你
I´ll hide in the forest and wait for you.

236
00:38:26,328 --> 00:38:29,789
像这样吹口哨，可以找到我
Whistle like that to find me.

237
00:38:31,041 --> 00:38:32,709
你一吹口哨
When you whistle,

238
00:38:33,168 --> 00:38:35,712
我就会从我的藏身之地出来
I´ll come out of my hiding place.

239
00:38:44,262 --> 00:38:46,014
我会给你带瓶酒的
I´ll bring the bottle for you.

240
00:39:41,529 --> 00:39:46,116
曼纽尔，把桌子准备好
Manuel, get the table ready.

241
00:40:02,298 --> 00:40:03,467
玛丽亚
Maria!

242
00:40:03,842 --> 00:40:06,970
你在哪儿呢？ 过来帮帮我
Where are you? Come help me clean.

243
00:40:07,804 --> 00:40:10,098
我要把祭品带到火山去
I´ll make an offering to the volcano.

244
00:40:10,140 --> 00:40:13,977
- 干嘛的？ 我已经做了 - 让她去吧
- What for? I already did. - Let her go.

245
00:40:14,687 --> 00:40:16,397
这很重要
It´s important.

246
00:40:25,071 --> 00:40:26,699
我的工资呢？
And my wages?

247
00:40:28,241 --> 00:40:31,244
你已经把你的薪水都喝掉了，就像派佩
You´ve already drunk more than your pay, like Pepe.

248
00:40:31,286 --> 00:40:33,121
你必须做到下一个收获季
You must do the next harvest

249
00:40:33,664 --> 00:40:36,916
才能冲抵你的债务
to be able to pay your debt.

250
00:40:38,502 --> 00:40:41,796
去见鬼吧，我不欠你任何东西
Go to hell. I owe you nothing.

251
00:40:42,881 --> 00:40:44,425
如果你不回来
If you don´t come back,

252
00:40:45,426 --> 00:40:47,428
老板也会抓到你的
the boss will come and get you.

253
00:40:49,722 --> 00:40:51,306
告诉你的朋友
Tell your friend.

254
00:40:53,726 --> 00:40:55,268
你自己告诉他吧
Tell him yourself.

255
00:40:55,310 --> 00:40:59,105
那个混蛋偷了我的钱，他这会儿正在穿越边境呢
That son of a bitch robbed me. He´s crossing the border now.

256
00:41:01,232 --> 00:41:02,568
下一个
Next.

257
00:41:18,667 --> 00:41:20,336
你要干什么？
What are you doing?

258
00:41:20,919 --> 00:41:22,338
派佩走了？
Pepe has left?

259
00:41:24,047 --> 00:41:26,675
- 什么时候？ - 昨天
- When? - Yesterday.

260
00:41:27,343 --> 00:41:28,968
没拿薪水？
Without being paid?

261
00:41:29,010 --> 00:41:32,305
这个混蛋知道他在干什么
The asshole knew what he was doing.

262
00:41:32,348 --> 00:41:34,350
他耍了我们
He fucked us over.

263
00:41:36,017 --> 00:41:38,144
你怎么看上他的？
Why are you looking for him?

264
00:41:42,023 --> 00:41:43,942
我能去你家吗？
Can I walk you home?

265
00:44:11,840 --> 00:44:13,425
你去哪儿了？
Where were you going?

266
00:44:16,177 --> 00:44:18,639
去火山了，去送祭品
To the volcano, to make an offering.

267
00:44:19,180 --> 00:44:20,766
我迷路了
I lost my way.

268
00:44:21,392 --> 00:44:24,728
我以为你对种植园非常熟悉呢
I thought you knew the plantation well.

269
00:44:25,354 --> 00:44:26,814
好奇怪啊
That´s weird.

270
00:45:31,879 --> 00:45:34,631
不，别动，让我看看
No, don´t move. Let me see.

271
00:45:37,551 --> 00:45:40,721
你为什么没注意你的例假
Why didn´t you count your moons?

272
00:45:41,680 --> 00:45:43,097
你怎么不说话？
Are you dumb?

273
00:45:44,558 --> 00:45:47,185
是那个叫派佩的混蛋吧
It was that bastard Pepe.

274
00:45:48,854 --> 00:45:50,397
什么时候开始的？
Since when?

275
00:45:52,399 --> 00:45:54,651
咖啡收获季的时候
When the coffee harvest began.

276
00:45:54,693 --> 00:45:59,406
我没注意，你都不告诉我？
You waited until I noticed it to tell me?

277
00:46:01,783 --> 00:46:03,660
我是不确定
I wasn´t sure.

278
00:46:03,702 --> 00:46:07,915
伊格纳西奥去城里，我们不会那么快结婚的
Ignacio went to the city. We can´t marry you in time.

279
00:46:11,710 --> 00:46:15,171
我最好离开，躲起来
I´d better leave. I´ll hide.

280
00:46:15,631 --> 00:46:20,677
有个大肚子，你就不能随心所欲了
With a big belly, you can´t do what you want.

281
00:46:20,719 --> 00:46:22,554
你是怎么想的？
What do you think?

282
00:46:22,596 --> 00:46:24,640
别犯傻了
Don´t be silly.

283
00:46:28,060 --> 00:46:29,853
我们必须把孩子打掉
We have to get rid of it.

284
00:46:46,495 --> 00:46:47,829
喝了
Drink this.

285
00:46:49,748 --> 00:46:51,333
你不想？
You don´t want to?

286
00:46:56,672 --> 00:46:59,007
派佩现在在哪儿？
Where is Pepe now?

287
00:47:10,268 --> 00:47:11,520
喝了
Drink it.

288
00:47:18,276 --> 00:47:19,736
都喝了
Drink it all.

289
00:47:58,483 --> 00:47:59,776
胡安娜
Juana.

290
00:48:01,111 --> 00:48:03,614
玛丽亚为什么吐的这么厉害
Why is Maria vomiting like this?

291
00:48:04,990 --> 00:48:06,491
她有点紧张
She is nervous.

292
00:48:08,284 --> 00:48:11,747
告诉她别吐了，我睡不着
Tell her to vomit further off. I can´t sleep.

293
00:48:41,109 --> 00:48:44,196
你这样做，是为了离家出走？
Did you do it because you plan to go away?

294
00:48:44,237 --> 00:48:46,198
我们有过承诺的
We gave our word.

295
00:48:46,698 --> 00:48:49,493
如果伊格纳西奥知道了
If Ignacio learns about this,

296
00:48:49,534 --> 00:48:52,037
你爸爸会丢掉工作的
your father will lose his job.

297
00:48:52,079 --> 00:48:55,499
我们又得到另一个农场，这是你期望的吗？
We´ll go from farm to farm. Is that what you want?

298
00:48:55,916 --> 00:48:57,125
嗯？
Huh?

299
00:49:21,024 --> 00:49:23,235
双脚一起使劲跳
Jump hard with both feet together.

300
00:49:23,276 --> 00:49:24,903
否则没有效果的
Otherwise it won´t work.

301
00:49:25,404 --> 00:49:27,364
我在和你说话，会没有效果的
I´m telling you, it won´t work.

302
00:49:28,448 --> 00:49:29,950
继续跳
Go on, do it right!

303
00:50:31,553 --> 00:50:33,388
这是生命的火焰
It´s the flame of life.

304
00:50:33,430 --> 00:50:36,475
我没办法了，这是命运
I can´t do anything. It is his destiny to live.

305
00:50:39,436 --> 00:50:41,271
我们必须告诉你爸爸
We must tell your father.

306
00:50:41,938 --> 00:50:43,440
系紧点
Tie it tightly.

307
00:50:47,110 --> 00:50:48,612
把肚子藏起来
Hide your belly.

308
00:51:07,839 --> 00:51:09,383
另一本杂志？
Another magazine?

309
00:51:10,675 --> 00:51:12,844
伊格纳西奥给我的
Ignacio gave it to me.

310
00:51:15,013 --> 00:51:18,183
别烧了，我没看完呢
Don´t burn it before I finish looking at it.

311
00:51:29,694 --> 00:51:31,238
你会告诉他吗？
Will you tell him?

312
00:51:33,031 --> 00:51:34,658
我会的
Then I will.

313
00:51:38,870 --> 00:51:42,958
伊格纳西奥会把我们赶走的，因为你的女儿
Ignacio will kick us out because of your daughter.

314
00:51:43,583 --> 00:51:45,378
除非那种产品无效
Besides, the product didn´t work.

315
00:51:45,419 --> 00:51:47,421
田地里还是有很多的蛇
The field is still full of snakes.

316
00:51:48,964 --> 00:51:51,091
今年玉米不会有很好的收成
There won´t be any corn this year.

317
00:51:51,675 --> 00:51:53,635
老板也不再需要我们了
The boss won´t need us.

318
00:52:00,308 --> 00:52:02,269
别再说了
Don´t say anything yet.

319
00:52:06,690 --> 00:52:09,318
你没看好她
You didn´t watch her.

320
00:52:09,360 --> 00:52:12,405
你看，女人就必须待在家里
You see, women must stay at home.

321
00:52:18,243 --> 00:52:20,371
我会有办法的
I´ll find a solution, as usual.

322
00:52:37,137 --> 00:52:39,764
你在其他种植园找到活了吗？
Did you find work in another plantation?

323
00:52:39,806 --> 00:52:43,143
带着两个女人和一个孩子是很难的事情
It´s hard with two women and a baby.

324
00:52:45,604 --> 00:52:47,147
再试试
Keep trying.

325
00:52:47,856 --> 00:52:49,232
我们必须小心
We must be careful.

326
00:52:49,274 --> 00:52:52,652
他们说，工头有手机的
The foremen have cell phones, they talk.

327
00:52:54,363 --> 00:52:59,534
我们要在伊格纳西奥回来之前找到个房子
We need to find a house before Ignacio comes back.

328
00:53:00,369 --> 00:53:03,204
没有工作，这太难了
It will be difficult. There´s no work.

329
00:53:04,247 --> 00:53:07,626
如果我自己把蛇都赶走了呢？
What if I chase the snakes off the field myself?

330
00:53:08,001 --> 00:53:11,880
等他回来的时候，我们已经播种了
We´ll be already sowing when he gets back,

331
00:53:11,922 --> 00:53:13,924
那样他就不会把我们赶走了
so he can´t kick us out.

332
00:53:14,299 --> 00:53:17,428
连教士都无法把蛇赶走
Even the spiritual guide couldn´t expel the snakes.

333
00:53:20,180 --> 00:53:21,390
谢谢
Thank you.

334
00:53:28,104 --> 00:53:29,689
你的帽子
Your hat!

335
00:53:39,824 --> 00:53:41,452
别担心
Don´t worry.

336
00:53:42,577 --> 00:53:45,498
孩子出生后，他会改变的
When the baby arrives, he´ll change.

337
00:53:47,707 --> 00:53:49,209
我不这么认为
I don´t think so.

338
00:53:50,251 --> 00:53:51,920
因为是个女孩儿？
Because it´s a girl?

339
00:53:54,172 --> 00:53:55,674
是的
Yes.

340
00:53:57,717 --> 00:53:59,553
你注意你的例假了吗？
So you count your moons?

341
00:55:18,549 --> 00:55:20,216
你看，见效了
You see, it worked!

342
00:55:21,718 --> 00:55:23,011
你太疯狂了
You´re crazy.

343
00:55:23,053 --> 00:55:25,680
这风会把种植园烧掉的
With this wind, you could burn the plantation down.

344
00:55:26,264 --> 00:55:28,224
告诉工人们
Tell the workers.

345
00:55:28,266 --> 00:55:31,686
伊格纳西奥回来之前，我们必须播种
We have to sow corn before Ignacio gets back.

346
00:55:34,731 --> 00:55:37,610
- 这没用啊 - 别冒险
- It didn´t work. - Don´t tempt fate.

347
00:55:37,651 --> 00:55:40,488
看，还是有蛇啊
Look, there are still snakes.

348
00:55:40,529 --> 00:55:42,113
别跑
Don´t run.

349
00:55:42,155 --> 00:55:44,575
- 他们会咬你的 - 走吧
- They´ll bite you. - Let´s go.

350
00:57:26,427 --> 00:57:28,596
早上好，你好吗？
Good morning. How are you?

351
00:57:29,513 --> 00:57:33,933
卫生部门，我来这里是为了人口普查
Health Department. I´m here for the population census.

352
00:57:34,351 --> 00:57:36,437
她会问你一些问题的
She´ll ask you some questions.

353
00:57:37,563 --> 00:57:41,065
你是来要咖啡的吗？
Will you come in for coffee?

354
00:57:41,609 --> 00:57:42,901
她说什么？
What did she say?

355
00:57:43,943 --> 00:57:46,946
她能给你咖啡，开始吧
She offers you coffee. Please go on.

356
00:57:47,615 --> 00:57:50,451
房子里住着几个人？
How many people live in this house?

357
00:57:50,492 --> 00:57:52,160
你们几个人？
How many are you?

358
00:57:53,953 --> 00:57:55,288
三个
Three.

359
00:57:55,997 --> 00:57:57,165
几个？
How many?

360
00:57:57,874 --> 00:57:59,627
很快就四个了
They will soon be four.

361
00:57:59,668 --> 00:58:01,462
女儿怀孕了
The daughter is pregnant?

362
00:58:03,631 --> 00:58:05,965
这里是你们的固定住所吗？
Is this your permanent address?

363
00:58:09,010 --> 00:58:10,845
这里是你们的住所吗？
What address will you give?

364
00:58:17,852 --> 00:58:19,688
这里是我们的住所
This is our address.

365
00:58:20,188 --> 00:58:23,233
- 他们要离开 - 他们要去哪里啊？
- They are leaving. - Where are they going?

366
00:58:23,817 --> 00:58:25,319
我不知道
I don´t know.

367
00:58:27,862 --> 00:58:31,367
这里没有电，没有饮用水
There´s no electricity, no drinking water...

368
00:58:31,408 --> 00:58:33,786
你结束了吗？ 走吧
You finished? Let´s go.

369
00:58:33,827 --> 00:58:37,038
没有他们我也得结束，非常感谢
I´ll finish without them. Thank you very much.

370
00:59:18,497 --> 00:59:20,499
每天按摩你的肚子
Massage your belly every day

371
00:59:20,541 --> 00:59:24,461
让孩子的头位于正确的位置
to bring the baby´s head in the right position.

372
00:59:29,048 --> 00:59:30,759
自己做
Do it yourself.

373
00:59:30,801 --> 00:59:32,010
就像这样
Like this.

374
00:59:36,055 --> 00:59:37,850
我有点心痛
I have heartburn.

375
00:59:37,891 --> 00:59:41,687
这是因为孩子已经有了头发
It´s because the baby has hair already.

376
00:59:50,571 --> 00:59:52,531
我感觉像火山一样
I feel like the volcano.

377
00:59:52,573 --> 00:59:55,451
你体内有了生命之火
You have the light of life inside you.

378
00:59:55,492 --> 00:59:58,244
这让你具有了魔力
That makes you magical.

379
00:59:58,286 --> 01:00:01,915
你必须把你的手放在你生病的躯体上
You must lay your hands on the sick hens.

380
01:00:02,875 --> 01:00:08,296
你能治愈他们，你的生命之火能驱赶恶人，忧郁的情绪，赶走不良反应
You can heal them. Your light expels demons, dark spirits, bad energies.

381
01:00:11,090 --> 01:00:13,259
我怀孕时
When I was pregnant,

382
01:00:14,177 --> 01:00:16,220
就有了母乳
I smelt of milk.

383
01:00:16,262 --> 01:00:21,643
母乳的味道可以驱赶蚊子，蝎子和苍蝇
The smell of my milk chased off mosquitos, scorpions, flies,

384
01:00:21,685 --> 01:00:23,978
甚至是蛇
even snakes.

385
01:00:33,279 --> 01:00:34,615
她在动
She´s moving.

386
01:00:34,656 --> 01:00:36,282
- 哪里？ - 这里
- Where? - Here.

387
01:00:36,325 --> 01:00:37,951
太好了
It´s wonderful.

388
01:00:39,243 --> 01:00:41,287
她听见我们的谈话了
She hears us talking.

389
01:00:43,206 --> 01:00:45,083
继续按摩
Go on with the massage.

390
01:00:57,513 --> 01:00:59,348
我们住哪儿？
Where will we live?

391
01:01:27,418 --> 01:01:29,420
我可以把它们赶走
I can chase them off.

392
01:01:30,546 --> 01:01:32,548
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?

393
01:01:35,258 --> 01:01:36,969
我说蛇
The snakes.

394
01:01:39,388 --> 01:01:41,432
我们还有机会
We still have a chance.

395
01:01:42,098 --> 01:01:44,393
如果我能把它们赶走，我们就可以播种了
If I chase them off, we can sow.

396
01:01:49,481 --> 01:01:52,025
就像你说的，我们就可以留在这里
And like you said, we can stay here.

397
01:01:53,276 --> 01:01:54,945
我是认真的
I´m serious.

398
01:01:56,112 --> 01:01:57,573
闭嘴
Shut up.

399
01:01:58,699 --> 01:02:00,826
怀孕的女人可以驱赶蛇
Pregnant women can chase snakes off.

400
01:02:01,410 --> 01:02:03,077
可以吗？
Can´t they?

401
01:02:15,757 --> 01:02:18,259
我怀孕的时候，你和我说的
You told me when you were pregnant,

402
01:02:18,301 --> 01:02:20,219
你可以驱赶蛇
you chased snakes off.

403
01:02:25,851 --> 01:02:29,521
你之前做过，我也可以的
You did it before. I can do it too.

404
01:02:30,063 --> 01:02:32,148
别相信我们说的任何话
Don´t believe everything we say.

405
01:02:32,190 --> 01:02:34,026
你看不见有什么不同吗？
Can´t you see the difference?

406
01:02:37,153 --> 01:02:39,280
为什么不试试呢？反正也没的选择了
Why not try? Nothing to lose.

407
01:02:39,323 --> 01:02:40,991
闭嘴
Shut up!

408
01:02:43,076 --> 01:02:45,244
让我们问问教士吧
Let´s ask the spiritual guide.

409
01:02:45,871 --> 01:02:47,372
看看他怎么说
See what he says.

410
01:04:27,931 --> 01:04:30,017
神圣的蛇，请离开这里
Sacred snakes, go away from here.

411
01:04:30,058 --> 01:04:34,980
让我们能去田间干活，听一听我们的祈祷
Let us work in this field. Hear our prayers.

412
01:04:35,397 --> 01:04:38,400
神圣的蛇，请离开这里
Sacred snakes, go away from here.

413
01:04:47,283 --> 01:04:49,703
你不必这样
You don´t have to.

414
01:04:49,745 --> 01:04:52,623
别相信他们说的任何话
Don´t believe everything they say.

415
01:04:52,664 --> 01:04:55,459
如果她怀疑，就没有效果了
If she doubts, it won´t work.

416
01:04:58,128 --> 01:05:00,296
感受你的脚步
The vibration of your footsteps...

417
01:05:00,339 --> 01:05:03,342
这能让你驱赶它们
That´s what will chase them off.

418
01:05:04,885 --> 01:05:06,845
如果你相信，就开始走
If you have faith, go.

419
01:05:11,224 --> 01:05:13,477
大步走
Walk heavily.

420
01:05:18,148 --> 01:05:19,566
大步走
Walk heavily.

421
01:05:47,010 --> 01:05:49,680
她被蛇咬了
A snake bit her!

422
01:05:50,430 --> 01:05:53,266
我告诉过你，带她走
I told you! Take her away.

423
01:05:53,307 --> 01:05:55,435
赶快
Hurry up!

424
01:06:03,402 --> 01:06:06,405
- 带她走 - 我们必须祈祷
- Take her away. - We must pray!

425
01:06:06,446 --> 01:06:09,741
闭嘴，把小车推过来
Shut up! Go get the cart!

426
01:06:09,783 --> 01:06:11,618
带她到伊格纳西奥那里
Take her to Ignacio´s place.

427
01:06:12,077 --> 01:06:13,453
和我一起祈祷
Pray with me.

428
01:06:13,787 --> 01:06:15,288
别祈祷了
Forget your prayers.

429
01:06:15,330 --> 01:06:17,082
把毒液放出来
Take out the venom.

430
01:06:18,375 --> 01:06:20,001
赶快
Hurry up!

431
01:06:20,377 --> 01:06:21,837
快走
Go faster.

432
01:06:30,095 --> 01:06:32,222
赶快，她快要死了
Hurry, she´s gonna die!

433
01:06:33,390 --> 01:06:34,683
使劲拉
Pull harder.

434
01:06:57,331 --> 01:06:59,333
我们就快到了
We´ll soon be there.

435
01:06:59,374 --> 01:07:00,792
醒醒
Wake up!

436
01:07:00,834 --> 01:07:03,295
会没事的，别离开我
It will be alright, stay with me.

437
01:07:16,308 --> 01:07:17,768
醒醒
Wake up.

438
01:07:19,436 --> 01:07:22,022
醒醒，会没事的
Wake up. It will be alright.

439
01:07:34,743 --> 01:07:37,287
快走啊，我们赶时间
Move! We must hurry!

440
01:07:43,043 --> 01:07:44,920
你为什么要这么做？
Why did you do this?

441
01:07:45,420 --> 01:07:50,467
我和你说过没用的
I told you it wouldn´t work.

442
01:07:51,092 --> 01:07:53,637
我告诉过你的，我的宝贝女儿
I told you, my little girl.

443
01:07:53,678 --> 01:07:57,350
我为什么要和你说这些呢？
Why did I let you do this?

444
01:08:00,185 --> 01:08:03,021
我很抱歉，原谅我
I´m so sorry! Forgive me.

445
01:08:03,688 --> 01:08:07,692
为什么啊，我的女儿，我很抱歉
Why, my little girl? I´m so sorry!

446
01:08:12,365 --> 01:08:17,285
我为什么要让你来做这件事呢
Why did I let you do this?

447
01:08:27,128 --> 01:08:28,797
醒醒，我的女儿
Wake up, my little girl.

448
01:08:36,888 --> 01:08:38,640
小心啊
Be careful with her.

449
01:08:41,977 --> 01:08:43,311
赶快
Hurry!

450
01:08:44,062 --> 01:08:46,523
找人看着车
Look out for cars!

451
01:08:47,858 --> 01:08:49,067
快跑
Run, run!

452
01:08:49,109 --> 01:08:50,861
请让开，快跑
Make way, please! Run!

453
01:09:03,290 --> 01:09:04,791
这边
This way!

454
01:09:10,130 --> 01:09:11,506
大门
The entrance!

455
01:09:12,173 --> 01:09:13,967
请让开
Make way, please!

456
01:09:19,348 --> 01:09:20,932
求你了，医生
Please! Doctor!

457
01:09:20,974 --> 01:09:22,517
有医生吗，快啊
A doctor, quick!

458
01:09:25,520 --> 01:09:28,231
帮帮我们，她快死了
Help us. She´s dying.

459
01:09:28,690 --> 01:09:30,484
帮帮我们，快啊
Help us, quick!

460
01:09:30,525 --> 01:09:32,527
请问有医生吗
A doctor, please!

461
01:09:34,779 --> 01:09:37,157
快点，医生呢
Come on, come on! A doctor!

462
01:09:37,198 --> 01:09:38,867
医生在哪儿？
Where is the doctor?

463
01:09:38,909 --> 01:09:40,328
医生
A doctor!

464
01:10:16,279 --> 01:10:18,114
这儿有个医生
There´s a doctor.

465
01:10:19,115 --> 01:10:20,451
快
Hurry up.

466
01:10:20,867 --> 01:10:23,119
我女儿怎样了？
How is my daughter?

467
01:10:23,161 --> 01:10:25,872
抱歉，我听不懂
Sorry, I don´t speak your language.

468
01:10:26,957 --> 01:10:28,417
坐下吧
Sit down.

469
01:10:28,459 --> 01:10:29,960
她说什么？
What did she say?

470
01:10:30,001 --> 01:10:31,586
我们还要等等
We have to wait.

471
01:10:48,521 --> 01:10:51,898
告诉他们她没事了，已经脱离了生命危险
Tell them she´s fine. She´s out of danger.

472
01:10:51,940 --> 01:10:53,984
和他们说说孩子
And tell them about the baby.

473
01:10:54,025 --> 01:10:56,861
他们救了玛丽亚
They saved Maria.

474
01:10:57,363 --> 01:10:59,323
她现在没事了
She´s fine now.

475
01:10:59,365 --> 01:11:02,784
非常感谢
Thank you very much.

476
01:11:02,826 --> 01:11:05,203
上帝保佑你，谢谢
God bless you. Thank you.

477
01:11:05,245 --> 01:11:07,831
- 请收下我的围巾 - 不，不
- Please have my shawl. - No, no.

478
01:11:07,872 --> 01:11:09,458
谢谢医生
Thank you, Doctor.

479
01:11:09,500 --> 01:11:11,419
孩子如何了？
What about the baby?

480
01:11:16,798 --> 01:11:18,342
孩子没保住
The baby is dead.

481
01:11:19,843 --> 01:11:21,429
哦，天啊
Oh, my God!

482
01:11:27,308 --> 01:11:30,563
- 她以后还能怀上孩子吗？ - 是的，没问题
- Can she still have children? - Yes, don´t worry.

483
01:11:30,604 --> 01:11:32,856
- 你确定？ - 是的
- Are you sure? - Yes, I am.

484
01:11:35,942 --> 01:11:37,986
这有个文件要签
There is a paper to sign.

485
01:11:39,654 --> 01:11:42,115
玛丽亚必须签字
Maria must sign this.

486
01:11:43,950 --> 01:11:47,746
- 这是什么？ - 我从没见过这样的文件
- What is it? - I never saw this kind of paper.

487
01:11:48,747 --> 01:11:50,749
她为什么一定要签字
Why must she sign it?

488
01:11:52,792 --> 01:11:55,629
得到葬礼的钱
To get money for the funeral.

489
01:11:55,670 --> 01:12:00,342
他们会给你们提供棺材，免费的
They´ll give you a coffin. You won´t have to pay.

490
01:12:00,384 --> 01:12:03,471
这是政府资助像你们这样贫穷的农民的
It´s government aid for poor peasants like you.

491
01:12:03,845 --> 01:12:06,599
请接受它，但是她必须签字
Accept it. But she must sign.

492
01:12:06,640 --> 01:12:08,141
这位女士在干什么？
What is the lady doing?

493
01:12:08,183 --> 01:12:11,936
她要玛丽亚来按手印
She´ll sign it with Maria´s fingerprint.

494
01:12:15,690 --> 01:12:17,025
她会按的
She´ll do it.

495
01:12:22,072 --> 01:12:23,990
按在哪里？
Where must she sign?

496
01:12:24,032 --> 01:12:25,158
这儿
Here.

497
01:12:32,625 --> 01:12:33,792
谢谢
Thank you.

498
01:12:34,793 --> 01:12:37,879
你很快就能出院了，我的孩子
You´ll soon be out of here, my girl.

499
01:12:37,921 --> 01:12:40,965
别担心，会没事的
Don´t worry, it will be alright.

500
01:12:41,007 --> 01:12:42,967
你会没事的
You´ll be fine.

501
01:12:43,760 --> 01:12:45,887
会好起来的
It will be alright.

502
01:13:50,034 --> 01:13:52,871
伊格纳西奥保留了我们的房子
Ignacio let us keep our house.

503
01:13:56,500 --> 01:13:59,085
为什么不让我看看孩子
Why didn´t they let me see the baby?

504
01:14:00,879 --> 01:14:03,965
看起来是毒液伤害了孩子
It seems the venom deformed the baby.

505
01:14:04,007 --> 01:14:06,092
你最好别看
Better for you not to see that.

506
01:14:15,728 --> 01:14:18,606
这是我的错，我试图流产的
It´s my fault, I tried to abort.

507
01:14:57,018 --> 01:15:00,188
我们要在坟墓上种棵树
We´ll plant this tree on the grave.

508
01:15:00,230 --> 01:15:02,857
树会成长，变得又高又壮
It will grow, become tall and strong

509
01:15:02,899 --> 01:15:04,984
感谢孩子给的呼吸
thanks to the baby´s breath.

510
01:15:05,026 --> 01:15:07,655
和我一起种树吧
Plant it with me.

511
01:15:08,364 --> 01:15:11,115
给，拿着
Here, take it.

512
01:15:14,536 --> 01:15:17,163
放下棺材吧
Let go of the coffin.

513
01:15:17,205 --> 01:15:19,375
- 让我看看她 - 放下去吧
- Let me see her! - Let go of it.

514
01:15:20,793 --> 01:15:23,002
- 我要见见她 - 冷静一下
- I want to see her! - Calm down.

515
01:15:36,057 --> 01:15:37,559
把她弄走
Let her go.

516
01:16:58,599 --> 01:17:00,224
你在干什么？
What are you doing?

517
01:17:00,266 --> 01:17:02,853
你的伤口会发炎的
Your scar could get infected.

518
01:17:02,895 --> 01:17:04,187
走吧
Let´s go.

519
01:17:07,273 --> 01:17:09,443
小猪需要照顾
The piglets need care.

520
01:17:09,984 --> 01:17:11,445
没关系的
It doesn´t matter!

521
01:17:27,293 --> 01:17:29,546
你一定要去看看孩子的坟墓
You must see the baby´s grave

522
01:17:30,004 --> 01:17:32,508
这样你才能让她安心离开
so you can let her go.

523
01:19:30,334 --> 01:19:32,251
你这是干了什么啊？
What have you done?

524
01:19:32,586 --> 01:19:35,254
你疯了吗？ 这是罪孽啊
Have you gone crazy? This is a sin.

525
01:19:35,296 --> 01:19:37,633
你打开了棺材
You opened the coffin!

526
01:19:37,674 --> 01:19:40,886
- 孩子呢？ - 她没有死
- Where´s the baby? - He´s not dead.

527
01:19:42,513 --> 01:19:44,890
原谅我，真主，原谅我们的鲁莽
Forgive me, Lord, for having been so blind.

528
01:19:44,932 --> 01:19:49,436
这都是我们的错，我们不配得到这样的礼物
It´s our fault. We weren´t worthy of this gift.

529
01:19:49,478 --> 01:19:51,939
是你让我们接受这样的考验吗
Are you sending us this trial

530
01:19:51,980 --> 01:19:55,567
让我们得到小女孩儿的祝福
to make sure we deserve the blessing of a baby girl?

531
01:19:55,609 --> 01:19:57,903
这不是我的女儿
This isn´t my daughter.

532
01:19:57,945 --> 01:20:01,615
是真的吗，真主啊，感谢你的仁慈
If it´s true, Lord, thank you for your generosity!

533
01:20:01,657 --> 01:20:04,618
谢谢，我们的孩子还活着
Thank you, our baby girl is alive.

534
01:20:04,660 --> 01:20:07,579
帮我们找到她吧
Help us find her.

535
01:20:07,621 --> 01:20:10,874
让我们去找她吧
Let´s go and look for her.

536
01:20:10,916 --> 01:20:14,127
感谢您的仁慈
Thank you for your generosity.

537
01:20:14,920 --> 01:20:18,799
给我们指引方向
Show us the way.

538
01:20:18,840 --> 01:20:22,344
让我们找到她吧
Please lead us to her.

539
01:20:23,762 --> 01:20:25,514
让我们找到她吧
Let´s go find her.

540
01:20:30,226 --> 01:20:32,270
你收到钱了吗？
Did you receive money?

541
01:20:37,526 --> 01:20:40,320
我能理解贫穷
I understand poverty.

542
01:20:41,321 --> 01:20:43,907
也许这很难养活一个孩子
Maybe it´s difficult to feed the baby.

543
01:20:44,741 --> 01:20:46,200
但是告诉我
But tell me,

544
01:20:46,660 --> 01:20:48,912
你把孩子卖了？
did you sell the baby?

545
01:20:50,455 --> 01:20:52,248
他在说什么？
What is he saying?

546
01:20:54,208 --> 01:20:55,877
母亲如何？
How´s the mother?

547
01:20:56,920 --> 01:21:00,090
我不知道，我们不能见她
I don´t know. We couldn´t see her.

548
01:21:00,132 --> 01:21:02,009
你把她拘留了
You keep her in custody.

549
01:21:07,931 --> 01:21:12,268
这里是从医院得到的，有母亲的手印
Here is the hospital form with the mother´s fingerprint.

550
01:21:12,769 --> 01:21:14,479
所有事都是计划好的
Everything is in order.

551
01:21:17,231 --> 01:21:19,401
你为什么让她签字？
Why did you let them sign?

552
01:21:19,443 --> 01:21:21,028
你讲西班牙语
You speak Spanish.

553
01:21:23,530 --> 01:21:26,950
一个人不应该在没有见到尸体的情况下签字
One shouldn´t sign this without seeing a corpse.

554
01:21:28,284 --> 01:21:30,286
他们能找到孩子？
They´ll find the baby?

555
01:21:33,957 --> 01:21:36,126
你知道是怎么回事
You know how things work.

556
01:21:36,668 --> 01:21:40,047
你可以提出上诉，我们可以再审
You can file a complaint, we´ll open a case.

557
01:21:40,088 --> 01:21:42,716
但是首要嫌疑人就是她的母亲
But the first suspect will be the mother.

558
01:21:42,758 --> 01:21:44,843
她会继续待在看守所里
She´ll stay in custody.

559
01:21:44,885 --> 01:21:46,887
你就是下一个
And you´ll be next.

560
01:21:49,473 --> 01:21:52,643
女孩儿还年轻，她还可以生孩子的
The girl is still young, she can have more children.

561
01:21:53,977 --> 01:21:56,563
这取决于你
It´s up to you.

562
01:21:59,941 --> 01:22:02,110
他们能找到孩子吗？
Will they find the baby?

563
01:22:02,527 --> 01:22:04,071
他们会努力的
They are trying.

564
01:22:05,197 --> 01:22:08,867
- 她在说什么？ - 她想回家了
- What did she ask? - She wants to leave.

565
01:22:09,910 --> 01:22:13,538
请帮我们找到孩子，先生
Please help us find the baby! Mister!

566
01:22:15,374 --> 01:22:17,542
先生，帮帮我们
Mister, please help us!

567
01:22:17,876 --> 01:22:19,211
先生
Mister.

568
01:22:20,128 --> 01:22:21,922
让我和他说几句
Let me talk to him.

569
01:22:21,963 --> 01:22:23,340
先生
Mister.

570
01:22:26,677 --> 01:22:28,637
别收走你的文件
Don´t close your file.

571
01:22:28,679 --> 01:22:32,182
请别走，帮帮我们
Please don´t go away! Help us.

572
01:22:32,224 --> 01:22:33,517
先生
Mister!

573
01:22:33,975 --> 01:22:36,520
我们该怎么办？
What are we going to do?

574
01:22:38,105 --> 01:22:39,606
别让我们失望
Don´t let us down.

575
01:22:39,648 --> 01:22:42,442
帮助我们找到孩子
Help us find the baby.

576
01:22:42,484 --> 01:22:44,361
你必须帮助我们
You must help us.

577
01:22:46,947 --> 01:22:49,282
你必须帮助我们
You must help us.

578
01:22:49,324 --> 01:22:52,953
冷静点，你会把事情搞砸的
Calm yourself. You´ll make things worse.

579
01:23:08,093 --> 01:23:10,929
他大概住在美国
He´s probably living in the United States

580
01:23:10,971 --> 01:23:15,308
一个大房子里，还有花园，就像杂志上那样
in a big house with a garden, like those in the magazine.

581
01:23:26,361 --> 01:23:28,572
他现在一定也讲英语了
He must speak English by now.

582
01:23:36,121 --> 01:23:37,873
她是个女孩儿
She is a girl.

583
01:23:38,749 --> 01:23:41,042
她太小，还不会说话
And she´s too young to talk.

584
01:23:43,712 --> 01:23:46,590
尽管她远离家乡长大
Even if she grows up far from the fields,

585
01:23:46,631 --> 01:23:49,718
她会继承你的思想
she inherited your fertile hands.

586
01:24:00,812 --> 01:24:03,857
别担心，她能活下来的
Don´t worry, she´ll survive anywhere.

587
01:24:05,400 --> 01:24:07,486
你知道，她可以的
You know she will.

588
01:24:24,711 --> 01:24:27,214
我无法和三个孩子生活在一起
I can´t stay alone with three children.

589
01:24:27,756 --> 01:24:29,883
我理解
I understand.

590
01:24:31,718 --> 01:24:34,429
她会逐渐恢复的，你知道的
She´ll recover little by little, you´ll see.

591
01:24:35,055 --> 01:24:37,557
这个我们很确定
We are sure of that.

592
01:24:37,599 --> 01:24:40,685
- 她是个健康的女人 - 是的
- She´s a strong woman. - So be it.

593
01:24:41,395 --> 01:24:45,023
我给你们带来了点东西
I have something for you and your family.

594
01:25:00,539 --> 01:25:02,040
这是给你的
That´s for you.

595
01:25:03,041 --> 01:25:05,502
买点什么，把她打扮的漂亮点
Buy something to make herself pretty with.

596
01:25:16,763 --> 01:25:18,723
非常感谢
Thank you very much.

597
01:25:20,767 --> 01:25:22,269
敬玛丽亚
To Maria.

598
01:25:23,228 --> 01:25:24,563
谢谢
Thank you.

599
01:25:30,277 --> 01:25:31,695
干杯
Cheers.