1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
-= 本字幕由 天天字幕组 原创翻译 =-
第三楼字幕网 http://www.disanlou.org

2
00:00:10,010 --> 00:00:15,000
天天字幕组官方新浪微博 http://weibo.com/ttsub2016
字幕仅供翻译学习交流使用 禁止用于商业用途

3
00:00:15,010 --> 00:00:20,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

4
00:01:18,570 --> 00:01:22,080
- 古巴  - 怎么说，索耶？
- Cuban.  - What's the word, Sawyer?

5
00:01:26,160 --> 00:01:28,000
看起来像一根火柴
Looks like a match.

6
00:01:31,340 --> 00:01:33,550
对，我是乔，我们遇到连环杀人案了
Yeah, it's Joe. We've got a series.

7
00:01:33,710 --> 00:01:36,590
一样的作案手法，一样的签名，没有DNA
Same M.O., same signature, no DNA.

8
00:01:37,930 --> 00:01:39,890
连根碎布片都没有
Not one goddamn shred.

9
00:01:40,050 --> 00:01:43,220
这话你已经说过一遍了，我已经尽力了
You said that already. I'm doing everything I can.

10
00:01:45,810 --> 00:01:47,430
他妈的混蛋
Goddamn fucking asshole.

11
00:01:49,060 --> 00:01:51,940
操
Fuck.

12
00:02:02,080 --> 00:02:03,410
我得去见见他
I need to go see him.

13
00:02:05,370 --> 00:02:06,370
乔
Joe.

14
00:02:11,670 --> 00:02:13,210
我想这是个错误
I think it's a mistake.

15
00:02:14,130 --> 00:02:16,550
你可以保留自己的意见
You're entitled to your own opinion.

16
00:02:16,710 --> 00:02:18,550
那让我重申一下
Well, let me rephrase that.

17
00:02:19,010 --> 00:02:20,630
我觉得这是大错特错
I think it's a big mistake.

18
00:02:20,800 --> 00:02:24,890
且不说时间和资源，它把一个未知事件
Apart from time and resources, it's bringing an unknown into a...

19
00:02:25,060 --> 00:02:27,850
- 变成了一个极度糟糕的事  - 这根本不是未知的
- into a really bad situation.  - Not unknown at all.

20
00:02:28,640 --> 00:02:31,270
我以前跟他合作过，他是我的朋友
I've worked with him before, and he's actually my friend.

21
00:02:31,440 --> 00:02:34,110
- 你说过他不稳定  - 我没说，凯瑟琳
- You said he's unstable.  - I did not, Katherine.

22
00:02:34,900 --> 00:02:36,650
我只是说他有过一段不好的经历
I said he's had a hard time.

23
00:02:39,240 --> 00:02:41,700
乔，现在说万福玛丽亚还为时过早
It's too early for a Hail Mary, Joe.

24
00:02:44,700 --> 00:02:48,330
你会明白，对于这种事，永远不会太早
You will learn it's never too early for one of those.

25
00:02:58,760 --> 00:03:01,380
见鬼，你看见了吗？
Goddamn, are you seeing this?

26
00:03:01,550 --> 00:03:05,010
看看这些，漂亮的绿色的东西啊
I mean, look at all this... pretty green shit.

27
00:03:09,890 --> 00:03:11,890
他在这住了多久了？
How long has he lived out here?

28
00:03:13,100 --> 00:03:16,400
两年，自从他女儿艾玛死后
Two years. Ever since his daughter Emma died.

29
00:03:16,940 --> 00:03:18,980
白血病，她死在他怀里
Leukemia. In his arms.

30
00:03:25,700 --> 00:03:30,120
他放弃了医疗实践，老天，他放弃了一切
Gave up his medical practice. Hell, he gave up everything.

31
00:03:36,590 --> 00:03:38,340
他妻子发生什么事了？
What happened to his wife?

32
00:03:40,920 --> 00:03:44,130
这个，这就是悲剧背后的真相
Well, therein lies the truth about tragedies.

33
00:03:44,300 --> 00:03:47,180
真相有时候会让有些人在一起
They bring some people closer together...

34
00:03:48,640 --> 00:03:50,310
也会让有些人分离
drives others apart.

35
00:04:06,410 --> 00:04:07,950
到了
There it is.

36
00:04:14,710 --> 00:04:17,960
你留在这吧，我单独去跟他谈谈？
Do you mind staying here? Let me talk to him alone?

37
00:04:18,130 --> 00:04:20,710
- 你本来都可以不用带我来  - 是可以…
- You could have left me in the city.  - I could've...

38
00:04:20,880 --> 00:04:24,010
但那样你就会错过绿色的美景
But you would have missed the pretty green shit.

39
00:04:29,390 --> 00:04:30,930
感情泛滥
Sentiment.

40
00:04:50,910 --> 00:04:52,490
干嘛？
Yeah?

41
00:04:55,540 --> 00:04:58,080
- 约翰？我是乔  - 对，我知道
- John? It's Joe.  - Yeah, I know.

42
00:05:00,840 --> 00:05:04,340
你不开门吗？我想和你聊聊
Are you gonna open the door? I'd like to talk to you.

43
00:05:04,510 --> 00:05:06,050
没兴趣
Not interested.

44
00:05:06,590 --> 00:05:09,850
约翰，我开了三小时车来找你
John, I just drove three hours to come and see you.

45
00:05:10,260 --> 00:05:14,350
快点，你很了解我，你知道不见到你我不会走的
Come on. You know me well enough to know that I'm not leaving.

46
00:05:14,520 --> 00:05:17,140
如果有必要，我会踹开门
And I'll kick down this door if I have to.

47
00:05:25,570 --> 00:05:27,400
我腰疼，知道吗
A real pain in the ass.

48
00:05:28,910 --> 00:05:31,280
是啊，我以前听说过
Yeah. I've heard that before.

49
00:05:40,920 --> 00:05:46,380
你知道，一年前我给你寄过一封信，你收到了吗？
You know, I sent you a letter like a year ago. Did you get it?

50
00:05:46,550 --> 00:05:48,720
收到了
Yep.

51
00:05:50,260 --> 00:05:52,010
信上怎么说的，约翰？
What did it say, John?

52
00:05:55,640 --> 00:05:58,020
“白发人不该送黑发人”
"No parent should outlive a child."

53
00:06:16,120 --> 00:06:18,790
- 你一直就穴居在这  - 嗯哼
- So you've been holed up here.  - Uh-huh.

54
00:06:20,790 --> 00:06:22,380
看得出你已经安顿下来了
I see you've settled in.

55
00:06:26,880 --> 00:06:30,800
- 这里的气候很宜人  - 他们就是这么跟我说的
- It's a beautiful day out there.  - That's what they tell me.

56
00:06:32,260 --> 00:06:33,930
这么说，你不太出门？
So you don't get out much?

57
00:06:50,810 --> 00:06:52,480
[FBI的秘诀，通灵护身符]

58
00:06:52,480 --> 00:06:54,400
[通灵者协助FBI找到失踪人口]

59
00:07:00,420 --> 00:07:02,960
- 喝汽水吗？  - 不用，谢谢
- Do you want a soda?  - No, thank you.

60
00:07:03,130 --> 00:07:04,670
我这没烟
I don't have cigarettes.

61
00:07:04,840 --> 00:07:06,710
没关系，几个月前我就该戒了
I gave them up a few months ago.

62
00:07:07,170 --> 00:07:08,710
这是我最新上瘾的东西
Meet my new addiction.

63
00:07:11,180 --> 00:07:12,800
劳拉和孩子都好吗？
Laura and the kid okay?

64
00:07:12,970 --> 00:07:15,140
是啊，他们都好，谢谢
Yeah, they're good. Thank you.

65
00:07:15,300 --> 00:07:17,470
你有伊丽莎白的消息吗？
Heard from Elizabeth yet?

66
00:07:17,640 --> 00:07:19,020
没有
No.

67
00:07:20,020 --> 00:07:21,520
你会的
You will.

68
00:07:24,190 --> 00:07:26,230
那个，除了想见你之外
So, besides wanting to see you...

69
00:07:27,980 --> 00:07:31,570
我有个案子，想让你看看
I've got a situation that I'd like you to take a look at.

70
00:07:32,200 --> 00:07:35,990
- 也许我可以跟你说说受害人的情况  - 我说了，我没兴趣
- I could just tell you about the victims.  - I'm not interested.

71
00:07:36,160 --> 00:07:38,450
对了，你女朋友是谁？
By the way, who's your girlfriend?

72
00:07:42,120 --> 00:07:45,580
这是我忠实的搭档，考尔斯探长
That is my loyal partner, Agent Cowles,

73
00:07:45,750 --> 00:07:49,000
显然，她从来都不听我的话
who apparently doesn't listen to a fucking word I say.

74
00:07:49,170 --> 00:07:50,840
空军一等兵，乔
S.A.C., Joe.

75
00:07:52,380 --> 00:07:54,840
我想你会想接一下这个电话
I thought you might want to take the call.

76
00:07:55,010 --> 00:07:56,550
失陪一下，约翰
Excuse me, John.

77
00:08:06,560 --> 00:08:08,400
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.

78
00:08:09,280 --> 00:08:12,440
- 我带来了案件的文件  - 用不着
- I brought the case files.  - It wasn't necessary.

79
00:08:13,360 --> 00:08:15,660
局里已经改变了破案的
The Agency has changed the guidelines

80
00:08:15,820 --> 00:08:18,240
指导方针
for the way we break down the cases.

81
00:08:18,410 --> 00:08:20,330
这些文件更易读
It makes them more readable.

82
00:08:20,500 --> 00:08:22,330
好吧，那我可以放心了
Oh. Well, that's a relief.

83
00:08:24,370 --> 00:08:25,920
我们该走了
We gotta go.

84
00:08:31,630 --> 00:08:34,050
三起谋杀，完全一样的作案手法
Three murders. Identical M.O.

85
00:08:34,630 --> 00:08:36,180
考尔斯探长
Agent Cowles.

86
00:08:47,900 --> 00:08:49,980
我把这些文件留在这
I'll leave the case files here.

87
00:08:56,030 --> 00:08:57,570
约翰
John.

88
00:08:59,280 --> 00:09:00,830
你没事吧？
You okay?

89
00:09:02,580 --> 00:09:05,040
如果你改变了心意…
If you change your mind about this...

90
00:09:06,580 --> 00:09:08,500
你知道上哪能找到我
you know where to find me.

91
00:10:15,300 --> 00:10:17,600
[我 是 谁？]

92
00:11:27,140 --> 00:11:29,470
- 嘿，乔  - 约翰
- Hey, Joe.  - John.

93
00:11:30,640 --> 00:11:32,190
我不承诺什么
I make no promises.

94
00:11:32,350 --> 00:11:36,270
我可能会待一天，也可能一星期
I'll stay maybe one day. Maybe one week.

95
00:11:36,730 --> 00:11:38,690
成交，不承诺
Deal. No promises.

96
00:11:40,280 --> 00:11:43,110
- 你知道我会回来？  - 我期望很高
- You knew I'd come back?  - I had high hopes.

97
00:11:43,990 --> 00:11:47,410
还记得考尔斯探长吗？我应该说考尔斯博士
You remember Agent Cowles? I should say "Dr." Cowles,

98
00:11:47,580 --> 00:11:50,620
- 博士学位是…  - 精神病理学
- with a doctorate in...?  - Psychopathology.

99
00:11:51,120 --> 00:11:54,750
在我们局把她弄过来之前，她一直想成为一个教授
She was to become a professor before the bureau snagged her.

100
00:11:54,920 --> 00:11:59,000
- 你为了这个疯人院放弃了大学？  - 他们让我可以带枪
- You gave up academia for this madhouse?  - They let me carry a gun.

101
00:11:59,170 --> 00:12:01,380
哇！真性感
Wow! So sexy.

102
00:12:04,010 --> 00:12:05,590
你们俩一会成为很好的团队的
You two will make a good team.

103
00:12:05,760 --> 00:12:10,270
约翰，你知道当某个人将做什么，凯瑟琳就知道该怎么做
John, you know when and Katherine, you know why someone's about to do something.

104
00:12:10,430 --> 00:12:12,730
在我们出来以前别关
Run this through until we come out.

105
00:12:12,890 --> 00:12:16,730
克兰西博士，无意冒犯，在我们上楼之前
Dr. Clancy, before we go upstairs, with all due respect,

106
00:12:16,900 --> 00:12:20,730
我从来没把超常学当做过一个领域
I don't hold an ounce of confidence in the paranormal as a field.

107
00:12:20,900 --> 00:12:23,400
我觉得它是伪学术，希望这没问题
I think it's a sham. I hope that's okay.

108
00:12:23,570 --> 00:12:26,530
完全没问题，我对心理学家的看法也是如此
No problem at all. I feel the same about shrinks.

109
00:12:26,700 --> 00:12:29,030
他们只追逐一件事：你的钱
After only one thing, your money.

110
00:12:29,200 --> 00:12:31,040
他们会全权控制你
They'll take your whole hand.

111
00:12:31,200 --> 00:12:34,370
说这话的人，显然没遇到过好的心理专家
Whoever said that has obviously never met a good one.

112
00:12:34,540 --> 00:12:36,080
说这话的人是弗洛伊德
It was Sigmund Freud.

113
00:12:40,550 --> 00:12:43,130
正如我所说，极好的团队
Like I said, a hell of a team.

114
00:12:43,300 --> 00:12:46,760
第一种一致性：手法
Consistency #1: method.

115
00:12:46,930 --> 00:12:50,720
每个受害者都是在颅骨处有一处穿刺伤
Each victim was killed by a puncture wound at the skull.

116
00:12:50,890 --> 00:12:54,270
是由一个五英尺的工具所致的
Inflicted by a five-inch instrument.

117
00:12:54,440 --> 00:12:57,270
它能直接进入延髓
It went straight into the medulla oblongata.

118
00:12:57,440 --> 00:13:00,820
据验尸官所说，即刻毙命，无痛的死刑
Immediate, according to the coroner. Painless execution.

119
00:13:00,980 --> 00:13:06,280
- 这些照片都是验尸前的  - 其中有两个看起来几乎还是活的
- These photos are all post-mortem.  - A couple of them almost look alive.

120
00:13:06,450 --> 00:13:08,950
第二种一致性：没有错误
Consistency #2: No mistakes.

121
00:13:09,120 --> 00:13:15,210
目前为止，犯罪现场，没有DNA，毛发
Crime scenes so far have yielded no evidence of DNA, hair-fibers,

122
00:13:15,370 --> 00:13:18,120
- 鞋印，什么都没有  - 也没有目击者
- shoe-prints, nothing.  - No witnesses, either.

123
00:13:18,290 --> 00:13:21,920
沃德就住在有保安的大楼里，没有任何强行闯入的痕迹
Ward lived in a secured building. No signs of forced entry.

124
00:13:22,090 --> 00:13:28,010
在心理分析领域，这是从未听说过的，不论从地域，年代
On the psych front, it's unheard of. There's no geographical, chronological

125
00:13:28,180 --> 00:13:30,890
或占星学上，都没有过
or astrological pattern to the murder.

126
00:13:31,060 --> 00:13:32,260
也没有抢劫
No robbery.

127
00:13:33,350 --> 00:13:36,890
除此之外，这个案子我们处理的都很好
Other than that, we got a good handle on this case.

128
00:13:41,270 --> 00:13:42,520
约翰？
John?

129
00:13:44,110 --> 00:13:45,320
约翰
John.

130
00:13:46,150 --> 00:13:47,240
在听
Yeah.

131
00:13:49,570 --> 00:13:51,910
罗伯特·艾利斯，芒特普林森的那个孩子
Robert Ellis, the kid in Mount Pleasant.

132
00:13:52,370 --> 00:13:55,160
- 他当时还在吃冰淇淋  - 是的
- He was eating ice cream.  - He was.

133
00:13:58,000 --> 00:14:00,250
你想从哪着手，约翰？
Where do you want to start, John?

134
00:14:01,250 --> 00:14:02,540
那个…
Well...

135
00:14:03,800 --> 00:14:05,760
从头开始？
at the beginning?

136
00:14:11,800 --> 00:14:16,020
这是埃塞尔·杰克逊女士的家，六十九岁
The residence of Mrs. Ethel Jackson, age 69.

137
00:14:16,980 --> 00:14:20,350
她和三只猫独居，经常去教堂
She lived alone with three cats. Was a regular at church.

138
00:14:20,520 --> 00:14:25,020
女房东因两天没见她，也没跟她说话就起了疑心
Landlady grew suspicious when she hadn't seen or talked to her in two days.

139
00:14:25,190 --> 00:14:27,900
她被发现死在摇椅上
She was found killed in that rocking chair.

140
00:14:28,530 --> 00:14:31,030
电视开着，正在播放烹饪节目
On the TV, the Cooking Channel played.

141
00:14:31,490 --> 00:14:34,160
而我们之前看到的那张纸条？
And the note we were looking at earlier?

142
00:14:34,330 --> 00:14:36,910
就在这，在这桌子上
Was here. On this table.

143
00:14:40,460 --> 00:14:42,130
是我老婆，抱歉，我接一下
My wife. I need to take this.

144
00:14:42,790 --> 00:14:44,340
宝贝，我…
Sweetheart, I...

145
00:14:48,590 --> 00:14:51,300
- 你对这纸条怎么看？  - 从心理学方面？
- What do you make of the note?  - As a shrink?

146
00:14:51,470 --> 00:14:54,100
- 对  - 这是一个经典谜语
- Yeah.  - It's a classic riddle.

147
00:14:55,470 --> 00:15:00,310
“我用两个字告诉你我是谁，做什么的，怎么生活的，可以吗？”
"I will tell you in two words who I am, what I do and how I live. May I?"

148
00:15:01,810 --> 00:15:04,650
嘲讽的问题旨在误导
Taunting questions designed to mislead.

149
00:15:05,440 --> 00:15:09,530
请求我们的允许，来揭示自己的身份，却从未这样打算过
Asking our permission to reveal himself, yet never intending to.

150
00:15:11,240 --> 00:15:16,660
这样好玩，但只有一个人在这玩，就是独居者
It's playful, but only one person is playing here. It's solitaire.

151
00:15:20,000 --> 00:15:21,710
还是有更重要的？
Or is it something more?

152
00:15:22,330 --> 00:15:23,880
是呼救？
Is it a cry for help?

153
00:15:24,040 --> 00:15:26,960
这个谜语在问他们自己，还有我们
An indication of split personality disorder,

154
00:15:27,130 --> 00:15:30,260
这是精神分裂的迹象
where the riddler is asking themselves, and us,

155
00:15:30,420 --> 00:15:34,720
他们究竟是谁？但是这与犯罪前后不一致
who they actually are? But no. That's not consistent with the crime.

156
00:15:34,890 --> 00:15:37,970
这控制的太好，太敏捷了
This is too controlled, too sharp.

157
00:15:38,140 --> 00:15:40,560
这其中另有玄妙
There's something else going on here.

158
00:15:43,350 --> 00:15:45,610
好像他在找谁
It's like he's looking for someone.

159
00:15:58,620 --> 00:16:01,750
- 那么？  - 她喜欢帽子
- So?  - She likes hats.

160
00:16:04,170 --> 00:16:06,210
嘿，怎么样了？
Hey. How are we doing?

161
00:16:06,380 --> 00:16:07,630
棒极了
Fantastic.

162
00:16:16,510 --> 00:16:19,720
关于这纸条，凯瑟琳做了全面的研究
Katherine works up a full profile based on the note.

163
00:16:19,890 --> 00:16:23,600
- 也就是说我要回家去把它完成了  - 好
- Which she's finishing at home.  - Okay.

164
00:16:23,770 --> 00:16:26,020
- 明早见  - 好
- I'll see you in the morning.  - Yes.

165
00:16:26,730 --> 00:16:28,020
约翰
John.

166
00:16:28,480 --> 00:16:32,400
我请你吃晚饭如何？特殊招待，全城最好吃的餐厅
How about I buy you dinner? Special treat. Best place in town.

167
00:16:32,570 --> 00:16:33,780
那要换身行头吗？
Do I need a jacket?

168
00:16:33,950 --> 00:16:38,200
当然不用，我跟那很熟，我认识那的老板
Hell, no, you don't. I got connections. I know the maître d'.

169
00:16:41,580 --> 00:16:43,870
见鬼，这太好吃了！
Goddamn it. This is so good!

170
00:16:44,040 --> 00:16:46,040
- 约翰？  - 不用，谢谢
- John?  - No, I'm fine, thanks.

171
00:16:46,210 --> 00:16:49,090
- 再给约翰来一个  - 马上来
- For John, one more please. Yeah?  - Coming up.

172
00:16:49,550 --> 00:16:53,550
我儿子今天在学校出状况了，今天又哭着回来了
My boy has a rough time in school. Came home in tears again today.

173
00:16:53,720 --> 00:16:55,340
- 被欺负了？  - 是啊
- Being bullied?  - Yeah.

174
00:16:55,510 --> 00:16:57,050
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.

175
00:16:58,550 --> 00:17:01,640
怎么会不知道，抱抱他，给他讲个笑话
Don't know. Give him a hug. Tell him a joke.

176
00:17:02,390 --> 00:17:05,180
- 笑话？  - 是啊，说个笑话
- A joke?  - Yeah. A joke.

177
00:17:05,640 --> 00:17:09,020
我不会讲笑话，我说真的，约翰，拜托
I don't know any jokes. I'm serious, John. Come on.

178
00:17:09,480 --> 00:17:11,860
以朋友的名义，给我讲个笑话
In the name of friendship, tell me a joke.

179
00:17:12,030 --> 00:17:14,400
我？我也不会讲笑话
Me? I don't know any jokes.

180
00:17:14,860 --> 00:17:16,360
好吧，有一个，呃…
Okay, just one. Um...

181
00:17:17,700 --> 00:17:20,200
有一个女人，琼斯太太
This woman, Mrs. Jones, uh,

182
00:17:20,660 --> 00:17:23,290
得了罕见的心脏病
was suffering from a rare heart condition.

183
00:17:23,450 --> 00:17:28,580
医生给她开了雄性激素，来提高她的睾酮，一天吃两片
The doctor prescribes male hormones to up her testosterone, 2 pills a day.

184
00:17:28,750 --> 00:17:31,840
一个月后，她回去跟医生说
A month later she goes back to the doctor and says...

185
00:17:32,000 --> 00:17:34,960
“雄性激素给我的心脏创造了奇迹
"That medicine is doing wonders for my heart.

186
00:17:35,130 --> 00:17:38,800
但我以前不长毛的地方都长出了毛”
But I'm growing hair where it has never grown before."

187
00:17:38,970 --> 00:17:44,220
“别担心，的确会导致过多的毛发，究竟长在哪呢？”
"Don't worry, excessive hair is to be expected. Where does it grow exactly?"

188
00:17:44,390 --> 00:17:46,560
她说，“在我的蛋上，医生”
She says, "On my balls, Doctor."

189
00:17:50,360 --> 00:17:51,900
很好笑吧
It's funny, isn't it?

190
00:17:53,030 --> 00:17:55,150
这种玩笑我不能讲给我儿子听啊
I can't tell that to my little boy.

191
00:17:55,780 --> 00:17:58,820
- 那就说“睾丸”  - 他们立刻切除了它对吗
- Say "testicles."  - That cleans it right up.

192
00:17:58,990 --> 00:18:01,070
是的，生物学
Yeah. Biology.

193
00:18:02,030 --> 00:18:03,790
- 这是个好笑话  - 是啊
- It's a good joke.  - Yeah.

194
00:18:03,950 --> 00:18:06,040
我觉得你会喜欢
I thought you'd like that.

195
00:18:06,210 --> 00:18:09,670
伊丽莎白跟我说过，这就是她爱上你的原因
Elizabeth told me that's why she fell in love with you.

196
00:18:10,330 --> 00:18:13,460
- 为什么？  - 你的微笑
- Why was that?  - That smile.

197
00:18:13,630 --> 00:18:16,800
- 哦，微笑  - 不是因为你讲的笑话
- Oh, the smile.  - Not your joke telling.

198
00:18:27,350 --> 00:18:30,980
约翰，咱们再吃一个三明治还是怎样？
John, do I have another sandwich coming here or what?

199
00:18:50,830 --> 00:18:53,960
今晚，自从我们从埃塞尔·杰克逊家出来以后
Tonight, as we were leaving Ethel Jackson's,

200
00:18:54,130 --> 00:18:56,300
- 你就心事重重的  - 嗯哼
- you were onto something.  - Hmm.

201
00:19:00,630 --> 00:19:03,430
拜托，约翰，告诉我你知道什么？
Come on, John. Talk to me. What do you know?

202
00:19:06,100 --> 00:19:09,020
我和你一样希望这能早点结束
I want this over as quickly and as badly as you do,

203
00:19:09,180 --> 00:19:11,770
但你得告诉我你看见什么了
but you gotta tell me what you're seeing.

204
00:19:11,940 --> 00:19:13,480
我还不知道
I don't know yet.

205
00:19:51,560 --> 00:19:53,190
约翰
John...

206
00:20:05,240 --> 00:20:06,950
约翰
John.

207
00:20:26,930 --> 00:20:30,100
一小时前我接到了一个
Received an anonymous call

208
00:20:30,270 --> 00:20:35,810
匿名电话，提供了彼得·沃德谋杀案的十分详尽的信息
an hour ago offering way too specific information about the Peter Ward murder.

209
00:20:35,980 --> 00:20:41,190
然后列出了市中心的一个地址，周边已经被保护起来了，等着我们进去
Then listed a midtown address. Perimeter is secured. They wait for us to go in.

210
00:20:46,070 --> 00:20:47,620
安全！
Clear!

211
00:20:48,990 --> 00:20:50,530
安全！
Clear!

212
00:20:57,380 --> 00:21:00,000
乔，看一下这个
Joe. Take a look at this.

213
00:21:09,600 --> 00:21:11,060
你怎么看？
What do you think?

214
00:21:11,220 --> 00:21:14,310
四点十六分，圣经章节？
Four-sixteen. Bible verse?

215
00:21:14,480 --> 00:21:16,520
不，是时间
No, it's the time.

216
00:21:17,100 --> 00:21:18,850
四分钟前
Four minutes ago.

217
00:21:20,360 --> 00:21:22,280
正好四点十六分
Four-sixteen precisely.

218
00:21:22,940 --> 00:21:24,400
你的表快了
Your watch is fast.

219
00:21:25,320 --> 00:21:26,780
操，他来了
Fuck. He's here.

220
00:21:49,930 --> 00:21:52,470
- 你没事吧？  - 我没事，走
- Are you good?  - I'm good. Go.

221
00:21:55,640 --> 00:21:57,730
雷蒙德太太吗？FBI
Mrs. Raymond? FBI.

222
00:22:13,700 --> 00:22:16,620
谁能把那玩意关了吗？
Would someone please turn that shit off?

223
00:22:23,130 --> 00:22:26,420
- 没错  - 伤口在脖子后面
- Bingo.  - Wound on the back of the neck.

224
00:22:26,590 --> 00:22:30,010
- 一样的  - 她已经死了五六个小时了
- Familiar.  - She's been dead for 5 or 6 hours.

225
00:22:30,180 --> 00:22:33,010
- 嫌犯应该就在附近  - 他几小时前就已经走了
- Perp must have hung around.  - He left hours ago.

226
00:22:37,270 --> 00:22:40,440
能劳烦你们俩帮我们清理下这个房间吗
Would you two mind clearing the room for us please?

227
00:22:41,100 --> 00:22:42,650
谢谢
Thank you.

228
00:22:45,980 --> 00:22:47,530
约翰
John.

229
00:22:49,650 --> 00:22:53,490
跟四点十六分，和埃塞尔·杰克逊家的纸条一样的字体
Same type font as 4:16 and the note at Ethel Jackson's.

230
00:22:53,660 --> 00:22:55,200
嗯
Mm-hmm.

231
00:22:58,620 --> 00:23:01,000
- 你没事吧？  - 该死
- You okay?  - Shit.

232
00:23:01,710 --> 00:23:04,000
- 去吧，去看看  - 我能碰她吗？
- Go ahead. Take a look.  - Can I touch her?

233
00:23:04,170 --> 00:23:05,710
可以
Yeah.

234
00:23:21,650 --> 00:23:23,900
大卫
David.

235
00:23:31,280 --> 00:23:33,360
大卫？
David?

236
00:24:29,300 --> 00:24:32,720
你在这，进来
There you are. Come in.

237
00:24:34,380 --> 00:24:35,930
帮我擦背
Wash my back.

238
00:24:46,060 --> 00:24:47,100
约翰？
John?

239
00:24:48,690 --> 00:24:50,730
- 你没事吧？  - 没事
- You all right?  - Yeah.

240
00:24:52,280 --> 00:24:54,700
- 你看见什么了？  - 我不确定
- What do you see?  - I'm not sure.

241
00:25:03,580 --> 00:25:05,830
- 好了  - 什么？
- Okay.  - What?

242
00:25:07,920 --> 00:25:10,340
- 别碰洗澡水  - 为什么？
- Don't touch the bathwater.  - Why?

243
00:25:10,500 --> 00:25:12,170
别碰就是我，我也不确定
I'm not sure why.

244
00:25:12,340 --> 00:25:14,720
瞧？老天，我们可能有疑犯了
Joe? Holy shit, we may have a suspect.

245
00:25:14,880 --> 00:25:16,430
- 谁？  - 大卫·雷蒙德
- Who?  - David Raymond.

246
00:25:17,050 --> 00:25:18,510
她丈夫
The husband.

247
00:25:29,610 --> 00:25:31,900
他说他整晚都在酒吧
He says he was at the bar all night.

248
00:25:32,070 --> 00:25:35,570
他的酒保和他的口气都证实了他说的话
His bartender and his breath corroborate his story.

249
00:25:36,660 --> 00:25:40,200
- 考尔斯探长，你准备好了吗？  - 是的，长官
- Agent Cowles are you ready?  - Yes, sir.

250
00:25:40,370 --> 00:25:42,120
那请你带路吧
I want you to take the lead.

251
00:25:54,510 --> 00:25:58,220
雷蒙德先生，喝杯咖啡
Mr. Raymond, a cup of coffee.

252
00:25:58,390 --> 00:26:02,180
- 你要跟我们熬一晚了  - 谢谢
- Been a long night for all of us.  - Thank you.

253
00:26:03,310 --> 00:26:04,810
如果你不介意…
If you don't mind...

254
00:26:05,810 --> 00:26:08,730
我就开门见山了，好吗？
I'm just gonna jump right into this. Okay?

255
00:26:08,900 --> 00:26:10,690
- 雷蒙德先生  - 是
- Mr. Raymond.  - Yeah?

256
00:26:11,360 --> 00:26:14,730
很遗憾地通知你，你妻子维多利亚
We regret to inform you that your wife Victoria

257
00:26:15,190 --> 00:26:16,740
昨晚死亡了
died last night.

258
00:26:18,740 --> 00:26:20,280
天呐
Jesus.

259
00:26:21,200 --> 00:26:22,740
老天
Jesus Christ.

260
00:26:26,120 --> 00:26:29,540
天呐，天呐…
Oh, God. Oh, God...

261
00:26:30,250 --> 00:26:32,080
雷蒙德先生…
Mr. Raymond...

262
00:26:32,880 --> 00:26:35,710
昨晚，你被看见
you were seen leaving your building

263
00:26:35,880 --> 00:26:39,300
情绪激动地离开了大楼，能告诉我们为什么吗？
last night in an agitated state. Can you tell us why?

264
00:26:40,050 --> 00:26:41,720
她有留言吗？
Did she leave a note?

265
00:26:41,890 --> 00:26:43,430
她有留言吗？
Did she leave a note?

266
00:26:44,680 --> 00:26:46,970
雷蒙德先生，你妻子系他杀
Mr. Raymond, your wife was murdered.

267
00:26:47,140 --> 00:26:50,350
- 什么？  - 你妻子是被杀害的
- What?  - Your wife was murdered.

268
00:26:50,520 --> 00:26:52,100
她没有留言
She didn't leave a note.

269
00:26:52,480 --> 00:26:55,440
不，不，老天！
No! No! Oh, Jesus, God!

270
00:26:56,110 --> 00:26:59,740
- 你觉得这会是怎么回事？  - 她不是自杀的？
- What do you think happened?  - She didn't commit suicide?

271
00:26:59,900 --> 00:27:01,450
你为什么会以为她是自杀？
Why do you think that?

272
00:27:03,490 --> 00:27:06,290
那封信，我写的…我…我写了一封信
The letter, I wrote... I... I wrote a letter.

273
00:27:09,620 --> 00:27:12,790
- 这封信吗？  - 不是，那是什么？
- This letter?  - No. What is that?

274
00:27:14,000 --> 00:27:15,540
这不是你写的？
You didn't write this?

275
00:27:16,170 --> 00:27:17,920
我留下了一封信
I left a letter.

276
00:27:18,090 --> 00:27:19,420
写了什么？
What did it say?

277
00:27:22,930 --> 00:27:24,390
大卫？
David?

278
00:27:36,400 --> 00:27:39,320
“我从未想过伤害或背叛你…”
"I never meant to hurt or betray..."

279
00:27:49,660 --> 00:27:52,410
大卫？信上怎么说的？
David? What did the letter say?

280
00:27:54,130 --> 00:27:55,500
他离开了她
He left her.

281
00:27:56,250 --> 00:27:57,750
我要离开她
I was leaving her.

282
00:27:58,840 --> 00:28:00,760
好
Okay.

283
00:28:01,220 --> 00:28:03,300
你要离开她，为什么？
You were leaving her. Why?

284
00:28:04,140 --> 00:28:05,720
他因为别的人而离开她
He left her for someone else.

285
00:28:05,890 --> 00:28:08,180
我因为别的人而离开她
I was leaving her for someone else.

286
00:28:16,150 --> 00:28:17,900
为了另一个女人？
For another woman?

287
00:28:23,570 --> 00:28:25,320
是的
Yes.

288
00:28:26,240 --> 00:28:27,780
他在撒谎
He's lying.

289
00:28:29,450 --> 00:28:31,580
维，对不起
Oh, V, I'm so sorry.

290
00:28:40,050 --> 00:28:43,050
我能和雷蒙德先生说两句吗？
Uh, could I have a word with Mr. Raymond?

291
00:28:43,220 --> 00:28:44,680
- 克兰西博士…  - 乔？
- Dr. Clancy...  - Joe?

292
00:28:45,390 --> 00:28:46,930
- 好  - 谢谢
- All right.  - Thanks.

293
00:28:57,480 --> 00:29:00,650
你说的话，至少有些是真的
You're telling the truth, or at least some of it.

294
00:29:02,070 --> 00:29:04,900
你妻子不是你杀的，对吗，雷蒙德先生？
You didn't kill your wife did you, Mr. Raymond?

295
00:29:05,820 --> 00:29:06,860
是的
No.

296
00:29:07,570 --> 00:29:12,450
但你觉得你留下的字条很可能会导致她自杀
But you believe the note you left could've driven her to take her own life.

297
00:29:13,330 --> 00:29:17,540
你妻子有过情绪不稳定病史
Your wife had a history of emotional instability.

298
00:29:19,250 --> 00:29:23,510
字条上说你为了别的人要离开她
And the note was telling her that you were leaving her for someone else.

299
00:29:25,300 --> 00:29:30,510
但你没有说你是为了一个男人
But your note failed to mention you were leaving her for a man.

300
00:29:40,860 --> 00:29:42,820
你他妈的是怎么知道的？
How the fuck do you know that?

301
00:29:42,980 --> 00:29:46,950
事实上，你已经感染了HIV
That, in fact, you had contracted HIV.

302
00:29:49,410 --> 00:29:50,950
对吗？
Is that right?

303
00:30:05,260 --> 00:30:07,300
她的血也被感染了
Her blood was contaminated.

304
00:30:07,470 --> 00:30:10,430
这就是为什么：“小心洗澡水”
That's why: "Careful with the bathwater."

305
00:30:10,600 --> 00:30:12,510
我想再看一下文件
I want to see the files again.

306
00:30:13,770 --> 00:30:16,560
现在七点半了，我家人都起床了，吃早餐吗？
It's 7:30. My family's up. Breakfast?

307
00:30:16,730 --> 00:30:18,270
- 好  - 我们走
- Yeah.  - Let's go.

308
00:30:27,030 --> 00:30:29,070
- 谢谢你  - 谢谢，劳拉
- Thank you.  - Thanks, Laura.

309
00:30:29,570 --> 00:30:32,200
- 你需要吃点东西  - 我不饿，宝贝，谢谢
- You need to eat.  - I'm good, baby. Thank you.

310
00:30:32,620 --> 00:30:35,410
- 乔，你们一家看起来不错  - 是啊
- Family is looking good, Joe.  - They are.

311
00:30:35,580 --> 00:30:38,750
我在尽力把时间用在和他们相处上
I try to spend as much time as I can with them.

312
00:30:38,920 --> 00:30:40,330
我们见到伊丽莎白了
We've seen Elizabeth.

313
00:30:41,920 --> 00:30:44,210
- 是吗？  - 我们有保持联络
- Oh, yeah?  - We've kept in touch.

314
00:30:44,880 --> 00:30:47,460
- 很好  - 她依然爱你，约翰
- Good.  - She still loves you, John.

315
00:30:52,600 --> 00:30:55,140
好了，那个…你怎么看？
All right. So, uh... What do you think?

316
00:30:55,310 --> 00:30:58,310
他们都得了不治不症，是临终病人
They were all incurably sick, terminally ill.

317
00:30:58,480 --> 00:31:02,310
- 这是一致的  - 我们已经探索过了，不符合
- That is the consistency.  - We explored that. It doesn't hold up.

318
00:31:02,480 --> 00:31:05,190
埃塞尔·杰克逊，假发，帽子
Ethel Jackson. The wigs, the hats...

319
00:31:05,360 --> 00:31:08,190
- 她化疗过  - 三年前
- She had chemotherapy.  - Three years ago.

320
00:31:08,360 --> 00:31:10,900
约翰，她已经痊愈了
She was in the clear, John.

321
00:31:11,070 --> 00:31:12,820
从来都没人痊愈过
No one's ever in the clear.

322
00:31:13,200 --> 00:31:18,540
百分之八十的癌症都会复发，不论是什么时候它们都很难根治
80 % of cancers return. Whenever they do, they're quite difficult to eliminate.

323
00:31:23,040 --> 00:31:24,080
所以？
So?

324
00:31:24,250 --> 00:31:27,380
所以伯德·伯德，碰巧得了肌萎缩性侧索硬化症
Peter Ward, it turns out, had Lou Gehrig's Disease.

325
00:31:27,550 --> 00:31:30,220
这病发过程很慢，死的会很痛苦
That can be a very slow, painful death.

326
00:31:30,380 --> 00:31:33,680
维多利亚·雷蒙德有慢性自杀倾向
Victoria Raymond suffered chronic suicidal depression,

327
00:31:33,850 --> 00:31:38,180
自残行为，刀伤，服药过量等等
self-destructive behavior, cutting, overdose, and so on.

328
00:31:38,350 --> 00:31:40,730
- 你吃完早餐了吗，儿子？  - 吃完了，妈妈
- Finished breakfast?  - Yes!

329
00:31:40,890 --> 00:31:42,520
嘿，书包！
Hey. Backpack!

330
00:31:43,270 --> 00:31:44,810
对哦
Yes.

331
00:31:46,440 --> 00:31:48,610
过来，跟约翰说再见
Come here, say goodbye to John.

332
00:31:48,780 --> 00:31:50,610
- 拜拜，约翰  - 再见，猴子
- Bye-bye, John.  - Goodbye, monkey.

333
00:31:50,780 --> 00:31:52,320
抱抱你老爹
Give your dad a hug.

334
00:31:53,240 --> 00:31:57,450
- 拜，爸爸，放学见  - 好，日安
- Bye, Dad. See you after school.  - Yeah. Have a good day.

335
00:31:57,620 --> 00:31:58,790
好
Okay.

336
00:31:59,250 --> 00:32:02,370
- 工作顺利  - 拜，宝贝
- Have a good day at work.  - Bye, honey.

337
00:32:04,290 --> 00:32:07,540
这么说吧，埃塞尔·杰克逊和彼得·沃德
Let's say I give you Ethel Jackson and Peter Ward.

338
00:32:07,710 --> 00:32:10,800
我说一句话就能推翻你的理论
Two words that destroy this whole theory:

339
00:32:11,220 --> 00:32:13,430
那个男孩罗伯特·艾利斯是健康的
The boy Robert Ellis was healthy,

340
00:32:13,590 --> 00:32:17,470
而且作为基督教信徒，他父母不相信医学
and as Christian Scientists, his parents don't believe in medicine.

341
00:32:17,640 --> 00:32:19,310
他没有任何病例
He had no medical file.

342
00:32:19,470 --> 00:32:21,220
- 那我们就去跟他们谈谈  - 好
- Well, let's go talk to them.  - Okay.

343
00:32:21,390 --> 00:32:23,480
记得你的约会吗？
Remember your appointment?

344
00:32:23,650 --> 00:32:28,520
对，我九点钟跟局长有个电话会议
Right. I have a phone call with the director at 9:00 am,

345
00:32:28,690 --> 00:32:33,360
这是我十分期待的，我就让凯瑟琳带你去吧
which I am immensely looking forward to. So Katherine will take you.

346
00:32:33,530 --> 00:32:35,070
好
Okay.

347
00:32:36,240 --> 00:32:37,990
克兰西博士
Dr. Clancy...

348
00:32:39,540 --> 00:32:41,080
你如何把它联系上？
How do you refer to it?

349
00:32:42,080 --> 00:32:43,580
联系什么？
To what?

350
00:32:43,750 --> 00:32:47,250
联系你已知的
To, uh, what you have?

351
00:32:48,420 --> 00:32:51,920
是预知，千里眼，先知？
Is it prescience, clairvoyance, precognition?

352
00:32:52,090 --> 00:32:54,760
是鸣响，不过一分钟的事
Oh, it's a hoot. A laugh a minute.

353
00:32:55,590 --> 00:32:58,140
算了，我是认真的
Never mind. I'm serious.

354
00:32:58,500 --> 00:32:59,300
[联邦调查局卷宗]

355
00:33:00,260 --> 00:33:01,930
你究竟看见了什么？
What is it you see exactly?

356
00:33:02,100 --> 00:33:05,020
你能看到人们的未来吗？
Do you see people's futures?

357
00:33:05,560 --> 00:33:08,190
有些是未来，有些是过去
Bits of their futures and of their pasts.

358
00:33:08,360 --> 00:33:10,400
但都无法改变最终结果
It's all the same in the end.

359
00:33:10,570 --> 00:33:13,610
- 这是神秘的，还是宗教的？  - 不，我是个科学教
- Is it mystical? Or religious?  - No. I'm a scientist.

360
00:33:13,780 --> 00:33:16,570
我相信理论物理还有…
I believe in theoretical physics and...

361
00:33:17,030 --> 00:33:18,950
生物化学，就这些
biochemistry and that's it.

362
00:33:19,120 --> 00:33:23,830
无论如何，我碰巧有超强的人们所谓的…
Whatever it is, I happen to get the deluxe edition of what people now call

363
00:33:24,000 --> 00:33:25,830
直觉或本能反应
intuition or gut reaction.

364
00:33:29,210 --> 00:33:30,880
你现在有看见什么吗？
Do you see anything now?

365
00:33:31,710 --> 00:33:34,050
什么意思？关于你的吗？
What do you mean? About you?

366
00:33:35,260 --> 00:33:37,130
也许吧
I guess so.

367
00:33:38,470 --> 00:33:40,010
没有，什么也没有
No. Nothing.

368
00:33:40,470 --> 00:33:42,810
- 一点都没？  - 一点都没
- At all?  - At all.

369
00:33:43,270 --> 00:33:44,930
什么都没有
Just nothing.

370
00:33:45,390 --> 00:33:47,060
什么都没有
Nothing at all.

371
00:33:54,150 --> 00:33:56,740
调查进行的怎么样了？
So how's the investigation going?

372
00:33:57,700 --> 00:33:59,280
有进展
It's improving.

373
00:33:59,450 --> 00:34:04,660
我们觉得已经知道了你儿子为什么被杀，为什么他被选中了
We believe we know why your son was killed. Why he was chosen.

374
00:34:05,620 --> 00:34:09,710
艾利斯先生，我想问你几个问题，但绝对不是想惹怒你
Mr. Ellis, I need to ask you a few questions but I don't want to upset you.

375
00:34:09,880 --> 00:34:13,130
没事，问吧，只要可以，我都愿意帮忙
It's all right. Ask. If I can, I'd like to help.

376
00:34:13,710 --> 00:34:19,050
你记得在罗伯特死前的几星期，或是几个月
Do you remember in the weeks or months leading up to Robert's death,

377
00:34:19,220 --> 00:34:22,100
他身体好吗？他还健康吗？
was he at his best? Was he healthy?

378
00:34:23,010 --> 00:34:26,020
- 很健康  - 他从没抱怨说哪里会疼
- Perfectly.  - He never complained of any pain?

379
00:34:26,180 --> 00:34:30,480
他在学校和别的男生有差距吗？
Did he ever have trouble keeping up with other boys at school?

380
00:34:30,650 --> 00:34:32,940
他有没有过呼吸短促
Was he ever short of breath?

381
00:34:33,650 --> 00:34:36,610
呃…没有，没有
Uh... No. No.

382
00:34:43,200 --> 00:34:45,620
- 小心  - 好的
- Be careful.  - I will.

383
00:34:49,710 --> 00:34:51,250
罗伯特是个雕刻家？
Robert was a sculptor?

384
00:34:51,420 --> 00:34:52,960
是啊，他很喜欢雕东西
Yeah. He enjoys it.

385
00:34:53,750 --> 00:34:56,960
很喜欢，他很擅长
He enjoyed it. He had very good hands.

386
00:35:00,340 --> 00:35:02,390
对不起，艾利斯先生
I'm so sorry, Mr. Ellis.

387
00:35:13,150 --> 00:35:16,070
- 它们都很漂亮  - 谢谢
- They're beautiful.  - Thank you.

388
00:35:16,860 --> 00:35:18,610
这一个是怎么了？
What happened to this one?

389
00:35:19,610 --> 00:35:22,740
他在死前的一两天把它踢坏了…
He knocked it over maybe a day or two before...

390
00:35:24,870 --> 00:35:26,660
他怎么踢坏它的？
How did he knock it over?

391
00:35:26,830 --> 00:35:29,910
我不记得，孩子们都是笨手笨脚的
I don't remember. Kids are clumsy.

392
00:35:30,080 --> 00:35:31,580
罗伯特尤其如此吗？
Robert especially?

393
00:35:32,290 --> 00:35:33,830
那个…
Well...

394
00:35:34,420 --> 00:35:37,960
有时候，他会摔掉餐桌上的玻璃杯
Sometimes. He'd upset his glass at dinner...

395
00:35:38,130 --> 00:35:41,970
- 你在跟他们说话？  - 他们刚到
- You're talking to them?  - They just got here.

396
00:35:43,260 --> 00:35:44,800
你们抓到他了吗？
Did you catch him?

397
00:35:45,180 --> 00:35:46,720
没有
No.

398
00:35:48,350 --> 00:35:51,390
- 那你们来这干什么？  - 艾利斯太太…
- Then what are you doing here?  - Mrs. Ellis...

399
00:35:51,810 --> 00:35:54,060
昨晚又发生了一起杀人案
There was another murder last night.

400
00:35:54,230 --> 00:35:57,230
我们相信那和杀死你儿子的是同一个人
We believe it's the same man that killed your son.

401
00:35:57,900 --> 00:36:03,070
其他所有的受害者都是有疾病的
All of the other victims have suffered from an illness or a condition...

402
00:36:03,240 --> 00:36:07,700
- 罗伯特才十二岁，他没病  - 我们想证实这点
- Robert was 12. He wasn't sick.  - We'd like to verify that.

403
00:36:07,870 --> 00:36:09,330
那你打算怎么做？
How are you going to do that?

404
00:36:09,500 --> 00:36:11,870
我们想解剖尸体
We conduct an autopsy.

405
00:36:12,040 --> 00:36:16,130
你打算把他的尸体挖出来，剖开，然后在他身上搜来搜去？
You dig his body up, pry him open and search around inside him?

406
00:36:16,290 --> 00:36:17,710
是的，没错
Yes, we do.

407
00:36:17,880 --> 00:36:20,510
- 你是谁？  - 我是个医生
- Who are you?  - I'm a doctor.

408
00:36:21,340 --> 00:36:23,340
他没病
He wasn't sick.

409
00:36:24,300 --> 00:36:27,550
就算病了，也不需要你这样的人
And even if he was, he did not need a man like you.

410
00:36:30,140 --> 00:36:31,810
这是命运
It's fate.

411
00:36:32,600 --> 00:36:35,810
只是有些人没有勇气
It's just that some people do not have the courage

412
00:36:35,980 --> 00:36:38,110
接受上帝的智慧
to accept the wisdom of the Lord.

413
00:36:39,150 --> 00:36:41,940
艾利斯太太，我完全同意你的看法
I agree with you, Mrs. Ellis, absolutely.

414
00:36:42,990 --> 00:36:45,360
我知道药物的局限性
I know the limitations of medicine,

415
00:36:45,530 --> 00:36:49,830
我诊断过的很多病人，体内都有致死的疾病
I've diagnosed many patients with death growing inside them.

416
00:36:49,990 --> 00:36:52,700
比如我女儿，她有白血病
Like my own daughter. She had Leukemia.

417
00:36:52,870 --> 00:36:56,170
两年来，我每天都去医院
For 2 years, I went to the hospital every day

418
00:36:56,330 --> 00:36:57,880
看着她受病痛折磨
and watched her suffer.

419
00:36:58,040 --> 00:37:01,920
当然每个过程，每次测试都是完全无用的
Every procedure, every test, all totally useless, of course.

420
00:37:02,510 --> 00:37:04,760
有一天，她死了
And one day she died.

421
00:37:06,590 --> 00:37:08,010
就这样
And that was that.

422
00:37:09,060 --> 00:37:11,470
终于，这是一种祝福
In the end, it was a blessing.

423
00:37:11,640 --> 00:37:14,890
所以，是的，我明白命运这东西，艾利斯太太
I do understand something about fate, Mrs. Ellis.

424
00:37:15,520 --> 00:37:20,270
而且，我当然不会用药物去改变上帝的旨意
And, uh, I certainly wouldn't use medicine to alter God's plan.

425
00:37:20,440 --> 00:37:24,320
我只是想知道你儿子为什么被杀
I... just want to know why your son was killed.

426
00:37:24,780 --> 00:37:27,320
而药物不能帮助我发现这些
And medicine can help me discover that.

427
00:37:27,780 --> 00:37:30,370
也许，这样能帮助我抓到那个
And then, perhaps, it can help me catch the man...

428
00:37:31,580 --> 00:37:34,000
杀害了你儿子的人
who killed your little boy.

429
00:38:05,570 --> 00:38:09,070
克兰西博士，有你的传真，标了急
Dr. Clancy. Fax for you. It's marked urgent.

430
00:38:15,290 --> 00:38:16,790
那是什么？
What is it?

431
00:38:18,830 --> 00:38:21,040
检查小脑叶
Check the cerebellar lobe.

432
00:38:27,260 --> 00:38:29,840
这是什么？
Whoa! What is this?

433
00:38:30,300 --> 00:38:33,010
- 好吧，这就是你找的答案  - 什么？
- Well, there's your answer.  - What?

434
00:38:35,310 --> 00:38:37,730
脑瘤，豌豆大小
Brain tumor. Size of a pea.

435
00:38:38,390 --> 00:38:40,190
藏在小脑里
Hidden in the cerebellar lobe.

436
00:38:45,940 --> 00:38:48,450
- 约翰？  - 怎么了，博士？
- John?  - What's up, Doc?

437
00:38:50,160 --> 00:38:51,200
天呐！
Christ!

438
00:39:00,250 --> 00:39:03,960
- 约翰？  - 我不干了，结束了
- John?  - I'm out. Finished.

439
00:39:10,380 --> 00:39:12,970
那传真？上面究竟写了什么？
The fax? What the hell did it say?

440
00:39:13,430 --> 00:39:16,310
我不知道，那是急件，而且是机密
I don't know. It was urgent and confidential.

441
00:39:16,470 --> 00:39:18,600
我看你是被训练的太乖了
Somebody trained you too well.

442
00:39:21,270 --> 00:39:22,810
约翰！
John!

443
00:39:23,400 --> 00:39:26,440
该死！你总得告诉我点什么吧！
Goddamn it! You gotta let somebody in on this!

444
00:39:27,440 --> 00:39:33,280
- 我们正在走向一个陷阱  - 什么？你告诉我啊
- We're walking right into a trap.  - What? You gotta talk to me.

445
00:39:34,700 --> 00:39:38,290
他抢在我们的前面，我们在做他希望我们想做的事
He's way ahead of us. And we do exactly what he wants us to do.

446
00:39:38,450 --> 00:39:40,000
难道你还不明白吗？
Don't you get it?

447
00:39:41,580 --> 00:39:43,120
我不干了
I'm out.

448
00:40:07,270 --> 00:40:09,030
克兰西博士呢？
Doctor Clancy?

449
00:40:21,960 --> 00:40:23,710
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.

450
00:40:29,670 --> 00:40:32,720
- 介意吗？  - 随便，反正你们报销
- Do you mind?  - Go ahead. You're paying for it.

451
00:40:40,810 --> 00:40:42,680
我们发现了一颗
So, we find a tumor...

452
00:40:43,140 --> 00:40:45,350
任何人之前都不知道的肿瘤
that no one could've known about.

453
00:40:45,860 --> 00:40:47,900
我们建立了
We've established connections

454
00:40:48,070 --> 00:40:52,030
受害者们之前的联系，我大方承认，这是我不可能想到的
between victims that, I freely admit, I could never have seen.

455
00:40:52,530 --> 00:40:55,660
但你没有上前一步，带领我们
And instead of stepping up and leading from the front,

456
00:40:55,820 --> 00:40:59,160
你要求解剖尸体
you run out of an autopsy, which you asked for,

457
00:40:59,620 --> 00:41:02,660
碰巧，没有任何解释
coincidentally, without any explanation,

458
00:41:02,830 --> 00:41:07,130
你现在就收拾包，打算回家了
and now you're packing your bags and you're going home.

459
00:41:08,130 --> 00:41:09,750
原谅我，克兰西
Forgive me, Clancy,

460
00:41:10,630 --> 00:41:12,170
但你他妈的到底干什么？
but what the fuck?

461
00:41:12,670 --> 00:41:14,220
嗯
Hmm.

462
00:41:16,340 --> 00:41:17,890
“我是谁？
"Who am I?

463
00:41:18,510 --> 00:41:22,890
我会用两个字告诉你我是谁，我是做什么的，我如何生活”
I will tell you in two words who I am, what I do, and how I live."

464
00:41:23,060 --> 00:41:25,020
凶手留下的谜语，怎么了？
What about that riddle?

465
00:41:25,190 --> 00:41:27,150
- 这不是谜语  - 那是什么？
- It's not a riddle.  - What is it?

466
00:41:27,310 --> 00:41:30,940
“我会用两个字告诉你我是谁，我是做什么的，我如何生活”
"Le diro con due parole, chi son, e che faccio, come vivo."

467
00:41:31,110 --> 00:41:35,280
- 出自普契尼的《波希米亚人》  - 这么说凶手是歌剧傻子
- It's from La Bohème by Puccini.  - So the killer is an opera nut.

468
00:41:35,450 --> 00:41:37,910
好极了，这对概况很有帮助
That really helps with the profile.

469
00:41:38,070 --> 00:41:39,620
- 谢谢你，克兰西  - 不
- Thank you, Clancy.  - No.

470
00:41:40,870 --> 00:41:42,910
我才是傻子，我是歌剧迷
I'm the nut. I'm the opera nut.

471
00:41:45,330 --> 00:41:50,630
我碰巧在看你的案件描述时，就在听这几句歌词
I happened to be listening to those lines, the very moment I read your case files.

472
00:41:51,170 --> 00:41:55,220
- 我…我不明白  - 他早就知道我会听那首歌剧
- I... I don't get it.  - He knew I'd be listening to that music.

473
00:41:55,380 --> 00:41:57,800
他也知道你们会请我帮忙
He knew that you would ask me to help.

474
00:41:57,970 --> 00:42:03,470
他知道我们会在四点十六分整抵达公寓
He knew we would arrive at the apartment at exactly 4:16 am.

475
00:42:03,640 --> 00:42:08,350
因为他知道一切
Because he knows everything.

476
00:42:09,650 --> 00:42:13,820
你看，他跟我一样，能看到东西
You see... He's just like me. He sees things.

477
00:42:14,280 --> 00:42:16,360
只不过他比我更厉害
Only he's better at it.

478
00:42:16,530 --> 00:42:18,910
要厉害的多，来，看这个
A whole lot better. Come, read that.

479
00:42:19,370 --> 00:42:20,910
来啊，看这个！
Come on, read it!

480
00:42:33,880 --> 00:42:35,800
“克兰西博士
"Dr. Clancy,"

481
00:42:40,680 --> 00:42:42,390
检查小脑叶”
"Check the cerebellar lobe."

482
00:42:44,520 --> 00:42:45,850
好吧
Okay.

483
00:42:47,060 --> 00:42:49,140
所以你才放弃
So that's why you're quitting.

484
00:42:49,650 --> 00:42:52,110
你棋逢对手了
You've met your match.

485
00:42:52,690 --> 00:42:54,230
不
Oh, no.

486
00:42:54,650 --> 00:42:57,690
不，这家伙，胜过我太多
No. This guy, he's way beyond me.

487
00:42:58,240 --> 00:43:01,570
我阻止不了他，这也就有了一个更重要的问题
I can't stop him, which begs a more important question.

488
00:43:01,740 --> 00:43:06,910
他真的值得被阻止吗？这些受害者，反正也是要死的人
Is he really worth stopping? These victims, they were dying anyway.

489
00:43:07,080 --> 00:43:11,080
他不是出于强迫，愤怒，或是任何
He's not killing them out of compulsion, or anger, or any...

490
00:43:11,540 --> 00:43:13,630
精神不正常之类的才杀他们的
deviant psychosis or so.

491
00:43:13,790 --> 00:43:19,220
不，他是那根雪茄，那个冰淇淋，那杯鸡尾酒，浴缸里的花
No, he's the cigar, the ice cream, the cocktails, the flowers in the bathtub

492
00:43:19,380 --> 00:43:23,050
和所有那些顶呱呱的东西，这家伙很聪明
and all that whacko stuff. This guy is brilliant.

493
00:43:23,220 --> 00:43:26,510
而且他是出于仁慈杀死了他们
And he's killing them with kindness.

494
00:43:28,890 --> 00:43:30,940
明白吗？安乐死
Get it? It's mercy killing.

495
00:43:31,100 --> 00:43:33,100
- 胡扯  - 是吗？
- Bullshit!  - Is it?

496
00:43:33,270 --> 00:43:35,320
- 这是凶杀  - 是吗
- It's murder.  - Mm-hmm.

497
00:43:36,400 --> 00:43:38,780
这也许能减轻很多痛苦
That may spare a lot of suffering.

498
00:43:38,940 --> 00:43:43,570
如果受害者是你女儿，你还会这么说吗，克兰西？
If this was your daughter, would you be saying the same thing, Clancy?

499
00:43:48,500 --> 00:43:51,000
抱歉，我不是故意…
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...

500
00:43:55,750 --> 00:43:57,300
只是…
It's just...

501
00:44:00,380 --> 00:44:04,180
我知道你的…我知道你的女儿死了
I know your... I know your daughter died.

502
00:44:07,390 --> 00:44:10,350
但我们有天都会死，不是吗？
But we all die someday, don't we?

503
00:44:12,440 --> 00:44:13,980
所以究竟是什么…
So what is it...

504
00:44:15,310 --> 00:44:19,900
严重到你不能说？
that's so terrible that you can't talk about?

505
00:44:22,200 --> 00:44:23,450
好吧！
Okay!

506
00:44:24,820 --> 00:44:26,910
这本是我不打算告诉你的
Here's what I'm not telling you.

507
00:44:27,080 --> 00:44:30,660
你十七岁在一个叫布鲁斯的喝醉了的学生身上
You lost your virginity to a drunk stud called Bruce

508
00:44:30,830 --> 00:44:33,330
在他那辆绿色的福特野马车后座失去了童贞
in the back of his green Ford Bronco at 17.

509
00:44:33,500 --> 00:44:35,710
你并不怎么高兴，因为
You didn't like it very much because

510
00:44:35,880 --> 00:44:37,340
他吐了你一身
he puked all over you.

511
00:44:37,500 --> 00:44:40,670
五年前，你找了个男朋友，叫凯文
5 years ago, you had a boyfriend called Kevin.

512
00:44:40,840 --> 00:44:42,380
不，抱歉，是加文
No, sorry. Gavin.

513
00:44:42,550 --> 00:44:45,640
你们俩谈了将近一年的恋爱
A year into that relationship you discovered

514
00:44:45,800 --> 00:44:48,680
你发现你怀了加文的孩子
he thought you were pregnant with his baby.

515
00:44:48,850 --> 00:44:52,180
加文不想要，但你想要，所以，加文就抛弃了你
Gavin didn't want it but you did, so he left you.

516
00:44:52,350 --> 00:44:55,020
两个半月后，婴儿出生了
And 21/2 months later, the baby was born.

517
00:44:55,190 --> 00:44:56,850
是个小女孩，叫阿曼达
A little girl, Amanda.

518
00:44:57,020 --> 00:45:00,480
真的很漂亮，但有天你决定把她交给领养机构
But one day you decided to give her up for adoption.

519
00:45:00,650 --> 00:45:02,400
她的纯真令你心碎
It's breaking your heart,

520
00:45:02,570 --> 00:45:07,820
那让你流干了眼泪，这就是为什么你满嘴刻薄话，而且冷酷
tearing your guts out and that's why you pretend to be so foul-mouthed and cool.

521
00:45:08,330 --> 00:45:12,910
一年两次的你父母的生日，多伦和弗兰克
Exactly twice a year on each of your parents' birthdays, Doreen and Frank,

522
00:45:13,080 --> 00:45:15,710
在他们生日的时候，分别是十一月十六日和十月二十三日
On their birthdays, 11/16 and 10/23,

523
00:45:15,870 --> 00:45:17,710
你在辛辛那提给他们电话
you call them in Cincinnati

524
00:45:17,880 --> 00:45:22,260
你告诉他们，你爱他们，他们回答“我们也很爱你，小宝贝”
and tell them you love them, they reply "We love you too, honey bunny."

525
00:45:22,420 --> 00:45:26,970
然后你会在红色的天鹅绒枕头上嚎啕大哭
And then you will cry your heart out on that red goose down pillow.

526
00:45:27,140 --> 00:45:30,010
而且，因为我告诉你这些，你现在恨透了我
And you'll hate my guts for telling you all this.

527
00:45:30,180 --> 00:45:33,890
但你知道吗，考尔斯探长？没人会在乎
But you know what, Agent Cowles? Nobody gives a shit.

528
00:45:40,610 --> 00:45:42,150
你还要我继续说吗？
You want me to go on?

529
00:45:42,900 --> 00:45:44,440
继续
Go ahead.

530
00:45:45,700 --> 00:45:47,360
你还看见了我什么，博士？
What else do you see for me?

531
00:45:49,450 --> 00:45:52,330
回家去吧，小凯
Just go home, Kathy.

532
00:45:54,200 --> 00:45:56,410
回家去吧
Just go home.

533
00:46:44,710 --> 00:46:46,380
我搜这边
I've gotta search.

534
00:47:08,650 --> 00:47:10,570
我的天呐
Holy Mother of God.

535
00:47:20,420 --> 00:47:24,590
不明嫌疑犯是男性，年龄在十八至三十五岁之间
Unsub is male, between the ages of 18 and 35.

536
00:47:24,750 --> 00:47:26,420
似乎有精神病
Mental illness likely.

537
00:47:27,840 --> 00:47:30,760
似乎是懂些医疗卫生
Look for a man with little personal hygiene,

538
00:47:31,470 --> 00:47:35,180
显然缺乏社交技巧，一个
someone conspicuously short on social skills. A...

539
00:47:36,350 --> 00:47:40,180
十分机智，有些艺术气质的人
mercurial or an artistic temperament.

540
00:47:41,730 --> 00:47:45,980
看在老天爷的份上，找到那条裙子的下半部分
And for Christ's sakes find the bottom half of that dress.

541
00:47:48,650 --> 00:47:52,570
性冲动，过分暴力
Sexually motivated, excessively violent.

542
00:47:54,030 --> 00:47:56,120
这跟我们要找的人差远了
This isn't even close to our guy.

543
00:48:58,640 --> 00:49:00,180
嘿，警察！
Hey, cop!

544
00:49:01,680 --> 00:49:04,690
- 乔  - 约翰
- Joe.  - John.

545
00:49:08,150 --> 00:49:09,690
约翰！
John!

546
00:49:12,690 --> 00:49:14,450
约翰，也许你说的对
Maybe you're right, John.

547
00:49:15,910 --> 00:49:18,660
也许我们抓不到这家伙，也许…
Maybe we can't catch this guy. Maybe...

548
00:49:18,830 --> 00:49:22,500
也许这就是他想要的，我们找到线索了，约翰
Maybe that's exactly what he wants. We found a clue, John.

549
00:49:23,160 --> 00:49:26,210
我觉得很有用，我希望你看看
And I think it's a good one. I want you to see it.

550
00:49:27,540 --> 00:49:30,040
就当是出于交情
Call it a personal favor.

551
00:49:32,710 --> 00:49:35,970
你知道，将有很糟糕的事要发生
You know, something really bad is going to happen.

552
00:49:37,890 --> 00:49:42,680
你神秘的传真是通过全匿名的网络发过来的
Your mystery fax was sent over the Internet by high anonymity proxy.

553
00:49:42,850 --> 00:49:44,520
我们无法追踪到
We had trouble tracking it.

554
00:49:44,690 --> 00:49:48,770
我们还对维多利亚·雷蒙德的洗澡水做了化学分析
We also did a chemical analysis of Victoria Raymond's bathwater.

555
00:49:48,940 --> 00:49:52,690
HIV阳性，我们从验尸官和你那里都已经知道了
HIV positive which we knew from the autopsy and from you.

556
00:49:52,860 --> 00:49:56,650
但我们还发现一种抗无脊椎动物毒药的微量元素
But we found trace elements of an anti-invertebrate toxin.

557
00:49:56,820 --> 00:49:58,700
杀螺剂，花朵上的
Snail poison. On the flowers.

558
00:50:00,990 --> 00:50:03,950
约翰，我要问你，你是本来就知道
John, I gotta ask. Do you just know this weird crap

559
00:50:04,120 --> 00:50:06,790
还是你现在从我脑子里看见的？
or are you seeing into my brain right now?

560
00:50:08,630 --> 00:50:11,090
我们到了
We're here.

561
00:50:11,460 --> 00:50:14,170
这就是那些花来自的地方
This is where the flowers came from.

562
00:50:16,170 --> 00:50:17,720
嘿
Hey.

563
00:50:19,090 --> 00:50:22,470
我欠你个道歉，我晚点再解释
I owe you an apology. I'll explain later.

564
00:50:24,180 --> 00:50:25,730
- 你没事吧？  - 约翰
- You okay?  - John.

565
00:50:25,890 --> 00:50:27,140
没事
Yeah.

566
00:50:27,980 --> 00:50:29,520
来了
Yeah.

567
00:50:30,690 --> 00:50:32,230
哇
Wow.

568
00:50:36,150 --> 00:50:37,990
我们不该这么做
We shouldn't be doing this.

569
00:50:38,410 --> 00:50:40,110
这边！
Over here!

570
00:50:42,240 --> 00:50:43,780
现在太迟了
Too late now.

571
00:50:53,960 --> 00:50:56,090
看起来是被剪下来的，不是被摘下来的
They look clipped. Not torn off.

572
00:50:57,420 --> 00:50:59,470
我叫人来取证
I'll call forensics.

573
00:50:59,630 --> 00:51:01,340
- 约翰？  - 怎么？
- John?  - Uh-huh?

574
00:51:01,510 --> 00:51:03,510
- 你要试试这个吗？  - 当然
- You up for this?  - Yeah, sure.

575
00:51:41,680 --> 00:51:43,470
在那里
It's over there.

576
00:51:47,770 --> 00:51:49,600
那条裙子的下半边
The bottom half of the dress.

577
00:51:49,770 --> 00:51:51,020
该死！
Shit!

578
00:51:51,900 --> 00:51:54,190
快点让奥蒂斯过来
Get Otis in from the 14th now!

579
00:51:54,650 --> 00:51:56,190
这就去办
I'm on it.

580
00:51:57,570 --> 00:52:02,070
我们在一个房屋的墙上发现了裙子的上半身
We found the top half of the dress pasted to a wall in a tenement.

581
00:52:02,570 --> 00:52:07,410
受害者流光了身体至少一半的血，我确定那不是我们要找的人
At least half the victim's blood supply. I was sure it wasn't our guy.

582
00:52:07,870 --> 00:52:09,620
我感觉还是不对
Still doesn't feel right.

583
00:52:11,080 --> 00:52:13,960
- 奥蒂斯来了  - 奥蒂斯是谁？
- Otis is here.  - And Otis is who?

584
00:52:15,500 --> 00:52:17,040
除了你
Besides you,

585
00:52:17,800 --> 00:52:19,420
他是最出色的了
he's the best there is.

586
00:52:21,340 --> 00:52:23,800
奥蒂斯，快点，伙计，我们走
Otis! Come on, boy. Let's go.

587
00:52:26,390 --> 00:52:28,850
- 目标在哪？  - 就在这
- Where's the item?  - Right here.

588
00:52:32,230 --> 00:52:34,730
我们走，孩子，找到它
Let's go, boy. Find it.

589
00:52:34,900 --> 00:52:36,900
我们走，快点！我们走！
Let's go! Move it up! Let's go!

590
00:52:37,610 --> 00:52:42,320
我们要划出三个街区的范围，我们正在去河边路的路上
I want a 3-block perimeter. We're on our way to Riverside.

591
00:52:42,490 --> 00:52:45,360
- 我们要跟他走多远  - 看他会走多远
- How far do we follow him?  - As far as he goes.

592
00:52:45,530 --> 00:52:49,290
我不相信它，这要么没用，要么
I don't trust it. Either this is useless or...

593
00:52:49,740 --> 00:52:52,660
他正在带领我们去什么地方，可能是陷阱
he's leading us somewhere, maybe into a trap.

594
00:52:52,830 --> 00:52:56,000
- 那你要我怎么做，约翰，不跟着？  - 不是
- John, should I not follow the lead?  - No.

595
00:52:56,170 --> 00:52:59,170
我们必须跟这，我不知道，感觉很奇怪
We have to follow him. Christ, no! It's weird.

596
00:53:03,300 --> 00:53:04,260
我们走！快点
Let's go!

597
00:53:04,430 --> 00:53:07,890
很可能就是目标的位置，把全体单位都调给我，快！
Possible subject location. Give me all units, now!

598
00:53:09,260 --> 00:53:12,310
- 你穿了防弹背心吗？  - 当然，我们都穿了，约翰
- You wearing a vest?  - Of course. We all are, John.

599
00:53:12,480 --> 00:53:14,390
我们走，快点！
Let's go! Move it up!

600
00:53:18,610 --> 00:53:22,650
每个出口两个人，六个进去，索耶在这划界限
2 men on each exit, 6 going in. Sawyer runs the perimeter.

601
00:53:22,820 --> 00:53:24,240
我们走
Let's go.

602
00:53:25,660 --> 00:53:27,200
走
Go!

603
00:53:31,080 --> 00:53:32,830
上楼
Stairway up.

604
00:53:35,330 --> 00:53:36,830
登陆，安全
Landing. Clear.

605
00:53:37,420 --> 00:53:38,920
上楼
Stairway up.

606
00:53:40,380 --> 00:53:41,920
登陆，安全
Landing. Clear.

607
00:53:43,590 --> 00:53:46,630
开门！开门！关闭左边的门
Open door! Closed door left.

608
00:53:46,800 --> 00:53:48,720
走廊，关闭右边的门
Hallway. Closed door right.

609
00:53:51,770 --> 00:53:53,520
关闭左边的门
Closed door left.

610
00:53:54,270 --> 00:53:55,890
关闭右边的门
Closed door right.

611
00:53:56,060 --> 00:53:57,440
关闭右边的门
Closed door right.

612
00:54:00,650 --> 00:54:02,650
FBI，开门！
FBI! Open up!

613
00:54:04,320 --> 00:54:05,360
走！
Go.

614
00:54:07,070 --> 00:54:09,280
FBI，FBI
FBI! FBI!

615
00:54:09,820 --> 00:54:11,620
待在左边！
Stay to your left!

616
00:54:12,870 --> 00:54:16,460
- 左边安全  - 右边安全
- Left side clear.  - Right side clear.

617
00:54:20,170 --> 00:54:21,710
房间安全！
Room clear!

618
00:54:24,550 --> 00:54:26,510
- 哇！  - 你住在这吗，先生？
- Whoa!  - Do you live here, sir?

619
00:54:26,680 --> 00:54:29,130
- 你住在这吗？  - 这是我的工作室
- Do you live here?  - This is my studio.

620
00:54:29,300 --> 00:54:30,840
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?

621
00:54:31,510 --> 00:54:33,140
莱纳斯·霍普
Linus Harp.

622
00:54:33,310 --> 00:54:36,480
莱纳斯先生，除了你，这工作室还有谁在用？
Do you know who occupies the opposite studio?

623
00:54:36,640 --> 00:54:38,560
没有，没别人了
No... No one does.

624
00:54:38,730 --> 00:54:41,860
- 松脂  - 我是个画家
- Turpentine?  - I'm a painter.

625
00:54:44,570 --> 00:54:47,700
好极了，能和我们出去一下吗？
That's great. Can you please step outside with us?

626
00:54:47,860 --> 00:54:49,610
我能先锁门吗？
Can I lock up first?

627
00:54:49,780 --> 00:54:52,570
不行，你的工作室是安全的，出来吧
No. Your studio is safe. Step outside.

628
00:54:53,660 --> 00:54:55,200
青蛙
Frogs.

629
00:55:20,350 --> 00:55:23,230
不许动！
Freeze!

630
00:55:25,360 --> 00:55:28,650
- 有人受伤！  - 快点！救护车！
- Man down!  - Move! Ambulance!

631
00:55:33,330 --> 00:55:35,200
有人受伤！
Agent down!

632
00:55:36,660 --> 00:55:38,250
犯人是步行
Suspect on foot!

633
00:55:38,790 --> 00:55:41,670
他跳窗户了！我马上下去
He jumped out the window! I'm coming down!

634
00:55:41,830 --> 00:55:43,330
我们逼他到县里去！
We gotta get him to county!

635
00:55:43,500 --> 00:55:45,540
- 什么？  - 伤的重吗？
- What?  - How's it look?

636
00:55:46,670 --> 00:55:49,010
不太妙，叫救护车，快点！
It's not great. Get an ambulance! Now!

637
00:55:49,510 --> 00:55:51,630
跟凯瑟琳一起去
Go with Katherine.

638
00:55:51,800 --> 00:55:53,430
快点，去抓他！
Come on and get him!

639
00:55:55,220 --> 00:55:58,470
- 有线索吗？  - 没有
- Got anything?  - No sign!

640
00:55:58,640 --> 00:56:00,600
有线索吗？有吗？
We got anything? Anything?

641
00:56:20,210 --> 00:56:22,370
- 我在找什么？  - 不知道
- What am I looking for?  - No idea!

642
00:56:22,540 --> 00:56:24,250
- 白人男性…  - 左边
- White male...  - Left!

643
00:56:24,420 --> 00:56:26,000
- 这里左转？  - 这里左转
- Left here?  - Left here.

644
00:56:26,170 --> 00:56:28,210
汽车往西…
Car heading west...

645
00:56:28,380 --> 00:56:31,380
- 正在追踪  - 给我们个方向
- In pursuit.  - Give us a description.

646
00:56:31,550 --> 00:56:33,510
- 右边！  - 我们有机会就会
- Right!  - We will when we can.

647
00:56:39,560 --> 00:56:42,180
黄色出租车，他偷了一辆黄色出租车
Yellow cab. He's stolen a yellow cab.

648
00:56:48,900 --> 00:56:50,650
我需要一个号码
I need a number.

649
00:56:54,240 --> 00:56:58,080
- 五、四、三  - 那里！
- Five. M. Four. Three.  - There!

650
00:57:15,600 --> 00:57:16,200
[全天停车，15美元]

651
00:57:19,260 --> 00:57:20,680
嘿！
Hey!

652
00:57:21,470 --> 00:57:23,020
小心！
Look out!

653
00:57:26,560 --> 00:57:28,110
我们要跟丢他了！
We're gonna lose him!

654
00:57:30,980 --> 00:57:32,530
嘿！
Hey!

655
00:57:33,240 --> 00:57:35,070
- 左转  - 他直走了！
- Take a left.  - He went straight!

656
00:57:35,240 --> 00:57:36,780
左转！
Take a left!

657
00:57:41,950 --> 00:57:43,290
- 好，停车！  - 坐稳了
- Okay, stop!  - Sit back!

658
00:57:43,460 --> 00:57:45,160
- 停车！  - 知道了！
- Stop the car!  - I got this!

659
00:57:45,330 --> 00:57:49,170
他妈的停车！你搞什么鬼？
Stop the fucking car! What's the matter with you?

660
00:57:49,920 --> 00:57:52,750
- 他会逃走的  - 他逃不掉，停车就行
- He's gonna get away.  - Just stop the car.

661
00:57:53,210 --> 00:57:55,550
- 你想让我放了他吗？  - 闭嘴
- You want me to let him go?  - Shut up!

662
00:57:58,600 --> 00:58:00,220
快点，快点！
Come on! Come on!

663
00:58:05,100 --> 00:58:06,640
右边，走！
Right. Go!

664
00:58:51,020 --> 00:58:54,650
- 你没事吧？  - 没事，你呢？
- You okay?  - Yeah. Are you?

665
00:58:55,110 --> 00:58:56,650
没事
Yeah.

666
00:58:58,030 --> 00:58:59,570
他在哪？
Where is he?

667
00:59:01,950 --> 00:59:03,530
他在哪？
Where is he?

668
00:59:18,300 --> 00:59:20,720
嘿，警察！
Hey, cop!

669
01:00:11,060 --> 01:00:14,400
你不是他
You're not him.

670
01:00:27,290 --> 01:00:30,000
- 你想和他单独谈谈吗？  - 是的
- You want a moment alone with him?  - Yeah.

671
01:00:53,730 --> 01:00:56,770
- 你抓到那家伙了吗？  - 我没有，凯瑟琳抓到了
- Did you get the guy?  - No, Katherine did.

672
01:00:57,150 --> 01:00:58,820
好极了
Good for her.

673
01:01:01,280 --> 01:01:03,150
不是那家伙，对吗？
It wasn't the guy, was it?

674
01:01:03,610 --> 01:01:05,160
不是
Nope.

675
01:01:06,410 --> 01:01:07,950
这么说你是对的
So you were right.

676
01:01:08,790 --> 01:01:10,950
他只是在误导我们
He was just leading us down a path.

677
01:01:11,120 --> 01:01:12,450
嗯
Mm-hmm.

678
01:01:12,620 --> 01:01:16,250
带我们找到了那个精神病患者
Handing us that psychopath.

679
01:01:18,340 --> 01:01:20,000
现在…
And now...

680
01:01:20,800 --> 01:01:24,050
现在他还有最后一个目标
Now he's got another terminal case to show for it.

681
01:01:24,930 --> 01:01:26,970
癌症晚期
Stage four cancer.

682
01:01:27,510 --> 01:01:29,680
你注意到了这点，不是吗？
You'd picked up on that, hadn't you?

683
01:01:30,180 --> 01:01:31,720
我明白了
I figured.

684
01:01:32,930 --> 01:01:37,060
我很感激你没有逼我说那事
I appreciate you not making me talk about it.

685
01:01:39,440 --> 01:01:40,980
我几个月前…
I got the diagnosis...

686
01:01:42,990 --> 01:01:45,650
就被诊断出了，而且…
a few months ago. And...

687
01:01:46,200 --> 01:01:48,870
已经太迟了，根本没的治
It's too advanced to do anything about it.

688
01:01:50,450 --> 01:01:51,990
你会…
You will...

689
01:01:52,830 --> 01:01:56,160
你会时不时去探望劳拉和我的小儿子吧？
You'll check on Laura and my little man now and then?

690
01:01:56,330 --> 01:01:58,250
我当然会
Yes, of course, I will.

691
01:02:01,880 --> 01:02:03,420
天呐，约翰！
Hell, John!

692
01:02:04,800 --> 01:02:06,720
我还没准备好死
I'm not ready to die.

693
01:02:07,550 --> 01:02:09,090
我觉得…
I guess, uh...

694
01:02:10,390 --> 01:02:15,730
你知道，我有做计划，我有些期待
You know, I'd been planning on it. I've been expecting it for a little bit.

695
01:02:15,890 --> 01:02:19,560
但没几个月了，你知道，我…
But not for a few more months. You know, I...

696
01:02:20,060 --> 01:02:21,820
我还有那么多事没做
I have so much stuff to do.

697
01:02:23,650 --> 01:02:26,490
我想带劳拉搬去乡下
I want to move Laura to the country.

698
01:02:26,990 --> 01:02:29,950
我想教我儿子开车
I want to teach my little boy to drive.

699
01:02:30,870 --> 01:02:33,450
你一直都是个烂司机
You were always a lousy driver.

700
01:02:33,910 --> 01:02:35,500
我知道
I know.

701
01:02:37,500 --> 01:02:39,960
我希望他继承他爸
I wanted him to take after his dad.

702
01:02:44,010 --> 01:02:47,050
你知道，我们…
You know, we, uh...

703
01:02:48,680 --> 01:02:51,090
我们一生中想要的太多
We want for so much in life, you know?

704
01:02:53,180 --> 01:02:54,770
然后我们得到了
And then we get it.

705
01:02:56,520 --> 01:02:58,020
我拥有了
I have it.

706
01:02:58,190 --> 01:03:01,520
但我已经没时间了，没时间了
But I've run out of time. There's just no time left.

707
01:03:03,150 --> 01:03:06,490
你这一生做了很多事
Well, you did a hell of a lot with your life and time.

708
01:03:07,070 --> 01:03:08,610
我的朋友
My friend.

709
01:03:09,360 --> 01:03:11,660
- 还不够，约翰  - 你做到了
- Not enough, John.  - You did.

710
01:03:12,530 --> 01:03:13,950
不
No.

711
01:03:18,540 --> 01:03:20,920
我很开心你回来了，你知道吗？
It's good having you back, you know?

712
01:03:22,250 --> 01:03:23,790
嘿
Hey.

713
01:03:24,250 --> 01:03:26,380
再跟我讲一个你的烂笑话
Tell me one of your crappy jokes.

714
01:03:28,170 --> 01:03:32,640
烂笑话？不如我把你拆开，这能让你笑吗？
Crappy joke? How about I disconnect you? Would that make you laugh?

715
01:03:33,640 --> 01:03:36,100
的确，你真的不能
It's true. You really fucking can't.

716
01:03:42,270 --> 01:03:44,060
又是那个微笑
That smile right there.

717
01:03:44,770 --> 01:03:48,190
帮我个忙，带着这微笑去找伊丽莎白，好吗？
You do me a favor. You take that to Elizabeth. Okay?

718
01:03:48,900 --> 01:03:50,450
你要弥补她
You make it up with her.

719
01:04:10,380 --> 01:04:13,430
抱歉，我昨晚说了那些话
I'm sorry I said to you what I said last night.

720
01:04:17,470 --> 01:04:20,100
想跟我说说那个公园的事吗
You wanted to tell me something at the park.

721
01:04:20,270 --> 01:04:21,810
什么？
What was that?

722
01:04:23,150 --> 01:04:24,690
对，我记得
Oh, yeah, I remember.

723
01:04:26,690 --> 01:04:28,230
是的，那是一个…
Yes, it was a...

724
01:04:30,110 --> 01:04:33,860
美丽的周日下午，一九九〇年六月二十四
beautiful Sunday afternoon. June 24th 1990.

725
01:04:35,160 --> 01:04:37,660
我看着我的女儿在花园里玩
I watched my daughter playing in the garden.

726
01:04:37,830 --> 01:04:40,120
所有人都在唱“生日快乐”
Everyone singing "Happy Birthday."

727
01:04:40,290 --> 01:04:42,040
那是她的第六个生日
It was her sixth birthday.

728
01:04:42,460 --> 01:04:44,960
其他的孩子们也都很开心
All the other kids had a great time.

729
01:04:45,130 --> 01:04:47,420
忽然间，我看见了…
Suddenly, there it was. I saw it...

730
01:04:48,300 --> 01:04:50,920
在她身后，在艾玛的身后
Standing just behind her, behind Emma.

731
01:04:52,800 --> 01:04:54,260
是一块阴影
It was a shadow.

732
01:04:54,430 --> 01:04:56,680
就像窗帘一样在飘动
It was moving like a curtain.

733
01:04:57,930 --> 01:04:59,510
在风中飘动
Moving in the breeze.

734
01:05:00,770 --> 01:05:05,150
我知道那不是光线的问题，我能感受它就在我身边
I knew it was no trick of the light. I could feel it all around me.

735
01:05:05,770 --> 01:05:07,860
- 在我身体里  - 天呐
- Inside me.  - Oh, God.

736
01:05:09,820 --> 01:05:11,360
感觉好怪
It was weird.

737
01:05:11,820 --> 01:05:15,490
然后它忽然就消失了，然后…
And then it just sort of faded away. And, uh...

738
01:05:17,070 --> 01:05:20,830
我没有告诉任何人，就连我妻子伊丽莎白也没有，谁也没告诉
I didn't tell anyone, not even my wife Elizabeth, no one.

739
01:05:21,290 --> 01:05:23,500
但我丝毫不怀疑
But I had no doubt, no doubt at all.

740
01:05:24,210 --> 01:05:29,710
二十年后的同一天，她给我们打电话
And 20 years later, to the exact day, she called us.

741
01:05:30,420 --> 01:05:32,840
星期四的早晨，九点二十三
Thursday morning, 9:23.

742
01:05:33,840 --> 01:05:36,550
我觉得，“好吧，来了，开始了”
I thought, "Okay, This is it. Here we go."

743
01:05:36,720 --> 01:05:38,390
然后是诊断书
Then came the diagnosis,

744
01:05:38,930 --> 01:05:40,470
白血病
Leukemia,

745
01:05:41,350 --> 01:05:45,140
接着是两年的痛苦的治疗
followed by two years of agonizing treatment.

746
01:05:45,600 --> 01:05:48,560
接着我人生中最阴霾的一天来临了…
Then came the worst day of my life when she...

747
01:05:49,440 --> 01:05:50,980
她死了
died.

748
01:05:51,820 --> 01:05:53,360
她走了
And she was gone.

749
01:05:55,070 --> 01:05:56,280
艾玛
Emma.

750
01:06:06,710 --> 01:06:10,130
在第三天，他死而复生
And on the third day, He arose from the dead,

751
01:06:10,460 --> 01:06:12,840
与经文上写的一致
In accordance with the scriptures.

752
01:06:13,550 --> 01:06:15,130
他飞升到天堂
He ascended into heaven

753
01:06:15,630 --> 01:06:18,260
坐在天父的右边
and sits at the right hand of the Father.

754
01:06:18,720 --> 01:06:21,510
他将再次带着荣光而来
He will come again in glory,

755
01:06:22,100 --> 01:06:24,310
审判活着的和死去的人们
to judge the living and the dead.

756
01:06:25,230 --> 01:06:28,520
在他的国，没有尽头
And his kingdom will have no end.

757
01:06:30,020 --> 01:06:31,400
阿门
Amen.

758
01:06:54,460 --> 01:06:56,010
凯文，过来
Kevin, come here.

759
01:06:58,260 --> 01:07:00,050
我知道，会好的
I know, okay.

760
01:07:08,600 --> 01:07:09,650
[斯坦福大学]

761
01:07:49,550 --> 01:07:51,550
[酒吧]

762
01:07:55,020 --> 01:07:57,150
嘿
Hey.

763
01:08:02,200 --> 01:08:05,160
♫ 你的时光近了 ♫
♪ Your time is near ♪

764
01:08:06,830 --> 01:08:10,080
- 还需要点什么吗，先生？  - 一样的再来一杯
- Anything else?  - I'll have the same again.

765
01:08:16,920 --> 01:08:19,840
我想见你好长时间了
I wanted to meet you for so long.

766
01:08:20,010 --> 01:08:22,050
我们终于见面了
We're finally face-to-face.

767
01:08:24,430 --> 01:08:25,850
给你
Here you go.

768
01:08:26,010 --> 01:08:28,810
- 能给我也来一杯吗？  - 当然
- Could I have another one of these?  - Sure.

769
01:08:32,810 --> 01:08:34,650
约翰，我夺走的每一条生命
John, each life I take,

770
01:08:35,110 --> 01:08:38,070
就是将生命从巨大的痛苦中挽救
it's a life that's saved from enormous pain.

771
01:08:38,820 --> 01:08:42,740
我看见了他们的未来，痛苦和疾病
I see what lies ahead for them. The suffering and the sickness.

772
01:08:42,910 --> 01:08:44,740
我看见他们在痛苦中翻滚
I see them writhing in agony.

773
01:08:44,910 --> 01:08:47,740
我听见他们在尖叫，祈求解脱
I hear them screaming, begging for release.

774
01:08:47,910 --> 01:08:50,620
他们祈求的，约翰
They beg for it, John.

775
01:08:52,250 --> 01:08:54,170
是我让他们如愿了
And I grant them their wish.

776
01:08:54,630 --> 01:08:56,170
唯一更好的是
Only better.

777
01:08:56,750 --> 01:08:59,380
我在他们许愿前就到了
I get there before the wish is even made.

778
01:08:59,710 --> 01:09:02,340
我在痛苦开始前就到了
I get there before the pain even starts.

779
01:09:02,880 --> 01:09:06,220
那些被遗留下的爱人们
As for their loved ones, there's always an autopsy

780
01:09:06,390 --> 01:09:08,810
总能从验尸官那知道他们本来就有癌症
when the existing condition is found.

781
01:09:08,970 --> 01:09:12,730
就在那时，我看见他们从震惊到感觉安慰
That's when I see them go from shock to relief.

782
01:09:13,440 --> 01:09:15,850
我听见他们说
I hear them say things like,

783
01:09:16,020 --> 01:09:18,020
“谢天谢地，这如此突然”
"Thank God it was so sudden."

784
01:09:18,190 --> 01:09:20,020
“至少她没有痛苦”
"At least she felt no pain."

785
01:09:20,860 --> 01:09:24,030
最终，他们感激我所做的
In the end, they're grateful for what I've done.

786
01:09:28,780 --> 01:09:31,700
所以我帮了你的朋友，乔
That's why I helped your friend Joe.

787
01:09:33,500 --> 01:09:37,790
他还有七十三天极度痛苦的日子
He had 73 days of horrific pain ahead.

788
01:09:39,000 --> 01:09:42,340
你知道他的家人得到了什么好处吗？
Do you know what benefits his family would've gotten?

789
01:09:42,510 --> 01:09:47,050
就职十四年，死于自然原因？不
Dying of natural causes, 14 years into his career? None.

790
01:09:47,220 --> 01:09:51,510
但现在他妻子拿到了抚恤金，让他儿子上大学
Now his wife gets a pension, putting their son through college.

791
01:09:51,680 --> 01:09:53,890
事实上，是斯坦福大学
Stanford, actually.

792
01:09:54,060 --> 01:09:57,020
你觉得乔不愿意接受这样的交易？
You think Joe wouldn't have taken that deal?

793
01:10:00,270 --> 01:10:02,320
请别叫他们
Please don't call to them.

794
01:10:02,480 --> 01:10:04,690
拜托，你知道我带了枪
Come on. You know I have a gun on me.

795
01:10:07,320 --> 01:10:11,580
- 他有枪！  - 枪！趴下！
- He's got a gun!  - Gun! Get down!

796
01:10:15,750 --> 01:10:17,620
放下枪！
Drop the gun!

797
01:10:22,000 --> 01:10:25,050
如果我没看到一切的可能性，我就不会来见你
I've seen all possible outcomes of this meeting.

798
01:10:25,220 --> 01:10:27,880
我会让大家都健健康康地走
I walk away healthy from each one.

799
01:10:28,510 --> 01:10:31,220
有一个版本，对我们的女服务员尤其可怕
One version's gruesome for our waitress

800
01:10:31,390 --> 01:10:35,350
她在交班后的两分钟就会发生不幸
who'd be unlucky as her shift ends in a couple of minutes.

801
01:10:35,940 --> 01:10:39,600
我并不享受我的所作所为，约翰，这不是迷恋
I don't enjoy the work I do. John, it's not a fetish.

802
01:10:40,860 --> 01:10:44,110
这是为了让那些将死之人
It's about allowing those who are already dying

803
01:10:44,280 --> 01:10:46,190
死的有尊严
to die with some dignity.

804
01:10:52,700 --> 01:10:57,120
有时候，爱最伟大的形式，往往是最难实施的
Sometimes the greatest acts of love are the hardest acts to commit.

805
01:11:06,420 --> 01:11:09,300
你为什么对我沉默以待？
Why are you giving me the silent treatment?

806
01:11:11,680 --> 01:11:14,810
我明白了，一下子很难接受
I got it. It's a lot to process.

807
01:11:23,190 --> 01:11:25,320
我没想到会发生这种事
That wasn't supposed to happen.

808
01:11:27,070 --> 01:11:29,780
继续，他有枪！
To be continued. He's got a gun!

809
01:11:29,950 --> 01:11:31,610
他有枪！他有枪！
He's got a gun! He's got a gun!

810
01:11:31,780 --> 01:11:36,080
老天，是他！别烦我，去抓他！
It's him for Christ's sake! Leave me alone! Get him!

811
01:11:38,410 --> 01:11:42,830
他当时在喝啤酒，但是不含酒精的
Oh, he was drinking beer. But it was non-alcoholic.

812
01:11:43,000 --> 01:11:45,380
他的前额有一个伤疤
He had a scar on his forehead.

813
01:11:45,550 --> 01:11:48,420
是锯齿状的伤疤
It was kind of jagged, like, scar.

814
01:11:50,840 --> 01:11:53,930
这些是过去的十年里关于杀人的
Here are all unsolved murders over the last 10 years

815
01:11:54,100 --> 01:11:55,890
悬案的所有资料
with terminally ill victims.

816
01:11:56,060 --> 01:11:58,930
- 有多少？  - 七个，没有骨髓穿刺
- How many?  - 7. No punctures to the medulla,

817
01:11:59,100 --> 01:12:00,690
但都是无痛的
but all painless.

818
01:12:00,850 --> 01:12:03,310
- 投毒，煤气  - 都是当地的？
- Poisons, gas.  - These are all local?

819
01:12:03,480 --> 01:12:05,610
全国资料也要？
You want the national data, too?

820
01:12:13,870 --> 01:12:16,910
你看到的是这个吗，约翰？阿提格斯是什么？
Is this how you saw it? What's Atticus?

821
01:12:17,080 --> 01:12:20,290
- 约翰？  - 我们是关联的
- John?  - We're connected.

822
01:12:20,460 --> 01:12:23,460
- 我们是同类  - 这看起来熟悉吗？
- We're the same animal.  - Does this look familiar?

823
01:12:23,630 --> 01:12:25,380
我好害怕
I'm scared.

824
01:12:25,540 --> 01:12:27,380
她有留言吗？
Did she leave a note?

825
01:12:35,510 --> 01:12:37,510
专注，约翰
Concentrate, John.

826
01:12:38,180 --> 01:12:39,720
集中注意，约翰
Focus, John.

827
01:12:42,060 --> 01:12:43,600
约翰！
John!

828
01:12:50,570 --> 01:12:53,150
- 嘿，警察！  - 我好害怕
- Hey, cop!  - I'm scared.

829
01:12:59,700 --> 01:13:02,160
专心
Just... focus.

830
01:13:06,090 --> 01:13:07,710
约翰
Concentrate, John.

831
01:13:08,400 --> 01:13:09,700
[钠注射液]

832
01:13:11,760 --> 01:13:13,130
专心
Focus.

833
01:13:21,680 --> 01:13:26,350
过去的十年里有六十二起，从朱诺到迈阿密海滩
62 in the last 10 years, ranging from Juneau to Miami Beach.

834
01:13:26,520 --> 01:13:28,060
该死！
Shit!

835
01:13:29,530 --> 01:13:33,570
再搜索一次，去掉绝症
Do one more search. Remove the terminal constraint.

836
01:13:33,740 --> 01:13:36,910
找找其他同一时期的案件
Look for other unsolveds in the same time period.

837
01:13:37,370 --> 01:13:41,370
这凶手可能知道他们有病，但其他人不知道
The killer may have known they were sick when no one else did.

838
01:13:42,330 --> 01:13:45,000
用这份描述，全网查找
Run everything against this description:

839
01:13:45,170 --> 01:13:49,920
男性，三十岁，左前额有伤口，几乎是手术后遗留的
Male, 30s, front-left cranial scar, almost certainly post-surgical.

840
01:13:50,090 --> 01:13:51,840
查到了什么
Bring me everything...

841
01:13:52,300 --> 01:13:54,720
全都给我看，好吗？
anything you come across. Okay?

842
01:14:04,850 --> 01:14:06,100
嗯
Hmm.

843
01:14:20,030 --> 01:14:24,250
当然，这意思是“祝贺你，搭档”
That's what it means, "Congratulations, partner."

844
01:14:24,410 --> 01:14:25,960
我升迁了
I'm getting upped!

845
01:14:27,290 --> 01:14:31,040
这就是一个富有的老头，能在二十分钟内给你的东西
That's what 20 minutes with a rich geriatric will get you.

846
01:14:34,550 --> 01:14:38,590
我是该公司历史上最年轻的合伙人
Well, I'm the youngest partner in the firm's history.

847
01:14:38,760 --> 01:14:40,850
你可以跟你的朋友们这么说
You can tell your friends that.

848
01:14:45,770 --> 01:14:49,730
我不知道，星期一带他们来找我吧？
I don't know, I mean... Bring me them on Monday?

849
01:14:49,900 --> 01:14:52,480
只要他们觉得能行的
Whatever they think is right.

850
01:14:52,650 --> 01:14:55,110
“如果留得住，世上是否有
How to keep. Is there any,

851
01:14:55,280 --> 01:14:56,820
是否没有那样的
is there none such

852
01:14:56,990 --> 01:15:00,990
鞠躬，或胸针，或发辫，或拥抱纠缠，或捕捉或钥匙或保留
bow or brooch or braid or brace, latch or catch or key to keep,

853
01:15:01,160 --> 01:15:04,700
保留没的，来自消失的美
keep it, beauty, beauty, beauty from vanishing away.

854
01:15:05,450 --> 01:15:09,670
世上是否没有那般深的皱眉？
"O is there no frowning of these ranked wrinkles deep down?"

855
01:15:09,830 --> 01:15:12,420
不要对这些信使挥手
No waving off of these messengers...

856
01:15:12,590 --> 01:15:15,800
那些信使也悲伤，偷取灰色信使
Still messengers sad and stealing messengers of grey.

857
01:15:15,960 --> 01:15:17,550
不，这世上没有
No, there's none.

858
01:15:17,720 --> 01:15:20,510
你也不能渴望成为你现在的样子，这叫做公平
Nor can you long be what you now are, called fair.

859
01:15:20,680 --> 01:15:23,100
做你也许会做的，做你能做的
Do what you may do, do what you may.

860
01:15:23,640 --> 01:15:25,850
早慧令人绝望
Wisdom is early to despair.

861
01:15:27,730 --> 01:15:29,270
所以，开始吧”
"So, be beginning..."

862
01:15:29,600 --> 01:15:32,020
- 你好啊，约翰  - 你好，查尔斯
- Hello, John.  - Hello, Charles.

863
01:15:33,070 --> 01:15:36,860
“没有任何事能够不受牵制而做，从灰白的头发
"Nothing can be done to keep at bay age and age's evils, hoar hair,"

864
01:15:37,030 --> 01:15:39,860
到皱纹，到裹尸布
ruck and wrinkle, death's winding sheets,

865
01:15:40,030 --> 01:15:43,620
到坟墓和蛆虫，化为灰烬“
"tombs and worms and tumbling to decay."

866
01:15:47,910 --> 01:15:50,040
总之，你说我说对了
Anyway, you were right about me.

867
01:15:50,210 --> 01:15:53,000
- 我是…怎么说的来着？  - 矛盾
- I was... What's the word?  - Conflicted.

868
01:15:53,170 --> 01:15:58,050
我对你很矛盾，对，但已经不再矛盾了，不会了
I was conflicted about you. Yeah. But not anymore. Oh, no.

869
01:15:58,590 --> 01:16:01,430
你无权夺走我朋友，乔·梅里威瑟的
You had no right to take one hour, one minute,

870
01:16:01,590 --> 01:16:07,100
一小时，一分，甚至一秒
not even one second of time away from my friend, Joe Merriweather.

871
01:16:08,310 --> 01:16:12,690
我不知道你是否认识某个将死之人
I don't know if you've ever really known anyone who was dying, Charles.

872
01:16:13,230 --> 01:16:16,980
看着他们在恐怖的边缘挣扎
Watched them struggling on the edge of terror and horror

873
01:16:17,360 --> 01:16:20,150
努力抓住最后一丝生机，我不知道
as they try to hold on to life. I don't know,

874
01:16:20,320 --> 01:16:25,700
但如果你认识，也许你会感激，最后
but if you had, perhaps you would have appreciated how time at the end is...

875
01:16:25,870 --> 01:16:27,870
还会觉得很珍贵
kind of precious, I guess.

876
01:16:30,210 --> 01:16:32,830
那一刻，即使是痛苦本身
At that point, even the pain of life itself

877
01:16:33,000 --> 01:16:37,170
或许也是美的，你明白我的意思吗？
may be quite beautiful. You know what I mean?

878
01:16:38,590 --> 01:16:40,460
你的女儿就是那种感觉吗？
Is that how your daughter felt?

879
01:16:41,220 --> 01:16:42,760
她的…
That her...

880
01:16:44,850 --> 01:16:48,140
- 她的痛苦是美丽的？  - 我的朋友
- her pain was "beautiful?"  - Well, my friend,

881
01:16:48,310 --> 01:16:50,560
也许你可以亲自感受一下
I'm afraid you won't find out.

882
01:16:55,230 --> 01:16:59,150
- 他妈的，你们是谁啊？  - 坐下，闭嘴
- Who the fuck are you guys?  - Sit down and shut up.

883
01:17:06,990 --> 01:17:08,620
我没看见你扣动了扳机
I don't see you pulling that trigger.

884
01:17:08,790 --> 01:17:10,330
同上
Ditto.

885
01:17:10,500 --> 01:17:13,330
- 这不是你的风格，也不是慈悲  - 不是吗？
- This is not your style. It's not mercy.  - No?

886
01:17:14,460 --> 01:17:18,130
眉心中弹，可比他接下来要承受的好得多
A bullet to the head is better than what he's got coming.

887
01:17:18,590 --> 01:17:21,170
你看，这位杰弗里
You see, Jeffrey here...

888
01:17:21,970 --> 01:17:25,470
即将和多发性神经纤维瘤战斗
has a fight ahead of him with neurofibromatosis.

889
01:17:26,470 --> 01:17:30,640
而那会让他成为一只翻滚的扭曲的野兽
And that's gonna turn him into a writhing, crooked beast.

890
01:17:31,730 --> 01:17:36,770
明晚，喝一点鸡尾酒，杰弗里会让他女朋友怀上孕
Tomorrow night, after some cocktails, Jeffrey gets his girlfriend pregnant.

891
01:17:36,940 --> 01:17:40,230
而NFB最神奇的一点是它是会遗传的
And the real charm about NFB is that it's hereditary.

892
01:17:40,400 --> 01:17:44,700
尽管那孩子只有百分之五十的可能得这病，但我现在可以告诉你
There's a 50 percent chance the kid gets it, but I can tell you now:

893
01:17:45,610 --> 01:17:48,200
那孩子，得了
The kid... gets it.

894
01:17:50,370 --> 01:17:53,870
- 什么是NFB？  - 你想把这痛苦送给他吗？
- What's NFB?  - And you want to gift him that suffering?

895
01:17:54,330 --> 01:17:56,170
一次摧毁三个人的性命？
Destroy three lives in one,

896
01:17:56,830 --> 01:18:00,290
就因为某种道德评判？
all because of some moral judgment?

897
01:18:01,250 --> 01:18:03,380
我们耍不了上帝
We can't play God.

898
01:18:03,550 --> 01:18:06,260
不，我对耍上帝没兴趣
No. I have no interest in playing God.

899
01:18:06,720 --> 01:18:11,140
只要是和他相关的事，我觉得都没什么了不起的
As far as His work is concerned, I'm not impressed.

900
01:18:21,020 --> 01:18:22,570
没事
It's okay.

901
01:18:23,070 --> 01:18:26,280
看看你，你这么困惑
Look at you. You're so confused.

902
01:18:27,240 --> 01:18:30,120
你甚至不知道我们俩谁会开枪
You don't even know which one of us to shoot.

903
01:18:31,370 --> 01:18:33,580
你很快就会知道了
You'll figure it out soon enough.

904
01:18:35,210 --> 01:18:37,790
你快叫救护车吧，你被二次下毒了
Call an ambulance. You've been poisoned.

905
01:18:37,960 --> 01:18:42,420
你需要去医院，抠，呕吐，什么都行，喝牛奶
You need to get to hospital. Throw up, vomit, whatever. Drink milk.

906
01:18:42,590 --> 01:18:44,130
祝你好运
Good luck.

907
01:18:46,630 --> 01:18:49,180
我想我们找到他了，你的研究报告有回复了
I think we got him. Your search came back.

908
01:18:49,340 --> 01:18:53,760
我在枪支记录中搜索了他，是一个叫查尔斯·安布罗斯的人买的
I crossed him with the gun records. Gun was bought by a Charles Ambrose.

909
01:18:53,930 --> 01:18:56,890
天呐，我们走
Oh, man. Let's go.

910
01:19:37,680 --> 01:19:39,520
专心，约翰
Concentrate, John.

911
01:19:41,860 --> 01:19:43,730
今晚有人会死
Someone dies tonight.

912
01:19:46,780 --> 01:19:48,320
现在可别跟丢我
Don't lose me now.

913
01:19:59,920 --> 01:20:03,920
FBI！打开右边的门！打开左边的门
FBI! Open door right! Open door left!

914
01:20:05,050 --> 01:20:08,010
进去！房间，安全！
Move in! Room, clear!

915
01:20:19,810 --> 01:20:23,230
这是什么地方？没有家具？什么都没有
What is this place? No furniture? Nothing?

916
01:20:23,900 --> 01:20:25,440
景色还不错
Not a bad view.

917
01:20:27,530 --> 01:20:29,070
听着！
Listen!

918
01:20:30,030 --> 01:20:31,570
凯瑟琳！
Katherine!

919
01:20:34,910 --> 01:20:36,830
查尔斯·安布罗斯是谁？
Who is Charles Ambrose?

920
01:20:38,410 --> 01:20:39,950
他究竟是谁？
Who is he, really?

921
01:20:40,120 --> 01:20:44,250
- 他是怎么做到的？  - 我当然知道他们会寻求什么
- How the fuck's he doing this?  - I know what they'll look for.

922
01:20:44,420 --> 01:20:48,420
有功能障碍的童年，包括虐待和忽视
Dysfunctional childhood that involved abuse and neglect.

923
01:20:49,420 --> 01:20:50,970
以后…
Later on...

924
01:20:51,130 --> 01:20:55,300
找不到工作，找不到伴侣
couldn't hold a job, couldn't keep a relationship.

925
01:20:56,220 --> 01:20:58,600
- 各方面都是错  - 这是什么…
- Wrong on all counts.  - What the...

926
01:21:07,650 --> 01:21:09,570
专心
Concentrate.

927
01:21:14,160 --> 01:21:17,240
妈妈从没离开我，爸爸也从没打过我
Mom never left me. Dad never beat me.

928
01:21:17,410 --> 01:21:21,950
你在我的过去找不到任何暴力或反社会的行为
You won't find any trace of violence or antisocial behavior in my past.

929
01:21:22,870 --> 01:21:24,330
我不是激进分子
I'm not a radical.

930
01:21:24,500 --> 01:21:27,420
我对名誉或权力不感兴趣
I have no interest in fame or power.

931
01:21:29,750 --> 01:21:33,380
我不过是一个无法回头的人
I'm simply a man who could no longer look away.

932
01:21:36,050 --> 01:21:37,720
别停下
Don't stop.

933
01:21:45,270 --> 01:21:49,400
上帝知道我宁愿过平静的生活
God knows I would prefer to live the quiet life...

934
01:21:51,360 --> 01:21:54,110
远离我所成为的样子
away from all that I have become.

935
01:21:56,200 --> 01:21:59,030
但我们并不总能选择自己是什么
But we don't always get to choose what we are.

936
01:22:02,370 --> 01:22:03,580
你来了
There you go.

937
01:22:25,060 --> 01:22:27,560
好疼
It hurts so bad.

938
01:22:28,190 --> 01:22:30,060
我好害怕
I'm so scared.

939
01:22:45,040 --> 01:22:48,040
皮尔斯警官，我是查尔斯·安布罗斯
Officer Pearce. My name is Charles Ambrose.

940
01:22:48,210 --> 01:22:53,630
告诉你的上司，你刚看见我了，这会给你的职业生涯创造奇迹，相信我
Tell your supervisor you just met me. It will do wonders for your career.

941
01:22:54,800 --> 01:22:56,760
分布，我是皮尔斯
Officer Pearce here.

942
01:22:57,380 --> 01:23:01,390
现在，救世主…需要被拯救
And now the savior... needs to be saved.

943
01:23:09,400 --> 01:23:12,650
克兰西不希望你接那个电话，考尔斯探长
Clancy doesn't want you to respond, Agent Cowles.

944
01:23:12,820 --> 01:23:14,940
所罗门
Sloman.

945
01:23:15,900 --> 01:23:19,660
那事发生的时候，他也不希望你去那，但你会去的
He doesn't want you there when it happens. But you will.

946
01:23:19,820 --> 01:23:22,030
你会接电话，你也会去那
You'll respond. You'll be there.

947
01:23:23,160 --> 01:23:24,830
你忍不住
You can't help yourself.

948
01:23:26,040 --> 01:23:27,580
嘿
Hey.

949
01:23:27,750 --> 01:23:29,500
嘿，一个巡警
Hey, a beat cop

950
01:23:30,290 --> 01:23:33,540
刚在亚什兰报告说，看见查尔斯·安布罗斯了
just reported a Charles Ambrose at Ashland Station.

951
01:23:35,840 --> 01:23:38,420
你去哪？嘿，回来！
Where are you going? Hey! Get back here.

952
01:23:39,130 --> 01:23:40,680
待会儿见
See you soon.

953
01:24:19,600 --> 01:24:23,850
[退休能带给你什么？]

954
01:25:01,380 --> 01:25:03,090
你来了
And here you are.

955
01:25:04,890 --> 01:25:07,970
- 欢迎  - 谢谢
- Welcome.  - Thank you.

956
01:25:08,520 --> 01:25:12,230
和我这几年看到的一样，你，我，这辆火车
Just as I've seen it all those years. You, me, this train.

957
01:25:12,390 --> 01:25:16,190
你也见过，对吗？你听见了，日复一日，月复一月
You've seen it, too, right? You've heard it? Day after day?

958
01:25:22,530 --> 01:25:24,610
除了有些东西不对劲
Except something's not right.

959
01:25:40,210 --> 01:25:44,590
我是考尔斯探长，犯人进入了亚什兰站
This is Agent Cowles. Our suspect is headed into Ashland Station.

960
01:25:44,760 --> 01:25:50,510
我们会跟工程师联系，在我们布置好了的地方，停下那辆车
We'll have the engineer stop the train in a station up ahead where we'll set up.

961
01:25:50,680 --> 01:25:52,850
- 然后呢？  - 我们抓他出来
- Then what?  - We take him out.

962
01:25:53,020 --> 01:25:56,270
- 我建议你留在安全的地方  - 队长，我不能躲在安全的地方
- I advise you to stay clear.  - I'm not staying clear.

963
01:25:56,440 --> 01:25:59,310
我们有控制，好好待着
We have control. Stay clear.

964
01:26:01,320 --> 01:26:02,610
该死！
Shit!

965
01:26:06,740 --> 01:26:08,280
我们联系上了
We're connected.

966
01:26:09,200 --> 01:26:13,200
- 同类  - 不，不，我不是杀人犯
- The same animal.  - No, no. I'm not a killer.

967
01:26:13,370 --> 01:26:17,330
- 这个我们可以七分钟后再聊  - 七分钟？
- We can talk about that in seven minutes.  - Seven minutes?

968
01:26:18,880 --> 01:26:20,880
那是你会杀人的时间
That's when you kill someone.

969
01:26:21,050 --> 01:26:23,840
- 那会是谁？  - 我
- Who might that be?  - Me.

970
01:26:24,340 --> 01:26:26,680
快，快，进去！
Move, Move! Move in!

971
01:26:27,300 --> 01:26:29,050
- 快点  - 行动！
- Let's go!  - Move!

972
01:26:29,220 --> 01:26:30,720
- 走！  - 快！
- Go!   - Move!

973
01:26:33,020 --> 01:26:35,020
快，走，走，走！
Go! Move! Move! Move!

974
01:26:37,310 --> 01:26:39,060
火车还有五分钟到站
Train is five minutes out!

975
01:26:39,940 --> 01:26:42,110
我们走，快！
Let's go! Move!

976
01:26:43,110 --> 01:26:44,690
我要死了，约翰
I'm dying, John.

977
01:26:44,860 --> 01:26:47,280
我不能继续做这种事了
I can't continue this work anymore.

978
01:26:47,450 --> 01:26:50,320
所以我需要一个人来继承我
That's why I need someone to carry on for me.

979
01:26:50,780 --> 01:26:53,540
需要一个能看到痛苦
Someone who can see the pain.

980
01:26:53,700 --> 01:26:56,330
挣扎，疾病的人
The suffering. Sickness.

981
01:26:56,830 --> 01:27:00,830
这是你没看到的，你必须射杀我的另一个原因
There's another reason you have to shoot me that you don't see.

982
01:27:01,000 --> 01:27:02,630
专心啊！
Concentrate!

983
01:27:06,630 --> 01:27:08,090
约翰
John.

984
01:27:08,260 --> 01:27:09,260
约翰
John.

985
01:27:09,890 --> 01:27:11,760
没错，谢谢
There it is. Thank you.

986
01:27:12,430 --> 01:27:14,010
考尔斯特工
Agent Cowles.

987
01:27:14,680 --> 01:27:16,520
你越来越喜欢她了
You've grown so fond of her.

988
01:27:17,440 --> 01:27:19,690
就像你女儿又回来了
It's like having your daughter back.

989
01:27:19,850 --> 01:27:22,190
抱歉，你丢失我了，查尔斯
I'm sorry. You've lost me, Charles.

990
01:27:22,360 --> 01:27:26,150
她不符合你的描述，你为什么要杀她？
She doesn't fit your profile. Why would you kill her?

991
01:27:26,320 --> 01:27:30,660
你说的对，我不会杀她，她健康的很
You're right. I won't kill her. She's perfectly healthy.

992
01:27:30,820 --> 01:27:34,370
这就是它的美感，你必须先阻止我
That's the beauty of it. You're going to stop me first.

993
01:27:34,540 --> 01:27:37,500
对，用一颗子弹，就这里
Yes. With one bullet, right here.

994
01:27:39,000 --> 01:27:42,960
- 在那之后，就没有回头路了  - 抱歉，朋友
- And after that, there's no turning back.  - Sorry, my friend.

995
01:27:43,130 --> 01:27:45,340
游戏现在停止
The game stops here and now.

996
01:27:45,510 --> 01:27:49,970
我要四个狙击手，三个在地面，一个在高地，火车还有六十秒
I want 4 shooters, 3 low, 1 high! Train is 60 seconds out.

997
01:27:50,130 --> 01:27:51,970
快走，行动！
Let's go. Move!

998
01:27:54,760 --> 01:27:55,810
FBI！
FBI!

999
01:27:55,970 --> 01:27:59,020
- 女士…  - 让我过去
- Ma'am...  - FBI! Let me through!

1000
01:28:01,230 --> 01:28:03,060
看着我，约翰
Look at me, John.

1001
01:28:04,020 --> 01:28:05,690
这看起来眼熟吗？
Does this look familiar?

1002
01:28:19,710 --> 01:28:21,540
现在看到了吗？
See now?

1003
01:28:24,420 --> 01:28:26,460
你的画面都成真了
All your visions become real.

1004
01:28:32,510 --> 01:28:34,180
距离目标还有五十秒
50 seconds to target.

1005
01:28:34,350 --> 01:28:37,180
- 你看见了吗？  - 队长
- Do you have a visual?  - Captain.

1006
01:28:37,350 --> 01:28:39,140
- 你看见了吗？  - 是的
- Do you have a shot?  - Affirmative.

1007
01:28:39,310 --> 01:28:42,440
她会准时到
She's going to make it just in time.

1008
01:28:45,360 --> 01:28:48,440
- 开枪！  - 开枪！
- Take the shot!  - Take the shot!

1009
01:28:49,150 --> 01:28:50,740
操！我看不见他了！
Fuck! I lost him!

1010
01:28:52,530 --> 01:28:54,660
开枪！
Take the shot!

1011
01:28:55,530 --> 01:28:59,580
目标已经锁定
Target is locked...

1012
01:28:59,750 --> 01:29:01,330
我们走！
Let's go!

1013
01:29:04,210 --> 01:29:06,340
和你的命运打声招呼吧，约翰
Say hello to your destiny, John.

1014
01:29:15,550 --> 01:29:16,930
开枪！
Fire!

1015
01:29:19,640 --> 01:29:21,480
停，停！
Hold! Hold!

1016
01:29:34,950 --> 01:29:36,700
我说过，你会杀了我
I told you you'd kill me.

1017
01:29:36,870 --> 01:29:39,280
可以开枪了！
Clear to fire!

1018
01:30:06,810 --> 01:30:09,520
- 约翰  - 你没事吧
- John.  - You're okay.

1019
01:30:11,780 --> 01:30:13,320
你没事
You're okay.

1020
01:30:40,560 --> 01:30:42,100
噢，嗨
Oh, hi.

1021
01:30:42,720 --> 01:30:43,770
嘿
Hey.

1022
01:30:45,270 --> 01:30:48,350
- 你还好吗？  - 我和主刀医生说过了
- How are you doing?  - I spoke to the chief surgeon.

1023
01:30:48,520 --> 01:30:50,860
他说手术很成功
He said the surgery was a success.

1024
01:30:51,270 --> 01:30:55,070
- 好极了  - 他说子弹完全被清除了
- Good.  - He said the bullet went clean through.

1025
01:30:57,860 --> 01:31:01,070
我希望你能考虑复职
I was hoping you would consider a reinstatement.

1026
01:31:01,240 --> 01:31:04,040
正如乔说的，我们会成为极好的团队
As Joe said, we'd make a hell of a team.

1027
01:31:04,200 --> 01:31:05,870
不，我想过平静的生活
Oh no, I want a quiet life.

1028
01:31:06,290 --> 01:31:07,830
是啊
Yeah.

1029
01:31:11,040 --> 01:31:13,130
乔会为你自豪的
Joe would be proud of you.

1030
01:31:25,020 --> 01:31:28,480
别哭，你是个好孩子
Don't cry. You're a good kid.

1031
01:31:32,770 --> 01:31:35,360
约翰，和你合作很愉快
It was good working with you, John.

1032
01:31:37,070 --> 01:31:39,700
- 再会  - 再会
- I'll see you around.  - See you around.

1033
01:31:40,820 --> 01:31:43,030
- 照顾好自己  - 我会的
- Take care of yourself.  - I will.

1034
01:31:46,450 --> 01:31:48,000
对了，呃…
Oh, yeah, um...

1035
01:31:49,000 --> 01:31:52,540
差点忘了，能帮我寄一下这个吗？
Nearly forgot. Could you help me with this?

1036
01:31:52,710 --> 01:31:54,380
把它寄出去
See it gets to delivered.

1037
01:31:59,720 --> 01:32:01,260
没问题
I got it.

1038
01:32:05,850 --> 01:32:07,140
乔
Joe.

1039
01:32:30,160 --> 01:32:31,790
你好，伊丽莎白
Hello, Elizabeth.

1040
01:32:32,460 --> 01:32:34,040
你好，约翰
Hello, John.

1041
01:32:34,840 --> 01:32:36,380
你看起来美极了
You look so beautiful.

1042
01:32:38,970 --> 01:32:42,630
我看了你的信，好几遍
I read your letter. Several times.

1043
01:32:44,100 --> 01:32:45,800
它和其他几封信不同
It's different than the others.

1044
01:32:45,970 --> 01:32:47,510
哪里不同？
Which way?

1045
01:32:49,350 --> 01:32:50,930
写的都是关于过去的
It's all about the past.

1046
01:32:51,850 --> 01:32:53,400
是吗？
Oh, yeah?

1047
01:32:54,360 --> 01:32:58,150
是啊，我很想艾玛，每天都想
Yeah, I think of Emma. Every single day.

1048
01:33:04,120 --> 01:33:05,820
过来
Come here.

1049
01:33:08,740 --> 01:33:10,750
没事了
It's okay.

1050
01:33:27,100 --> 01:33:29,140
好疼
It hurts.

1051
01:33:31,640 --> 01:33:33,440
我好害怕
I'm scared.

1052
01:33:36,400 --> 01:33:38,610
我好害怕
I'm so scared.

1053
01:33:45,820 --> 01:33:48,370
我好害怕
Oh, my... It hurts.

1054
01:34:32,790 --> 01:34:35,960
有时候，爱最伟大的形式…
Sometimes the greatest acts of love...

1055
01:34:36,120 --> 01:34:38,420
往往是最难实施的
are the hardest acts to commit.

1056
01:34:46,340 --> 01:34:48,390
我们散散步吧，好吗？
Let's walk, shall we?

1057
01:34:49,890 --> 01:34:51,810
再会，约翰
See you soon, John.

1058
01:34:51,900 --> 01:34:54,830
导演
阿方索·博雅特

1059
01:35:56,500 --> 01:36:00,260
安东尼·霍普金斯

1060
01:36:01,200 --> 01:36:05,010
杰弗里·迪恩·摩根

1061
01:36:05,900 --> 01:36:09,710
艾比·考尼什

1062
01:36:34,200 --> 01:36:38,000
通灵神探

