1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
翻译｜Lavigkaye
中英文合并调整 部份句子修改及更正
Translate by Lavigkaye

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

3
00:01:04,800 --> 00:01:06,990
叫我马丁吧
Call me Martin.

4
00:01:07,030 --> 00:01:09,590
我经历过你无法相信的事
I've seen things you wouldn't believe.

5
00:01:09,630 --> 00:01:12,390
那不是一个孩子应该看到的
Things a boy shouldn't see.

6
00:01:12,430 --> 00:01:15,250
但是…我已经不是普通的男孩了
But... I'm not a normal boy anymore.

7
00:01:15,290 --> 00:01:17,230
而世界也非正常的世界了
And it ain't a normal world.

8
00:01:17,260 --> 00:01:18,560
习惯就好
Get used to it.

9
00:01:18,590 --> 00:01:20,890
“先生”是这么告诉我的
That's what Mister tells me.

10
00:01:20,930 --> 00:01:23,660
我们受他统治，或是死去
We live by his rules or we die.

11
00:01:23,700 --> 00:01:25,090
或者更糟
Or worse.

12
00:01:25,120 --> 00:01:26,610
死了又活过来
We die and we come back.

13
00:01:31,130 --> 00:01:33,880
让我们从头说起吧
But let's begin at the beginning.

14
00:01:33,920 --> 00:01:37,020
和其他孩子一样，我有一个家
I was like any other kid, I had a family.

15
00:01:37,060 --> 00:01:38,390
我去上学
I went to school,

16
00:01:38,430 --> 00:01:40,490
不相信有恶魔
I didn't believe in the boogey man.

17
00:01:42,370 --> 00:01:44,020
然而世界改变了，像一场噩梦
But then the world woke up to a nightmare.

18
00:01:52,890 --> 00:01:56,380
…待在家里，晚上不要出门
...Stay in your homes and not to travel by night.

19
00:01:56,430 --> 00:01:58,020
二十二号公路…
Route 22...

20
00:01:58,060 --> 00:01:59,580
也许我们该等等
Maybe we should wait.

21
00:02:01,850 --> 00:02:03,820
我们走小路，那里会安全些
We'll take the back roads, you'll be safer there.

22
00:02:08,900 --> 00:02:11,080
不要，马丁，回来！
No. Martin, come back!

23
00:02:11,120 --> 00:02:12,180
嘿！
Hey!

24
00:02:12,220 --> 00:02:13,480
马丁！
Martin!

25
00:02:15,790 --> 00:02:17,020
库柏！
Cooper!

26
00:02:17,530 --> 00:02:18,680
库柏！
Cooper!

27
00:02:20,390 --> 00:02:21,410
库柏…
Cooper...

28
00:02:23,960 --> 00:02:25,080
库柏…
Cooper...

29
00:02:26,960 --> 00:02:28,440
库柏！
Cooper!

30
00:02:48,380 --> 00:02:50,110
马丁，快跑！
Martin, run!

31
00:02:52,260 --> 00:02:53,450
妈妈！
Mom!

32
00:02:58,080 --> 00:02:59,850
嘘！嘘！
Shh! Shh!

33
00:02:59,890 --> 00:03:01,510
如果你不想死，就得听我的
You wanna live boy, you listen to me.

34
00:03:01,550 --> 00:03:03,150
你要是尖叫，我就拧断你脖子
You scream, I'll break your neck.

35
00:03:03,190 --> 00:03:03,620
他们都死了！
They're dead!

36
00:03:03,660 --> 00:03:05,810
除了杀死那东西，没有其他办法
There's nothing to be done about it but kill that thing.

37
00:03:07,550 --> 00:03:08,950
你会用枪吗？
Can you shoot?

38
00:03:08,990 --> 00:03:10,890
你要是敢射我，我宰了你！
You shoot me I'll fuckin' kill you!

39
00:03:36,820 --> 00:03:39,250
…二十四小时寻人热线
...A 24 hour hotline for missing persons

40
00:03:39,290 --> 00:03:40,980
以应对这场突如其来的灾难
attributed to the outbreak

41
00:03:41,020 --> 00:03:44,280
已经在县政府开通
has been set up on a county by county basis.

42
00:03:45,720 --> 00:03:48,410
热线从四面八方打进来
Phone lines in all areas have been flooded in.

43
00:03:48,450 --> 00:03:50,110
官员呼吁大家保持冷静
Officials ask for patients as

44
00:03:50,150 --> 00:03:53,580
搜救队正竭尽所能
recovery teams are doing all they can to maintain order

45
00:03:53,610 --> 00:03:55,270
维持东海岸线上的秩序…
on the east coast...

46
00:04:03,450 --> 00:04:07,350
重复一遍，日落后不要冒险外出
...I repeat, do not venture outside after sundown.

47
00:04:07,380 --> 00:04:10,740
待在家里，锁好门窗
Stay in your homes and lock the doors and windows...

48
00:05:18,110 --> 00:05:19,570
拿锤子来！
Get a fuckin' hammer!

49
00:05:28,810 --> 00:05:30,830
我只有两只手，小子，你来敲！
I only got two hands, boy. Do it!

50
00:06:18,500 --> 00:06:19,990
救他…
Save him...

51
00:06:38,130 --> 00:06:41,290
某天你会不再做梦
One day you'll learn not to dream at all.

52
00:06:41,330 --> 00:06:42,730
拿上你的护套
Get your shit.

53
00:07:16,060 --> 00:07:17,790
欢迎来到“分界地”，小子
Welcome to Stake Land, kid.

54
00:07:33,770 --> 00:07:39,270
分界地
STAKE LAND

55
00:07:44,030 --> 00:07:47,020
在这样不分白天夜晚的日子里，几个月过去了
Months passed in a blur of days and nights.

56
00:07:47,060 --> 00:07:49,660
我们东走走，西走走，不过一直都是往北
We traveled east and west, but always north.

57
00:07:49,700 --> 00:07:51,710
逃离死亡
Away from death.

58
00:07:51,760 --> 00:07:53,420
我们避开那些城市
We avoided the cities.

59
00:07:53,460 --> 00:07:54,690
“先生”说那里最糟
Mister said they were the worst,

60
00:07:54,730 --> 00:07:56,990
一开始就受到重创
hit the hardest in the beginning.

61
00:07:57,030 --> 00:07:58,720
因为人们聚集在一起寻求安全
As people flocked together for safety,

62
00:07:58,760 --> 00:08:00,420
灾难从他们紧锁的大门蜂拥而入
the plague marched through their locked gates

63
00:08:00,460 --> 00:08:02,820
人们成群死去
and they became death traps.

64
00:08:02,860 --> 00:08:06,920
后来政府倒台，我们所知道的美国也就完蛋了
When Washington fell, it was over for America as we knew her.

65
00:08:06,960 --> 00:08:10,390
政府倒台了，我们伟大的领导者们逃跑了
As government blew away, our great leaders ran for it.

66
00:08:10,420 --> 00:08:12,410
希望没有了
And hope was abandoned.

67
00:08:15,930 --> 00:08:17,910
现在我们只能靠自己
We were on our own now.

68
00:08:17,950 --> 00:08:20,150
我和“先生”
Me and Mister.

69
00:08:20,190 --> 00:08:22,620
在这遭毁灭的土地上四处游走
Traveling through a ruined land.

70
00:08:22,660 --> 00:08:24,920
文明所剩无几
Pockets of civilization survived.

71
00:08:24,960 --> 00:08:27,080
小镇都用篱笆封锁起来
Towns locked down behind fences

72
00:08:27,120 --> 00:08:29,990
晚上都有人持枪看守
and guns holding the night away.

73
00:08:30,020 --> 00:08:33,360
在南部各州，宗教狂热如野火般蔓延
Cults spread like wildfire across the southern states.

74
00:08:33,390 --> 00:08:36,720
等待弥赛亚到来，然而他终未出现
Waitin' for the messiah, but he never came.

75
00:08:39,620 --> 00:08:41,250
代之而来的是死亡
Death came instead.

76
00:08:43,190 --> 00:08:44,520
并伴随着“长牙”而来
And it came with teeth.

77
00:09:43,550 --> 00:09:45,240
这蠢蛋自己掉进陷阱
Dumb fuck got himself trapped.

78
00:09:45,280 --> 00:09:46,680
被太阳给烧了
Burnt up in the sun.

79
00:09:53,150 --> 00:09:55,050
狂暴战士
Berserker.

80
00:09:55,080 --> 00:09:57,180
吸血鬼中最古老的一族
It's the oldest of the vamps.

81
00:09:57,220 --> 00:09:58,940
木桩插不进他们的胸部
Can't stake 'em in the chest.

82
00:09:58,980 --> 00:10:00,540
胸骨像铁一样硬
Got a breast bone like iron.

83
00:10:00,580 --> 00:10:02,410
得从头骨底部插进去
Gotta get 'em in the base of the skull.

84
00:10:02,450 --> 00:10:04,010
吸血鬼
Vamps...

85
00:10:04,050 --> 00:10:06,750
的行动由原始脑控制
function from the reptile brain.

86
00:10:06,790 --> 00:10:10,300
就像是给电脑接通电源
It's like pullin' the plug on a computer.

87
00:10:18,410 --> 00:10:20,940
我们都是孤儿
We were all orphans.

88
00:10:20,980 --> 00:10:24,350
寻找着，想要抓住些什么
Just lookin' for something to hold on to.

89
00:10:24,380 --> 00:10:25,870
他是一个“先生”
He's a Mister.

90
00:10:27,710 --> 00:10:29,680
也许就是这个原因，他把我留在身边
Maybe that's why he keeps me with him.

91
00:10:37,440 --> 00:10:38,600
那是什么？
What's that?

92
00:10:38,640 --> 00:10:40,510
大蒜油
Garlic oil.

93
00:10:40,550 --> 00:10:41,950
真的有用吗？
Does that really work?

94
00:10:41,980 --> 00:10:43,380
反正没坏处
Don't hurt.

95
00:10:47,210 --> 00:10:48,470
全力一击
One strike boy.

96
00:10:48,510 --> 00:10:50,040
功到而成
Make it true.

97
00:11:32,890 --> 00:11:35,990
上帝把世界隔为两地
AND GOD SMOTE THE WORLD A SUNDER

98
00:11:50,540 --> 00:11:52,200
你们从哪儿来？
Where you boys comin' from?

99
00:11:52,240 --> 00:11:53,230
南部
South.

100
00:11:53,270 --> 00:11:54,530
下车
Get outta the car.

101
00:12:09,000 --> 00:12:10,590
有收获吗？
Did you get any?

102
00:12:23,640 --> 00:12:25,470
他们没问题，让他们过去
They alright boys, let 'em roll.

103
00:12:39,870 --> 00:12:42,900
又一个小镇， 封锁的小镇
Another town, another lockdown.

104
00:12:42,940 --> 00:12:45,420
人们试着这样继续下去
People just tryin' to go on.

105
00:12:45,470 --> 00:12:49,990
期待有一天醒来，一切都只是噩梦一场
Hopin' they'd wake up and it would all be a bad dream.

106
00:12:50,040 --> 00:12:52,330
回归原来的生活
They could go back to their lives,

107
00:12:52,370 --> 00:12:54,890
原来的家庭和工作
families and careers.

108
00:12:59,670 --> 00:13:01,800
他需要更多新鲜食物
He needs more fresh food.

109
00:13:03,830 --> 00:13:06,770
还有维他命，如果你能找到的话
And some vitamins, if you can find them.

110
00:13:06,800 --> 00:13:08,930
他的家人呢？
Where's his folks?

111
00:13:08,970 --> 00:13:10,440
死了
Dead.

112
00:13:12,060 --> 00:13:14,550
他最好留在这儿
He'd be better of here.

113
00:13:14,600 --> 00:13:17,330
和人们一起
With people.

114
00:13:17,370 --> 00:13:19,030
和其他孩子一起
Other children.

115
00:13:22,960 --> 00:13:24,490
我要怎么谢你？
What do I owe you?

116
00:13:28,770 --> 00:13:30,390
这些我都用得上
I could use all of them.

117
00:13:30,430 --> 00:13:32,050
很好
Good.

118
00:13:40,230 --> 00:13:41,960
嗨
Hey.

119
00:13:41,990 --> 00:13:44,050
这里哪儿能弄到酒？
Got any liquor in this town?

120
00:13:44,100 --> 00:13:45,530
杰克家
Jake's.

121
00:13:45,570 --> 00:13:47,360
大多是自制的
Homemade, mostly.

122
00:13:47,400 --> 00:13:48,880
他有一些桶装啤酒
We got some tap beer.

123
00:13:48,930 --> 00:13:51,720
有点发酸，不过害不死你
Little sour, but it won’t kill ya.

124
00:13:53,630 --> 00:13:55,290
这孩子需要剪头发
Boy needs a haircut.

125
00:14:18,090 --> 00:14:20,080
治安官说你们需要什么尽管拿
Sheriff said take whatever you need.

126
00:14:20,130 --> 00:14:21,490
全算我的
It's on me.

127
00:14:23,800 --> 00:14:26,020
你们经过过汉格斯镇吗？
Have you been through Haggerstown?

128
00:14:26,060 --> 00:14:27,610
我家在那里
I had family there.

129
00:14:27,660 --> 00:14:29,650
都被吸血鬼占了，这里以南的所有地方
Vamped out, everything south of here.

130
00:14:30,530 --> 00:14:31,860
真的？
Rea?

131
00:14:36,290 --> 00:14:38,260
他真的杀死它们了，嗯？
He really kills 'em, huh?

132
00:14:39,990 --> 00:14:41,930
你得刺中它们的心脏
You gotta get 'em in the heart.

133
00:14:41,960 --> 00:14:44,010
穿透胸骨
Pierce the breast plate.

134
00:14:44,010 --> 00:14:47,610
枪能伤害它们，不过你得防止那群笨蛋再来
Guns hurt them but you must save the spoony keep coming

135
00:14:48,220 --> 00:14:49,780
有口香糖吗？
You got any gum?

136
00:14:51,490 --> 00:14:53,250
嗯
Yes.

137
00:14:53,290 --> 00:14:54,550
真棒
Cool.

138
00:14:57,490 --> 00:14:58,960
啊，只是…
Ah, just...

139
00:15:01,390 --> 00:15:02,940
那么你是谁？
So who are you?

140
00:15:04,020 --> 00:15:05,720
他的助手
His helper.

141
00:15:05,760 --> 00:15:07,660
哪里，呃…你们要去哪里？
Where are you, uhh... where are you guys headin'?

142
00:15:07,690 --> 00:15:08,590
北部
North.

143
00:15:08,620 --> 00:15:10,520
呃，“先生”说人口越少，吸血鬼也越少
Uh, Mister says less population, less bloodsuckers.

144
00:15:10,560 --> 00:15:11,220
等等…
Wait, wait, wait...

145
00:15:11,260 --> 00:15:12,840
不是去新伊甸吧？
Not New Eden right?

146
00:15:14,790 --> 00:15:17,280
我们这儿有一人，他从那里过来
We had a fella, he came through here.

147
00:15:17,320 --> 00:15:21,310
他说那里什么都没有，连食物都没有
He said there's nothing there, there's no food at all.

148
00:15:21,350 --> 00:15:24,550
他说你要担心的不是吸血鬼…
He said it's not the Vamps ya need to worry about...

149
00:15:24,590 --> 00:15:26,180
而是食人族
it's the cannibals.

150
00:15:26,220 --> 00:15:27,590
谢谢
Thanks.

151
00:15:37,390 --> 00:15:40,980
有时候我想我可以在这样的地方待下来
Sometimes I think I could stay in a place like this.

152
00:15:41,020 --> 00:15:43,580
交朋友，在阳光下生活
Make friends, live in the daylight.

153
00:15:43,620 --> 00:15:44,980
做一个正常的孩子
Just be a kid.

154
00:15:45,020 --> 00:15:49,350
但事实是我在人群中无法找到安全感
But the truth is I don't feel safe around people.

155
00:15:49,380 --> 00:15:52,680
随便他们怎么想，新伊甸是真的存在的
They can think what they want but New Eden was real.

156
00:15:52,720 --> 00:15:56,050
它是所有这些问题的答案，我们要找到它
It was the answer to all of this and we were gonna find it.

157
00:15:56,090 --> 00:15:58,880
一路向北战斗，到达新的领地
Fight our way north, make the open territories.

158
00:15:58,920 --> 00:16:00,820
就像“先生”说的
Like Mister says.

159
00:16:00,850 --> 00:16:03,250
要么自由地活着，要么悲惨地死去
'Live free or die tryin'.

160
00:16:03,290 --> 00:16:04,880
去他妈的食人族
Fuck the cannibals.

161
00:16:15,350 --> 00:16:16,610
她叫什么？
What's her name?

162
00:16:18,380 --> 00:16:19,750
我没问
I didn't ask.

163
00:16:32,450 --> 00:16:34,100
为什么会发生这种事？
 Why did this happen?

164
00:16:34,150 --> 00:16:36,740
上帝怎么能容许这种事发生？
How can God let this happen?

165
00:16:36,780 --> 00:16:38,710
他的爱怎么会是这样…
How can this be his love...

166
00:17:15,480 --> 00:17:17,740
哦…哦，上帝！
Oh... oh, God!

167
00:17:19,150 --> 00:17:22,130
哦…哦，上帝！
Oh... oh, God!

168
00:17:25,010 --> 00:17:25,570
没事了，女士
It's okay, lady.

169
00:17:25,610 --> 00:17:26,940
- 不要！不要！ - 嘘，嘘
- No! No!  - Shh. Shh.

170
00:17:26,980 --> 00:17:28,210
没事了！
It's okay!

171
00:17:28,250 --> 00:17:30,330
- 不！不！ - 没事了！
- No! No!  - It's alright!

172
00:17:31,110 --> 00:17:32,700
不！
No!

173
00:17:32,740 --> 00:17:34,140
没事了，没事了
It's okay. It's okay.

174
00:17:34,180 --> 00:17:36,300
没事了，没事了
it's okay, it's okay.

175
00:17:59,540 --> 00:18:01,170
“先生”
Mister,

176
00:18:02,580 --> 00:18:04,740
这些吸血鬼是从哪儿来的？
where'd all that hate come from?

177
00:18:07,170 --> 00:18:08,800
我从没问过
I never asked.

178
00:18:16,700 --> 00:18:18,360
那些人
Those men that...

179
00:18:21,270 --> 00:18:23,970
他们说他们是基督徒
They said they were Christians.

180
00:18:24,010 --> 00:18:26,400
我们不做考证
We don't do history.

181
00:18:26,440 --> 00:18:28,370
这对谁都没好处
Doesn't do anybody any good.

182
00:18:30,810 --> 00:18:32,370
做陷阱，孩子
Grab them traps, boy.

183
00:18:59,940 --> 00:19:01,490
手指伸给我
Give me a finger.

184
00:19:54,830 --> 00:19:56,310
是时候收网了
Time to go fishin'.

185
00:21:06,730 --> 00:21:07,990
拿上长杆
Get the long pole.

186
00:21:11,290 --> 00:21:13,550
阿加莎姐妹
Sister Agitha.

187
00:21:13,590 --> 00:21:14,780
我们以为她死了
We thought she was dead.

188
00:21:14,820 --> 00:21:16,090
她是死了
She is.

189
00:21:17,230 --> 00:21:18,160
你们要干什么？
What are you gonna do?

190
00:21:18,190 --> 00:21:19,850
我要杀死那东西
I'm gonna kill that thing.

191
00:21:23,820 --> 00:21:24,690
上帝与你同在
Go with God.

192
00:21:24,720 --> 00:21:26,020
锁好门
Lock the door.

193
00:21:34,060 --> 00:21:35,650
新手，这没那么难
Newbie. Shouldn't be too hard.

194
00:21:46,360 --> 00:21:48,440
肉太厚，我打不断脊椎
Too fat, I can't break the spine.

195
00:22:22,320 --> 00:22:24,640
你没刺中心脏，蠢蛋
You missed the heart ya, dumb shit.

196
00:22:25,450 --> 00:22:26,940
该死的吸血鬼！
Fuckin' vamps!

197
00:22:33,980 --> 00:22:34,970
住手！
Stop it!

198
00:23:31,180 --> 00:23:32,840
“先生”挖了一座墓
Mister dug a grave.

199
00:23:34,180 --> 00:23:36,480
我想他是为那位姐妹感到难过
I think he felt bad for the sister.

200
00:23:39,480 --> 00:23:42,600
他有拔出长牙，不过…
He did pull the fangs out, but...

201
00:23:42,650 --> 00:23:45,170
他一直等到那位姐妹去采花时才动手
he waited till she went to pick the flowers.

202
00:23:55,810 --> 00:23:58,100
那东西你杀了多少了？
How many of those things have you killed?

203
00:23:59,740 --> 00:24:01,570
没多少
Not enough.

204
00:24:03,610 --> 00:24:06,000
人呢？
And people?

205
00:24:06,040 --> 00:24:07,400
那两个人？
Those two men?

206
00:24:07,440 --> 00:24:10,140
在我的字典里，强奸犯就该死
In my book, rapists got no place to live.

207
00:24:11,910 --> 00:24:13,210
这不是由我们来决定的
It's not ours to judge.

208
00:24:13,250 --> 00:24:14,130
那就不
Then don't.

209
00:24:14,170 --> 00:24:15,830
下一个小镇，我们让你下车
Next lockdown, we drop you off.

210
00:24:15,870 --> 00:24:17,360
你可以去拯救一些灵魂
You go save some souls.

211
00:24:17,410 --> 00:24:19,740
那么他呢？
And what about him?

212
00:24:19,780 --> 00:24:21,210
他只是个孩子
He's just a boy.

213
00:24:21,240 --> 00:24:22,400
是的
Yeah.

214
00:24:22,450 --> 00:24:23,870
一个活着的孩子
A live one.

215
00:24:49,740 --> 00:24:51,790
但是我们没让她下车
But we never dropped her off.

216
00:24:52,940 --> 00:24:54,630
她能去哪里？
Where was she gonna go?

217
00:25:00,570 --> 00:25:02,470
撒旦的士兵在夜晚游行
 Satan's soldiers march the night,

218
00:25:02,500 --> 00:25:04,870
但是上帝没有抛弃我们
but God has not abandoned us.

219
00:25:04,900 --> 00:25:08,360
相信上帝的人不会倒下
Those who believe in him shall never fall.

220
00:25:08,410 --> 00:25:11,860
耶稣和天使就要到来，审判即将来临
Jesus and the angels are coming and judgment is upon us

221
00:25:11,900 --> 00:25:16,430
雅利安人的基督教军队会来到这里为你们作战
and the Christian Army of Aryans are here to fight for you.

222
00:25:16,470 --> 00:25:20,360
为我们中的虔诚者创建安全的庇护所
And have created a safe refuge for the holy among us.

223
00:25:20,400 --> 00:25:22,730
兄弟姐妹们，加入我们
Join us brothers and sisters,

224
00:25:22,770 --> 00:25:27,420
拉菲特山谷欢迎正直纯洁的人
Lafayette Valley welcomes the righteous and the pure.

225
00:25:27,470 --> 00:25:31,190
我们同心协力，让世界重回光明
Together we shall lead the world back to the light.

226
00:25:31,230 --> 00:25:35,230
让正义、上帝钟爱的美国重回光明
And the right, the America God loves.

227
00:25:43,070 --> 00:25:47,790
在绝望的时代，假冒的上帝到处存在
In desperate times, false gods abound.

228
00:25:47,830 --> 00:25:51,630
人们把他们的信念寄托于大声的祈祷中， 希望他们做的是对的
People put their faith in the loudest preacher and hope they're right.

229
00:25:59,470 --> 00:26:02,300
但是通常他们都是错的
But sometimes they're wrong.

230
00:26:02,340 --> 00:26:03,960
错得离谱
Dead wrong.

231
00:27:20,520 --> 00:27:24,520
我是杰比戴亚·洛文
My name is Jebedia Loven.

232
00:27:24,560 --> 00:27:27,040
你杀了我两个人
And you killed two of my men.

233
00:27:27,090 --> 00:27:30,180
冷血的
In cold blood.

234
00:27:30,220 --> 00:27:32,990
一个背上被木桩打中
Staked one in the back.

235
00:27:35,230 --> 00:27:37,080
他是我儿子
He was my son.

236
00:27:38,790 --> 00:27:41,280
我的亲骨肉
My own boy.

237
00:27:41,320 --> 00:27:43,290
他才十六岁
He was only sixteen.

238
00:27:52,760 --> 00:27:58,310
在他死之前他哭着喊他妈妈，喊了三小时
He cried for his mother for three hours before he died.

239
00:27:59,860 --> 00:28:02,380
上帝会让他的灵魂安息
God rest his soul.

240
00:28:02,430 --> 00:28:04,380
你长得不错，小伙子
Now you a fine looking young buck.

241
00:28:06,650 --> 00:28:08,090
他是你父亲？
That's your father?

242
00:28:12,760 --> 00:28:14,720
我父亲已经死了
My father's dead.

243
00:28:19,990 --> 00:28:21,510
哦，别担心
Oh, don't you worry.

244
00:28:22,980 --> 00:28:24,850
我们会让你有信仰
We'll get you some religion.

245
00:28:27,290 --> 00:28:30,410
带你去见上帝，走上正道
Bring you to God and the right way.

246
00:28:35,820 --> 00:28:37,550
好货
Good stock.

247
00:28:40,090 --> 00:28:41,740
你还能用
You'll still serve.

248
00:28:42,280 --> 00:28:46,340
至于你，“先生”
As for you, Mister.

249
00:28:46,390 --> 00:28:48,150
哦，是的
Oh, yeah.

250
00:28:48,190 --> 00:28:50,150
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.

251
00:28:50,180 --> 00:28:52,370
你杀掉那些死后回来的人
You kill them that come back,

252
00:28:52,420 --> 00:28:54,540
那些为我们服务
them that serve us,

253
00:28:54,580 --> 00:28:57,950
那些上帝派来为他做事的人
them that God brought down to do his work.

254
00:28:57,990 --> 00:29:02,410
只留下我们，以净化我们天父的血
Leavin' us to purify the blood of our fathers.

255
00:29:02,450 --> 00:29:04,210
当那一天来临
And when that day comes,

256
00:29:04,250 --> 00:29:06,340
他会带它们平安回来
he will bring them back

257
00:29:06,390 --> 00:29:10,140
地球将一片纯洁
in peace and purity will reign on the earth.

258
00:29:10,180 --> 00:29:11,840
永远！
Forever!

259
00:29:11,880 --> 00:29:12,850
阿门！
Amen!

260
00:29:12,880 --> 00:29:14,470
阿门！
Amen!

261
00:29:17,350 --> 00:29:20,680
你有什么要说的，罪人？
What do you have to say for yourself, sinner?

262
00:29:26,350 --> 00:29:29,000
去你妈，去你妈的上帝
Fuck you and fuck your God.

263
00:29:35,720 --> 00:29:37,570
好吧…
Well...

264
00:29:37,610 --> 00:29:40,310
你可以自己跟他说
You can tell him that yourself.

265
00:29:40,350 --> 00:29:42,140
你就要去见他了
You're about to meet him.

266
00:30:13,510 --> 00:30:15,840
欢迎来到“他们之谷”
Welcome to the Valley of Them.

267
00:30:17,640 --> 00:30:20,310
脆弱信仰的终点站
Last stop for the weak of faith.

268
00:30:25,270 --> 00:30:26,760
把他带下来！
Get him out here!

269
00:30:32,210 --> 00:30:33,370
哇噢！
Ow!

270
00:30:48,580 --> 00:30:50,160
啊，看看他们
Ah, look at them.

271
00:30:50,200 --> 00:30:52,730
救赎的孩子们
The children of salvation.

272
00:30:52,770 --> 00:30:55,040
它们应我的召唤而来
They come at my calling.

273
00:30:55,070 --> 00:30:56,940
它们以不虔诚者为食
They feed on the unfaithful.

274
00:31:00,570 --> 00:31:02,090
嘘
Shh.

275
00:31:04,770 --> 00:31:07,820
它们说地狱很冷
They say hell is cold,

276
00:31:07,870 --> 00:31:09,360
狩猎者
Hunter.

277
00:31:10,900 --> 00:31:12,960
不要让这火灭了
Don't let that flame burn out.

278
00:31:44,140 --> 00:31:45,790
退后，它们这群吸血鬼
Get back, you bloodsuckers.

279
00:31:57,800 --> 00:31:59,700
你的头还好吗？
How's your head?

280
00:31:59,740 --> 00:32:01,290
“先生”
Mister.

281
00:32:01,340 --> 00:32:03,060
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.

282
00:32:18,170 --> 00:32:21,020
到下面小溪，把它们装满
Go down to the creek, fill 'em up.

283
00:32:21,070 --> 00:32:22,690
带回来
Bring 'em back.

284
00:32:27,270 --> 00:32:28,320
等等
Wait.

285
00:32:49,130 --> 00:32:50,520
嗨，小子
Hey, boy.

286
00:32:52,700 --> 00:32:55,060
你要逃走也可以
You can run if you want to.

287
00:32:55,100 --> 00:32:57,920
外面只有日落和吸血鬼
Ain't nothing out there but sundown and them.

288
00:32:59,430 --> 00:33:01,260
你走不了多远
You won't get far.

289
00:33:49,260 --> 00:33:51,820
“先生”教我怎样利用星星确定方位
Mister taught me how to read the stars.

290
00:33:51,860 --> 00:33:53,550
我可以找到回到车那里的路
I could make my way back to the car,

291
00:33:53,590 --> 00:33:54,550
拿上武器
get the weapons,

292
00:33:54,590 --> 00:33:56,050
找到那群穿长袍的疯子
find them robe-wearin' crazies

293
00:33:56,090 --> 00:33:58,790
送他们去见他们一直念叨的上帝
and send them back to that God they kept talking about.

294
00:34:09,090 --> 00:34:10,560
我得一直走
I had to keep movin'.

295
00:34:10,590 --> 00:34:12,850
得在天黑前赶到车那里
Had to make the car before night came.

296
00:34:14,050 --> 00:34:15,780
“先生”走了
Mister was gone.

297
00:34:15,820 --> 00:34:18,050
独自一人在外面，我活不了多久
And out here alone I didn't stand a chance.

298
00:35:29,420 --> 00:35:30,640
嘘
Shh.

299
00:35:33,020 --> 00:35:35,000
外面有几个那东西？
How many of them things out there?

300
00:35:38,050 --> 00:35:39,380
一个
One.

301
00:35:39,720 --> 00:35:41,550
但是她已经走开了
But she's really pissed off.

302
00:35:41,580 --> 00:35:42,920
弄出点动静来
Make some noise.

303
00:35:44,380 --> 00:35:46,810
嗨！在这里！
Hey! In here!

304
00:35:46,850 --> 00:35:48,210
嗨！
Hey!

305
00:35:48,250 --> 00:35:49,870
嗨，嗨，嗨！
Hey, hey, hey!

306
00:35:50,750 --> 00:35:52,770
来抓我啊！
Come and get me!

307
00:35:52,810 --> 00:35:54,500
对，就是这样，来啊！
Yeah, that's right, come on!

308
00:35:55,750 --> 00:35:57,140
我在这里！
I'm in here!

309
00:35:58,280 --> 00:36:00,550
嗨，我在这里！
Hey, I'm in here!

310
00:36:00,580 --> 00:36:02,010
嗨！
Heeeey!

311
00:36:06,180 --> 00:36:08,010
加油，孩子 加油，孩子
Come on, baby, come on, baby.

312
00:36:21,710 --> 00:36:23,070
马丁
Martin.

313
00:36:24,080 --> 00:36:26,240
我恨他妈的吸血鬼
I hate fuckin' vampires.

314
00:37:11,440 --> 00:37:14,070
兄弟会需要你们的眼睛，跟随者们
 The Brotherhood needs your eyes, followers.

315
00:37:14,110 --> 00:37:16,470
在我们中间有恶人
There are evildoers among us.

316
00:37:16,500 --> 00:37:20,100
这个美国的公敌带着信仰四处走
This enemy of America walks with faith.

317
00:37:20,140 --> 00:37:23,930
他的名字叫“先生”，有一个男孩和他一起
His name is Mister and he is traveling with a young boy.

318
00:37:23,980 --> 00:37:25,730
他们随带武器，十分危险
They are armed and dangerous.

319
00:37:25,770 --> 00:37:26,260
怎么了？
What happened?

320
00:37:26,300 --> 00:37:28,830
他们一直往北，最后一次见到他们是在拉斐特山谷
 They were last seen heading north to Lafayetteville.

321
00:37:28,870 --> 00:37:32,670
如有发现，立即杀死他们
If spotted, dispatch of them immediately.

322
00:37:32,710 --> 00:37:35,430
行动者有赏
These actions will not go unrewarded.

323
00:37:55,300 --> 00:37:57,570
我们早上出发
We're gonna leave in the morning.

324
00:37:57,600 --> 00:37:58,590
我们得走小路
We'll have to take a back road.

325
00:37:58,640 --> 00:38:00,610
兄弟会把其他路都封锁了
Brotherhood got the rest locked down.

326
00:38:02,400 --> 00:38:04,060
别再想着了，孩子
Let it go, boy.

327
00:38:14,830 --> 00:38:16,030
到那里去
Get over there.

328
00:38:16,070 --> 00:38:18,260
早上精神会好点
You're gonna be crispy in the mornin'.

329
00:38:18,300 --> 00:38:19,260
来吧，威利！
Come on, Willy!

330
00:38:19,310 --> 00:38:20,760
搭把手！
Give him a hand!

331
00:38:29,960 --> 00:38:30,990
哇噢！
Whoa!

332
00:38:43,000 --> 00:38:44,930
你拿什么来换？
What have ya got for trade?

333
00:38:44,970 --> 00:38:46,490
抗生素
Antibiotics.

334
00:38:46,540 --> 00:38:47,930
一些烟叶
Some weed.

335
00:38:49,560 --> 00:38:50,930
还有这些
And these.

336
00:38:57,830 --> 00:38:59,690
该死
Goddamn.

337
00:39:00,630 --> 00:39:02,290
这个很大
That's a big one.

338
00:39:06,660 --> 00:39:07,790
这孩子要什么？
What about the boy?

339
00:39:07,830 --> 00:39:09,090
我这儿没有苏打水
I ain't got no soda pop.

340
00:39:09,130 --> 00:39:10,650
给他一个杯子
Give him another glass.

341
00:39:14,130 --> 00:39:16,590
你们看起来像是遇到麻烦了
You fellas look like you've seen some trouble.

342
00:39:16,630 --> 00:39:18,820
有一点
A little.

343
00:39:18,860 --> 00:39:19,690
吸血鬼？
Vamps?

344
00:39:19,730 --> 00:39:21,250
圣灵降临派的人
Holy rollers.

345
00:39:24,220 --> 00:39:26,950
哦，我们这里不容许宗教、政治纠纷
Yeah, well, we don't tolerate religion or politics in here.

346
00:39:26,990 --> 00:39:28,720
下一个小镇是哪里？
Where's the next lockdown?

347
00:39:28,760 --> 00:39:30,230
翻过山就是
Just over the mountains.

348
00:39:30,260 --> 00:39:31,920
不在拉斐特山谷范围
Past Lafayette Valley.

349
00:39:31,960 --> 00:39:33,110
不过那是兄弟会的地盘
But that's Brotherhood territory.

350
00:39:33,170 --> 00:39:34,990
他们对陌生人不太友好
They don't take too kindly to strangers.

351
00:39:38,260 --> 00:39:42,190
我在那里颤栗了整整一夜
# ...I'll shiver the whole night through

352
00:39:42,230 --> 00:39:46,120
她的丈夫是一个苦工
# Her husband, was a hardworking man

353
00:39:46,160 --> 00:39:49,650
就在离这里大约一里的地方
# Just about a mile from here

354
00:39:49,700 --> 00:39:50,630
谢谢
Thanks.

355
00:39:50,660 --> 00:39:53,420
那里在谈论一个狩猎者
Been talk there was a hunter about.

356
00:39:53,460 --> 00:39:55,650
他们都认为你们已经死了
Thought you was all dead by now.

357
00:39:55,690 --> 00:39:56,850
还没呢
Not yet.

358
00:39:58,560 --> 00:40:02,540
我的女孩，不要对我撒谎
# ...My girl, my girl, don't lie to me

359
00:40:02,590 --> 00:40:06,680
告诉我昨晚你在何处安眠
# Tell me where did you sleep last night.

360
00:40:06,730 --> 00:40:10,780
在松林里，那里太阳永远无法照亮
# In the pines, in the pines, where the sun never shines,

361
00:40:10,820 --> 00:40:16,420
我在那里颤栗了整整一夜
# I'd shiver the whole night through.

362
00:40:19,130 --> 00:40:20,750
谢谢
Thank you.

363
00:40:23,660 --> 00:40:25,390
我们还准备了一首
We got one more for ya.

364
00:40:25,430 --> 00:40:26,760
准备好了么，先生们？
Ready, boys?

365
00:41:01,290 --> 00:41:07,550
玛利亚，不要现在离开我，我需要你
# Maria please don't leave me now I need ya

366
00:41:09,290 --> 00:41:11,380
我是个通缉犯
# I'm a wanted

367
00:41:11,420 --> 00:41:15,470
无处可去
# There's nowhere I can go

368
00:41:18,320 --> 00:41:20,450
我不再高高在上
# My up's turned down

369
00:41:20,490 --> 00:41:24,110
我的好运气转身离去
# My luck's spun round and left me

370
00:41:26,320 --> 00:41:27,980
我看不到它…
# No I didn't see it...

371
00:42:14,680 --> 00:42:17,380
她叫贝拉
Her name was Belle.

372
00:42:17,420 --> 00:42:20,100
她的故事和其他人没什么不同
Her story was no different from anyone else's.

373
00:42:20,140 --> 00:42:21,080
家没了
Home gone.

374
00:42:21,110 --> 00:42:22,840
亲人死了
Family gone.

375
00:42:22,880 --> 00:42:25,780
哦，她怀孕了
Oh, and she was pregnant.

376
00:42:25,820 --> 00:42:28,830
不过我想生活会继续
But I guess life goes on.

377
00:42:28,880 --> 00:42:31,340
她想在孩子出生前到达新伊甸
She wanted to get to New Eden before the baby came.

378
00:46:44,230 --> 00:46:45,130
嗨
Hi.

379
00:46:49,420 --> 00:46:50,980
小鬼！ 在阁楼！
Scamp! In the attic!

380
00:47:43,980 --> 00:47:45,180
动手
Do it.

381
00:47:45,620 --> 00:47:47,020
插死她
Stake the bitch.

382
00:47:51,310 --> 00:47:51,870
插死她！
Stake the bitch!

383
00:47:51,910 --> 00:47:53,750
我放开她，她就会吃了你！
I let her go and she'll eat your ass!

384
00:47:53,780 --> 00:47:55,310
小鬼
A Scamp.

385
00:47:55,350 --> 00:47:58,470
这是“先生”对那些吸血鬼小孩的称呼
That's what Mister called the kid vamps.

386
00:47:58,520 --> 00:48:00,070
她还是个孩子
She was just a kid.

387
00:48:01,410 --> 00:48:05,350
如果不是“先生”，我可能也会和她一样
And if not for Mister, I might have become like that.

388
00:48:30,210 --> 00:48:31,740
从车里滚出来！
Out of the fuckin' car!

389
00:48:32,880 --> 00:48:34,470
从车里滚出来！
Out of the fuckin' car!

390
00:48:37,910 --> 00:48:39,340
把手放到头上
Get your hands on your head.

391
00:49:26,880 --> 00:49:28,670
射得漂亮，孩子
That's a nice shot, kid.

392
00:49:45,010 --> 00:49:46,370
该死
Fuck.

393
00:49:46,410 --> 00:49:47,710
嗨，嗨
Hey, hey.

394
00:49:49,700 --> 00:49:51,900
到底发生什么事了，伙计
What the hell happened to you, man?

395
00:49:51,940 --> 00:49:54,300
该死的兄弟会把我从一辆卡车上扔下来
Fuckin' Brotherhood dumped me out of a truck.

396
00:49:54,340 --> 00:49:56,040
做吸血鬼诱饵
For vamp bait.

397
00:49:56,080 --> 00:49:57,570
这里是他们的地盘
This is their territory.

398
00:49:57,610 --> 00:49:59,090
我们离开这儿
Let's get the fuck out of here.

399
00:50:07,410 --> 00:50:08,960
我在海军陆战队服役
I was in the Marines.

400
00:50:11,300 --> 00:50:13,530
战争一开始我就从战场被召回
Got called back from the war when it started.

401
00:50:14,440 --> 00:50:16,990
那场战争出什么问题了？
What happened with the war?

402
00:50:17,030 --> 00:50:19,300
没有人跟我们作战
No one left to fight it.

403
00:50:19,340 --> 00:50:21,200
中东不存在了
The Middle East is gone.

404
00:50:21,240 --> 00:50:22,400
成了吸血鬼的领地
Vamp land.

405
00:50:22,440 --> 00:50:24,630
你是怎么到这里的？
How did you end up here?

406
00:50:24,670 --> 00:50:28,600
我们被派去负责向加拿大撤离的工作
We were deployed to see to the evacuation to Canada.

407
00:50:28,640 --> 00:50:30,100
负责维持秩序
Keep the peace.

408
00:50:32,110 --> 00:50:33,830
但是我们没法维持
But we couldn't contain it.

409
00:50:35,470 --> 00:50:38,660
大部分士兵都走了，只想把他们的家人安顿好
Most of their troops left, tryin' to make it home to their families.

410
00:50:41,070 --> 00:50:43,330
我想你已经听说总统死了
I guess you heard the President's dead.

411
00:50:44,070 --> 00:50:46,360
现在的总统是哪个混蛋？
Which asshole's president now?

412
00:50:46,400 --> 00:50:48,060
我不知道
Beats me.

413
00:50:48,100 --> 00:50:49,500
我所知道的是
Way I see it,

414
00:50:49,540 --> 00:50:52,530
恶魔已经和我们预约，我们现在命悬一线
muthafuckas booked and left us with our dick in our hands.

415
00:51:25,000 --> 00:51:27,590
宝贝别哭
(singing) Baby don't you cry.

416
00:51:27,630 --> 00:51:29,930
爸爸保证不…
Papa's gonna make sure don't...

417
00:51:31,960 --> 00:51:32,720
请帮帮我！
Please help!

418
00:51:32,760 --> 00:51:33,730
不要！
No!

419
00:51:33,760 --> 00:51:35,060
拜托！
Please!

420
00:51:35,100 --> 00:51:36,690
我需要医生
I need a doctor.

421
00:51:36,730 --> 00:51:37,930
孩子要出来了
The baby's coming.

422
00:51:37,970 --> 00:51:39,480
你到底从哪儿来的，姑娘？
Where the hell did you come from, girl?

423
00:51:39,540 --> 00:51:43,390
我和三个男人一起赶路，但是他们帮不了我
I'm traveling with three men, but they can't help me.

424
00:51:43,430 --> 00:51:44,090
他们在哪里？
Where are they?

425
00:51:44,130 --> 00:51:45,320
就在你后面
Right behind you.

426
00:51:47,470 --> 00:51:48,950
你应该去当演员
You should have been an actress.

427
00:51:49,790 --> 00:51:50,950
他们在干什么？
What are they doing?

428
00:51:50,990 --> 00:51:53,590
他们用抓到的吸血鬼把那些封锁起来的小镇毁掉
They've been takin' out the lockdown towns with captured vamps.

429
00:51:53,630 --> 00:51:56,570
他们用卡车冲进路障 放吸血鬼出去攻击人们
They crash the trucks into roadblocks and let the vamps do their thing.

430
00:51:56,870 --> 00:51:59,190
他们一开始甚至用飞机装满吸血鬼再撞向城市
They even crached a few planes loaded up with vamps into cities at the beginning.

431
00:51:59,390 --> 00:52:01,120
华盛顿就是这样被摧毁的
That's what took down Washington.

432
00:52:34,100 --> 00:52:35,420
检查一下另一个
Check the other one.

433
00:52:39,230 --> 00:52:40,690
你好，我是克莱姆
Howdy, Clem.

434
00:52:48,490 --> 00:52:49,820
这是你孩子，克莱姆？
This your boy, Clem?

435
00:52:52,560 --> 00:52:53,710
该死！
Shit!

436
00:53:08,520 --> 00:53:10,220
那个女人在哪里？
Where's the woman?

437
00:53:11,460 --> 00:53:13,150
那婊子逃走了
Bitch run off.

438
00:53:15,960 --> 00:53:17,650
我们只是想保护她
We was just tryin' to protect her.

439
00:53:27,260 --> 00:53:28,590
快跑！
Run!

440
00:54:12,950 --> 00:54:16,470
吸血鬼从很远就能够闻到血味
Vamps could smell blood from miles off.

441
00:54:16,510 --> 00:54:18,280
“先生”知道这一点
Mister knew it.

442
00:54:18,310 --> 00:54:20,370
杰比戴亚·洛文也知道
And so did Jebedia Loven.

443
00:54:23,020 --> 00:54:24,750
我从他的眼睛里能看出来
I could tell by the look in his eye.

444
00:54:56,150 --> 00:54:58,340
我们一直往北走
We were movin' north.

445
00:54:58,380 --> 00:54:59,750
远离兄弟会
Away from The Brotherhood,

446
00:54:59,780 --> 00:55:01,610
沿着阿迪朗达克山脉
skirting the Adirondacks

447
00:55:01,650 --> 00:55:03,800
镇子越来越少，人也越来越少
Less towns, less people.

448
00:55:11,540 --> 00:55:13,630
还没碰上过吸血鬼
Hadn't seen any vamps yet.

449
00:55:13,680 --> 00:55:16,650
“先生”说这山窝里对吸血鬼来说太冷了
Mister said it was too cold for them up here in the mountains.

450
00:55:16,680 --> 00:55:18,150
不过他们本来就是冷血的
They were cold-blooded.

451
00:55:18,180 --> 00:55:20,300
和爬行动物一样
Like reptiles.

452
00:55:20,340 --> 00:55:22,400
等我们到达低地后，他们就会出现了
When we hit the lowlands, they'd be back.

453
00:55:34,980 --> 00:55:36,410
如果你接收到这个信号
 If you are receiving this signal,

454
00:55:36,450 --> 00:55:38,960
你正接近“奋斗城”边界
you are approaching the Strivington border.

455
00:55:39,010 --> 00:55:42,410
它处于美国民兵保护下
Under protection of the United States volunteer militia.

456
00:55:42,440 --> 00:55:43,740
所有寻求庇护的
All those seeking asylum

457
00:55:43,780 --> 00:55:46,440
将经过审核后作相应安排
will be processed and dealt with accordingly.

458
00:55:46,480 --> 00:55:48,460
武器要被没收
Weapons will be confiscated...

459
00:56:00,040 --> 00:56:01,230
在你离开时会归还
You get 'em back when you leave.

460
00:56:01,270 --> 00:56:02,260
呣…
Mm-hmm.

461
00:56:02,310 --> 00:56:03,170
你从哪儿来？
Where you comin' from?

462
00:56:03,210 --> 00:56:04,010
南部
South.

463
00:56:04,040 --> 00:56:05,530
拉菲特山谷
Lafayetteville.

464
00:56:05,580 --> 00:56:07,300
在兄弟会那儿遇上麻烦没？
Any trouble with The Brotherhood?

465
00:56:07,340 --> 00:56:09,030
我们没什么解决不了的
Nothin' we couldn't handle.

466
00:56:45,270 --> 00:56:48,140
他们把镇子改名叫“奋斗城”
They renamed their town Strivington.

467
00:56:48,170 --> 00:56:50,730
取得很好
Said it all.

468
00:56:50,770 --> 00:56:53,060
它让我对人有了希望
It gave me hope for people.

469
00:56:53,100 --> 00:56:55,190
对新伊甸有了希望
It gave me hope for New Eden.

470
00:56:57,200 --> 00:56:58,900
有时候希望是你唯一拥有的
Sometimes hope is all ya got.

471
00:59:47,220 --> 00:59:49,310
然后又没了，就像这样
And it was over, like that.

472
00:59:49,350 --> 00:59:50,480
这美好的一切
All that goodness.

473
00:59:50,520 --> 00:59:54,290
被一群基督教疯子给毁了，他们空投吸血鬼下来
Shattered by some Christian crazies droppin' vamps from the sky.

474
00:59:54,320 --> 00:59:56,410
我们要在这里待到天亮
We're gonna stay right here till morning.

475
00:59:56,450 --> 00:59:57,920
我觉得没问题
Fine by me.

476
01:00:09,120 --> 01:00:10,920
你怎么样，妈妈？
How you doin', mama?

477
01:00:27,350 --> 01:00:28,820
她死了
She's gone.

478
01:00:39,520 --> 01:00:41,700
不幸的老人
Tough old lady.

479
01:00:41,750 --> 01:00:44,110
就这样爬上楼梯，什么都没说
Climbed those stairs and didn't say a word.

480
01:01:31,280 --> 01:01:34,210
该死的兄弟会混蛋
Damn Brotherhood shit-kickers.

481
01:01:34,250 --> 01:01:35,710
死了十个
Ten dead.

482
01:01:38,010 --> 01:01:39,100
现在我们已经控制局面了
We've got things under control now.

483
01:01:39,140 --> 01:01:41,300
我们要提高戒备等级，时刻警戒
We'll have this place up and runnin' in no time.

484
01:01:43,280 --> 01:01:45,710
你确定不待上一阵吗？
Sure you won't stick around for a while?

485
01:01:45,750 --> 01:01:47,170
这样我们能有两个好帮手
We could use a couple good men.

486
01:01:47,210 --> 01:01:48,000
不了
No.

487
01:01:48,040 --> 01:01:49,530
我们要往北去
We're headin' north.

488
01:01:52,350 --> 01:01:54,210
一定要走小路
Stick to the back roads.

489
01:01:54,250 --> 01:01:56,230
这是从这里出去的唯一一条路
They're the only way outta here.

490
01:01:56,270 --> 01:01:58,430
其他出路都被兄弟会控制了
Brotherhood owns the rest.

491
01:01:58,470 --> 01:02:00,370
祝你好运
Good luck to you.

492
01:02:00,410 --> 01:02:01,600
谢谢
Thanks.

493
01:02:46,470 --> 01:02:48,370
我们已经走了很久了
We'd come far.

494
01:02:50,680 --> 01:02:52,930
不知道前面等待我们的是什么
We didn't know what was waitin' for us.

495
01:02:55,240 --> 01:02:57,930
但是肯定会比留在我们后面的好
But anything had to be better than what we left behind.

496
01:03:01,700 --> 01:03:04,000
至少我一直这样告诉自己
At least I kept telling myself that.

497
01:03:05,240 --> 01:03:07,900
但是当我闭上眼睛
But when I close my eyes,

498
01:03:07,940 --> 01:03:09,870
我总是看到那个小女孩僵硬的双腿
I kept seein' that little girl's dead legs

499
01:03:09,900 --> 01:03:12,160
裸露在油布外面
stickin' out from under that tarp.

500
01:03:30,670 --> 01:03:31,790
啊，该死
Ah, fuck.

501
01:03:35,970 --> 01:03:37,520
怎么了？
What is it?

502
01:03:37,560 --> 01:03:39,360
该死的散热器
Fuckin' radiator.

503
01:03:39,400 --> 01:03:40,630
你能修好吗？
Can you fix it?

504
01:03:40,670 --> 01:03:42,030
这回不行了
Not this time.

505
01:03:42,070 --> 01:03:44,260
她报废了
She's dead.

506
01:03:44,300 --> 01:03:46,590
每个人拿上自己的东西
Everybody grab your shit.

507
01:04:47,560 --> 01:04:51,050
在树林里待了一星期，我们都变样了
One week in the woods and we were becoming different people.

508
01:04:51,090 --> 01:04:53,180
简短的谈话没有了
Small talk stopped.

509
01:04:53,230 --> 01:04:56,130
我们像是一个团队，每个人有自己的分工
We worked as a pack, each to his task.

510
01:04:58,670 --> 01:05:04,560
炎热过后这里很冷，不过我们还没碰上吸血鬼
It was cold here in the hot passes, but we hadn't seen any vamps.

511
01:05:04,590 --> 01:05:08,220
森林在我们上空施了某种魔法
The forest cast a kind of magic over us.

512
01:05:08,260 --> 01:05:10,250
远离人群
Away from people.

513
01:05:12,430 --> 01:05:14,920
我不再回想过去
I stopped thinking about the past.

514
01:05:14,960 --> 01:05:17,190
回想我的家人
And about my family.

515
01:05:17,230 --> 01:05:19,150
我找到了新的家人
I had found a new one.

516
01:05:30,920 --> 01:05:32,650
你觉得我们能做到吗？
You think we'll make it?

517
01:05:33,860 --> 01:05:35,690
我担心那个女孩
I'm just worried about the girl.

518
01:05:35,730 --> 01:05:37,620
她在拖累我们的进度
She's slowin' us down.

519
01:07:25,450 --> 01:07:27,670
没风
There's no wind.

520
01:08:29,250 --> 01:08:30,500
狂暴战士
Berserkers.

521
01:08:35,840 --> 01:08:37,070
快跑！
Run!

522
01:08:53,370 --> 01:08:55,500
快点，我们要快跑
Come on! We gotta run now, let’s go.

523
01:08:55,540 --> 01:08:56,740
快走！
Move!

524
01:09:00,040 --> 01:09:01,330
她来了！
She's comin'!

525
01:09:07,380 --> 01:09:08,460
不，不，不！ 你在干什么？！
No, no, no! What are you doin'?!

526
01:09:08,500 --> 01:09:10,090
你在干什么？！ 我们得快走！
What are you doin'?! We gotta go!

527
01:09:11,040 --> 01:09:12,400
别停下！
Keep movin'!

528
01:09:13,610 --> 01:09:15,300
- 拜托，拜托，我们得快走  - 就给我一秒钟
- Please, Please. We gotta move.  - I need one second!

529
01:09:17,300 --> 01:09:18,630
姐妹？
Sister?

530
01:09:20,570 --> 01:09:22,730
我带你，我带你，再往前一点
I got you, I got you. Just a little bit further.

531
01:09:22,770 --> 01:09:23,640
快点，继续走
Come on, keep moving.

532
01:09:28,500 --> 01:09:29,830
她来了！
She's comin'!

533
01:09:34,040 --> 01:09:34,900
继续走
Keep going.

534
01:09:34,940 --> 01:09:35,920
快点，我们走吧
Come on, we gotta go.

535
01:09:35,970 --> 01:09:37,160
我们得走更快点
We gotta go faster.

536
01:09:49,670 --> 01:09:51,030
快点，你这笨蛋
Come on, you fuckers.

537
01:09:58,970 --> 01:10:00,770
上帝赐予我力量
The Lord is my strength.

538
01:10:00,800 --> 01:10:02,950
我的上帝是我的…
My Lord is my...

539
01:10:13,260 --> 01:10:14,660
天国的父
Father,

540
01:10:16,000 --> 01:10:17,430
原谅我
forgive me.

541
01:10:50,290 --> 01:10:52,890
马丁，我们走吧
Martin, let's go.

542
01:10:59,030 --> 01:11:00,990
我想她不会来了，马丁
I don't think she's coming, Martin.

543
01:11:06,430 --> 01:11:07,910
走吧
Come on.

544
01:12:42,090 --> 01:12:45,710
我们已经走了很久，还没见到过一个活人
We've been travelin' for days now and hadn't seen a soul.

545
01:12:45,760 --> 01:12:49,010
就好像人都已经消失了
It was like people had just disappeared.

546
01:12:49,050 --> 01:12:51,310
但是“先生”没有放松警惕
But Mister wasn't takin' any chances.

547
01:13:54,010 --> 01:13:56,070
有什么不对劲吗？
What's wrong?

548
01:13:56,110 --> 01:13:58,240
没什么
Nothing.

549
01:13:58,280 --> 01:14:00,150
我看来是老了，变得胆小了
I'm just getting old and scary.

550
01:14:15,350 --> 01:14:16,440
你还好吗？
You okay?

551
01:14:16,480 --> 01:14:17,780
哦，是的…
Oh, yeah...

552
01:14:19,750 --> 01:14:22,370
孩子在踢我，我没事
Baby just kicked, I'm okay.

553
01:14:22,410 --> 01:14:23,900
这里，把你的手给我
Here, give me your hand.

554
01:14:23,940 --> 01:14:25,140
- 想要感受一下吗？ - 好啊
- Wanna feel?  - Yeah.

555
01:14:27,780 --> 01:14:29,070
哦，哇噢
Oh, wow.

556
01:14:29,870 --> 01:14:31,310
让我来证实一下
Let me check that out.

557
01:14:31,340 --> 01:14:32,570
这里，把手给我，等一下
Here, give me your hand, wait.

558
01:14:34,410 --> 01:14:35,710
刚才孩子狠狠地踢了一下
That kid's got a strong kick.

559
01:14:35,750 --> 01:14:37,770
好像在说：让我出去，我要见见你们每个人
She's like, "Let me out, I wanna meet everybody."

560
01:15:20,110 --> 01:15:20,800
醒醒
Wake up.

561
01:15:20,840 --> 01:15:22,810
穿上鞋，拿好枪
Get your boots on and your guns ready.

562
01:15:24,310 --> 01:15:25,490
威利不见了
Willie's missin'.

563
01:16:21,730 --> 01:16:22,530
有东西死了
Something's dead.

564
01:16:22,570 --> 01:16:23,860
还是新鲜的
It's fresh.

565
01:16:47,340 --> 01:16:48,820
上帝！该死…
Jesus! Fuck...

566
01:16:49,830 --> 01:16:51,190
哦，该死
Oh, fuck.

567
01:16:52,000 --> 01:16:53,260
哦，该死
Oh, fuck.

568
01:16:54,830 --> 01:16:55,760
该死
Fuck.

569
01:17:03,070 --> 01:17:04,590
哦，上帝…
Oh, my God...

570
01:17:08,730 --> 01:17:09,790
快点，快点
Come on. Come on.

571
01:17:09,830 --> 01:17:11,300
- 快点，我们得走了  - 我不行了
- Come on. We have to go.  - I can't.

572
01:17:11,330 --> 01:17:12,390
快点
Come on.

573
01:17:15,530 --> 01:17:18,650
从现在开始你要准备好你的武器，寸步不离
From now on you keep your weapons close and ready.

574
01:17:18,700 --> 01:17:20,290
那东西把威利带走后杀了他
That thing took Willie away to kill him.

575
01:17:20,330 --> 01:17:22,590
他避开了我们的陷阱
He got around our traps.

576
01:17:22,630 --> 01:17:24,090
你在说什么？
What are you saying?

577
01:17:24,130 --> 01:17:26,220
这个吸血鬼会用脑思考
This one uses its brain.

578
01:17:26,260 --> 01:17:27,590
我见过很多吸血鬼
I've seen a lot of mutant vamps

579
01:17:27,630 --> 01:17:29,690
但是我从未见过会思考的吸血鬼
but I ain't never seen a thinker before.

580
01:18:18,160 --> 01:18:21,020
我们要进入低地了
We were entering the lowlands.

581
01:18:21,050 --> 01:18:23,080
新伊甸就在这山后面
New Eden was just beyond the mountains.

582
01:18:23,120 --> 01:18:24,590
我们越来越接近了
We were getting close.

583
01:18:24,620 --> 01:18:27,420
但是到目前为止，没有任何…
But so far no sign of anything...

584
01:18:27,460 --> 01:18:28,850
活物的迹象
Alive anyway.

585
01:18:40,720 --> 01:18:41,980
- 你还好吗，姑娘？ - 我…
- You okay, girl?  - I...

586
01:18:44,190 --> 01:18:45,680
我抽筋了
I have cramps.

587
01:18:47,550 --> 01:18:49,580
我的背部真的很痛
My back hurts really bad.

588
01:18:49,620 --> 01:18:50,420
我只是…
I just...

589
01:18:50,450 --> 01:18:52,720
我只是需要坐一会儿
I just need to sit for a minute.

590
01:18:52,760 --> 01:18:54,050
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

591
01:18:54,090 --> 01:18:56,010
- 我们得继续走  - 我不行了
- We gotta keep movin'.  - I can't.

592
01:18:56,060 --> 01:18:57,210
没关系
It's okay.

593
01:19:00,050 --> 01:19:01,420
我来抱你
I got you.

594
01:19:02,920 --> 01:19:04,410
你还好吗？
You okay?

595
01:19:07,950 --> 01:19:11,650
我小时候，我爸爸也这样抱过我
My daddy used to carry me like this when I was little.

596
01:19:11,690 --> 01:19:13,350
我不是你爸爸
I'm not your daddy.

597
01:19:15,720 --> 01:19:18,210
你不是个凶悍的人，你知道的
You ain't such a hard ass, you know.

598
01:19:45,010 --> 01:19:46,410
让她睡吧
Let her sleep.

599
01:19:46,450 --> 01:19:47,850
她需要睡眠
She needs it.

600
01:19:47,880 --> 01:19:50,670
白天我们要继续赶路
At daylight were gonna put some distance between us and this place.

601
01:19:54,480 --> 01:19:57,040
孩子要出生的时候我们该做些什么？
What are we gonna do when the baby comes?

602
01:20:48,410 --> 01:20:50,070
哦，该死
Oh, fuck.

603
01:20:50,110 --> 01:20:51,270
该死
Fuck.

604
01:21:04,250 --> 01:21:05,600
这边，这边离它近
This way. It's close.

605
01:21:22,310 --> 01:21:22,940
是她
That's her.

606
01:21:24,040 --> 01:21:25,200
是她
That's her.

607
01:21:26,540 --> 01:21:27,530
等等
Wait.

608
01:21:30,110 --> 01:21:31,810
它在引导我们，孩子
It's leadin' us, boy.

609
01:21:35,710 --> 01:21:36,800
去他妈的
Tough shit.

610
01:22:34,370 --> 01:22:35,770
大口喝，小子
Drink up, boy.

611
01:22:46,200 --> 01:22:48,390
我是复仇之神
I am a vengeful god.

612
01:22:48,430 --> 01:22:49,690
以眼还眼
Eye for eye.

613
01:22:49,730 --> 01:22:51,030
以牙还牙
Tooth for tooth.

614
01:22:51,070 --> 01:22:53,090
儿子还儿子
Son for son.

615
01:22:54,900 --> 01:22:57,890
这是我跟你之间的事，你这婊子养的吸血鬼
This is between me and you, you bloodsuckin' son-of-a-bitch.

616
01:23:15,260 --> 01:23:19,430
在你把我留给他们的时候，我祈祷了
When you left me for them, I prayed.

617
01:23:19,470 --> 01:23:23,190
我祈祷了，上帝听到了
I prayed and God listened.

618
01:23:24,430 --> 01:23:27,420
于是当他们来咬我之时
So when they came for me,

619
01:23:27,460 --> 01:23:29,930
那群饿鬼
the hungry ones,

620
01:23:29,970 --> 01:23:34,020
我心甘情愿地献上我的血，狩猎者
I gave my blood, willingly, hunter.

621
01:23:40,530 --> 01:23:41,890
谢谢你
Thank you.

622
01:23:44,890 --> 01:23:48,260
我现在是你的神了
I am your God now.

623
01:23:49,970 --> 01:23:51,080
呀
Yah.

624
01:23:54,930 --> 01:23:57,450
有种，小子
Nice try, child.

625
01:23:58,670 --> 01:23:59,990
尝尝这个，混蛋
Try this, you fucker.

626
01:25:44,820 --> 01:25:46,580
这回学学怎么开车
'Bout time you learn how to drive.

627
01:25:50,250 --> 01:25:51,470
差一点就到了
Almost there.

628
01:25:52,680 --> 01:25:53,910
差一点
Almost.

629
01:25:54,850 --> 01:25:56,650
‘差一点’是个很大的词
'Almost' is a big word.

630
01:26:10,080 --> 01:26:11,240
该死
Fuck.

631
01:27:09,480 --> 01:27:10,970
待在那里别动
Hold it right there!

632
01:27:14,140 --> 01:27:15,730
别动
Don't move.

633
01:27:25,910 --> 01:27:27,000
谢谢
Thank you.

634
01:27:28,240 --> 01:27:30,080
你们看起来很惨
You boys look like hell.

635
01:27:30,110 --> 01:27:31,070
碰上倒霉事了
Shit happens.

636
01:27:31,100 --> 01:27:32,870
嗯，肯定是
Yeah, sure does.

637
01:27:32,910 --> 01:27:34,570
但是就像我妈妈常说的
But like my mom used to say,

638
01:27:34,610 --> 01:27:37,600
事情就是那样，你得习惯
"Things are what they are. Get used to 'em."

639
01:27:37,640 --> 01:27:39,080
聪明的女人
Smart woman.

640
01:27:39,110 --> 01:27:41,130
这地方是她的
She owned this place.

641
01:27:41,170 --> 01:27:44,160
这里是荒野的最后一站
Last stop before the wilderness.

642
01:27:44,210 --> 01:27:46,900
埋了她之后，我就一直一个人
Buried her out back and I've been on my own ever since.

643
01:27:46,940 --> 01:27:49,300
除了他们
Except for them.

644
01:27:49,350 --> 01:27:50,890
射得漂亮
It's good shootin'.

645
01:27:50,940 --> 01:27:52,230
射了很多次了
Lots of practice.

646
01:27:52,270 --> 01:27:53,640
我要到处看看
I'm gonna take a look around.

647
01:28:02,670 --> 01:28:04,000
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?

648
01:28:05,810 --> 01:28:07,700
马丁
Martin.

649
01:28:07,740 --> 01:28:09,200
我叫佩姬
I'm Peggy.

650
01:28:13,240 --> 01:28:15,540
我很久没有见到一个男孩子了
It's been a long time since I seen a boy.

651
01:28:48,940 --> 01:28:49,920
动手吧
Come on.

652
01:28:51,970 --> 01:28:53,550
你得等到他进到那个地方
You gotta wait 'til it's in the lot.

653
01:28:55,230 --> 01:28:56,890
它怎么了？
What's wrong with it?

654
01:28:56,930 --> 01:28:59,090
他们没东西可吃了，所以他们…
They're runnin' out of food so they're...

655
01:28:59,140 --> 01:29:00,690
很瘦，还行动缓慢
skinnier but meaner.

656
01:29:03,100 --> 01:29:04,530
它闻到我们了
It smells us now.

657
01:29:11,200 --> 01:29:12,630
哦该死
Oh shit.

658
01:29:12,660 --> 01:29:14,930
又是瓦尔特
It's Walter again.

659
01:29:14,960 --> 01:29:16,090
我们一起上高中
I went to high school with him

660
01:29:16,130 --> 01:29:18,460
我总是没能一次搞定
and I haven't been able to get a clean shot.

661
01:29:18,500 --> 01:29:19,730
他完全就是个混蛋
He was such an asshole.

662
01:29:21,930 --> 01:29:23,400
我去干掉他
I'll get him.

663
01:29:24,330 --> 01:29:25,130
马丁！
Martin!

664
01:29:25,170 --> 01:29:26,600
不要，站住！
No, stop!

665
01:29:26,630 --> 01:29:28,400
快进来，你要干什么？
Get in here. What are you doing?

666
01:29:29,600 --> 01:29:30,750
马丁！
Martin!

667
01:32:53,900 --> 01:33:00,300
欢迎来到加拿大
新伊甸园

668
01:33:17,000 --> 01:33:22,000
翻译｜Lavigkaye
中英文合并调整 部份句子修改及更正
Translate by Lavigkaye

669
01:33:22,000 --> 01:33:27,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

670
01:35:15,300 --> 01:35:22,200
刑柱之地

