1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

2
00:02:17,570 --> 00:02:18,870
时间晚了，警官
It's getting late, officer.

3
00:02:56,870 --> 00:02:58,310
保安官，你得下来看看
Sheriff, you gotta get down here.

4
00:03:30,210 --> 00:03:31,670
知道她的身份吗？
We got an ID on her?

5
00:03:31,670 --> 00:03:33,110
不知道，长官
No, sir.

6
00:03:33,110 --> 00:03:34,440
和保罗跟卡洛没有亲戚关系
No relation to Paul and Carol.

7
00:03:39,450 --> 00:03:40,650
她是谁？
Who's she?

8
00:03:42,080 --> 00:03:43,720
呃，目前来说，她身份不明
Well, for now, she's a Jane Doe.

9
00:03:46,290 --> 00:03:47,590
有什么发现吗？
You got something?

10
00:03:47,590 --> 00:03:49,060
没有东西被偷
Nothing was stolen.

11
00:03:49,060 --> 00:03:50,790
房子的外面也没有任何破坏的迹象
Not a scratch on the outside of the house either.

12
00:03:52,190 --> 00:03:54,460
看起来不像有人闯入
Doesn't look like someone broke in.

13
00:03:54,460 --> 00:03:57,060
在我看来，他们好像试图冲出去
To me, it looks like they were trying to break out.

14
00:06:04,330 --> 00:06:06,330
死因呢？
Cause of death?

15
00:06:06,330 --> 00:06:09,230
今晚先略过这个部分如何？
How about we skip this part tonight?

16
00:06:09,230 --> 00:06:12,070
拜托，这个很简单好吗
Come on, this one's a soft ball.

17
00:06:14,570 --> 00:06:16,970
烟尘吸入
Smoke inhalation.

18
00:06:16,970 --> 00:06:20,740
你是说烟尘杀了豪尔先生？
You're telling me that smoke killed Mr. Howard?

19
00:06:20,740 --> 00:06:23,340
呃，鼻腔受损
Well, damaged nasal passage

20
00:06:23,350 --> 00:06:25,450
喉咙受损，肺部受损…
damaged throat, damaged lungs..

21
00:06:25,450 --> 00:06:27,050
肺部受损，没错
Damaged lungs, yes.

22
00:06:27,050 --> 00:06:29,650
但是不会致命
But incompatible with life.

23
00:06:29,650 --> 00:06:31,020
你的意思是说，这不是死因？
So, you're saying that's not the COD?

24
00:06:31,020 --> 00:06:33,620
我的意思是做结论前要先想清楚
I'm saying look before you leap.

25
00:06:36,390 --> 00:06:38,290
警方在哪里发现尸体的？
Where did the police find the body?

26
00:06:38,290 --> 00:06:40,460
呃，在他家厨房
Uh, in his kitchen.

27
00:06:40,460 --> 00:06:43,300
房子失火，前门在三十尺的距离外
House on fire. Front door is 30 feet away

28
00:06:43,300 --> 00:06:44,830
但是他并没有试图跑向前门
yet, he's not  trying to get there.

29
00:06:44,830 --> 00:06:46,800
肺部受损
Lungs are damaged

30
00:06:46,800 --> 00:06:49,400
但是气管的破坏程度并不严重
but airways not denuded nearly enough.

31
00:06:51,640 --> 00:06:52,870
所以，在火势变大之前
So, he stopped breathing

32
00:06:52,880 --> 00:06:54,510
他就已经停止呼吸了？
before that fire really got going?

33
00:06:57,010 --> 00:06:58,110
打开头盖骨
Open him up.

34
00:07:01,920 --> 00:07:03,380
现在
Now.

35
00:07:03,390 --> 00:07:04,520
你看到这里了吗？
Now you see here?

36
00:07:04,520 --> 00:07:07,350
- 在枕骨下面  - 骨折
- Down below the occipital.  - A fracture.

37
00:07:09,520 --> 00:07:11,160
这就解释了他的大脑肿胀的原因
That explains the swelling in his brain.

38
00:07:11,160 --> 00:07:13,760
硬脑膜下血肿
Subdural hematoma.

39
00:07:13,760 --> 00:07:16,700
这是致死的原因，不是烟尘
That's what did it. Not the smoke.

40
00:07:18,130 --> 00:07:20,600
每个人都有秘密
Everybody has a secret.

41
00:07:20,600 --> 00:07:23,100
只是有些人隐藏得比较好而已
Some just hide them better than others.

42
00:07:23,110 --> 00:07:26,210
有些人比较擅长把它们挖出来
Some people are better at finding them.

43
00:07:26,210 --> 00:07:28,410
你做得很好，你会成功的
You did good. You'll get there.

44
00:07:32,250 --> 00:07:35,180
到现在都没有人来领尸
Nobody's even claimed him yet.

45
00:07:35,180 --> 00:07:36,680
他独居，所以就死了
He was all alone, that's why he died.

46
00:07:36,690 --> 00:07:38,990
他会死是因为跌倒撞到头
He died because he fell and hit his head.

47
00:07:43,760 --> 00:07:46,130
你今晚有什么计划吗？
You got plans tonight?

48
00:07:46,130 --> 00:07:48,300
艾玛想去斯特兰德街看电影
Emma wants to go see a movie at the strand.

49
00:07:49,430 --> 00:07:52,270
我以为那个地方被封闭了
I thought they'd closed that place down.

50
00:07:52,270 --> 00:07:54,170
呃，没有，爸，你上次去看电影
Uh, no, when was the last time

51
00:07:54,170 --> 00:07:55,870
是什么时候的事？
you even went to go see a movie, dad?

52
00:07:58,310 --> 00:08:01,140
呃，她患了阿兹海默症
Uh, she has Alzheimer's

53
00:08:01,140 --> 00:08:04,340
他帮她盖房子
and he's building her a house.

54
00:08:05,510 --> 00:08:06,850
《手札情缘》？
The notebook?

55
00:08:06,850 --> 00:08:09,480
噢，没错，你妈妈要我和她一起去看
Oh, yeah, your mother made me go and see it with her

56
00:08:09,490 --> 00:08:11,280
庆祝她生日
for her birthday.

57
00:08:11,290 --> 00:08:12,620
进去五分钟我就睡着了
I fell asleep five minutes in.

58
00:08:16,460 --> 00:08:18,260
是喔
Yeah.

59
00:08:18,260 --> 00:08:19,730
让你收尾可以吗？
Are you alright finishing up?

60
00:08:19,730 --> 00:08:20,960
可以
Yeah.

61
00:08:24,570 --> 00:08:27,000
你是怎么了，提尔登？
What's up, tilden?

62
00:08:27,000 --> 00:08:28,940
血肿
Hematoma.

63
00:09:50,220 --> 00:09:51,550
史丹利
Stanley.

64
00:09:53,750 --> 00:09:54,960
喔
Oh.

65
00:09:58,290 --> 00:10:00,860
爸！
Hey, dad!

66
00:10:00,860 --> 00:10:02,330
史丹利又抓到一只
Stanley got another one.

67
00:10:12,340 --> 00:10:13,670
爸？
Dad?

68
00:10:57,920 --> 00:10:59,450
天啊！
Jesus Christ!

69
00:10:59,450 --> 00:11:01,390
太容易了！
It's so easy!

70
00:11:01,390 --> 00:11:02,490
你怎么下来的？
How'd you get down here?

71
00:11:02,490 --> 00:11:03,820
钥匙在电梯里
The key was in the elevator.

72
00:11:03,830 --> 00:11:06,290
噢，天啊
Oh, my god.

73
00:11:06,290 --> 00:11:09,600
我得说这里和我想像的不一样
I gotta say, this is not what I was expecting.

74
00:11:09,600 --> 00:11:12,370
你说过这里很古老，但是，哇
You said it was old but wow.

75
00:11:12,370 --> 00:11:14,670
我以为我们是在前门碰面
I thought we were supposed to meet out front.

76
00:11:14,670 --> 00:11:16,740
呃，我对于等人这件事觉得很厌烦了
Well, I got tired of waiting.

77
00:11:16,740 --> 00:11:18,640
你，你要去哪里？
Where, where are you going?

78
00:11:18,640 --> 00:11:20,570
我要参观一下
I'm having a little look.

79
00:11:20,580 --> 00:11:22,310
回来
Come back.

80
00:11:22,310 --> 00:11:24,440
天啊，这个地方一直在运作
God, the place  just keeps going.

81
00:11:24,450 --> 00:11:27,280
呃，三代的提尔登家人 一直不断地扩张
Well, three generations  of tildens keep expanding

82
00:11:27,280 --> 00:11:29,820
最后就成了这个最现代化的设施
end up with this  state-of-the-art facility.

83
00:11:29,820 --> 00:11:32,190
喂，走吧
Hey, come on.

84
00:11:32,190 --> 00:11:33,790
急什么？
What's the rush?

85
00:11:33,790 --> 00:11:35,420
我已经在这里待了一整天了
I've been down here all day.

86
00:11:38,660 --> 00:11:41,930
你看过我工作的样子， 为什么我不能看你工作的样子？
You got to see me at my job, why can't I see you at yours?

87
00:11:41,930 --> 00:11:43,360
你是在书店工作
You work at a book store.

88
00:11:57,410 --> 00:11:58,910
这里面都是人吗？
Are these all people?

89
00:11:58,910 --> 00:12:00,210
今晚只有三个
Just three tonight.

90
00:12:02,450 --> 00:12:03,550
我可以看看吗？
Can I see one?

91
00:12:03,550 --> 00:12:06,350
呃，不行，不行，你不可以看
Well, no. No. You cannot see one.

92
00:12:06,350 --> 00:12:07,390
为什么？
Why not?

93
00:12:07,390 --> 00:12:09,720
因为里面…
Because there's...

94
00:12:09,730 --> 00:12:11,930
有些东西你不能看，行吗？
some things you can't un-see, okay?

95
00:12:11,930 --> 00:12:13,390
别这样，我撑得住
Come on, I can handle it.

96
00:12:13,400 --> 00:12:16,900
不行，不行，而且我爸很严格
No. No. And my dad is way too strict.

97
00:12:16,900 --> 00:12:18,030
你可以试试看
Try me.

98
00:12:20,270 --> 00:12:22,270
所以，要看吗？
So, what'll it be?

99
00:12:24,310 --> 00:12:26,510
你是说真的？
Are you serious?

100
00:12:26,510 --> 00:12:28,040
你真的想看？
Are you?

101
00:12:28,040 --> 00:12:29,610
当然
Hell yeah.

102
00:12:29,610 --> 00:12:30,840
选一个
Pick one.

103
00:12:50,130 --> 00:12:51,660
不要那个
Not that one.

104
00:12:51,670 --> 00:12:52,730
旁边那个
The one next to it.

105
00:12:52,730 --> 00:12:55,000
尸体都一样
A body's a body.

106
00:12:55,000 --> 00:12:56,500
嗯，啊，我选那个
Yeah, well, I pick that one.

107
00:13:21,530 --> 00:13:22,630
那是做什么用的？
What's that for?

108
00:13:22,630 --> 00:13:25,170
用来确定他真的死了
To make sure he's dead.

109
00:13:25,170 --> 00:13:26,700
曾经有一段时间，很难分辨
There used to be a time it was hard to tell

110
00:13:26,700 --> 00:13:28,470
一个人是昏迷还是死亡
a comatose person from a dead one.

111
00:13:28,470 --> 00:13:31,840
所以验尸官在停尸室的每具尸体上都绑上铃铛
So coroners tied bells to everybody in the morgue.

112
00:13:31,840 --> 00:13:32,870
如果他们听见“叮”的声音
So if they heard a 'ting'

113
00:13:32,870 --> 00:13:34,470
就知道里面有某个人
they knew somebody down there

114
00:13:34,480 --> 00:13:36,310
还没有准备要离开这个世界
wasn't quite ready to go.

115
00:13:36,310 --> 00:13:37,540
那么，为什么你要绑铃铛？
So, why do you have one?

116
00:13:37,550 --> 00:13:41,110
呃，我…我有一点坚持传统
Well, I'm... I'm a bit of a traditionalist.

117
00:13:45,650 --> 00:13:46,790
为什么要把他的脸盖起来？
Why did you cover his face?

118
00:13:46,790 --> 00:13:49,590
他的脸没有剩下多少部分好盖的
There wasn't much of a face left to cover.

119
00:13:49,590 --> 00:13:52,890
近距离枪击就会造成这种结果
Point blank gun shot blast tend to do that.

120
00:13:52,890 --> 00:13:54,160
谁杀他的？
Who shot him?

121
00:13:54,160 --> 00:13:57,060
子弹角度说明他是自杀的
Angle of entry suggests he did it to himself.

122
00:13:57,070 --> 00:14:00,070
直到我们在他体内发现士的宁
Until we found strychnine in his system

123
00:14:00,070 --> 00:14:02,470
根据药品在他血液里运送的状况来看
and judging by the progress  it made  through his bloodstream

124
00:14:02,470 --> 00:14:06,440
在某人轰掉他的脸之前，他早就死了
he was already dead by the time somebody blew his face off.

125
00:14:06,440 --> 00:14:08,370
为什么会有人做这种事？
Why would anyone do that?

126
00:14:08,380 --> 00:14:10,340
你说话的样子就和你男朋友一模一样
You sound like your boyfriend.

127
00:14:11,510 --> 00:14:13,780
“为什么”的问题留给警察和精神科医师去解决
Leave the "why" to the cops and the shrinks.

128
00:14:13,780 --> 00:14:16,680
我们只负责找出死因
We're just here to find cause of death.

129
00:14:16,690 --> 00:14:18,750
仅止于此
No more, no less.

130
00:14:29,100 --> 00:14:30,860
你不会想看的
You don't wanna see that.

131
00:14:32,370 --> 00:14:33,600
没关系
It's alright.

132
00:14:55,320 --> 00:14:56,720
还说你很轻松
Look who's easy now.

133
00:14:56,730 --> 00:14:58,390
你应该看看你脸上的表情
You should have seen the look on your face.

134
00:14:58,390 --> 00:14:59,990
我迫不及待想看你今晚没人跟你上床时
I can't wait to see the look on your face

135
00:15:00,000 --> 00:15:01,090
你脸上的表情
when you're not getting laid tonight.

136
00:15:01,100 --> 00:15:02,960
噢，等等 等等
Whoa, whoa. Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.

137
00:15:02,960 --> 00:15:06,130
就算我用爆米花和酸甜糖喂你也不行？
Not even if I ply you with popcorn and sourpatch kids?

138
00:15:08,600 --> 00:15:10,100
幸好你很可爱
You're lucky you're cute.

139
00:15:12,240 --> 00:15:13,540
你怎么能够习惯那种情况？
How do you get used to that?

140
00:15:15,910 --> 00:15:17,710
你以为习惯了，但其实没有
You do and you don't.

141
00:15:20,880 --> 00:15:22,120
保安官？
Sheriff?

142
00:15:24,550 --> 00:15:26,850
- 你父亲在哪里？ - 怎么了？
- Where's your dad?  - What happened?

143
00:15:26,860 --> 00:15:28,250
把她推到后面来，谢尔敦
Bring her back here,  Sheldon.

144
00:15:33,960 --> 00:15:35,060
爸，如果你需要我留下来…
Dad, if you need me to stay...

145
00:15:35,060 --> 00:15:36,500
噢，别担心
oh, don't worry about it.

146
00:15:36,500 --> 00:15:37,830
你们去玩你们的
You two go have your fun.

147
00:15:49,540 --> 00:15:52,150
你有没有看到伯克脸上的表情？
Did you see the look on Burke's face?

148
00:15:52,150 --> 00:15:55,750
我是说，如果不重要的话，他不会 这么晚了还来这里
I mean, he wouldn't be here this late if it wasn't important.

149
00:15:55,750 --> 00:15:56,820
又来了
Here we go.

150
00:15:56,820 --> 00:15:59,090
- 呃，我爸…  - 就是这样
- Well, my dad...  - there it is.

151
00:15:59,090 --> 00:16:00,120
我不能丢下他
I can't ditch him.

152
00:16:00,120 --> 00:16:01,990
所以你又要丢下我
So you're ditching me again.

153
00:16:01,990 --> 00:16:03,720
你离开的时候，他会怎么样？
What's he gonna do when you leave?

154
00:16:07,060 --> 00:16:08,090
你还没有告诉他？
You haven't told him yet?

155
00:16:08,100 --> 00:16:10,430
没有，没那么容易
No. It's not that simple.

156
00:16:10,430 --> 00:16:11,860
哇
Wow.

157
00:16:11,870 --> 00:16:13,200
宝贝
Babe.

158
00:16:13,200 --> 00:16:15,070
我会告诉他的，好吗？
I'm gonna tell him, okay?

159
00:16:15,070 --> 00:16:17,340
你以为我想待在这里？
Hey, you think i wanna be here?

160
00:16:17,340 --> 00:16:19,070
在那下面？
Down there?

161
00:16:19,070 --> 00:16:20,440
这不是我要的生活
This isn't my life.

162
00:16:20,440 --> 00:16:23,440
我不想做奥斯丁 提尔登， 停尸间的工人
I don't wanna be Austin tilden, the morgue worker.

163
00:16:25,080 --> 00:16:28,350
只是，现在他需要我帮忙
Just, he needs my help right now.

164
00:16:29,150 --> 00:16:31,220
拜托，已经两年了
Come on, it's been two years.

165
00:16:31,220 --> 00:16:32,890
他可以照顾自己
He can take care of himself.

166
00:16:36,120 --> 00:16:37,820
几个小时以后你再来
Come back in a few hours.

167
00:16:37,830 --> 00:16:41,730
我们可以去看午夜场，到通顿喝一杯…
We'll catch the midnight show, grab a drink at Thornton's..

168
00:16:41,730 --> 00:16:43,400
两杯
Two drinks.

169
00:16:43,400 --> 00:16:46,630
十一点，我就是你的，我保证
11 o'clock, I'm all yours. I promise.

170
00:16:47,970 --> 00:16:49,370
不要，你知道，不要微笑
And don't, you know, don't smile

171
00:16:49,370 --> 00:16:50,840
因为微笑代表“好”，你知道的
because a smile means "yes" you know.

172
00:16:52,470 --> 00:16:53,640
我知道你会答应
I know it's in there.

173
00:16:53,640 --> 00:16:55,310
装不下去了吧
Now, you're gonna blow your whole game.

174
00:17:00,350 --> 00:17:01,580
也许吧
Maybe.

175
00:17:04,750 --> 00:17:05,950
你性感极了！
You're hot!

176
00:17:21,640 --> 00:17:24,570
在道格拉斯家的地下室发现的
Found her in the basement  of the Douglas' place.

177
00:17:24,570 --> 00:17:27,940
身份不明，找不到指纹记录
No ID, no fingerprints in the system.

178
00:17:27,940 --> 00:17:29,810
没有人知道她是谁
No one has a clue  who she is.

179
00:17:29,810 --> 00:17:31,940
我想你应该不知道她怎么会出现在那里吧？
I don't suppose you know  how she wound up there?

180
00:17:33,180 --> 00:17:34,450
史丹利！
Stanley.

181
00:17:36,920 --> 00:17:38,820
可恶的家伙，一天比一天凶
Damn thing gets meaner by the day.

182
00:17:41,320 --> 00:17:44,560
亚维拉兹在保罗和卡洛那里工作
Alvarez there was working at Paul and Carol's place.

183
00:17:44,560 --> 00:17:47,560
我的想法？他杀了我们的无名氏
My best bet? He killed our Jane Doe.

184
00:17:47,560 --> 00:17:49,430
他需要一个地方弃尸
Needed a place  to dump the body.

185
00:17:49,430 --> 00:17:51,300
道格拉斯家的人常常不在家
Didn't count the Douglas'  being home

186
00:17:51,300 --> 00:17:52,730
或是保罗有把点三八
or Paul having a .38.

187
00:17:52,730 --> 00:17:54,130
明天早上第一件事，我会找他来问话
First thing tomorrow, I'll bring him in

188
00:17:54,140 --> 00:17:55,470
但是现在，她是第一优先
but for now, she's the priority.

189
00:17:55,470 --> 00:17:56,770
噢，不过如果能够看一下犯罪现场
Oh, still, it would  have been nice

190
00:17:56,770 --> 00:17:58,240
还是不错的
to take a look  at the crime scene

191
00:18:05,010 --> 00:18:06,310
死了四个人
I got four people dead

192
00:18:06,310 --> 00:18:08,780
而我完全不知道他们之间有什么关系
and no god damn clue how any of it connects.

193
00:18:08,780 --> 00:18:11,950
没有人怪你，保安官
Nobody's pissin' in your grits here, shel.

194
00:18:11,950 --> 00:18:13,420
但是我们确实有程序要跑
But we do have protocol.

195
00:18:14,920 --> 00:18:17,890
早上，媒体就需要这件事的答案
Press is gonna need answers on this in the morning

196
00:18:17,890 --> 00:18:19,130
而我什么都没有
and I got nothing.

197
00:18:23,530 --> 00:18:25,470
现在他们会接受验尸官的说词
Now they'll buy a 10-79.

198
00:18:25,470 --> 00:18:28,130
我可以说是强行闯入，结果事态失控
I can give them a b and e gone haywire.

199
00:18:28,140 --> 00:18:30,800
但是关于她，我却毫无说法
But what I can't sell is her.

200
00:18:33,970 --> 00:18:36,110
有多少时间？
Time frame?

201
00:18:36,110 --> 00:18:37,880
今天晚上要搞定
It's gotta be tonight.

202
00:18:37,880 --> 00:18:38,980
好
Okay.

203
00:18:42,220 --> 00:18:43,680
你不必回来
You didn't have to come back.

204
00:18:44,920 --> 00:18:46,050
我知道
I know.

205
00:19:05,910 --> 00:19:08,740
对身份不名的女性进行验尸
This is the autopsy of an unidentified female

206
00:19:11,150 --> 00:19:13,110
验尸将由我本人
henceforth known as "Jane Doe." Performing the autopsy will be myself

207
00:19:13,110 --> 00:19:14,850
主任验尸官汤米 提尔登进行
Tommy tilden, attending coroner.

208
00:19:14,850 --> 00:19:17,580
医疗技工奥斯丁 提尔登
I will be assisted by Austin tilden

209
00:19:17,590 --> 00:19:20,390
将提供协助
certified medical technician.

210
00:19:20,390 --> 00:19:23,720
本次验尸将分为四个阶段
This autopsy will be conducted in four stages

211
00:19:23,730 --> 00:19:26,490
首先是外观评估
beginning with an external evaluation

212
00:19:26,490 --> 00:19:28,390
接着进行内部评估
followed by an internal evaluation

213
00:19:28,400 --> 00:19:30,730
针对心脏和肺脏、消化器官
of the heart and lungs, the digestive organs

214
00:19:30,730 --> 00:19:32,900
最后是大脑
and finally, the brain.

215
00:19:32,900 --> 00:19:34,300
接下来几天的天气很好
We've got some beautiful  weather here for the next few days.

216
00:19:35,700 --> 00:19:40,010
大体的年纪约二十来岁，将近三十
Subject is in her mid to late 20s.

217
00:19:40,010 --> 00:19:41,910
看起来是这样
Appears to be.

218
00:19:41,910 --> 00:19:46,150
大体的年纪约二十来岁，将近三十
Subject appears to be in her mid to late 20s.

219
00:19:46,150 --> 00:19:49,120
高加索白人，皮肤看起来正常
Caucasian. Skin appears normal.

220
00:19:49,120 --> 00:19:53,390
没有外在的流血或瘀伤
No outwards signs of bleeding or bruising.

221
00:19:53,390 --> 00:19:56,560
没有伤疤，没有明显的外在标记
No scarring, no distinctive external markings.

222
00:19:59,190 --> 00:20:01,690
头发，棕色
Hair, brown.

223
00:20:02,260 --> 00:20:03,430
眼睛…
Eyes..

224
00:20:05,830 --> 00:20:06,970
…灰色？
...grey?

225
00:20:10,800 --> 00:20:11,940
呵
Huh.

226
00:20:14,170 --> 00:20:15,640
这种眼睛只有在
You don't see clouding like that

227
00:20:15,640 --> 00:20:17,480
人死了好几天以后才会出现
unless a body's been dead  for days.

228
00:20:21,280 --> 00:20:23,820
没有绀
There's no lividity.

229
00:20:23,820 --> 00:20:25,590
也没有死后僵直
No rigor mortis either.

230
00:20:25,590 --> 00:20:27,290
你觉得她是什么时候死的？
When do you think she died?

231
00:20:27,290 --> 00:20:29,590
呃，她的体温比环境温度低
Well, she's colder than the ambient temperature.

232
00:20:29,590 --> 00:20:31,260
怎么，犯罪现埸的空调造成的？
What, conditions  at the scene?

233
00:20:31,260 --> 00:20:33,430
可能还有别的因素
Could be confounding factors.

234
00:20:33,430 --> 00:20:35,630
你看她的腰多细
Look how small her waist is.

235
00:20:35,630 --> 00:20:37,600
好像根本和她身体的其他部位不符
Like it doesn't really fit the rest of her frame.

236
00:20:37,600 --> 00:20:38,800
可能是先天性的
Could be congenital.

237
00:20:38,800 --> 00:20:40,470
没有解剖前无法确定
We won't know until we open her up.

238
00:20:40,470 --> 00:20:42,740
把它写在黑板上，待会儿再来看这件事
Mark it down on the board. We'll come back to it later.

239
00:21:11,160 --> 00:21:12,930
她的手腕和膝盖有骨折
Her wrists and ankles are fractured.

240
00:21:14,500 --> 00:21:17,000
要怎么做才能让手腕和膝盖骨折
How do you break  your wrists and ankles

241
00:21:17,010 --> 00:21:18,970
但是完全没有外显的迹象？
without any outward signs?

242
00:21:18,970 --> 00:21:21,140
噢，我经常看到这种情形
Oh, I see it all the time.

243
00:21:21,140 --> 00:21:22,340
单纯的骨折
Simple fractures.

244
00:21:22,340 --> 00:21:24,980
单纯？才不是，她的关节都碎了
Simple? Uh-uh. Her joints are shattered.

245
00:21:29,320 --> 00:21:31,680
那是什么？那是什么？灰？
What is that?  What is it? Dirt?

246
00:21:31,690 --> 00:21:34,250
不是，这个东西比较稠
No, no, this is denser.

247
00:21:34,260 --> 00:21:36,860
比较重
Heavier.

248
00:21:36,860 --> 00:21:39,360
这个是…这个是泥炭
It's... this is peat.

249
00:21:39,360 --> 00:21:42,300
很久没见过这东西了
Haven't seen this stuff in ages.

250
00:21:42,300 --> 00:21:44,130
脚趾甲底下也有
It's under her toenails,  too.

251
00:21:44,130 --> 00:21:47,630
嗯，头发里也有一些
Yeah. There are trace amounts in the hair.

252
00:21:48,700 --> 00:21:51,300
她全身都被泥炭覆盖了
She's covered in it.

253
00:21:51,310 --> 00:21:52,710
或许，她是被埋在泥炭里？
Like, maybe she was buried in it?

254
00:21:54,410 --> 00:21:55,980
在哪里才找得到泥炭啊？
Where do you even find peat?

255
00:21:55,980 --> 00:21:58,680
苗圃可以买得到
You buy it at a nursery.

256
00:21:58,680 --> 00:22:01,210
但是地里当然也有…
But naturally in the ground..

257
00:22:02,420 --> 00:22:03,750
…北方
...up north.

258
00:22:03,750 --> 00:22:05,320
这一带没有
Not around here.

259
00:22:09,720 --> 00:22:13,730
鼻腔没有发炎现象
Nasal passages, no sign of inflammation.

260
00:22:13,730 --> 00:22:16,830
没有液体和外来的物质
No fluid and no foreign substances

261
00:22:16,830 --> 00:22:19,170
耳道…
and ear canals are..

262
00:22:21,770 --> 00:22:22,970
…很干净
...clear.

263
00:22:28,380 --> 00:22:30,580
噢
Oh.

264
00:22:30,580 --> 00:22:32,480
出乎我意料之外
I hadn't expected that.

265
00:22:32,480 --> 00:22:33,580
舌头…
Tongue has been...

266
00:22:33,580 --> 00:22:35,350
被割断了
severed.

267
00:22:35,350 --> 00:22:37,550
手法很粗糙，不是用手术的方式
Crudely. Non surgically.

268
00:22:37,550 --> 00:22:38,820
呃，可能是她自己咬断的
Well, she could have bitten it off, you know

269
00:22:38,820 --> 00:22:40,550
她吃了什么过量的药，发生痉挛…
she ods on something, tensed up...

270
00:22:40,560 --> 00:22:42,520
这些不是咬痕
these aren't bite marks.

271
00:22:42,520 --> 00:22:46,130
你看，条纹，蛤？
See, striations. Huh?

272
00:22:52,270 --> 00:22:54,870
我以前见过这种情形
I've seen something like this before

273
00:22:54,870 --> 00:22:57,670
大约十五年前
about 15 years back.

274
00:22:57,670 --> 00:23:00,610
诺福克附近的人口走私
Human trafficking around Norfolk.

275
00:23:01,540 --> 00:23:03,340
两个女孩
Two girls

276
00:23:03,340 --> 00:23:06,110
手和脚
hands and feet

277
00:23:06,110 --> 00:23:08,810
被绑得紧紧的
bound tight

278
00:23:08,820 --> 00:23:10,820
防止她们逃走
to keep them from running.

279
00:23:10,820 --> 00:23:12,990
她们的舌头被割掉
Cut out their tongues

280
00:23:12,990 --> 00:23:14,350
因为弄出太多声音…
for making too much noise...

281
00:23:14,360 --> 00:23:17,820
你觉得这跟卖淫有关？
you think this was some kind of a prostitution thing?

282
00:23:17,830 --> 00:23:19,590
不能排除
Can't rule it out.

283
00:24:04,370 --> 00:24:08,010
这里，她的左下侧少了一颗臼齿
Here, she has a molar missing on the lower left side.

284
00:24:08,810 --> 00:24:10,510
取些牙模
Take some impressions.

285
00:24:33,270 --> 00:24:36,240
这一定是某种纤维
It's definitely some kind of fabric.

286
00:24:36,240 --> 00:24:39,270
装起来，送去化验
Bag it. Send it to the lab.

287
00:25:01,230 --> 00:25:04,760
外部没有精液
No external seminal fluid present.

288
00:25:04,770 --> 00:25:06,330
给我一根棉花棒
Give me a swab.

289
00:25:35,960 --> 00:25:39,530
啊，她里面都被撕裂了
Ah, she's torn up inside.

290
00:25:39,530 --> 00:25:43,340
肌肉组织里有裂痕
There are ridges,  grooves in the tissue.

291
00:25:43,970 --> 00:25:45,100
擦伤？
Abrasions?

292
00:25:45,110 --> 00:25:47,410
不，是割伤
No. Cuts.

293
00:25:48,310 --> 00:25:50,180
人为的
Deliberate.

294
00:25:55,950 --> 00:25:58,520
舌头被割断，关节粉碎
Severed tongue,  shattered joints

295
00:25:58,520 --> 00:26:00,890
阴道创伤…
vaginal trauma..

296
00:26:00,890 --> 00:26:03,090
之前的理论说得通
The theory tracks.

297
00:26:03,090 --> 00:26:05,060
外部检查差不多了
We're barely out of the external.

298
00:26:06,130 --> 00:26:07,690
还有很多事要做
We got a ways to go.

299
00:26:18,100 --> 00:26:21,210
现在我们要继续进行内部的检验
We'll now proceed with the internal examination

300
00:26:21,210 --> 00:26:23,640
首先是心脏和肺脏
starting with the heart and lungs.

301
00:26:24,780 --> 00:26:26,180
帮忙把她的头垫起来
Help me with the block.

302
00:27:38,750 --> 00:27:42,020
不应该会这样流血，对吧？
They're not supposed to bleed like that. Right?

303
00:27:45,290 --> 00:27:47,490
我见过这种情况
I've seen it.

304
00:27:47,500 --> 00:27:50,060
但是只有刚死的人才会这样
But only on a fresh corpse.

305
00:27:50,060 --> 00:27:51,730
刚死一个钟头，也许两个钟头
An hour dead, maybe two.

306
00:27:51,730 --> 00:27:54,700
压力累积的关系
It's caused by a build up of pressure.

307
00:28:10,680 --> 00:28:12,020
那是什么？
What is that?

308
00:28:12,020 --> 00:28:14,020
也许是黑素瘤？
Melanoma maybe?

309
00:28:15,490 --> 00:28:17,620
长在里面？
On the inside?

310
00:28:17,630 --> 00:28:19,320
有可能
Possible.

311
00:28:19,330 --> 00:28:21,590
看看实验室会给我们什么答案
Let's see what the lab comes back with.

312
00:28:31,970 --> 00:28:33,740
可以把断肋器拿给我吗？
Can you hand me  the rib cutters?

313
00:28:42,920 --> 00:28:44,280
今天可以吗？
Today?

314
00:29:00,100 --> 00:29:01,370
靠
Shit.

315
00:29:05,840 --> 00:29:07,040
你做了什么事？
What did you do?

316
00:29:07,040 --> 00:29:09,010
噢，我来处理
Oh, I got it.

317
00:29:09,010 --> 00:29:10,740
我需要你专注在这里
I need you to focus here.

318
00:29:11,750 --> 00:29:13,610
知道了
I got it.

319
00:29:17,120 --> 00:29:19,790
呃，你说得没错
Well, you were right.

320
00:29:20,920 --> 00:29:23,490
她的腰和她的体型不符
Her waist doesn't fit her frame.

321
00:29:23,490 --> 00:29:24,720
不是天生的
It's not congenital.

322
00:29:24,730 --> 00:29:25,990
那是什么造成的？
Then what is it?

323
00:29:25,990 --> 00:29:30,400
呃，如果穿着紧身衣的时间够长…
Well, if you wear one long enough, a corset...

324
00:29:30,400 --> 00:29:33,600
那不是几百年前就不流行了吗？
didn't those go out of style a couple of hundred years ago?

325
00:29:56,320 --> 00:29:57,920
肺脏
The lungs

326
00:29:57,930 --> 00:30:00,660
严重黑化
severely blackened.

327
00:30:00,660 --> 00:30:03,600
没想到她是个烟枪
Wouldn't have taken her for a smoker.

328
00:30:03,600 --> 00:30:05,160
就算她一天
She could smoke

329
00:30:05,170 --> 00:30:08,400
抽十包烟，连抽三十年
ten packs a day for 30 years

330
00:30:08,400 --> 00:30:09,840
也无法解释这个现象
wouldn't explain this.

331
00:30:12,140 --> 00:30:13,710
但这就是她的死因，是吧？
But that's what killed her, right?

332
00:30:13,710 --> 00:30:16,710
不是，不过看到这种程度的肺部破坏
No, this amount of lung damage though

333
00:30:16,710 --> 00:30:21,610
我会预期身体上到处都是三级烧伤
I'd expect the body to be covered in third degree burns.

334
00:30:21,620 --> 00:30:24,580
这就像发现一颗…在大脑里发现一颗子弹
It's like finding a... a bullet in the brain

335
00:30:26,090 --> 00:30:27,920
但是没有枪伤
but with no gunshot wound.

336
00:30:36,730 --> 00:30:39,060
她的心脏上有伤痕
Her heart's marked up.

337
00:30:39,070 --> 00:30:41,130
几乎就像是被割过
Almost like it's been cut.

338
00:30:44,540 --> 00:30:47,070
呃，不只是她的心脏
Well, not just her heart.

339
00:30:47,070 --> 00:30:50,180
你觉得那是什么东西？基因缺陷？
What do you think that is?  Genetic defect?

340
00:30:50,180 --> 00:30:51,840
也许是瘢痕组织
Probably scar tissue.

341
00:30:51,850 --> 00:30:54,380
瘢痕组织？
Scar tissue?

342
00:30:54,380 --> 00:30:55,780
什么原因造成的？
From what?

343
00:30:58,180 --> 00:31:00,520
想像一下，这些内部创伤
Imagine all this internal trauma

344
00:31:00,520 --> 00:31:03,420
全部呈现在体外
was reflected externally.

345
00:31:03,420 --> 00:31:05,620
粉碎的膝盖和手腕
Shattered ankles and wrists

346
00:31:05,630 --> 00:31:09,060
被火烧伤的肺部，有伤痕的器官
fire-burned lungs,  scarred organs.

347
00:31:09,060 --> 00:31:10,630
她看起来会是什么样子？
What would she look like?

348
00:31:10,630 --> 00:31:13,270
血肉模糊
She'd be mangled.

349
00:31:13,270 --> 00:31:16,070
被破坏到完全无法辨识
Disfigured beyond recognition

350
00:31:16,070 --> 00:31:18,000
但她没有
but she's not.

351
00:31:19,510 --> 00:31:22,270
我是说，到底要怎样才能做到这个样子？
I mean, how the hell do you even do this?

352
00:31:29,220 --> 00:31:31,380
如果你想杀一个人，开枪杀他
If you wanna kill someone you shoot them

353
00:31:31,390 --> 00:31:34,220
或是下毒，或是淹死他
or poison them or drown them.

354
00:31:34,220 --> 00:31:35,950
几百万种简单的方法
A million easy ways.

355
00:31:35,960 --> 00:31:38,220
你不会这么费力
You don't go to these lengths

356
00:31:38,230 --> 00:31:41,830
除非你想让他多受痛苦
unless you wanna make them suffer

357
00:31:49,270 --> 00:31:50,300
搞什…
what the...

358
00:31:50,300 --> 00:31:51,740
我去看看
I'll get it.

359
00:32:24,040 --> 00:32:25,770
这么干净
So clean.

360
00:33:08,720 --> 00:33:10,320
你到底发生了什么事？
What happened to you?

361
00:34:55,390 --> 00:34:57,320
到底怎么了？
What the hell happened?

362
00:34:57,320 --> 00:34:58,760
你没事吧？
Are you okay?

363
00:34:58,760 --> 00:35:00,660
有东西在通风管里
Something's in the vent.

364
00:35:05,670 --> 00:35:07,000
谢谢
Thanks.

365
00:35:13,340 --> 00:35:14,770
噢，该死
Oh, shit.

366
00:36:48,130 --> 00:36:49,600
给我一分钟
Give me a minute.

367
00:37:38,850 --> 00:37:40,250
你在做什么？
What are you doing?

368
00:37:41,790 --> 00:37:44,390
冰柜
The drawer..

369
00:37:44,390 --> 00:37:46,490
一定是没关好
Must have not closed it all the way.

370
00:37:55,330 --> 00:37:58,170
史丹利实在很烦
Stanley was a pain in the ass.

371
00:37:58,170 --> 00:38:00,270
但他是你妈妈的猫
But he was your mother's.

372
00:38:00,270 --> 00:38:02,670
少数我仅有的关于她的东西之一
One of the few things  of hers I had left.

373
00:38:04,510 --> 00:38:06,080
嗯，我也想念她
Yeah, I miss her, too.

374
00:38:06,080 --> 00:38:08,380
是啊， 我们继续吧
Right. Let's keep going.

375
00:38:11,750 --> 00:38:15,350
这是无名女尸的验尸第三阶段
This is stage three  of the autopsy of Jane Doe.

376
00:38:16,160 --> 00:38:17,690
从胃部开始
Beginning with the stomach

377
00:38:17,690 --> 00:38:20,030
以及肠胃系统
and the gastro-intestinal system.

378
00:38:25,130 --> 00:38:28,870
爸，你可以跟我聊
Dad, you can talk to me.

379
00:38:28,870 --> 00:38:31,670
我没有对你隐瞒什么
I'm not keeping anything from you.

380
00:38:31,670 --> 00:38:35,270
你只是…你在别人面前做出这个样子…
You just... you put up this act for people...

381
00:38:36,680 --> 00:38:38,240
我没事
I'm fine.

382
00:38:41,510 --> 00:38:42,980
好吧
Alright.

383
00:38:55,130 --> 00:38:56,560
那是什么？
What is that?

384
00:38:58,330 --> 00:39:00,200
一朵花？
A flower?

385
00:39:18,250 --> 00:39:21,620
紫曼陀罗，麻痹药
Jimson weed. Paralyzing agent.

386
00:39:21,620 --> 00:39:24,420
或许可以解释她的器官发炎现象
Probably explains the inflammation on her organs.

387
00:39:25,690 --> 00:39:28,360
噢，有一件奇怪的事
Hmm. Here's a weird thing.

388
00:39:38,070 --> 00:39:39,640
这样可以肯定她来自北方
That settles it. She's from up north.

389
00:39:41,270 --> 00:39:43,140
是啊，但她是怎么出现在这里的？
Yeah, but how did she end up here?

390
00:39:43,140 --> 00:39:44,910
一个一个来
One thing at a time.

391
00:39:44,910 --> 00:39:47,050
我只是想弄清楚这一切
I'm just trying to make sense of all this.

392
00:39:51,590 --> 00:39:54,920
现在阵风风速最高达每小时六十哩
Gusts are now being reported  at up to 60 miles per hour.

393
00:39:54,920 --> 00:39:57,990
预计雨量会在一小时内达到三寸
Rain is expected to top  three inches within the hour.

394
00:39:57,990 --> 00:40:01,390
这场雨可能会大得令人不可置信
This one might be  a bigger deal  than we were led to believe.

395
00:40:01,400 --> 00:40:05,760
爸，我们明天早上再完成后续的事如何？
Dad, how about we just finish this in the morning?

396
00:40:07,470 --> 00:40:10,030
伯克今晚就要知道死因
Burke needs a COD tonight.

397
00:40:10,040 --> 00:40:12,940
我们还是一点头绪也没有
We're not even close.

398
00:40:12,940 --> 00:40:15,810
只要开始了，就要做完它
When we start something, we finish it.

399
00:40:17,440 --> 00:40:19,680
如果你想走…
You wanna leave..

400
00:40:19,680 --> 00:40:20,910
…就走
...leave.

401
00:41:12,630 --> 00:41:15,700
看起来像是某种寿衣
It looks like  some kind of shroud.

402
00:41:15,700 --> 00:41:18,940
噢，而且很古老
Hmm. And old.

403
00:41:18,940 --> 00:41:20,870
胃酸早该溶解这东西了
Stomach acids should have dissolved this thing.

404
00:41:20,870 --> 00:41:25,010
我是说它还能保持完整，颇令人惊讶
I mean, the fact that it's intact at all is amazing.

405
00:41:27,610 --> 00:41:30,280
你看那是什么东西？
Now see, what is that?

406
00:41:30,280 --> 00:41:31,820
罗马数字？
Roman numerals?

407
00:41:51,100 --> 00:41:52,800
好
Okay.

408
00:41:52,810 --> 00:41:55,670
这个数字
These numerals.

409
00:41:55,680 --> 00:41:59,340
顺序，T，还有…这个S
The order. T and... and this s.

410
00:41:59,350 --> 00:42:00,610
搭不起来
It doesn't fit.

411
00:42:03,950 --> 00:42:05,680
你想做什么？
What are you doing?

412
00:42:25,240 --> 00:42:27,210
有人把她的牙齿拔出来
Someone pulled out her tooth

413
00:42:27,210 --> 00:42:28,510
把它包在布里，再强迫她
wrapped it in fabric and forced her

414
00:42:28,510 --> 00:42:29,670
吞下去
to swallow it.

415
00:42:31,110 --> 00:42:32,380
那画呢？
And the drawing?

416
00:42:32,380 --> 00:42:33,380
我不知道，跟宗教有关？
I don't know. Religious?

417
00:42:33,380 --> 00:42:35,850
也许是某种仪式？
Possibly, uh, ritualistic?

418
00:42:35,850 --> 00:42:38,780
嗯，我们来弄清楚这一点
Well, let's play that one out.

419
00:42:38,790 --> 00:42:40,990
每种仪式都有它的目的
Every ritual has its purpose.

420
00:42:40,990 --> 00:42:43,690
到目前为止，我们看到哪些手法？
What mo have we seen so far?

421
00:42:43,690 --> 00:42:45,960
首先，他们把她绑起来
First they bound her.

422
00:42:45,960 --> 00:42:49,390
然后割掉她的舌头，对她下毒
Then they ripped out  her tongue, poisoned her

423
00:42:49,400 --> 00:42:52,730
麻痹她，强迫她吞下那块布
paralyzed her forced her  to swallow the cloth.

424
00:42:52,730 --> 00:42:59,170
然后，呃，割伤，体内的伤害，刺伤
Then, uh, the cuts, the  internal mutilation, stabs.

425
00:42:59,170 --> 00:43:02,810
接下来，好像这样还不够，他们还烧了她
Then as if that wasn't enough, they burned her.

426
00:43:07,680 --> 00:43:09,810
几乎就像是用人当祭品
Almost like a human sacrifice

427
00:43:11,320 --> 00:43:13,520
我必须告诉大家全国各地的气象观测站
I got to tell you we have  serious weather reports

428
00:43:13,520 --> 00:43:16,320
都传来很严重的气象报告
coming in from all  the monitoring stations  across the state.

429
00:43:16,320 --> 00:43:18,620
现在已经发布洪水警报
We've got  a flash flood warning  now in full effect

430
00:43:18,630 --> 00:43:20,290
全格兰山郡都在影响范围内
for all of grantham county.

431
00:43:22,800 --> 00:43:25,000
当局很担心…
They've got concerns about..

432
00:43:25,970 --> 00:43:27,630
没有办法用这个方式杀死一个人
You can't kill someone this way

433
00:43:27,630 --> 00:43:30,170
却没有在身体表面留下任何痕迹
without leaving a trace on the outside.

434
00:43:30,170 --> 00:43:33,200
她甚至连指甲都没有断裂
She doesn't even have a broken nail.

435
00:43:33,210 --> 00:43:35,840
如果我们能够知道她为何受到凌虐…
If we could just find out why she was tortured...

436
00:43:35,840 --> 00:43:38,110
这下面，如果你看不到的话
down here, if you can't see it

437
00:43:38,110 --> 00:43:41,050
摸摸看，没关系
touch it, it doesn't matter.

438
00:43:41,050 --> 00:43:45,120
爸，这些尸体不只是一个个的死因
Now, these bodies are not just cods, dad.

439
00:43:45,120 --> 00:43:47,250
她发生这种事一定有原因
This happened to her for a reason.

440
00:43:47,250 --> 00:43:48,820
相信我，我可以告诉你
Trust me when I tell you

441
00:43:48,820 --> 00:43:51,660
你绝对不会想被困在这样的暴风雨里
this is not a storm you  wanna get caught in, folks.

442
00:43:53,390 --> 00:43:54,790
如果你在家，就留在家里
If you're home, stay home.

443
00:43:56,730 --> 00:43:58,360
有一件事可以确定
One thing's for sure.

444
00:43:58,370 --> 00:43:59,830
你哪里都去不成
You're not going anywhere.

445
00:44:14,850 --> 00:44:16,010
嘿，爸？
Hey, dad?

446
00:44:19,690 --> 00:44:22,550
我觉得或许我们应该离开这里
I think maybe we should get out of here.

447
00:44:40,510 --> 00:44:42,940
帮我一下
Help me with this.

448
00:45:04,530 --> 00:45:05,760
靠
Holy shit.

449
00:45:41,940 --> 00:45:43,230
是怎样？
What the fuck?

450
00:45:47,610 --> 00:45:49,940
爸？爸？
Dad? Dad?

451
00:45:49,940 --> 00:45:51,240
我在这里！
Here!

452
00:46:06,630 --> 00:46:08,630
我们离开这里
Let's get the fuck out of here.

453
00:46:19,840 --> 00:46:22,170
走，走
Come on, come on.

454
00:46:31,120 --> 00:46:32,450
发电机
The generator.

455
00:46:38,920 --> 00:46:40,590
电力不够
There's not enough power.

456
00:46:54,040 --> 00:46:56,070
卡住了
It's stuck.

457
00:46:56,080 --> 00:46:59,480
帮我一下，帮我一下！
Help me with this.  Help me with this!

458
00:47:04,420 --> 00:47:05,850
那棵老梧桐树倒了
The old sycamore fell.

459
00:47:12,930 --> 00:47:14,890
干！
Fuck!

460
00:47:14,890 --> 00:47:17,230
办公室，用市内电话
The office. The landline.

461
00:47:50,330 --> 00:47:52,730
- 那到底是什么东西？ - 不知道
- What the hell was that?  - I don't know.

462
00:47:55,170 --> 00:47:56,670
噢，感谢老天
Oh, thank god.

463
00:47:59,340 --> 00:48:01,310
哈丁郡警局
Harding county  Sheriff Department.

464
00:48:01,310 --> 00:48:04,040
我是汤米 提尔登，紧急事故，我们需要帮助
This is Tommy tilden. It's an emergency. We need help.

465
00:48:04,040 --> 00:48:05,440
抱歉，我听不清楚…
Sorry, I've trouble  hearing...

466
00:48:05,450 --> 00:48:06,940
叫柏克听电话
put Burke on the line.

467
00:48:10,550 --> 00:48:11,950
我是柏克
This is Burke.

468
00:48:11,950 --> 00:48:15,350
柏克，我是汤米，你最好立刻过来
Sheldon, this is Tommy. You better get over here now.

469
00:48:15,360 --> 00:48:18,220
喂？汤米，我几乎听不到你的声音，断断续续的
Hello? Tommy, I can  scarcely hear you.  Your voice is breaking up.

470
00:48:18,220 --> 00:48:21,490
柏克！柏克！我们被困在下面了，该死…
Sheldon! Sheldon, we're trapped down here, godda..

471
00:48:21,490 --> 00:48:23,160
- 柏克，请你…  - 汤米
- Sheldon, please...  - Tommy.

472
00:50:02,590 --> 00:50:04,100
到底是怎么回事？
What the fuck is going on?

473
00:50:06,470 --> 00:50:07,800
是她
It's her.

474
00:50:09,530 --> 00:50:12,340
在柏克送她过来之前，一切都很好
Everything was fine until Burke wheeled her through that door.

475
00:50:12,340 --> 00:50:15,410
- 孩子…  - 从我们割开她的时候开始
- Son...  - until we cut into her.

476
00:50:15,410 --> 00:50:17,910
你说的是一具尸体
You're talking about a corpse.

477
00:50:30,720 --> 00:50:33,420
我们在她身体里发现的东西
These things we found inside her

478
00:50:33,430 --> 00:50:36,730
她的伤势，那些伤痕
her injuries, those marks.

479
00:50:36,730 --> 00:50:38,630
你没办法说她只是一具尸体
You can't say she's just a body.

480
00:50:57,450 --> 00:51:00,650
我们早该离开的
We should have left.

481
00:51:00,650 --> 00:51:02,050
我曾经想要离开
I wanted to leave.

482
00:51:11,360 --> 00:51:12,530
爸！
Dad!

483
00:51:18,940 --> 00:51:20,600
噢
Oh.

484
00:51:20,610 --> 00:51:22,410
不！
No!

485
00:51:22,410 --> 00:51:24,540
爸！爸！
Dad! Dad!

486
00:51:34,850 --> 00:51:36,090
爸！？
Dad?

487
00:51:36,090 --> 00:51:38,390
噢，靠，噢…
Oh, shit. Oh..

488
00:51:50,570 --> 00:51:51,900
噢，天啊
Oh, my god.

489
00:51:52,700 --> 00:51:54,040
噢，天啊
Oh, my god.

490
00:51:54,810 --> 00:51:56,870
小心，小心
Careful, careful.

491
00:51:58,280 --> 00:52:01,250
天啊！噢
Oh, god! Ohh.

492
00:52:01,250 --> 00:52:02,910
- 扶我起来  - 好
- Help me up.  - Yeah.

493
00:52:06,720 --> 00:52:08,050
我没事
I'm fine.

494
00:52:10,260 --> 00:52:11,760
本来是灰色的
They were grey.

495
00:52:14,130 --> 00:52:15,630
她的眼睛
Her eyes.

496
00:52:16,960 --> 00:52:18,630
那东西的眼睛是她的
It had her eyes.

497
00:52:19,970 --> 00:52:22,900
那就是我一直试着告诉你的事
That's what I've been trying to tell you.

498
00:52:22,900 --> 00:52:24,070
是她
It's her.

499
00:52:25,200 --> 00:52:27,000
噢，不，不可能
Oh, no, that's not possible.

500
00:52:27,010 --> 00:52:28,840
不，她的身体
No, her body

501
00:52:28,840 --> 00:52:32,010
我们在她身体里发现的东西， 那些都是不可能发生的
those things we found inside, those were impossible.

502
00:52:34,210 --> 00:52:37,780
不管这里发生了什么事…
Whatever the hell happened in here..

503
00:52:37,780 --> 00:52:40,450
…都已经超越了可能的范围
...we are way past possible.

504
00:52:42,050 --> 00:52:43,390
是她
It's her.

505
00:52:46,730 --> 00:52:50,230
那么我们要怎么办？
So, what do we do?

506
00:54:04,370 --> 00:54:05,700
快速腐败
Rapid decomp.

507
00:54:05,710 --> 00:54:08,040
我们从她身体里拿出来的所有东西
Everything we took out of her.

508
00:54:10,540 --> 00:54:13,640
好像她的身体在保存它们一样
That's almost like her body was preserving it.

509
00:54:13,650 --> 00:54:15,650
必须把她弄到焚化炉去
Must get her to the crematorium.

510
00:55:26,690 --> 00:55:27,850
靠
Fuck it.

511
00:55:58,980 --> 00:56:00,150
天啊！
Jesus!

512
00:56:04,390 --> 00:56:06,120
灭火器，在你后面
Behind you, the extinguisher.

513
00:56:08,460 --> 00:56:10,130
插梢，拉开插梢
The pin. Pull the pin.

514
00:56:37,290 --> 00:56:38,560
不可能
No.

515
00:56:48,930 --> 00:56:50,270
电梯
The elevator.

516
00:57:21,600 --> 00:57:22,930
走
Come on.

517
00:57:27,570 --> 00:57:29,240
不，不，不！干！
No, no, no, no! Fuck!

518
00:58:06,380 --> 00:58:09,710
快，快，快
Come on. Come on. Come on.

519
00:58:11,450 --> 00:58:12,780
快啊！
Come on!

520
00:58:42,210 --> 00:58:43,710
走啊，爸，快
Go, dad. Come on.

521
00:58:49,320 --> 00:58:50,320
拜托
Come on.

522
00:59:31,100 --> 00:59:32,600
艾玛
Emma.

523
00:59:32,600 --> 00:59:34,060
噢，不！
Oh, no!

524
00:59:34,070 --> 00:59:36,130
噢，不，不！
Oh, no, no!

525
00:59:36,140 --> 00:59:38,140
噢，天啊！
Oh, my god!

526
00:59:39,440 --> 00:59:41,940
噢，不！不！
Oh, no! No!

527
00:59:44,340 --> 00:59:45,510
不！
No!

528
00:59:46,280 --> 00:59:48,210
噢，天啊
Oh, my god.

529
00:59:48,210 --> 00:59:50,210
不！
No!

530
00:59:58,690 --> 01:00:03,030
- 噢，不，不，不！ - 奥斯丁
- Oh, no, no, no!  - Austin..

531
01:00:17,310 --> 01:00:18,880
奥斯丁，电梯
Austin, the elevator.

532
01:00:18,880 --> 01:00:20,880
走吧，走吧
Come on, now. Come on.

533
01:00:25,320 --> 01:00:26,820
走吧，儿子
Come on, son.

534
01:00:48,210 --> 01:00:49,540
干！
Fuck!

535
01:00:52,940 --> 01:00:54,110
干！
Fuck!

536
01:01:09,760 --> 01:01:11,930
我叫她回来找我
I told her to come back for me.

537
01:01:13,230 --> 01:01:15,230
我叫她回来的
I told her to come back.

538
01:01:16,530 --> 01:01:18,370
不，这不是你的错
No, you didn't do this.

539
01:01:20,910 --> 01:01:23,610
你根本不应该在这里
You shouldn't be here.

540
01:01:23,610 --> 01:01:27,510
一切都是我的错
All this is my fault.

541
01:01:27,510 --> 01:01:30,610
- 你不可能知道会发生这种事  - 是啊
- You couldn't have known.  - Yeah.

542
01:01:30,620 --> 01:01:33,520
是啊，每个人都这么跟我说…
Yeah, that's what everyone told me..

543
01:01:33,520 --> 01:01:35,020
…关于你妈妈的事
...about your mom.

544
01:01:40,690 --> 01:01:43,030
你知道我为什么总是叫她光线吗？
You know why i used to call her ray?

545
01:01:45,800 --> 01:01:47,460
意思是阳光的光线
Ray of sunshine.

546
01:01:49,900 --> 01:01:51,600
她觉得那种叫法太土了
She thought it was corny  as shit.

547
01:01:52,840 --> 01:01:54,340
但是很特别
But it stuck.

548
01:01:58,140 --> 01:01:59,540
如果我早知道的话，我早就帮她了
If I'd have known,  I would have helped her.

549
01:01:59,550 --> 01:02:01,180
你知道的，对不对？
You know that, don't you?

550
01:02:03,110 --> 01:02:05,350
我是说，她总是这么阳光
I mean, she was always so bright.

551
01:02:06,350 --> 01:02:07,680
这么开心
So happy.

552
01:02:08,720 --> 01:02:11,890
想到她一直忍受那种痛苦
To think she was carrying around all that

553
01:02:11,890 --> 01:02:15,590
每天忍受那种不快乐
pain, all that unhappiness every day.

554
01:02:15,590 --> 01:02:17,460
我早该发现的
I should've seen it.

555
01:02:17,460 --> 01:02:18,960
但是我没有
But I didn't.

556
01:02:21,170 --> 01:02:23,670
她不得不自己去面对
She had to deal with it alone.

557
01:02:26,840 --> 01:02:28,740
这一切的错误…
All these mistakes..

558
01:02:30,110 --> 01:02:32,110
…我的错误…
...my mistakes..

559
01:02:35,750 --> 01:02:37,750
…而你却得为它们付出代价
...and you had to pay for them.

560
01:03:10,650 --> 01:03:12,780
为什么她还不杀死我们？
Why hasn't she killed us yet?

561
01:03:12,790 --> 01:03:15,850
呃，显然不是想试一试
Well, it's not for want of trying.

562
01:03:15,850 --> 01:03:17,850
看看她有什么能耐…
Well, look what she can do..

563
01:03:19,660 --> 01:03:21,490
…如果她想要我们死的话
...if she wanted us dead.

564
01:03:26,560 --> 01:03:29,330
当我们解剖她的时候…
When we cut into her..

565
01:03:29,330 --> 01:03:32,140
…每次她都试图阻止我们
...she tried to stop us  each time.

566
01:03:32,140 --> 01:03:35,810
好像有什么东西她不想让我们发现
It's like there's something she doesn't want us to find.

567
01:03:50,220 --> 01:03:51,860
你想回去那里？
You wanna go back in there?

568
01:03:51,860 --> 01:03:56,190
如果我们留在这里，就死定了
If we stay here, we're dead.

569
01:03:56,200 --> 01:03:58,660
如果我们能够弄清楚她是怎么死的…
If we could just figure out how she died..

570
01:04:00,970 --> 01:04:05,170
…或许我们可以知道该如何阻止她
...maybe we can figure out how to stop her.

571
01:05:16,670 --> 01:05:18,510
- 爸？ - 我在你后面
- Dad?  - Right behind you.

572
01:05:20,140 --> 01:05:21,980
继续走
Keep moving.

573
01:05:28,490 --> 01:05:29,990
奥斯丁？
Austin?

574
01:05:33,290 --> 01:05:35,290
- 啊！ - 爸？
- Ah!  - Dad?

575
01:05:36,990 --> 01:05:38,160
不！
No!

576
01:05:41,830 --> 01:05:43,170
爸？
Dad?

577
01:05:59,980 --> 01:06:02,550
爸，爸
Dad. Dad.

578
01:06:02,550 --> 01:06:04,050
快，快
Come on. Come on.

579
01:06:26,280 --> 01:06:27,940
来
Come on.

580
01:06:36,420 --> 01:06:37,920
好
Okay.

581
01:07:05,180 --> 01:07:08,150
大脑…正常
Brain...Is normal.

582
01:07:09,020 --> 01:07:11,020
一定有什么东西
There's got to be something.

583
01:07:12,390 --> 01:07:14,720
她的其他器官全都有伤疤
All her other organs  are scarred.

584
01:07:36,650 --> 01:07:38,450
哇靠
What the fuck?

585
01:07:38,450 --> 01:07:39,780
怎么了？
What is it?

586
01:07:58,870 --> 01:08:01,870
难怪我们找不到死因
That's why we couldn't find cause of death.

587
01:08:06,140 --> 01:08:07,810
她还活着
She's still alive.

588
01:08:09,350 --> 01:08:10,510
活着？
Alive?

589
01:08:11,550 --> 01:08:14,650
我们点火烧她
We lit her on fire.

590
01:08:14,650 --> 01:08:16,490
把她的心脏拿出来
We took out her heart.

591
01:08:18,260 --> 01:08:22,090
有某种东西，某种能量
There's something, some energy.

592
01:08:22,090 --> 01:08:25,300
随便你要怎么称呼它，那东西让她一直活着
Call it what you want,  something is keeping  her going.

593
01:08:44,350 --> 01:08:46,120
这是…
What the..

594
01:08:53,020 --> 01:08:54,820
利未记
Leviticus.

595
01:08:59,030 --> 01:09:00,800
让我看看
Let me see that.

596
01:09:04,470 --> 01:09:06,000
利未记
Leviticus.

597
01:09:07,400 --> 01:09:09,840
二十章，二十七节
Twenty. Twenty seven.

598
01:09:18,350 --> 01:09:19,980
如果这些是罗马数字
If these are Roman numerals

599
01:09:19,990 --> 01:09:21,150
那么就是…
then they'd be..

600
01:09:28,660 --> 01:09:30,660
…一六九三
...1693.

601
01:09:31,560 --> 01:09:33,430
“无论男女…
"Any man or woman

602
01:09:33,430 --> 01:09:35,470
是交鬼的或行巫术的
"who consults  the spirits of the dead

603
01:09:35,470 --> 01:09:37,700
总要治死他们
"shall be put to death

604
01:09:37,700 --> 01:09:39,600
因为他们…”
for they are.."

605
01:09:43,610 --> 01:09:46,510
爸
Dad.

606
01:09:46,510 --> 01:09:48,480
十七世纪
Seventeenth century.

607
01:09:48,480 --> 01:09:50,280
东北方
North east.

608
01:09:53,220 --> 01:09:54,720
新英格兰
New england.

609
01:10:05,030 --> 01:10:06,760
是行巫术的
"They are a witch

610
01:10:06,770 --> 01:10:10,070
罪要归到他们身上”
and their blood shall be on their own heads."

611
01:10:18,910 --> 01:10:21,510
完全符合
It fits.

612
01:10:21,510 --> 01:10:23,180
女巫只是传说
Witches are a myth.

613
01:10:25,350 --> 01:10:28,180
你不能继续否认
You can't keep denying.

614
01:10:28,190 --> 01:10:30,220
撒冷没有女巫
There were no witches in Salem.

615
01:10:31,020 --> 01:10:33,990
她们都是孩子，年轻女孩
They were kids. Young girls.

616
01:10:33,990 --> 01:10:36,590
被诬告，完全歇斯底里
Falsely accused, wrapped up in hysteria

617
01:10:36,600 --> 01:10:38,760
一个指控一个，不断地指控下去
one pointing to the next, who pointed to the next

618
01:10:38,760 --> 01:10:41,360
但她们都是，全都是无辜的
but they were all,  all innocent.

619
01:10:43,830 --> 01:10:47,670
只不过…他们没有把她吊死…
Only...They didn't hang her..

620
01:10:47,670 --> 01:10:49,510
…或是把她绑在木椿上烧死
...or burn her at the stake.

621
01:10:50,340 --> 01:10:52,240
他们虐待她…
They tortured her..

622
01:10:54,010 --> 01:10:55,280
…毫不留情
...mercilessly.

623
01:10:55,280 --> 01:10:58,650
仪式
The ritual.

624
01:10:58,650 --> 01:11:00,050
没有作用
It didn't work.

625
01:11:14,060 --> 01:11:15,770
如果…
What if..

626
01:11:16,900 --> 01:11:18,300
如果
What if

627
01:11:18,300 --> 01:11:21,270
在无辜的人身上举行仪式
the ritual,  performed on an innocent

628
01:11:21,270 --> 01:11:26,440
却意外地创造出我们试图毁灭的东西呢？
accidentally created the very thing we're trying to destroy?

629
01:11:28,880 --> 01:11:30,880
他们对她做的每一件事
Everything they did to her.

630
01:11:30,880 --> 01:11:33,220
我们对她做的每一件事
Everything we've done to her.

631
01:11:34,020 --> 01:11:35,850
她都可以感受得到
She can feel it.

632
01:11:39,690 --> 01:11:45,530
她要我们…也感受到这些痛苦
She wants us...To feel it too.

633
01:11:53,040 --> 01:11:55,340
所以她才让我们继续活着
That's why she's keeping us alive.

634
01:11:59,910 --> 01:12:01,980
这是她的复仇
This is her revenge.

635
01:12:04,450 --> 01:12:07,650
这是她的仪式
This is her ritual.

636
01:12:12,160 --> 01:12:13,920
但为什么是我们？
But why us?

637
01:12:13,930 --> 01:12:15,020
为什么是道格拉斯家？
Why the Douglas'?

638
01:12:15,030 --> 01:12:17,190
为什么选这些人？
Why anybody?

639
01:12:17,200 --> 01:12:18,630
我们正好在挡在她的路上，就这么简单
We're on her path, that's all.

640
01:12:18,630 --> 01:12:20,800
我们只是路上的一处停靠站
We were just stops along the way.

641
01:12:22,670 --> 01:12:25,300
生存下来的人把她丢弃
Those who survived  got rid of her

642
01:12:25,300 --> 01:12:27,300
尽可能把她埋得远一点
and buried her as far away as possible.

643
01:12:28,140 --> 01:12:30,070
这样做没能阻止她
That hasn't stopped her.

644
01:12:30,080 --> 01:12:33,680
因为没有人接近到够近的距离
Because no one got close enough.

645
01:12:34,980 --> 01:12:39,450
没有人能够看到我们看到的事
No one could see what we have seen.

646
01:12:47,190 --> 01:12:48,520
她仍然在受苦…
She's still suffering..

647
01:12:50,760 --> 01:12:52,960
…而且不会停止
...and it won't stop.

648
01:12:53,930 --> 01:12:55,900
受苦不会停止，除非…
It won't stop until..

649
01:12:56,470 --> 01:12:58,430
除非怎样？
Until what?

650
01:13:01,670 --> 01:13:04,270
爸，除非怎样？
Dad, until what?

651
01:13:17,120 --> 01:13:18,620
我不会反抗你
I won't fight you.

652
01:13:19,390 --> 01:13:21,120
但是求求你…
But please..

653
01:13:22,060 --> 01:13:24,890
…不要伤害他
...please don't hurt him.

654
01:13:25,760 --> 01:13:27,100
让我帮助你
Let me help you.

655
01:13:27,630 --> 01:13:28,630
爸！
Dad!

656
01:13:59,530 --> 01:14:00,630
爸？
Dad?

657
01:14:04,470 --> 01:14:05,640
不！
No!

658
01:14:07,070 --> 01:14:08,070
爸！
Dad!

659
01:15:01,490 --> 01:15:02,630
爸
Dad.

660
01:15:13,440 --> 01:15:14,500
不
No.

661
01:15:21,550 --> 01:15:22,710
拜托…
Please..

662
01:15:24,750 --> 01:15:26,080
拜托…
Please..

663
01:15:27,320 --> 01:15:28,520
拜托…
Please..

664
01:16:47,730 --> 01:16:49,630
汤米！
Tommy!

665
01:16:49,630 --> 01:16:51,970
奥斯丁！你在里面吗？
Austin! Are you there?

666
01:16:51,970 --> 01:16:53,140
柏克？
Burke?

667
01:16:58,240 --> 01:16:59,910
有人在吗？
Anyone there?

668
01:17:00,410 --> 01:17:01,740
柏克
Burke.

669
01:17:03,150 --> 01:17:05,110
奥斯丁！
Austin!

670
01:17:09,120 --> 01:17:11,290
奥斯丁！你在下面吗？
Austin! Are you down there?

671
01:17:11,290 --> 01:17:14,690
我们正在锯断挡住你家门口的一棵树
We're sawing down a tree  blocking your door.

672
01:17:14,690 --> 01:17:16,890
我们马上就到，好吗
We'll be with you  right now, alright.

673
01:17:24,330 --> 01:17:25,400
奥斯丁！
Austin!

674
01:17:25,400 --> 01:17:26,600
我在这里！
I'm here!

675
01:17:26,600 --> 01:17:28,700
快好了
Almost there.

676
01:17:28,710 --> 01:17:30,070
你会没事的
You'll be alright.

677
01:17:30,070 --> 01:17:32,140
现在就把门打开
Just open up the door now.

678
01:17:32,140 --> 01:17:34,240
- 卡住了  - 再试一次，孩子
- It's stuck.  - Try again, son.

679
01:17:34,250 --> 01:17:35,910
没办法，它不动
I can't. It won't.

680
01:17:37,080 --> 01:17:38,880
现在应该开了
Should open up now.

681
01:17:38,880 --> 01:17:40,250
- 不行  - 应该开了
- It won't.  - Should open up.

682
01:17:41,180 --> 01:17:42,750
我正在试，它卡住了
I'm trying. It's stuck.

683
01:17:42,750 --> 01:17:45,020
开门
Open up.

684
01:17:45,020 --> 01:17:47,320
- 打不开  - 开门！
- I can't.  - Open up!

685
01:17:47,330 --> 01:17:48,960
打不开
I can't.

686
01:19:14,950 --> 01:19:17,550
没有明显的强行闯入迹象
No obvious signs  of forced entry.

687
01:19:17,550 --> 01:19:18,750
看起来很像是他…
Looks an awful lot like he...

688
01:19:18,750 --> 01:19:20,850
我认识他们一家二十年了
I've known his family 20 years.

689
01:19:22,320 --> 01:19:24,390
不管看起来像怎样，都不是那样子
Whatever it looks like,  that ain't it.

690
01:19:27,260 --> 01:19:29,130
啊，今天又是好天气
Well, it's going to be  another nice one out there.

691
01:19:29,130 --> 01:19:31,490
今天是连续第四个大晴天了
Today's our fourth  straight day of sunshine.

692
01:19:31,500 --> 01:19:33,660
温度可望高达七十五度
Looking at a high of 75.

693
01:19:33,660 --> 01:19:34,800
美好的户外天气
Beautiful outdoor weather

694
01:19:34,800 --> 01:19:36,930
但是要记得用防晒油
but remember to use  your sunscreen.

695
01:19:41,470 --> 01:19:43,740
这里到底发生了什么事？
What the hell happened here?

696
01:19:51,450 --> 01:19:52,780
你要怎么处理她？
What do you want to do with her?

697
01:19:54,180 --> 01:19:56,320
- 把她弄出去  - 已经有车在等了
- Get her out of here.  - Already got a car waiting.

698
01:19:56,320 --> 01:19:58,620
卢克森有一个葬仪社
There's that, uh, funeral home over in ruxton.

699
01:19:58,620 --> 01:20:01,020
把她弄出我的郡
Get her out of my county.

700
01:20:01,030 --> 01:20:03,430
送她去维吉尼亚联邦大学
Take her over to vcu.

701
01:20:03,430 --> 01:20:05,090
让华特 拉蒙去处理她
Let ward lamon deal with her.

702
01:20:53,440 --> 01:20:55,950
现在，宝贝，再听一次
Now, baby, listen that was one time.

703
01:20:57,580 --> 01:20:58,950
对，没错，那是一个应许
Hell, yes, that's a promise.

704
01:20:58,950 --> 01:21:00,650
你知道希伯来书第四章说什么吗
And you know what hebrews  chapter four says

705
01:21:00,650 --> 01:21:04,390
“神的话是有力量的”
"the word of god is powerful."

