1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
字幕来源｜网络　　后期｜Lee.

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

3
00:00:24,600 --> 00:00:28,900
迈克尔•帕尔

4
00:00:29,600 --> 00:00:33,800
南茜•艾伦

5
00:00:36,100 --> 00:00:40,880
一九四三年 美国海军进行了一系列的实验

6
00:00:40,900 --> 00:00:45,670
目的是为了让盟军的船舰 能在敌方的雷达中消失

7
00:00:45,680 --> 00:00:48,490
这些测试结果从未公布于世

8
00:00:48,500 --> 00:00:53,000
而最后一次实验导致整个计划终止 这就是后人称的费城实验

9
00:00:53,300 --> 00:01:00,800
费城实验

10
00:00:56,110 --> 00:00:58,990
…这里有最新的新闻亮点
...but first here with the highlights of the latest news...

11
00:00:59,000 --> 00:01:01,880
东部战区时间上午八时…九月十四日
8 a.m. Eastern War Time... September 14th.

12
00:01:02,110 --> 00:01:04,910
马克·韦恩·克拉克指挥的美国第五军团
When the 5th Army advanced to the Gulf of Salerno in Italy...

13
00:01:04,920 --> 00:01:07,330
战斗还在意大利萨莱诺海湾持续
...extremely heavy fighting continues.

14
00:01:07,380 --> 00:01:10,130
德国人利用希特勒的党卫军装甲师
The Germans are using tanks and elements of three divisions

15
00:01:10,160 --> 00:01:12,960
还有十多辆各类型战车 装甲车
with Hermann Goering and the 15th and 16th Panzers.

16
00:01:13,060 --> 00:01:15,070
夺回了二到三处阵地
At one or two points they have regained

17
00:01:15,070 --> 00:01:18,070
部分阵地在最近两天又被夺了回来
some of the ground taken from them in the last day or two,

18
00:01:18,080 --> 00:01:20,680
盟军现在新增了
but the powerful Allied Forces receiving

19
00:01:20,680 --> 00:01:22,680
源源不断的援军和物资
a steady stream of reinforcements and supplies,

20
00:01:22,690 --> 00:01:24,060
正在稳步推进
are advancing steadily to gain

21
00:01:24,060 --> 00:01:26,480
以获得沿海平原周围的弧形山麓
the foothills arcing around the coastal plain...

22
00:01:26,480 --> 00:01:27,880
那时我们为着陆准备
...that we made our landing.

23
00:01:27,930 --> 00:01:30,670
我们已经牢牢确立了自己在沿海地区
We have firmly established ourselves in the coastal area,

24
00:01:30,680 --> 00:01:33,430
不过就要到达德国炮兵的山脚下…
but as long as German artillery in place in the foothills...

25
00:01:33,750 --> 00:01:35,460
詹姆斯 去睡吧
Come on, James, get some sleep.

26
00:01:37,290 --> 00:01:39,090
也许还有什么遗漏的
We MIGHT have missed something.

27
00:01:40,420 --> 00:01:43,590
都实验了上千次了还有什么会遗漏的
A thousand triple checks and we might have missed something?

28
00:01:43,800 --> 00:01:46,370
詹姆斯 明天我们将创造历史
James, tomorrow we make history!

29
00:01:47,510 --> 00:01:48,840
明早见
See you in the morning.

30
00:01:49,340 --> 00:01:52,060
…回到昨天 这让战斗的清晰画面
...back yesterday, which gives a clear picture of the fighting.

31
00:01:52,260 --> 00:01:56,120
德国装甲师还在继续挺进中
Details of an American unit which advanced, knocking-out 12 enemy tanks...

32
00:01:56,120 --> 00:01:58,700
美军和其他盟军还在继续战斗中 双方死亡人数不断增加
...the projected backup is a German counterattack

33
00:01:58,760 --> 00:02:02,000
一些坦克越过我们的一个哨所
overrunning one of our observation posts with several war tanks.

34
00:02:02,310 --> 00:02:04,680
美军持续增援兵力中…
Enemy fighters, approximately a hundred and twenty are...

35
00:02:32,060 --> 00:02:34,630
要不要和你的朋友聊聊
I really have to talk to you about your friend.

36
00:02:44,110 --> 00:02:46,420
别这样好不好
Would you stop that!

37
00:02:46,490 --> 00:02:48,860
你以为我是那种女孩
What kind of girl do you think I am?

38
00:02:49,080 --> 00:02:53,570
哦 要知道这也许是我最后一支舞了
I figured you're the kind that understands that this might be my last dance.

39
00:02:53,960 --> 00:02:56,530
亲爱的 你应该知道事实并非如此
That's a lot of malarkey and you know it.

40
00:02:56,750 --> 00:02:59,250
你所要做的是
All you're doing is taking a joy-ride around the harbor

41
00:02:59,250 --> 00:03:01,250
出海环游六个月 远离战争
and getting out of the war for six months.

42
00:03:01,360 --> 00:03:03,830
真是个冷笑话
Isn't that a great excuse though?

43
00:03:10,260 --> 00:03:13,430
我们不用去办公室 真好
We're not going back to the office and that's final.

44
00:03:23,820 --> 00:03:26,360
- 照顾好宝贝  - 好的
- Take care of junior for me.  - Okay.

45
00:03:34,180 --> 00:03:36,200
那才是我喜欢的节奏
That's more my speed!

46
00:03:37,130 --> 00:03:40,130
甜心 要不要换个舞伴﹖好啊
How do you fell about an old, married man who's raring to go?

47
00:03:40,130 --> 00:03:41,090
好的
Sure!

48
00:03:41,120 --> 00:03:42,830
- 没问题吧  - 不 不行
- Hey, is it okay?  - No, it's not.

49
00:03:42,900 --> 00:03:46,880
- 跳一首曲  - 有何不可
- C'mon. Hey, Babe, you wanna cut a rug.  - Why not?

50
00:03:56,120 --> 00:03:58,640
- 你会是个好妈妈的  - 那是一种恭维吗 就当是吧
- Motherhood suits ya.  - Is that a compliment?

51
00:03:58,860 --> 00:04:01,890
吉米真是个幸运的家伙
Yes, it's supposed to. Jimmy's a lucky guy.

52
00:04:02,190 --> 00:04:04,150
你也不是没有机会啊
Well, you had your chance.

53
00:04:04,990 --> 00:04:06,860
是啊 的确
Yeah, I guess I did.

54
00:04:09,490 --> 00:04:10,330
喝什么
Want something to drink?

55
00:04:10,870 --> 00:04:12,070
可乐
A Coke.

56
00:04:19,750 --> 00:04:21,290
啤酒和可乐
Give me a beer and a Coke.

57
00:04:22,250 --> 00:04:23,910
看 是那个家伙
Hey, there goes the Whiz Kid.

58
00:04:25,120 --> 00:04:27,110
郎斯特 他看上去有些紧张
He doesn't look too happy, does he?

59
00:04:28,220 --> 00:04:30,210
也许他知道一些我们不知道的事
Maybe he knows somethin' we don't.

60
00:04:30,510 --> 00:04:32,220
谢谢你的安慰
Thanks, Steve, that's just what I wanted to hear.

61
00:04:32,470 --> 00:04:37,380
- 嘿 你和桃瑞丝怎么了  - 不关你的事
- Hey, uh, how's it going with Doris?  - None of your business.

62
00:04:53,660 --> 00:04:55,370
你何时动身去加州
When are you going to California?

63
00:04:55,580 --> 00:04:56,910
明天
Tomorrow.

64
00:04:56,910 --> 00:04:59,580
我留在这里也没用
Since you're gonna be quarantined for a month, there's no use in my staying.

65
00:04:59,710 --> 00:05:02,880
你不会把我们忘了吧 不会的
Yeah.. hey, say hello to everybody for me, all right?

66
00:05:03,090 --> 00:05:05,860
有你爸爸的消息了
I will. Have you heard from your dad?

67
00:05:07,610 --> 00:05:10,270
没有 他在萨加缅度
No. He's up at Sacramento.

68
00:05:10,270 --> 00:05:12,500
他不会放弃他的赛车的
He's not gonna let the war get in the way of his racing.

69
00:05:15,850 --> 00:05:18,260
先生女士们 最后一支舞曲
Ladies and gentlemen, this'll be the last dance.

70
00:05:18,730 --> 00:05:20,550
- 什么  - 最后一支舞曲
- What?  - The last dance!

71
00:05:21,560 --> 00:05:22,380
再见
See ya, Babe.

72
00:05:24,690 --> 00:05:27,500
- 好了 我要回那边去了  - 好的
- Look after Jimmy for me, will ya?  - Yeah.

73
00:05:28,200 --> 00:05:30,890
来吧 亲爱的
Come on, Honey, it's the last dance.

74
00:07:16,390 --> 00:07:19,140
戴维 看 看 帕米拉
Pam! Davy, look, it's Pam!

75
00:07:19,350 --> 00:07:22,320
嗨！帕米拉 亲爱的
Hi, Pam! I hear the baby!

76
00:07:22,980 --> 00:07:27,750
- 嗨！嗨！  - 我爱你 亲爱的 我会想你的
- Hi! Hi!  - I love you, Sweetie! I love you! I'll miss you.

77
00:07:27,980 --> 00:07:30,120
我爱你
I love you!

78
00:08:48,360 --> 00:08:49,900
担心吗 约翰
You worried about losing your job, Joe?

79
00:08:50,860 --> 00:08:53,240
我相信他们会成功的
I'll believe it when I see him do it.

80
00:08:53,700 --> 00:08:56,490
好吧 马上就会揭晓的
Well, we'll find out soon enough.

81
00:09:10,050 --> 00:09:12,090
嗨 伙计们 准备好享受这趟旅程了吗
You fellas goin' on another joy-ride?

82
00:09:12,300 --> 00:09:16,580
史密斯 听说你老婆和舰长有一腿
Hey, Smitty, I heard your old lady ran off with a Skimmer Puke.

83
00:09:16,600 --> 00:09:20,040
- 据我所知不是那样  - 我听说他们两个都和舰长有一腿
- I heard it was an Airedale.  - I heard it was both of 'em!

84
00:09:27,030 --> 00:09:29,600
你昨晚和帕米拉打的很热火啊
Well, we get to go out without Pam tonight, hotshot!

85
00:09:29,820 --> 00:09:32,330
是啊 今晚开始我们就要与世隔绝了
Yeah, we'll be in quarantine's time tonight.

86
00:09:32,330 --> 00:09:33,470
是啊 与世隔绝
Forget quarantine!

87
00:09:33,660 --> 00:09:36,100
- 我有一大堆事情要做 伙计  - 是的
- I got it all worked out, buddy.  - Yeah?

88
00:09:58,430 --> 00:10:01,420
- 早安  - 早安 长官
- Good morning, gentlemen.  - Good morning, Sir.

89
00:10:02,440 --> 00:10:04,440
- 一切正常  - 是的 长官
- Is everything in order?  - Yes, Sir.

90
00:10:04,610 --> 00:10:06,960
检查过无线电讯号强度了吗
Have you checked the communications link to the shore?

91
00:10:07,130 --> 00:10:09,280
是的 五格满表 长官
Yes, Sir! Clear as a bell!

92
00:10:09,840 --> 00:10:13,490
全体注意 所有无关人员请准备下船
Now hear this: All visitors prepare to disembark,

93
00:10:13,490 --> 00:10:17,490
特别人员除外 请准备开始
except for special sea detail. Prepare to get underway!

94
00:10:19,120 --> 00:10:22,370
- 这是干什么  - 不知道
- What the hell was that all about?  - I don't know.

95
00:10:45,860 --> 00:10:49,560
距离一千八百三十码 方位一二八
Range 2000 yards, bearing 1-2-8.

96
00:10:49,780 --> 00:10:52,290
他们不可能就这样把这玩意藏起来
No way they're gonna hide this turkey!

97
00:10:52,290 --> 00:10:53,690
看得见 看不清楚
Now you see it, now you don't.

98
00:10:53,820 --> 00:10:56,280
好了干活了
All right, Men, let's concentrate!

99
00:11:07,150 --> 00:11:11,640
全员注意 再次检查十三号特别装置和设备
Now here this: Secure the specialty and anchor detail,

100
00:11:11,640 --> 00:11:12,670
开动计时中
set the underway watch.

101
00:11:12,680 --> 00:11:15,590
彩虹一号试验准备
Experimental detail, prepare for the Rainbow One.

102
00:11:15,800 --> 00:11:18,200
请关闭全监雾灯
The smoking lamp is out throughout the ship.

103
00:11:33,910 --> 00:11:37,110
喂 给你们介绍一下这是朗斯特博士 和他的助理
Hey, Joe, you've met Dr. Longstreet and his assistant?

104
00:11:37,330 --> 00:11:38,340
欢迎你们上船 长官
Welcome aboard, Sir.

105
00:11:38,760 --> 00:11:40,370
- 欢迎你们上船  - 谢谢
- Welcome aboard.  - Thank you.

106
00:11:42,250 --> 00:11:44,410
整艘船都已经准备好了 长官
The ships are on-station, Sir.

107
00:11:53,180 --> 00:11:55,130
可以启动发电机了吗 船长
You can start the generators now, Captain.

108
00:11:55,350 --> 00:11:56,760
开始运作
Commence operations.

109
00:11:56,870 --> 00:11:59,890
“海狗”呼叫“男孩” 启动彩虹一号
This is Sea Dog to Small Boy, activate Rainbow One.

110
00:12:00,770 --> 00:12:02,840
“男孩”收到完毕
This is Small Boy, roger, out.

111
00:12:03,980 --> 00:12:06,930
- 全员注意 准备倒数计时  - 开始了
- All sections, stand-by for countdown.  - Here we go!

112
00:12:23,420 --> 00:12:28,380
- 发电机已经启动 长官  - 开到最大马力
- Generators activated, Sir.  - Power to the main field.

113
00:13:10,760 --> 00:13:12,440
简直不敢相信
I don't believe this!

114
00:13:14,970 --> 00:13:17,150
埃尔德里奇号的讯号正在减弱
The Eldridge is beginning to fade, Sir!

115
00:13:20,620 --> 00:13:22,030
她消失了
She's gone!

116
00:13:24,520 --> 00:13:26,850
我以为这是不可能的
I didn't think it was possible.

117
00:13:27,360 --> 00:13:30,160
- 可是雷达找不到她  - 恭喜你 博士
- She's radar invisible!  - Congratulations, Doctor!

118
00:13:30,360 --> 00:13:33,980
看来可以打垮整个德国舰队了
Looks like you've just taken the entire German fleet out of this war.

119
00:13:50,090 --> 00:13:53,370
- 到底怎么回事  - 真让人发毛
- How is it?  - It's gettin' kinda spooky in here!

120
00:14:13,650 --> 00:14:16,220
罗宾逊舰长 刚刚收到报告
Captain Robertson, Sir, it's the cutter.

121
00:14:16,220 --> 00:14:18,630
他们说埃尔德里奇号消失不见了
They say that the Eldridge has vanished!

122
00:14:18,670 --> 00:14:20,360
当然了 雷达探测不到她
Of course she has, she's radar invisible!

123
00:14:20,520 --> 00:14:22,410
不 长官 是真的“消失”了
No, Sir, she's REALLY vanished!

124
00:14:22,620 --> 00:14:23,620
不见了
She's gone!

125
00:14:23,830 --> 00:14:25,990
给我用无线电接埃尔德里奇号的舰长
Get me the captain of the Eldridge on the radio right away!

126
00:14:26,210 --> 00:14:27,450
这不可能
It's impossible!

127
00:14:27,940 --> 00:14:30,710
“海狗”呼叫“男孩” 听到请回答
Small Boy this is Sea Dog, over.

128
00:14:31,730 --> 00:14:33,850
“海狗”呼叫“男孩” 听到请回答
Small Boy this is Sea Dog.

129
00:14:34,090 --> 00:14:35,190
关掉
Shut that down!

130
00:14:36,050 --> 00:14:38,510
关掉发电机 叫埃尔德里奇号快点关掉
Tell the others to kill the generators. TELL 'EM!!!

131
00:14:38,720 --> 00:14:41,890
- 他们通讯断了 长官  - 继续呼叫
- They've broken-off communications, Sir.  - Keep trying.

132
00:14:44,310 --> 00:14:47,650
注意 搜索救护人员请待命
Attention all the search and rescue personnel, stand-by!

133
00:14:48,260 --> 00:14:51,180
搜索救护人员请待命
Repeat, all search and rescue personnel, stand-by!

134
00:14:58,070 --> 00:14:59,650
这到底怎么回事 出什么事了
What is going on here?

135
00:15:01,910 --> 00:15:04,910
- 把机器关掉  - 快关掉
- What is it?  - Shut the damn thing... shut it down!

136
00:15:11,110 --> 00:15:14,430
- 吉米 你没事吧  - 还好 出去
- Jimmy! Are you okay?  - I'm okay! Get outta here!

137
00:15:14,470 --> 00:15:15,590
我们赶快出去吧 快点
Let get the hell outta here!

138
00:15:23,230 --> 00:15:24,550
快起来
C'mon! Get up!

139
00:15:51,460 --> 00:15:53,090
这是怎么回事 我也不知道
What is this? What's goin' on?

140
00:15:53,300 --> 00:15:54,850
你看见什么了
I don't know, what do you see right now?

141
00:15:54,850 --> 00:15:58,150
星星 好像是晚上吧 啊 是晚上
The stars, the moon, it's night!

142
00:15:58,300 --> 00:16:00,590
你看见一条船了吧 那条船还有城市
Did you see the ship? I mean did... you see the ship, the town?

143
00:16:00,810 --> 00:16:04,090
看到了好像是在漩涡里 到底是怎么回事
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's spinnin' around! What's goin' on here?

144
00:16:04,850 --> 00:16:08,830
- 你的手怎么了  - 还好 我想是灼伤了
- What about your hand?  - It looks okay now, there's nothing wrong with it.

145
00:16:14,050 --> 00:16:17,030
- 那是什么鬼东西  - 我不知道 什么东西
- What the hell is it?  - I don't know... what is that?

146
00:16:27,330 --> 00:16:29,160
他又回来了 戴维
It's comin' back again, Davy!

147
00:16:32,380 --> 00:16:34,360
天哪
Oh, my god.

148
00:16:36,630 --> 00:16:37,590
快 吉米
C'mon!

149
00:16:39,400 --> 00:16:40,350
快跑
Run!

150
00:16:41,380 --> 00:16:42,740
快 快跑
Run! Run!

151
00:17:10,960 --> 00:17:13,500
放开手 吉米
Let go, Jimmy! Let go!

152
00:17:18,780 --> 00:17:21,500
走 我们离开这里 快跑
We gotta get outta here! C'mon! Run!

153
00:18:02,850 --> 00:18:05,440
- 你没事吧  - 还好 没事
- You all right?  - Yeah, I'm okay.

154
00:18:05,560 --> 00:18:07,410
- 这是最后一根了  - 谢谢
- It's the last one.  - Thanks.

155
00:18:08,230 --> 00:18:11,070
- 你还有什么好主意没有  - 是的
- You have any more brilliant ideas?  - Yeah.

156
00:18:11,900 --> 00:18:16,060
我们应该还在费城 这可能是试验的一部份
We're still in Philadelphia. This is all part of the experiment.

157
00:18:16,280 --> 00:18:18,190
可能是他们在我们脑子里搞什么名堂吧
They did something to our minds!

158
00:18:18,450 --> 00:18:23,510
- 费城可没有沙漠  - 也许这一些都是假的
- There's no desert in Philly.  - Maybe all this isn't real.

159
00:18:23,660 --> 00:18:27,110
只是一种幻觉而已 给我们搞催眠术
Maybe it's a hallucination, they could've hypnotized us.

160
00:18:27,330 --> 00:18:28,830
知道吗 他们干的出来的
Ya know, they do that to people, ya know?

161
00:18:28,940 --> 00:18:31,190
你是说现在这一切都是假的
You're tellin' me this is my imagination?

162
00:18:31,190 --> 00:18:33,290
是幻觉 冻的半死也是假的
And we're not freezin' our asses off out here?

163
00:18:33,500 --> 00:18:35,410
昨天晚上他们想要杀死我们难到也是假的
And they didn't try to kill us last night?

164
00:18:35,630 --> 00:18:39,050
他们不会的 这一切都只是试验的一部份
They wouldn't do that! It's all part of the experiment.

165
00:18:39,260 --> 00:18:41,720
我觉得是这样 你还以为海军这么有把握吗
You think the Navy knows what they're doing?

166
00:18:41,930 --> 00:18:43,970
你看见船上那些人的惨状吗
You saw the guys on the boat.

167
00:18:43,970 --> 00:18:46,970
不该发生这种事 一定是出了大差错了
This wasn't supposed to happen, Jimmy! This is a BIG mistake.

168
00:18:47,100 --> 00:18:51,600
- 那我们该怎么办  - 继续走吧
- So what do we do, huh?  - Let's keep on goin'.

169
00:18:55,690 --> 00:18:57,820
那不是海滩吗
Isn't that water up ahead?

170
00:18:57,820 --> 00:19:02,340
不 是沙漠 是虚幻的 海市蜃楼
No, this is a desert, and that's a mirage.

171
00:19:16,050 --> 00:19:19,050
你说虚幻会持续多久
How much longer do you think this mirage is gonna last?

172
00:19:28,600 --> 00:19:31,090
- 这是什么  - 一种啤酒
- What is it?  - Some sorta beer.

173
00:19:34,610 --> 00:19:35,600
德国的
German!

174
00:19:38,660 --> 00:19:39,380
嘿
Hey!

175
00:19:43,700 --> 00:19:45,160
是可口可乐
Coca-cola!

176
00:19:45,970 --> 00:19:49,950
好轻啊 什么做的
Oh, it's so light! What the hell's it made of?

177
00:19:51,880 --> 00:19:53,840
我怎么知道
Well, hell if I know.

178
00:20:04,220 --> 00:20:07,180
- 那是什么  - 应该是报废的雪弗兰
- What is it?  - It's an old Chevy.

179
00:20:10,020 --> 00:20:13,120
- 他冲我们来  - 快过来 快
- It's headin' right for us.  - C'mon!

180
00:20:25,790 --> 00:20:27,410
这是什么
What the hell was that?

181
00:20:39,840 --> 00:20:43,510
红鹰呼叫红二基地 我们看不到任何城镇的影子 长官
Red Leader to Dry Wells Base, we don't see any town site.

182
00:20:43,720 --> 00:20:45,760
红二基地呼叫红鹰请重覆
Dry Wells Base to Red Leader, repeat!

183
00:20:45,970 --> 00:20:47,750
实验前它还在那里
It was there before the experiment,

184
00:20:47,750 --> 00:20:49,890
它一定还在附近 继续找
it's got to be there now! Keep looking!

185
00:20:49,960 --> 00:20:53,470
红二 半个城市难到就这样消失了吗
How could the damn town just disappear?

186
00:20:53,470 --> 00:20:54,950
继续搜寻 完毕
Continuing search, over.

187
00:21:06,600 --> 00:21:08,400
现在是朗斯特里特
That's Longstreet now, punch-up code 84

188
00:21:08,410 --> 00:21:10,580
提高到八四 再搜查整个区域
and run another check of the area.

189
00:21:30,480 --> 00:21:32,470
我们刚刚搜过一遍
We just finished our first run.

190
00:21:32,690 --> 00:21:35,810
什么都没有发现 没有不规则的电磁场
There's nothing, no anomalous electromagnetic fields.

191
00:21:36,030 --> 00:21:38,020
也没有热能 没有辐射
No heat build-up, no radiation.

192
00:21:38,240 --> 00:21:41,240
整个城市就这样消失了
The whole damned town just disappeared, James!

193
00:21:41,450 --> 00:21:42,780
再检查一次
Run a second check.

194
00:21:43,200 --> 00:21:44,620
我们刚刚查完
We are already doing it,

195
00:21:44,620 --> 00:21:47,660
这种事情怎么可能发生呢 怎么可能
but, I mean, how the hell could this thing have happened?

196
00:21:48,790 --> 00:21:52,370
我不想让华盛顿介入此事 现在还不是时候
I don't want Washington involved... not yet.

197
00:21:52,670 --> 00:21:57,060
明白 一个小时之内我们就能查完了
I understand. We'll be through in an hour.

198
00:22:12,480 --> 00:22:13,990
这里使用长镜头 那里也拍一张
All right, I want a shot here and then

199
00:22:14,000 --> 00:22:15,310
还有后面使用广角镜 把整个都拍下来
I want a shot featuring that section down there.

200
00:22:15,520 --> 00:22:17,900
我希望有一个整体概述和报告
And then I want a wide shot of the whole assembly.

201
00:22:19,860 --> 00:22:20,860
这是什么
What is it?

202
00:22:22,410 --> 00:22:24,710
还不知道 长官
We don't know, Sir,

203
00:22:24,710 --> 00:22:26,780
不过我们在行动之前
but it wasn't here when we started, that's for DAMN sure.

204
00:22:27,700 --> 00:22:29,990
斩波到了那边的安全围栏
The chopper went down over there by the security fence.

205
00:22:30,030 --> 00:22:31,990
它不在这里直升机搜查过什么也没发现
There's not a piece of it left that's bigger than a matchstick.

206
00:22:32,330 --> 00:22:34,460
会不会安全上有漏洞
How about the security breach?

207
00:22:35,540 --> 00:22:38,670
我们都搜查过了 我敢保证绝对没有问题
CQ's checking into it, but I can guarantee you it's a mistake.

208
00:22:38,880 --> 00:22:41,420
就算是一只野兔子也无法穿过防区 长官
Not even a jack rabbit could get through this perimeter.

209
00:22:41,730 --> 00:22:43,260
长官
Excuse me, Sir.

210
00:22:43,990 --> 00:22:44,790
我是可拉克 请讲
Clark here.

211
00:22:44,820 --> 00:22:48,490
- 我们发现了一些东西  - 好的 我们走
- We got somethin' for ya.  - Right! Griffin! Let's go!

212
00:22:49,230 --> 00:22:51,030
硬钢的钢丝
Three-eighths, it's hard steel coil,

213
00:22:51,030 --> 00:22:55,160
我至少有三十年没有看到过这种东西
haven't seen anything like it in at least 30 years!

214
00:23:04,180 --> 00:23:08,400
我会说那是个龙卷风来了
If I was back in Missouri, I'd swear there was a tornado brewing-up there.

215
00:23:56,750 --> 00:23:58,890
嘿 伙计们 怎么了
Hey, man, what's happening?

216
00:24:08,890 --> 00:24:12,390
- 进来还是不进来  - 好啊
- You comin' in, or what?  - Yeah.

217
00:24:38,300 --> 00:24:40,490
小伙子们 想喝杯咖啡吗
You boys want some coffee?

218
00:24:42,300 --> 00:24:43,770
是 好啊
Yes.

219
00:24:44,970 --> 00:24:47,360
想来点特制的火腿和鸡蛋吗
We got a special on the ham and eggs.

220
00:24:53,020 --> 00:24:54,810
好啊 听起来不错
Yeah, sounds good.

221
00:24:56,360 --> 00:24:59,410
- 我也是  - 蛋要怎样的
- Yeah, me, too.  - How do you want the eggs?

222
00:25:00,190 --> 00:25:04,190
- 全熟的吗  - 两个都全熟的
- Scrambled.  - Two specials, scrambled!

223
00:25:04,200 --> 00:25:06,260
还好她说英语
At least she speaks English.

224
00:25:06,660 --> 00:25:07,690
我来问一问
You don't mind?

225
00:25:10,790 --> 00:25:11,950
这个地方叫什么名字
Wha... what... what's the name of this place?

226
00:25:11,950 --> 00:25:13,700
史考特结部旁边是“内华达测试”基地
Scotty's Junction.

227
00:25:13,920 --> 00:25:16,540
所有的地图都找不到我们这里 我向你保证
You won't find it on any map, I can tell ya' that!

228
00:25:17,920 --> 00:25:19,250
内华达州
Nevada?

229
00:25:20,260 --> 00:25:22,710
难道你们连自己在那个州都不知道吗
You boys don't know what state you're in?

230
00:25:23,880 --> 00:25:26,990
哦 请问这附近有一个海军基地吗
Yeah, there's a... there's a navy base around here?

231
00:25:27,030 --> 00:25:30,380
我没听说过 只有在一个在“内华达测试”基地
Not that I know of. Just the base up at Dry Wells.

232
00:25:32,100 --> 00:25:33,470
这就是它
That's it!

233
00:25:34,960 --> 00:25:38,940
- 你有电话吗  - 在外面 加油机旁边那
- Do you have a phone?  - Outside, by the pump.

234
00:25:39,190 --> 00:25:42,480
给我一点零钱 我要联络基地
Give me some of that money, see if I can get a hold of Base.

235
00:26:03,950 --> 00:26:05,420
什么
What?

236
00:26:06,930 --> 00:26:09,340
你已经把工作给别人了
You gave the job to somebody else?

237
00:26:10,770 --> 00:26:14,390
我在芝加哥和盐湖城都有打电话给你
I... I did call! I called from Chicago,

238
00:26:14,390 --> 00:26:16,410
你没有收到我的留言吗
I called from Salt Lake! Didn't he get the message?

239
00:26:17,020 --> 00:26:21,260
我不明白 因为你 我才放弃了我原先那份工作
I don't think you understand! I quit my job to come work for you.

240
00:26:21,800 --> 00:26:25,520
当然 我很生气 我开了整整两天的车
Of course I'm upset! I've been driving for two days!

241
00:26:27,160 --> 00:26:30,210
不 我不要在和你说了
No, I don't wanna come stay with you.

242
00:26:30,910 --> 00:26:33,320
为什么呢 已经没有什么好谈的
What for? There's nothing to talk about.

243
00:26:33,540 --> 00:26:37,520
听着 有人在等电话 就这样 再见
Look, there's someone waiting for the phone... goodbye.

244
00:26:39,790 --> 00:26:41,540
谢谢
Thank you.

245
00:26:55,830 --> 00:26:59,520
接线生 帮我接一个长途电话 谢谢 费城
Operator, yes, I want to call long distance, Philadelphia.

246
00:27:00,110 --> 00:27:02,060
美国海军基地
United States Naval Base.

247
00:27:02,860 --> 00:27:05,000
是的 对方付费
Well, yeah, I gotta reverse the charges,

248
00:27:05,000 --> 00:27:07,360
我是一等兵大卫 赫迪
this is Seaman First Class David Herdeg.

249
00:27:07,360 --> 00:27:09,150
我是大卫 赫迪 找罗伯逊指挥官
Want a Commander Robertson.

250
00:27:18,080 --> 00:27:20,040
- 吃的怎么样 长官  - 本
- How are your victuals, Sir.  - Hey, Ben!

251
00:27:24,380 --> 00:27:26,380
把糖包给我好吗
You got any Sweet 'n' Low?

252
00:27:30,140 --> 00:27:31,850
那里的糖包
The Sweet 'n' Low.

253
00:27:32,930 --> 00:27:35,740
- 我们不接受支票和信用卡  - 谢谢
- Don't take any checks or credit cards.  - Thanks.

254
00:27:57,410 --> 00:28:01,840
你在干什么
Hey! What in the hell do you think you're doing?

255
00:28:03,340 --> 00:28:05,280
孩子 给我站住
C'mon back here, boy!

256
00:28:05,990 --> 00:28:08,200
- 我们得离开这里  - 这是怎么了
- We gotta get outta here, Davy.  - What's goin' on?

257
00:28:08,240 --> 00:28:09,900
站在那里别动
All right, hold it right there, boy!

258
00:28:10,050 --> 00:28:12,930
你得赔我店里那两台机器的钱
Now, you're paying for both them machines before you leave my place.

259
00:28:12,970 --> 00:28:14,270
我没碰过你的机器
I didn't do anything to your machines!

260
00:28:14,410 --> 00:28:16,320
听着 我不知道你在说什么
Mister, I don't know what you're talkin' about...

261
00:28:16,320 --> 00:28:18,230
还有你 你们是在一起的 你也有份
You shut up, or I'll blow your head off, too.

262
00:28:18,440 --> 00:28:20,790
- 我们还是先去叫警察吧  - 别多嘴 回里头去
- Pa, I already called the Sheriff.  - Now, you just get back inside.

263
00:28:21,000 --> 00:28:23,630
好了 都退后
All right, stay back! Everybody! Stay back!

264
00:28:23,670 --> 00:28:25,350
- 放松  - 大家都退后
- Easy, Mister! C'mon, take it easy.  - Get back!

265
00:28:25,380 --> 00:28:26,950
- 到车里去  - 我什么也没做
- Get in the car, Jimmy.  - I didn't do anything, Davy.

266
00:28:26,990 --> 00:28:28,400
快到车里去
Just get in the car!

267
00:28:33,220 --> 00:28:35,470
当心 都退后
Stay back, just stay back, we'll get 'em later.

268
00:28:36,210 --> 00:28:37,490
钥匙在哪里
Where are the keys?

269
00:28:37,710 --> 00:28:39,860
这车是我仅有的财产 你们就不能换别辆车吗
It's everything I own, could you take another car?

270
00:28:39,900 --> 00:28:41,370
快把钥匙拿来
Just give me the damn keys!

271
00:28:50,810 --> 00:28:52,600
这是怎么回事
What's the matter?

272
00:28:53,330 --> 00:28:56,270
- 离合器在那里  - 这是自排的啊
- Where the hell's the clutch?  - It's automatic!

273
00:28:56,440 --> 00:28:57,430
什么自排
What is an "automatic"?

274
00:28:57,640 --> 00:29:01,200
- 上车 你来开  - 天啊 真的疯了
- Get in, you're driving.  - Jesus Christ.

275
00:29:01,240 --> 00:29:02,290
别管那些包包了
Hey, forget the bag!

276
00:29:02,360 --> 00:29:06,880
- 不带它们我不走  - 老天爷 快上车去
- I'm not leaving without my stuff.  - For God's sake, get in the car!

277
00:29:09,430 --> 00:29:12,470
快走 快 快 快
Go! Go! Come on! Go! Go!

278
00:29:24,510 --> 00:29:27,080
我会听话的 别伤害我好吗
Look, I'll cooperate, but just don't hurt me, okay?

279
00:29:27,300 --> 00:29:29,210
没人会伤害你的 开好你的车
We're not gonna hurt you, just keep on drivin'.

280
00:29:29,210 --> 00:29:30,110
有联络上基地吗
Did you get through to the Base.

281
00:29:30,220 --> 00:29:33,140
他们从来没听过罗伯逊指挥官 他们是这样说的
They never even heard of a Commander Robertson... that's what they said.

282
00:29:33,180 --> 00:29:35,890
他们在说谎 他们为什么要这么做
But that's a lie! Why would they do that?

283
00:29:36,100 --> 00:29:37,300
让我看看
Let me see that.

284
00:29:38,310 --> 00:29:41,930
感觉不太妙 大卫 刚才那里又出现一次状况
It doesn't feel too good, Davey. It happened again back there.

285
00:29:42,150 --> 00:29:43,640
你应该去医院
You know, you should be in the hospital.

286
00:29:43,640 --> 00:29:45,880
他应该去医院 你知道吗
He should be in a hospital, you know that!

287
00:29:46,740 --> 00:29:48,180
今天是几号
What's the date?

288
00:29:48,280 --> 00:29:51,300
- 今天是 十七号  - 哪一年
- The date, it's the 17th.  - The year!

289
00:29:51,990 --> 00:29:54,640
你开玩笑吧 当然是一九八四年
Are you kidding? It's 1984!

290
00:29:56,620 --> 00:29:58,830
你们俩到底是怎么了 是不是嗑药了
What's going on with you two? Are you on drugs or something?

291
00:29:58,920 --> 00:30:01,230
- 一九八四年  - 战争现在如何
- 1984.  - What about the War?

292
00:30:01,340 --> 00:30:03,130
- 战争  - 战争
- What war?  - The War!

293
00:30:03,170 --> 00:30:04,120
越战
Vietnam?

294
00:30:04,340 --> 00:30:06,800
二战啊 德国和日本
World War II, Germany and Japan!

295
00:30:07,300 --> 00:30:08,550
二战怎么了
What about it?

296
00:30:09,550 --> 00:30:10,810
谁赢了
Who won?

297
00:30:13,140 --> 00:30:15,530
谁赢了 我们啊 不然你以为谁
We won, what do you think?

298
00:30:17,690 --> 00:30:19,540
你们让我觉得很奇怪
Are you guys putting me on or somethin'?

299
00:30:21,270 --> 00:30:24,040
- 下一个镇有多远  - 不晓得
- How far to the next town?  - I don't know.

300
00:30:24,150 --> 00:30:25,710
你有烟吗
Hey, do you have any cigarettes?

301
00:30:26,070 --> 00:30:28,150
没啊 我上个月刚戒掉
No, I quit last month.

302
00:30:44,860 --> 00:30:50,300
〇一号呼叫〇六 回答
Roger, one-niner, you're advised to clear quadrant Delta...

303
00:30:50,500 --> 00:30:54,870
〇六回答 已经到基地
Roger, this is one-niner, we copy, standing by for base communications.

304
00:31:08,300 --> 00:31:09,100
早安 长官
Good morning, Sir.

305
00:31:09,100 --> 00:31:11,210
- 朗斯特博士来了吗  - 是的
- Is Dr. Longstreet down there?  - Yes, he is.

306
00:31:26,630 --> 00:31:29,430
我不理解这个实验和我们其他的反导弹测试之间
I don't understand any significant difference between this experiment

307
00:31:29,430 --> 00:31:32,010
有任何显著性差异
and any other anti-missile test we've run so far.

308
00:31:32,010 --> 00:31:32,940
拉里
Larry!

309
00:31:34,680 --> 00:31:36,190
这不足以这样
It wouldn't be enough to do it.

310
00:31:36,190 --> 00:31:38,220
当然有 这是唯一解释
Of course it would, it's the only variable.

311
00:31:38,440 --> 00:31:39,480
导弹发射使
The amount of energy it took to deflect

312
00:31:39,480 --> 00:31:41,780
多维空间的能量偏差变大
the missiles into hyperspace was so great

313
00:31:41,860 --> 00:31:43,520
- 看  - 以至于产生了时空交叠
- Look!  - it created a wrinkle in the continuum!

314
00:31:43,730 --> 00:31:46,310
但我们切断了能源 并关掉了发电机
We shut the energy off, we turned the generators down,

315
00:31:46,530 --> 00:31:48,480
为什么城镇还没有还原出现
why didn't the town simply re-materialize?

316
00:31:48,700 --> 00:31:51,140
或许还有另外一个能量源存在
Maybe there is another power source functioning.

317
00:31:52,700 --> 00:31:56,270
- 哪儿  - 那个区域 多维空间里
- Where?  - Inside the zone, in hyperspace itself.

318
00:31:56,500 --> 00:31:58,780
可能还有其他能量源
What would be the possible source?

319
00:31:59,000 --> 00:32:01,440
- 你有气象报告吗  - 是的
- Did you get the meteorological report?  - Yes.

320
00:32:01,790 --> 00:32:04,950
不可思议 有一个非常强的气漩同一时间段
It's incredible, it's as if every storm front in the region

321
00:32:04,950 --> 00:32:06,950
已经有三个龙卷风形成
were being sucked into this one tiny zone.

322
00:32:07,010 --> 00:32:09,760
更多的正在发生中
We have three separate reports of tornadoes, and that doesn't happen here.

323
00:32:09,800 --> 00:32:10,860
中心位置于那里
Where's it centered now?

324
00:32:11,450 --> 00:32:13,870
- 克拉克少校想见你  - 大约往东四十公里处
- Major Clark wants to see you.  - About 40 miles due east of here.

325
00:32:14,160 --> 00:32:15,480
我马上回来
I'll be back.

326
00:32:16,180 --> 00:32:18,160
另外一个能力源会是什么
What other the possible energy source?

327
00:32:18,390 --> 00:32:19,630
很抱歉打断你
I'm sorry to interrupt,

328
00:32:19,630 --> 00:32:22,280
但我想告诉你 的确是出现安全漏洞
but I thought you should know, there WAS a security break.

329
00:32:22,730 --> 00:32:25,940
至少有两个人曾经出现在实验区内
At least two men were in the area of the experiment when it took place,

330
00:32:25,940 --> 00:32:26,940
在我们发布全面警戒后
I put out a full alert.

331
00:32:27,030 --> 00:32:29,410
他们运气真好 那里可是连野兔都跑不过去的
So much for the jack rabbit theory.

332
00:32:30,070 --> 00:32:32,730
放心我一定会抓到他们的 我向你保证
We'll catch them, I can guarantee THAT.

333
00:32:32,730 --> 00:32:34,510
你一定会的 我要看到成果
When you do, I'll want to see them.

334
00:33:27,380 --> 00:33:30,510
最高机密 美国海军“爱尔德里奇号”

335
00:34:33,990 --> 00:34:35,620
吉米 快看
Jimmy, look at this!

336
00:34:37,160 --> 00:34:39,440
我不喜欢这样 大卫 这一切都乱了套
I don't like it, Davey, it's all wrong.

337
00:34:39,580 --> 00:34:42,450
- 我们是不是该去找一家医院了  - 开你的车
- PLEASE, can we find a hospital?  - Just keep drivin'.

338
00:34:42,490 --> 00:34:45,560
- 不能这样 大卫  - 那你想怎么样
- We can't, Davey.  - Then what do you wanna do?

339
00:34:45,790 --> 00:34:49,400
- 我们要想办法回家  - 你们家在那里
- Let's just try and get home.  - Where's home?

340
00:34:51,010 --> 00:34:52,670
加州
California.

341
00:34:53,870 --> 00:34:55,830
又来了 大卫
It's comin' back, Davey.

342
00:35:04,250 --> 00:35:07,210
- 你们两个人是怎么了  - 小心前面
- What the hell is wrong with you two?  - Look out!

343
00:35:19,950 --> 00:35:21,730
好了 都不许动
All right, nobody move!

344
00:35:21,850 --> 00:35:24,350
天啊 你是在开玩笑吗
Jesus Christ, you gotta be kidding!

345
00:35:27,210 --> 00:35:29,960
他们被电击了 叫尼尔逊下来
I need an E.K.G. and get Nielson down here, it looks like a possible...

346
00:35:30,170 --> 00:35:32,770
他们自称来自加利福尼亚州
All I know he's living somewhere in California.

347
00:35:32,810 --> 00:35:33,760
- 不知道具体是那里  - 不
- But you don't know where?  - No.

348
00:35:33,800 --> 00:35:36,660
帮这位女士尺骨未端拍一张X光片
She may be distended on her left proximal radius and ulna,

349
00:35:36,660 --> 00:35:37,670
我过一会就来
be back in a few minutes.

350
00:35:38,140 --> 00:35:40,380
请坐在这里 脱下你的的外套
Could you sit over here, please, and take your own coat off.

351
00:35:40,390 --> 00:35:43,260
我没有骨折 只有一点点的疼痛而已
Ya know, there's nothing wrong with my arm, it's just a little bit sore.

352
00:35:43,270 --> 00:35:45,690
我们确认一下总是安全的
Let's be on the safe side and check it out anyway, okay?

353
00:35:46,690 --> 00:35:48,050
等这里完事后
When we're finish here,

354
00:35:48,050 --> 00:35:50,450
请您跟我回局里做个笔录合口供
we need you to come to the station and fill-out a statement.

355
00:35:50,940 --> 00:35:53,320
- 他们会怎么样  - 请不要动
- What's gonna happen to them?  - Hold still, please.

356
00:35:53,360 --> 00:35:56,480
持枪绑架 至少要判九到十二年监禁
Kidnapping with a dangerous weapon carries a minimum of 9 to 12 years.

357
00:35:56,700 --> 00:35:58,320
十二年监禁
12 years?

358
00:35:59,790 --> 00:36:02,810
- 你怎么样  - 没事
- How are ya?  - Fine.

359
00:36:02,920 --> 00:36:06,080
事发当时 你有没有注意到不寻常的迹象吗
Did anything unusual happen to you or the others prior to the accident?

360
00:36:06,290 --> 00:36:07,320
比如说像什么
Like what?

361
00:36:07,340 --> 00:36:11,220
可能是奇怪的放电现象 诸如此类吧
Well, did you come in contact with any radiation or anything like that?

362
00:36:13,090 --> 00:36:14,710
我也说不准
I don't know, I mean,

363
00:36:14,720 --> 00:36:17,280
我的汽车突然的发出红光
the car just, like, just lit-up before we hit the barricade

364
00:36:17,420 --> 00:36:20,570
- 不知道是什么原因  - 转动你的手臂
- I don't really know what caused it.  - Turn your arm, please.

365
00:36:20,980 --> 00:36:22,410
为什么 什么是错的
Why, what's wrong?

366
00:36:22,520 --> 00:36:25,760
一个人快要死了 但老实说我还没找到原因
There's a man dying up there and for the life of me I don't know why.

367
00:36:26,770 --> 00:36:31,330
- 为什么不找他朋友谈谈  - 他不肯和任何人交谈
- Well, why don't you talk to his friend?  - He refuses to talk to anyone.

368
00:36:32,900 --> 00:36:35,830
请别动 谢谢
Don't move, please... thank you.

369
00:37:19,180 --> 00:37:21,680
你想抽支烟吗
Would you like a cigarette?

370
00:37:22,760 --> 00:37:24,020
是
Yeah.

371
00:37:33,410 --> 00:37:35,530
- 谢谢  - 当然
- Thank you.  - Sure.

372
00:37:38,760 --> 00:37:41,210
你为什么要打伴成这样
What the hell are you dressed like that for?

373
00:37:43,850 --> 00:37:45,550
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?

374
00:37:45,970 --> 00:37:47,220
赫迪
Herdeg!

375
00:37:51,740 --> 00:37:57,340
祝好运 水手
Good luck... sailor.

376
00:37:57,950 --> 00:38:01,240
- 她为什么不想起诉  - 她就是那样说
- Now, what do you mean she won't press charges?  - That's what she said.

377
00:38:01,450 --> 00:38:02,620
那对老夫妇呢
The old couple?

378
00:38:02,830 --> 00:38:04,430
他们说他们不想在再惹更多的麻烦了
They don't want to drive into town,

379
00:38:04,430 --> 00:38:06,030
他们还想继续做生意
said they can't run their business and be at the court.

380
00:38:06,250 --> 00:38:07,290
天啊
Jesus Christ!

381
00:38:07,290 --> 00:38:09,400
自己都放弃了 还指望别人来帮他们
How do these people expect us to help them,

382
00:38:09,400 --> 00:38:10,290
真是太让人意外了
when they won't help themselves?

383
00:38:11,550 --> 00:38:14,070
难怪这世界这么乱 见鬼去吧
No wonder the God damned country's going to hell.

384
00:38:17,740 --> 00:38:19,820
艾莉森 这是警长贝茨
Excuse me, Allison, this is the Sheriff Bates.

385
00:38:19,820 --> 00:38:21,350
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.

386
00:38:21,810 --> 00:38:24,280
我听说你不打算起诉了吗
I understand you don't want to press charges anymore?

387
00:38:24,280 --> 00:38:25,810
请告诉我为什么呢
Can you tell me why?

388
00:38:26,730 --> 00:38:29,500
- 是的 我改变了主意  - 就这样
- I changed my mind.  - Just like that?

389
00:38:29,570 --> 00:38:32,110
没有任何理由你就决定了
No particular reason, you just decided to let

390
00:38:32,110 --> 00:38:35,050
我要放走的家伙可是绑架了你的人
the guys get away with kidnapping you?

391
00:38:35,530 --> 00:38:38,950
我只是觉得不应该让他们去坐十二年的牢
I just don't think they deserve to go to jail for 12 years,

392
00:38:38,950 --> 00:38:40,490
他们遇到了别的麻烦
they have other problems

393
00:38:40,660 --> 00:38:45,170
他们现在要解决的问题是 别再拿枪指着别人
We've all got problems, honey, but we don't solve 'em with guns.

394
00:38:48,790 --> 00:38:50,870
你确定不想再改主意了
Now, you SURE you won't change your mind?

395
00:38:51,590 --> 00:38:53,130
确定
I'm sure.

396
00:38:56,910 --> 00:38:59,530
你知道吗 你是个幸运的兔崽子
You're a lucky sonofabitch, you know that?

397
00:39:05,440 --> 00:39:07,030
祝你好运
Good luck.

398
00:39:10,380 --> 00:39:13,660
- 你还好吗  - 很好
- How you doin'?  - Fine.

399
00:39:15,200 --> 00:39:19,700
我们还没有相互自我介绍 我叫艾莉森 海斯
We haven't actually met yet, I'm Allison Hayes.

400
00:39:20,510 --> 00:39:22,390
大卫 赫迪
David Herdeg.

401
00:39:32,420 --> 00:39:33,800
那里感觉怎样
How does that feel?

402
00:39:33,800 --> 00:39:40,330
卡农医生到精神一科 卡农医生马上到到精神一科
Dr. Cannon to Neuro 1, Dr. Cannon to Neuro 1 immediately.

403
00:39:47,230 --> 00:39:50,100
嘿 吉米 你还好吧
Hey, Jimmy, how you doin'?

404
00:39:52,610 --> 00:39:54,090
大卫
Davey.

405
00:39:56,530 --> 00:40:00,020
我做了一个伤心的梦
I was having this... dream.

406
00:40:02,240 --> 00:40:07,790
- 那是帕米拉是吗  - 不是
- Pam? Is that... is Pam with you?  - No.

407
00:40:11,440 --> 00:40:14,430
孩子就要出生了
The baby's coming... soon.

408
00:40:15,170 --> 00:40:18,060
她希望生个男孩
She wants it... to be a boy.

409
00:40:19,200 --> 00:40:22,180
她说要生个男孩子
She said, "Make it a boy."

410
00:40:26,850 --> 00:40:31,000
大卫 不要离开我 我不能忍受了
Don't leave me, Davey, I can't go through this again.

411
00:40:38,320 --> 00:40:41,120
对不起 请你们马上离开
I'm sorry, you're going to have to leave right now, thank you.

412
00:40:45,350 --> 00:40:48,250
- 我们要叫医生吗  - 他没事 他马上就会好的
- Do we need the doctor?  - No, I think he's gonna be all right.

413
00:40:48,350 --> 00:40:51,300
如果你不告诉我说发生了什么事的话 我是帮不了你们的
They can't help him if you DON'T tell them what happened.

414
00:40:56,760 --> 00:41:00,650
- 我们参加了一次试验  - 怎么样的试验
- We were involved in an experiment.  - What kind of an experiment?

415
00:41:02,390 --> 00:41:04,790
电子战的 对抗敌方雷达
It's electronic... deflecting radar

416
00:41:04,790 --> 00:41:07,560
以使海上的船舰无法被敌人发现
so a ship couldn't be detected at sea...

417
00:41:07,560 --> 00:41:09,560
我并不十分明白
I didn't understand all of it.

418
00:41:10,570 --> 00:41:15,970
你们被暴露在强电场 或其他什么的
You were exposed to an electronic energy field of some sort?

419
00:41:17,530 --> 00:41:21,860
我想是的 但是试验间出了别的事情
I think so, but there was something else... something else happened.

420
00:41:23,490 --> 00:41:28,900
然后我们便遇到了这荒谬的事情 仅我们两个人
We got caught-up in this freak thing... just the two of us.

421
00:41:30,000 --> 00:41:31,720
我不知道这到底算什么
I don't know what it was,

422
00:41:31,720 --> 00:41:33,890
但不知何故 我们做了时空旅行
but somehow we got moved in time.

423
00:41:34,610 --> 00:41:36,100
什么意思
What do you mean?

424
00:41:37,470 --> 00:41:39,230
现在此时此刻
Time... this now, this time,

425
00:41:39,230 --> 00:41:43,880
并不是属于我们的时间 不知道为什么会这样
it's not ours, we weren't here when it happened.

426
00:41:44,140 --> 00:41:46,850
试验是在费城军港内的一艘军舰上进行的
The experiment took place on a ship in a Philadelphia Harbor.

427
00:41:47,060 --> 00:41:49,880
时间是一九四三年十月
It was 1943... October.

428
00:41:54,230 --> 00:41:56,280
这听起来很疯狂吗
Does this sound crazy,

429
00:41:56,280 --> 00:41:59,160
要知道 这并非不是不可能的
ya know, or is this sort of thing possible now?

430
00:42:01,990 --> 00:42:04,760
你对一九四三年的记忆是如何
What are your memories of 1943?

431
00:42:05,200 --> 00:42:06,990
还清晰吗
Are they clear to you?

432
00:42:07,750 --> 00:42:09,200
你认为是我编造了一切
You think I'm makin' this up?

433
00:42:09,290 --> 00:42:10,870
我没那样说过
I didn't say that,

434
00:42:10,870 --> 00:42:14,430
我只是想要你描述一些一九四三年的事务
I just want you to describe something in 1943 for me.

435
00:42:14,460 --> 00:42:17,630
我可以告诉你一切 一九四三年对我而言这是昨天
I can describe everything! 1943 was yesterday for me!

436
00:42:17,630 --> 00:42:18,740
那就设法让我相信
I'm not doubting you, Mr. Herdeg.

437
00:42:18,740 --> 00:42:21,330
你不会相信我的 我说什么你都不会信
Like hell you're not doubting me, you don't believe anything I'm sayin'.

438
00:42:21,370 --> 00:42:22,800
大卫 他只是想帮助你
David, he's just trying to help.

439
00:42:22,850 --> 00:42:25,200
嘿 我没有说谎 你觉得这些都是我编的
Hey! Look! I'm not lying! You think I'd make this up?

440
00:42:25,200 --> 00:42:27,200
我为什么要编呢
What the hell would I make it up for?

441
00:42:27,570 --> 00:42:30,710
- 是的  - 医生 请你赶快过来一下
- Yes.  - Dr. Magnussen, you better come quickly.

442
00:42:31,210 --> 00:42:34,980
- 怎么回事呢  - 这是B病房的病人
- What is it?  - It's the patient in B.

443
00:42:36,550 --> 00:42:38,610
抱歉 请原谅
You'll have to excuse me a moment.

444
00:42:40,220 --> 00:42:42,360
是吉米 我敢肯定是吉米
That's Jimmy, I know it's Jimmy!

445
00:42:52,250 --> 00:42:54,850
- 给他注射安定剂  - 我们已经注射了十毫克了
- Give him I.V. valium!  - I've already given him 10 milligrams!

446
00:42:54,890 --> 00:42:55,930
准备CPR急救
Stand by C.P.R.

447
00:42:58,490 --> 00:43:02,050
- 对不起 请让一让  - 快点弄进来
- Excuse me, clear the way!  - Come on, let's get that in here.

448
00:43:02,820 --> 00:43:04,750
让开让担架进来
Clear for the backboard coming in.

449
00:43:05,840 --> 00:43:07,230
急救设备进来
Ambu bag coming in.

450
00:43:16,990 --> 00:43:19,270
用力按住他别让他伤到自己
Try and restrain him so he doesn't hurt himself!

451
00:43:19,870 --> 00:43:22,300
- 这里发生了什么呢  - 多拿点胰岛素来
- What the hell is going on here?  - Get some more insulin here.

452
00:43:25,830 --> 00:43:28,330
后退
Get back! Get back! Get back!

453
00:43:29,040 --> 00:43:30,290
后退
Get back.

454
00:43:35,460 --> 00:43:37,500
别接触到他
Don't let anybody touch him!

455
00:43:39,890 --> 00:43:41,260
我的天啊
Oh, my God.

456
00:43:47,560 --> 00:43:50,020
大卫 大卫 你去那里
David, what's wrong?

457
00:43:50,380 --> 00:43:54,300
大卫 等等 让我走 我想和他一起
David? David, wait... let me go, I want to be with him.

458
00:43:54,330 --> 00:43:56,700
别过去 他很危险的
Stay away from him, I don't know what it is, but...

459
00:43:56,710 --> 00:43:58,970
- 他就另外一个  - 逮捕他
- That's the other one.  - Pick him up!

460
00:43:59,600 --> 00:44:00,660
大卫
David?

461
00:44:03,470 --> 00:44:04,750
你去哪里
Where are you going?

462
00:44:15,490 --> 00:44:17,370
- 到底是什么  - 另一个电梯
- What the heck!  - I got the other elevator.

463
00:44:17,370 --> 00:44:19,050
到五楼 统计
Security, to 5th floor, stat.

464
00:44:19,490 --> 00:44:22,320
到五楼 统计
Security, to 5th floor, stat.

465
00:44:39,240 --> 00:44:42,610
- 我必需要逮捕你回去 办不到  - 我什么也没做
- Look, I'm gonna have to take you in.  - I didn't do anything.

466
00:44:43,120 --> 00:44:46,340
- 你让我别无选择  - 我又没有做任何事情
- Don't give me any trouble.  - I didn't do anything!

467
00:44:46,770 --> 00:44:48,340
你在干嘛
What are you doing?

468
00:44:49,280 --> 00:44:51,470
现在小心 停下
Look out now! Stop that shit!

469
00:45:05,140 --> 00:45:06,600
他在那里
There he is!

470
00:45:22,050 --> 00:45:23,270
妈的 该死
Aw, shit!

471
00:45:37,230 --> 00:45:38,600
走楼梯 快
Up the stairs!

472
00:45:48,160 --> 00:45:50,050
对不起
Sorry, sorry.

473
00:45:50,520 --> 00:45:52,430
来吧 别让他跑了
Come on, God damn it, let's go!

474
00:46:10,250 --> 00:46:12,230
你在这干什么 快离开这
What the hell are you doing, get outta here!

475
00:46:12,350 --> 00:46:15,020
大卫 快上车
David! David get in!

476
00:46:17,000 --> 00:46:18,940
- 拦住他 该死 拦住他  - 他们是谁
- Stop him! God damn it, stop him!  - Who are they?

477
00:46:18,940 --> 00:46:20,500
我不知道 继续走
I don't know, just keep goin'.

478
00:46:21,280 --> 00:46:22,550
吉米是怎么回事
What happened to Jimmy?

479
00:46:22,660 --> 00:46:23,900
是因为那个什么秘密试验
Does it have to do with the experiment?

480
00:46:23,900 --> 00:46:26,900
是一个秘密 对不对
Is it... is it some kind of secret thing? Is that it?

481
00:46:27,310 --> 00:46:31,220
天啊 大卫 我希望能帮助你 请告诉我
For God's sake, David, I'm just trying to understand! I want to help you!

482
00:46:31,500 --> 00:46:34,240
- 你知道加州的圣保拉吗  - 不知道
- Do you know where Santa Paula, California is?  - No.

483
00:46:35,570 --> 00:46:37,700
你的家人在那里是不是
Is your family there, is that it?

484
00:46:38,130 --> 00:46:39,700
以前是
They used to be.

485
00:46:41,110 --> 00:46:44,660
我正好要去洛杉矶 顺路 我们去看看
I have to go to Los Angeles anyway... we'll find it.

486
00:46:46,240 --> 00:46:48,450
你为什么要为我做这一切
Why are you doin' all this, Allison?

487
00:46:49,790 --> 00:46:51,580
我也不知道
I don't know.

488
00:46:51,620 --> 00:46:54,610
我对医生说的那些话
All that stuff I told the doctor back there, did you believe it,

489
00:46:54,610 --> 00:46:55,700
你相信吗
believe any of it?

490
00:46:57,590 --> 00:46:59,790
我相信你所相信的
I believe that you believe.

491
00:47:24,700 --> 00:47:28,070
- 读数如何  - 我想是仪器失灵了
- How's your reading?  - I think there's a malfunction.

492
00:47:28,120 --> 00:47:31,770
气压力不断在降低 这是不可能的
I keep getting negative pressure and it keeps dropping, it's impossible.

493
00:47:31,830 --> 00:47:36,090
不 空气正在被吸进去 它会把一切都吸进去
No, it's pulling the air in, it's pulling everything in.

494
00:47:36,220 --> 00:47:39,980
- 怎么吸  - 天上有个洞 巴尼
- How?  - We opened up a hole, Barney.

495
00:47:40,400 --> 00:47:44,310
是我们打开的 而且关不上
We opened it up and it stayed open.

496
00:47:47,220 --> 00:47:53,360
我的老天 你感觉到了吗 你能感觉到它的能量
My God, you can feel it, you can you feel the energy.

497
00:48:03,610 --> 00:48:06,970
内华达州上空的低气压云团仍然持续
What is described as a freakish low pressure system continues

498
00:48:06,970 --> 00:48:08,280
而且不断扩大中
to stall over Nevada,

499
00:48:08,510 --> 00:48:11,990
导致数千人与外界失去联络 一百五十英里时速的风速
leaving thousands virtually cut off from the rest of the world.

500
00:48:12,030 --> 00:48:14,200
附近的传输电缆线已经被关闭 到处都在停电
With roads closed, power wires down...

501
00:48:14,210 --> 00:48:18,180
损坏了主要输电线路
...to one hundred fifty miles an hour have downed major power lines

502
00:48:18,210 --> 00:48:20,490
导致数百户住家停电
leaving hundreds of families without power...

503
00:48:20,590 --> 00:48:24,150
麦金塔出品的个人电脑
...personal computer from Digital with two separate microprocessors.

504
00:48:24,180 --> 00:48:25,220
拥有两个高阶处理器
One for today's jobs,

505
00:48:25,220 --> 00:48:26,930
一个为今日工作 另一个为明日的生活
another for tomorrow.

506
00:48:26,970 --> 00:48:29,110
彩虹系列 来自麦金塔电脑设备有限公司
The Rainbow from Digital Equipment Corporation,

507
00:48:29,110 --> 00:48:32,110
欢迎来电询问 一 八〇〇 〇八〇〇
call 1-800-DIGITAL for the store nearest you.

508
00:48:32,350 --> 00:48:33,220
电话
Phone!

509
00:48:33,440 --> 00:48:35,730
- 你要我先接那个  - 两个都接
- What do you want me to answer first?  - Both!

510
00:48:35,830 --> 00:48:38,220
两个都接
Both of 'em! Both of 'em!

511
00:48:39,000 --> 00:48:41,800
请稍等 谢谢
Hold the line please... thank you.

512
00:48:57,610 --> 00:48:59,540
今晚走不了了
It's unbelievable out there!

513
00:48:59,540 --> 00:49:02,540
我把车藏起来了 明天去租另一辆
Oh, I hid the car around back, we can rent a new one in the morning.

514
00:49:04,260 --> 00:49:06,090
喔 你在看老电影
Oh, I see you found an old movie to watch?

515
00:49:06,300 --> 00:49:08,840
是啊 至少那些我还能看的懂
Yeah, it's the only thing I seem to understand around here.

516
00:49:11,600 --> 00:49:15,360
我给你买了些杂志 还有替换的衣服
I got you some magazines and a change of clothes... I hope they fit.

517
00:49:15,690 --> 00:49:17,080
我不知道
Hey, ya know, I don't know how

518
00:49:17,080 --> 00:49:19,640
或许我无法尝还你的这些
I'm gonna be able to pay you back for all this.

519
00:49:19,800 --> 00:49:23,110
不用担心这个 你喜欢中国菜吗
Don't worry about it now. You like Chinese food?

520
00:49:23,200 --> 00:49:26,380
- 喜欢 那很好吃-祝你好胃口
- Yeah, sounds good.  - Enjoy.

521
00:49:29,210 --> 00:49:30,740
筷子 这个给你
Here, dig in.

522
00:49:37,840 --> 00:49:39,340
你怎么了
Are you okay?

523
00:49:40,170 --> 00:49:42,840
就算我们到达了加州圣保拉
What if we get all the way out to Santa Paula, and...

524
00:49:43,470 --> 00:49:45,370
我也不知道他是否还活着
there's nobody left out there left alive that I know?

525
00:49:45,370 --> 00:49:47,430
我来的时候我父亲已经不年轻了
My father isn't a young man.

526
00:49:47,550 --> 00:49:49,640
打个电话问清楚就好了
Well, let's call, we'll find out.

527
00:49:50,450 --> 00:49:51,850
他家没有电话
He doesn't have a phone.

528
00:49:53,040 --> 00:49:55,970
大卫 现在每个人都有电话 试试看
David, everyone has a phone... let's try.

529
00:50:06,780 --> 00:50:10,630
我想查询 加州的圣保拉
Uh, yes, information please for Santa Paula, California, the number for...

530
00:50:10,680 --> 00:50:14,090
- 约翰 赫迪的电话号码  - 约翰 赫迪 是赫迪
- John Herdeg.  - John Herdeg, that's H-E-R-D-E-G.

531
00:50:14,090 --> 00:50:15,710
好的
Right, right, right.

532
00:50:18,000 --> 00:50:19,550
有附近其他别的地址吗
Is there any other place?

533
00:50:20,500 --> 00:50:22,600
试试“帕克牧场” 那里以前有电话
Try the Parker Ranch, they always had a phone.

534
00:50:22,800 --> 00:50:25,040
请帮我查查“帕克牧场”谢谢
Do you have the number for the Parker Ranch?

535
00:50:27,230 --> 00:50:28,560
谢谢
Thank you.

536
00:50:37,000 --> 00:50:38,520
通了
It's ringing.

537
00:50:39,020 --> 00:50:41,270
我要说什么
But what... what am I gonna say to 'em?

538
00:50:42,240 --> 00:50:45,290
喂 有听到吗 你是谁
Hello, who's this speaking, please?

539
00:50:47,370 --> 00:50:48,770
帕米拉
Pam?

540
00:50:53,120 --> 00:50:54,330
发生什么事了吗
What happened?

541
00:50:54,410 --> 00:50:57,080
是她 吉米的妻子帕米拉
It was her! It was Jim's wife, Pamela.

542
00:50:57,080 --> 00:50:58,790
那你为什么挂电话
Well, why... why did you hang up?

543
00:50:58,790 --> 00:51:01,200
我要怎么跟她吗
What am I gonna say to her?

544
00:51:01,880 --> 00:51:05,010
好吧 还不错 现在至少我们知道她在那里
Well, that's good, at least we know she's there.

545
00:51:05,010 --> 00:51:07,760
那又怎样 要是他那我不在等我们呢
What if they're there? What if they're waitin' for us?

546
00:51:07,760 --> 00:51:09,760
天晓得他们是不是设了个陷阱在等我们
They know where I'm from, this could all be a trap!

547
00:51:10,350 --> 00:51:13,850
或许我们该找别人说说这件事
Well... maybe we should tell the story to someone else

548
00:51:13,890 --> 00:51:15,410
是啊 你不相信这件事 对吗
and get them to come with us

549
00:51:15,410 --> 00:51:16,510
等等 你不相信这个故事
Wait, the story you don't believe right, that one?

550
00:51:16,540 --> 00:51:18,990
大卫 我不知道该相信什么
David, I don't know what to believe,

551
00:51:18,990 --> 00:51:19,980
你又怎么知道
how do you know what to believe? Maybe...

552
00:51:20,120 --> 00:51:23,230
或许他们给你下了药 也许这一切都不是真实的
maybe they gave you some drugs, maybe none of this is real at all.

553
00:51:23,400 --> 00:51:27,480
哦 是的 当然 就是这样 这是不是真的
Yeah, maybe none of this is real. Hey! Maybe this isn't real, right?

554
00:51:27,700 --> 00:51:28,800
是啊 不是真的
Maybe this isn't real! I mean,

555
00:51:28,800 --> 00:51:30,230
或许这也不是真的 对不对
maybe this isn't real, maybe none of this is real!

556
00:51:30,240 --> 00:51:31,900
或许这一切都不是真的 也许你不是真的
Maybe I'm not real! Maybe you're not real!

557
00:51:32,120 --> 00:51:33,400
这个怎么样
How about that?

558
00:51:40,170 --> 00:51:41,580
听着
Look...

559
00:51:42,030 --> 00:51:44,900
我想我可能没办法再帮你了
All right, ya know, I don't think I can really help you anymore,

560
00:51:44,900 --> 00:51:48,930
你必须自己想办法了 你一个人
I think you gotta go through this, ya know, by yourself, and...

561
00:51:49,430 --> 00:51:52,180
我知道你有困难 但是我也被吓坏了
I'm sure you're gonna be fine, but, ya know,

562
00:51:52,180 --> 00:51:55,180
很害怕 所以 我们还是再见 好吗
I'm scared, too, so, I'll see ya later, okay?

563
00:52:00,960 --> 00:52:04,030
留下来 求你
Wait... please.

564
00:52:05,400 --> 00:52:08,390
听着 我很抱歉 艾莉森
Look, I'm sorry, Allison.

565
00:52:10,280 --> 00:52:12,360
我没打算伤害你
I didn't mean to hurt you.

566
00:52:14,790 --> 00:52:16,800
请留下和我一起
Please stay with me.

567
00:52:19,080 --> 00:52:20,500
我需要你
I need you.

568
00:52:23,490 --> 00:52:25,060
真的 拜托
Please.

569
00:53:15,560 --> 00:53:16,920
令人难以置信
I can't believe this,

570
00:53:16,920 --> 00:53:20,670
德国和日本是我们的盟友 俄罗斯是我们的敌人
Germany and Japan are our friends, and Russia's the enemy now?

571
00:53:20,750 --> 00:53:23,540
- 你不觉得累吗 大卫  - 是的
- Aren't you getting tired, David?  - Yeah.

572
00:53:23,540 --> 00:53:26,700
闹钟已设定时间 六点一刻
Alarm set, six thirty a.m.

573
00:53:27,910 --> 00:53:31,720
- 别睡太晚了 好吗  - 好的
- Well, don't stay up too late, okay?  - Okay.

574
00:53:31,790 --> 00:53:33,370
晚安
G'night.

575
00:53:34,610 --> 00:53:35,580
晚安
G'night.

576
00:53:35,680 --> 00:53:38,490
但是每一次他们在这里实验
But we just know that every time they do an experiment around here,

577
00:53:38,490 --> 00:53:39,490
天气都会变化
the weather changes.

578
00:53:42,750 --> 00:53:46,250
他们应该为这一切负责
They're responsible for everything that's goin' on around here.

579
00:53:48,530 --> 00:53:50,600
我们现在联系到了朗斯特博士
We tried to contact Dr. James Longstreet,

580
00:53:50,640 --> 00:53:53,990
本次试验的负责人
who is in charge of experiments here at the Base, but unfortunately

581
00:53:54,060 --> 00:53:56,690
- 但很可惜他不能来  - 她刚刚说谁
- he's unavailable for comment.  - What was that name she just said?

582
00:53:56,820 --> 00:53:59,110
什么 谢谢你的报道 玛格丽特
What? Thanks for your report, Margaret, we'll be

583
00:53:59,190 --> 00:54:01,760
我们待命以为将来的发展 没事的
standing by for future developments. Nothing, never mind.

584
00:54:01,970 --> 00:54:03,950
现在去国会
And now moving to the national

585
00:54:03,950 --> 00:54:07,190
曾经在好莱坞拒绝聘用导演
in Hollywood once, who refused to hire his director,

586
00:54:07,220 --> 00:54:08,370
他们拒绝
in the picture they refused to hire the director

587
00:54:08,370 --> 00:54:10,400
聘用导演是错的
before it turned out to be a failure.

588
00:54:10,570 --> 00:54:12,100
- 接下来导演的名字出现了  - 艾莉森
- The next time the director's name came up  - Allison!

589
00:54:12,100 --> 00:54:14,400
- 制片人说 不 他是  - 什么事
- the producer said, no, he was  - What?

590
00:54:14,540 --> 00:54:16,930
我认识这个人这不是电影吧
I know this guy! Is this another movie?

591
00:54:18,540 --> 00:54:22,000
不 大卫 这不是电影
No, David, this is not a movie.

592
00:54:35,250 --> 00:54:45,730
现在时间十二点二十六分
Twelve forty-six a.m., Twelve forty-six a.m., Twelve forty-six a.m.

593
00:54:47,610 --> 00:54:48,900
抱歉
Sorry.

594
00:54:51,460 --> 00:54:52,810
晚安
G'night.

595
00:55:20,480 --> 00:55:22,720
一定有什么东西维持着连接
It almost seems connected to something in this area.

596
00:55:22,940 --> 00:55:26,080
相较原先的试验地点已经移动了五十英里
It hasn't moved more than 50 miles from the original test site, since...

597
00:55:26,190 --> 00:55:27,770
现在的位置
Where is it now?

598
00:55:28,680 --> 00:55:30,650
- 待命  - 在第二象限
- Standby!  - B quadrant.

599
00:55:30,680 --> 00:55:33,090
- 正朝我们这里来  - 不稳定
- Moving this way again.  - Destabilizing.

600
00:55:34,290 --> 00:55:36,770
摄影机运载火箭已经就位 长官
Cameras moving into position now, Sir.

601
00:56:01,850 --> 00:56:03,180
准备发射
Launch ready.

602
00:56:03,570 --> 00:56:05,430
摄影机准备就绪 长官
Cameras mounted and ready, Sir.

603
00:56:05,470 --> 00:56:08,820
好吧 让我们看看那里面到底有什么
Okay, let's see what the hell we got in there. .

604
00:56:08,820 --> 00:56:10,820
这里是指挥部 开始执行
This is control, commence operations

605
00:56:19,120 --> 00:56:20,920
发射
Sequence activated.

606
00:56:25,800 --> 00:56:28,460
发射完毕 一五二〇
Launch complete, fifteen hundred and twenty.

607
00:56:28,740 --> 00:56:29,790
一千二百
Twelve hundred.

608
00:56:30,270 --> 00:56:33,170
九 八 七
9, 8, 7,

609
00:56:33,540 --> 00:56:36,360
六 五 四
6, 5, 4,

610
00:56:36,410 --> 00:56:40,790
进去了
3, 2, 1. We're in.

611
00:56:46,690 --> 00:56:49,060
- 天啊 在那里  - 那是什么
- Good God, there it is!  - What is that?

612
00:56:49,060 --> 00:56:50,810
消失的城镇
It's the town.

613
00:56:53,600 --> 00:56:56,940
- 该死  - 那是艘船  - 怎么会有艘船
- What the hell!  - Is that a ship?  - What's a ship doing in there?

614
00:57:03,440 --> 00:57:05,290
回放画面
Play it back.

615
00:57:09,970 --> 00:57:12,420
找保安部克拉克少校
Major Clark from security there?

616
00:57:14,100 --> 00:57:16,260
请让他尽快到这里来
Let me know as soon as he is, please.

617
00:57:19,350 --> 00:57:21,470
好了 我们看到它
All right, here it comes again.

618
00:58:10,070 --> 00:58:12,880
那工作只是给了我一个
That job was just an excuse to get to L.A.

619
00:58:12,880 --> 00:58:15,000
去洛杉矶的借口而已
It's where I want to go, anyway.

620
00:58:15,160 --> 00:58:17,230
那里有很多机遇
There are a lot of opportunities out there.

621
00:58:17,540 --> 00:58:20,550
知道吗 我有双学历
You know, I have two diplomas. One from an art school.

622
00:58:20,550 --> 00:58:22,310
还有双份奖学金
I've won a couple of awards.

623
00:58:22,330 --> 00:58:25,020
我在辛辛那提是优等生
I'm very well thought of in Cincinnati!

624
00:58:26,460 --> 00:58:27,920
不骗你
I am!

625
00:58:28,590 --> 00:58:31,210
你现在也很优秀啊
You're very well thought of here, too.

626
00:58:32,340 --> 00:58:34,830
我就是想去洛杉矶看看
I just know when I get to L.A. somethin's gonna work out.

627
00:58:35,080 --> 00:58:36,690
应该会很好
It's gonna be fine.

628
00:58:39,180 --> 00:58:42,190
这让我想起了麦克
What pisses me off is that jerk Michael.

629
00:58:42,220 --> 00:58:44,750
我通常善于分析人的个性
I'm usually a good judge of character.

630
00:58:45,440 --> 00:58:48,020
- 我烦到你了吗  - 没
- Does the music bother you?  - No.

631
00:58:49,780 --> 00:58:51,900
那你后半生呢
What about the rest of life?

632
00:58:53,140 --> 00:58:55,200
你结婚了吗
Don't you want to get married?

633
00:58:55,680 --> 00:58:57,660
现在还没有 还没有遇得到合适的人
Yeah, if I meet the right guy.

634
00:58:57,870 --> 00:59:00,080
孩子呢 要不要孩子
Kids? Don't you want to have kids?

635
00:59:00,110 --> 00:59:02,530
不一定要非结婚才能有孩子
You don't have to be married to do that!

636
00:59:03,750 --> 00:59:06,230
哦 我永远不会同意那种说法
Ah, I'm never gonna agree with that.

637
00:59:07,230 --> 00:59:09,650
- 要喝可乐吗  - 好啊
- Do you want a Coke?  - Yeah.

638
00:59:15,240 --> 00:59:17,120
你怎么弄的
How did you do that?

639
00:59:23,330 --> 00:59:25,200
帮了我大忙
Hey, that's pretty neat.

640
00:59:26,270 --> 00:59:29,570
- 你为什么加入海军  - 知道一句彦语吗
- Why did you join the Navy?  - You know the old saying:

641
00:59:30,170 --> 00:59:32,270
“每个港口都有女孩在等你”
"A girl in every port."

642
00:59:33,800 --> 00:59:36,970
- 你喜欢旅行  - 是的
- Do you like to travel?  - Yeah.

643
00:59:37,010 --> 00:59:38,590
我也是
Yeah, me too.

644
00:59:39,060 --> 00:59:41,920
- 不介意吧  - 没关系
- Do you mind?  - Go ahead.

645
00:59:43,830 --> 00:59:46,530
- 这才适合我  - 很好听
- That's me.  - Yeah.

646
00:59:48,000 --> 00:59:50,920
- 那是什么  - 喔 因该是一辆保时捷
- What is that?  - Oh, I think it's a Porsche.

647
00:59:51,470 --> 00:59:53,330
那车的很适合我
Now that's REALLY me.

648
01:00:21,880 --> 01:00:24,360
这就是消失了的那个人
This is the one that disappeared.

649
01:00:29,930 --> 01:00:31,450
帕克 吉米
Parker.

650
01:00:42,760 --> 01:00:44,690
这是另一个人吗
Is that the other one?

651
01:00:46,200 --> 01:00:48,620
是的 大卫 赫迪
Yes, this is the Herdeg.

652
01:00:51,620 --> 01:00:53,220
就是他
That's him.

653
01:00:54,130 --> 01:00:55,330
谢谢你 医生
Thank you, Doctor.

654
01:00:55,630 --> 01:00:58,510
我想了解更多 帕克到底发生什么事
I'd like to know more about what happened to Parker.

655
01:00:58,590 --> 01:01:01,850
我很感谢你的关心 但现在不是时候
I appreciate your curiosity but this is not the time.

656
01:01:01,860 --> 01:01:04,710
我的司机会送您回医院去 医生
But he's... My driver will take you back now, Doctor.

657
01:01:05,890 --> 01:01:08,150
再次感谢
And thank you.

658
01:01:14,770 --> 01:01:19,520
根据档案 他们都住在加州圣保拉
Herdeg's file, they both lived in Santa Paula, California.

659
01:01:23,030 --> 01:01:27,450
- 你怎么知道的  - 少校 请只管尽快找到他们
- How did you know?  - Major, would you just bring him in, please.

660
01:01:34,580 --> 01:01:36,040
最新报告
The latest run.

661
01:01:36,190 --> 01:01:38,650
那个气旋涡已经扩大了两倍了
The vortex is almost twice the size.

662
01:01:38,660 --> 01:01:40,800
它已经开始吸收入地表的物质
It started pulling at surface matter.

663
01:01:40,860 --> 01:01:44,710
詹姆士 不快点想办法设法让它停下来
James, if we don't stop this thing soon,

664
01:01:44,710 --> 01:01:46,450
整个地球都要遭殃了
the whole damned planet's in trouble.

665
01:01:47,660 --> 01:01:50,290
我们到底该怎么办
What the hell are we gonna do?

666
01:02:04,700 --> 01:02:07,390
那个就是吉米结婚的教堂
That's the church Jimmy got married in.

667
01:02:09,450 --> 01:02:12,210
这是火车站 看上去还不错
That's the railroad station... looks good.

668
01:02:13,170 --> 01:02:16,000
现在 我们看到的这颗大的树
And here we come up to the big tree.

669
01:02:16,250 --> 01:02:18,900
它现在可能已经超过一百岁了
It must be over a hundred years old by now.

670
01:02:19,210 --> 01:02:21,260
上面刻有我的名字
My name's carved in it somewhere.

671
01:02:33,140 --> 01:02:35,020
那是你父亲的修车厂
Is that your father's place?

672
01:02:36,310 --> 01:02:38,220
已经变了样子
It's different.

673
01:02:39,030 --> 01:02:43,830
我们过去加点油 看看到底怎样
Well, let's get some gas and check it out.

674
01:03:09,720 --> 01:03:11,850
我和你一起
I'll be right with ya!

675
01:03:18,980 --> 01:03:21,100
有什么我可以效劳的吗 伙计们
Now, what can I do for you folks?

676
01:03:21,100 --> 01:03:22,280
请帮忙把油加满好吗
Can you fill it up, please?

677
01:03:23,150 --> 01:03:25,260
- 无铅汽油  - 是的
- Unleaded?  - Yeah.

678
01:03:31,180 --> 01:03:33,760
- 是他吗  - 嗯
- Is that him?  - Yes.

679
01:03:33,990 --> 01:03:35,890
是个英俊的男子
Good looking man.

680
01:03:36,860 --> 01:03:40,410
那辆车是我们从新泽西带回来的赛车
That's the car we bought out with us when we moved from New Jersey.

681
01:03:43,970 --> 01:03:47,770
- 那是你  - 没错
- That's you.  - That's right.

682
01:03:49,220 --> 01:03:52,420
嘿 你们的车子油箱几乎就是满的啊
Hey, your car was almost full.

683
01:03:52,430 --> 01:03:53,950
要不要检查一下机油
Did you want me to check the oil?

684
01:03:53,980 --> 01:03:55,440
不 不用了
No, that's okay.

685
01:03:55,440 --> 01:03:57,940
你知道照片上那个人现在在那里
Do you know what happened to the guy in these pictures?

686
01:03:57,970 --> 01:04:00,090
- 约翰 赫迪  - 是的
- What, John Herdeg?  - Yeah.

687
01:04:00,110 --> 01:04:03,310
他是个很有名的家伙
Well, he was a pretty famous guy,

688
01:04:03,310 --> 01:04:05,060
得过很多大奖
won a helluva a lot of big races in his time.

689
01:04:05,110 --> 01:04:09,900
- 什么意思  - 不知道 应该是从四十或五十年代开始
- When was that?  - Oh, I don't know, late '40s, early '50s I guess.

690
01:04:11,330 --> 01:04:13,510
他后来搬回东部某个地方去了
He moved back East somewhere,

691
01:04:14,510 --> 01:04:17,510
那是绝大部份车赛举行的地方 几年前他去世了
that's where most of the racing circuits are... died a few years ago.

692
01:04:20,420 --> 01:04:25,200
你们车子的油箱本来就很满 只花了四块钱
Your car was almost full... it's only 4 dollars.

693
01:04:26,990 --> 01:04:28,510
大卫 我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

694
01:04:30,280 --> 01:04:31,730
大卫
David?

695
01:04:36,890 --> 01:04:39,430
大维 你没事吧
Thanks. David!

696
01:04:40,300 --> 01:04:43,980
- 要我来开车吗  - 不 我没事
- Do you want me to drive?  - No, I'm fine.

697
01:05:14,960 --> 01:05:16,940
对不起 大卫
I'm sorry, David.

698
01:05:19,340 --> 01:05:21,480
不 他很棒
But at least he made it.

699
01:05:22,190 --> 01:05:25,630
他实现了诺言 当时没人相信他能做到
He did what he said he was gonna do when nobody thought he could,

700
01:05:25,630 --> 01:05:27,190
即便是我我也不相信
not even me!

701
01:05:30,080 --> 01:05:31,990
你很棒 爸爸
Good for you, Pop.

702
01:05:33,450 --> 01:05:35,070
真的很棒
Good for you!

703
01:06:09,370 --> 01:06:13,170
- 要不要再打个电话  - 不会有事的
- I shoulda called her again.  - It'll be okay.

704
01:06:15,290 --> 01:06:17,570
如果她认出我来呢
What if she doesn't recognize me?

705
01:06:18,830 --> 01:06:20,600
那就全告诉她
We'll just tell her.

706
01:07:10,600 --> 01:07:12,260
有事吗
Can you help you?

707
01:07:12,640 --> 01:07:15,080
- 帕米拉  - 是
- Mrs. Parker?  - Yes.

708
01:07:15,970 --> 01:07:19,900
- 帕克太太吗  - 是
- Pamela?  - Yes.

709
01:07:20,400 --> 01:07:25,070
你还认识我吗 还记得起来吗
Don't you know me? Don't you recognize me?

710
01:07:25,570 --> 01:07:29,510
是我大卫 大卫 赫迪
It's me, it's David. It's Davey Herdeg.

711
01:07:32,990 --> 01:07:36,410
- 不 这不可能的 啊  - 真的是我 帕姆
- No, it's not, it can't be.  - It's me, Pam.

712
01:07:39,130 --> 01:07:40,590
请帮助我
Please help me.

713
01:07:45,670 --> 01:07:48,380
我的天 大卫
Oh my God, David!

714
01:07:52,990 --> 01:07:54,870
我们可以进去吗
May we come in?

715
01:07:55,700 --> 01:07:57,840
可以
Ah... yes.

716
01:07:58,500 --> 01:08:00,820
我叫艾莉森
I'm Allison.

717
01:08:23,360 --> 01:08:26,510
他告诉我的都是真的
All of this time he was telling the truth.

718
01:08:27,630 --> 01:08:32,440
都是真的 但没人相信他 即使是我 我也不相信
All of this time and nobody would believe him, not even me.

719
01:08:33,220 --> 01:08:35,790
- 谁告诉你的  - 吉米
- Who was telling the truth?  - Jimmy.

720
01:08:37,140 --> 01:08:39,640
- 这么说他回来了  - 是的
- Then he came back!  - Yes.

721
01:08:41,770 --> 01:08:43,770
发生什么事了
Well, what happened?

722
01:08:44,980 --> 01:08:48,930
没人相信他 我们都相信海军的说法
Well, nobody would listen to him. We all believed the Navy,

723
01:08:49,160 --> 01:08:52,120
他是受到了那次实验的影响
and they said he had been affected by the experiment.

724
01:08:52,580 --> 01:08:54,450
那么船还有其他人呢
And the ship and the other guys?

725
01:08:55,660 --> 01:08:59,240
有些人烧伤 有些人死了
Burned, some of them, some of them died.

726
01:09:00,020 --> 01:09:02,860
那我呢 我怎么样
What about me? What happened to me, Pamela?

727
01:09:04,090 --> 01:09:06,260
你没有回来过 大卫
You never came back, David.

728
01:09:07,170 --> 01:09:09,130
不知为什么 你就是没有回来
You just never came back...

729
01:09:11,950 --> 01:09:13,920
直到现在
'til now.

730
01:09:24,630 --> 01:09:25,940
那是吉米
Jimmy?

731
01:09:26,240 --> 01:09:28,830
他仍然精力充沛
He still likes to go out there and work.

732
01:09:35,100 --> 01:09:36,870
我过一会就回来
I'll be right back.

733
01:09:39,660 --> 01:09:41,270
大卫
Davey!

734
01:09:42,310 --> 01:09:46,320
- 他已经不像以前那样了  - 我知道
- He's not like he used to be.  - I know.

735
01:10:03,440 --> 01:10:04,610
吉米
Jimmy.

736
01:10:05,000 --> 01:10:07,960
是我 大卫 啊
Jimmy, it's me, David.

737
01:10:10,840 --> 01:10:13,210
我知道你认出我了 吉米
I know you recognize me, Jimmy.

738
01:10:13,600 --> 01:10:17,840
我想要和你谈谈 发生了什么事
I just want to talk to you about what... about what happened.

739
01:10:18,770 --> 01:10:22,280
怎么了 让马停下来 我要和你谈谈
Now, what's the matter, c'mon, stop this, I want to talk to you.

740
01:10:24,880 --> 01:10:27,640
快点 停下马 和我说说
Now, c'mon, talk to me, stop the horse!

741
01:10:28,420 --> 01:10:30,670
停下这该死的马 和我说句话吧
Stop this god damned horse and talk to me, damn it!

742
01:10:30,780 --> 01:10:33,690
- 走开 别理我  - 告诉我到底发生什么事
- Leave me alone.  - Just tell me what happened!

743
01:10:34,640 --> 01:10:36,990
让他走
Get him outta here! Just get him outta here!

744
01:10:37,000 --> 01:10:40,020
告诉我到底发生了什么事
Tell me what happened. Tell me what happened!

745
01:10:41,060 --> 01:10:43,440
- 这是怎么回事呢  - 吉米
- What's the matter?  - Jimmy?

746
01:10:44,040 --> 01:10:46,240
- 吉米  - 发生什么事了吗
- Jimmy?  - What's happening? What's going on?

747
01:10:46,280 --> 01:10:48,520
你们走吧 恐怕他又要复发了
I better go now, I'm afraid he's going to get sick, please, please go.

748
01:10:48,740 --> 01:10:50,610
但他知道的事情可以帮助大卫
Wait! You can't do this! You've got to help David!

749
01:10:50,860 --> 01:10:54,110
他不能再经历一次了 请别再打扰他
He can't go through this again! Please, please leave him alone!

750
01:10:58,080 --> 01:11:03,290
- 大卫 没事吧  - 没事
- David, are you all right?  - Yeah, I'm fine.

751
01:11:15,180 --> 01:11:17,810
为什么不肯跟他说话
Why didn't you want to speak with him, Jimmy?

752
01:11:18,310 --> 01:11:19,930
说些什么
What for?

753
01:11:22,560 --> 01:11:25,390
他只是想要你告诉他一些事
He just wanted you to tell him some things.

754
01:11:26,380 --> 01:11:28,420
他还是不知道的比较好
It's better he doesn't know.

755
01:11:29,650 --> 01:11:31,360
为什么不坐下来
Why don't you come sit down?

756
01:11:35,450 --> 01:11:39,030
我不能再经历一次了 帕米拉
I can't go through all that again, Pamela.

757
01:11:39,870 --> 01:11:41,960
我就是不能
I just can't.

758
01:11:42,170 --> 01:11:45,790
我知道 吉米 我明白了
I know you can't, Jimmy, I do understand.

759
01:11:55,510 --> 01:11:58,290
你看 他真的是一点都没变 不是吗
He looks just the same, doesn't he?

760
01:11:59,310 --> 01:12:01,010
的确
Yes, he does.

761
01:12:01,270 --> 01:12:05,290
愿上帝保佑他 一切都会过去
I wish to God it was all over for him.

762
01:12:19,680 --> 01:12:21,300
我要再回去
I'm goin' back.

763
01:12:21,730 --> 01:12:26,850
没用的 他吓坏了 他得病了 她告诉我了
It won't do any good, he's frightened, he's a sick man, she told me.

764
01:12:26,920 --> 01:12:28,440
我不管
I don't care.

765
01:12:28,510 --> 01:12:31,200
他们会当你是疯子 他们会把你扔进医院
David, they thought he was crazy, they put him in a hospital,

766
01:12:31,230 --> 01:12:33,880
你想要再来一次吗
do you think he wants to go through that again?

767
01:12:34,430 --> 01:12:36,550
我只是想和他谈谈
All I want to do is talk to him.

768
01:12:36,760 --> 01:12:40,650
你已经知道了你需要知道的一切 你没能回去 大卫
You already know what happened, you didn't go back, David.

769
01:12:41,000 --> 01:12:44,590
在他身上发生的事情 难道不会发生在你身上吗
What happened to him is not gonna happen to you.

770
01:12:50,680 --> 01:12:51,980
噢 该死的
Oh shod!

771
01:13:03,310 --> 01:13:05,550
天哪
Jesus Christ!

772
01:13:06,860 --> 01:13:08,480
让他慢下来
Slow him down!

773
01:13:10,240 --> 01:13:11,540
小心
Look out!

774
01:13:15,030 --> 01:13:20,480
- 大卫  - 下来
- David!  - Get down! Shit! Shit! Shit!

775
01:13:22,250 --> 01:13:23,630
继续
Keep going!

776
01:13:30,560 --> 01:13:32,610
下来
Get down! Get down!

777
01:13:50,530 --> 01:13:52,160
等一等
Hang on!

778
01:14:10,340 --> 01:14:11,750
当心
Look out!

779
01:14:12,790 --> 01:14:14,940
- 别挂  - 大卫 停
- Hold on!  - David, stop!

780
01:14:24,210 --> 01:14:26,270
大卫 你要去哪里
David, where are you going?

781
01:14:29,840 --> 01:14:31,670
大卫 快回来 我们要走了
David, come on!

782
01:14:32,220 --> 01:14:33,690
妈的
Damn it!

783
01:14:33,810 --> 01:14:36,330
快回来 我们要离开这里
Please, David, let's get out of here!

784
01:14:39,390 --> 01:14:40,640
干威尔斯
Dry Wells.

785
01:14:40,640 --> 01:14:42,920
- 大卫 我们得快离开这里  - 干威尔斯
- David, we gotta get out of here...  - Dry Wells!

786
01:14:42,960 --> 01:14:46,140
这沙漠基地就是我和吉米第一次出现的地方
This is close to the place that me and Jimmy first came in in the desert.

787
01:14:46,630 --> 01:14:49,660
大卫 这些是联邦文件 我们快走 吧
Please, David, these are federal documents, let's go.

788
01:14:49,700 --> 01:14:51,360
就是这家伙 这就是主持
This is the guy! This is the guy who

789
01:14:51,360 --> 01:14:54,360
我们参加那次实验的那位男子 詹姆士 朗斯特博士
was in charge of the experiment we were in, Dr. James Longstreet!

790
01:14:54,610 --> 01:14:57,430
好啦 上车 这家伙会向我们解释清楚的
All right, get in the car, this guy will know exactly what's goin' on.

791
01:14:57,490 --> 01:14:59,720
大卫 他们可能正在找这辆车
David, they're gonna be looking for this car.

792
01:14:59,720 --> 01:15:00,910
我们在想别的办法
We'll get there some other way.

793
01:15:08,250 --> 01:15:10,750
轻轻的慢慢来 小心他的胳膊
Easy on his arm there! Easy! Easy!

794
01:15:41,980 --> 01:15:44,280
我们已经通过了与内华达州边界
We're just crossing the Nevada border.

795
01:15:47,810 --> 01:15:49,660
怎么了
What's goin' on, Allison?

796
01:15:56,640 --> 01:15:58,360
告诉我 你怎么了
C'mon, what's the matter?

797
01:16:04,100 --> 01:16:07,240
你为什么不肯放弃
Why can't you just let it go?

798
01:16:08,270 --> 01:16:12,550
我是说 我们可以去某个地方
I mean... we could go away somewhere, together,

799
01:16:12,550 --> 01:16:14,970
总之 只有你和我
just... just you and me.

800
01:16:14,990 --> 01:16:17,230
艾莉森 我不能逃避 我要找出来真相来
Allison, I can't let it go, I gotta find out!

801
01:16:17,570 --> 01:16:21,600
那值得你为它而死吗 这不值得
Is it worth dying for? It's not worth it.

802
01:16:23,000 --> 01:16:25,390
不值得为此而杀了人
It's not worth killing people for.

803
01:16:25,460 --> 01:16:28,020
是他们想要先杀死我们 你记得吗
THEY were trying to kill US, remember?

804
01:16:30,550 --> 01:16:34,260
我知道你不想被卷入这一切
Look, if you want to bail-out of this, ya know, I'll understand.

805
01:16:34,290 --> 01:16:36,740
那你还待在这里干什么
I don't know what the hell you're doing here anyway.

806
01:16:41,220 --> 01:16:43,410
大卫 我不会丢下你的
No, I don't want to leave you.

807
01:16:51,000 --> 01:16:54,930
但是 我只是有点害怕
I'm just... I'm just frightened.

808
01:16:56,780 --> 01:17:00,180
不用害怕
Oh, jeez, come here.

809
01:18:10,610 --> 01:18:13,170
峡谷关闭 阻止它在那里
The canyon's is closed, hold it up right there!

810
01:18:17,180 --> 01:18:20,340
请马上调头转回去
I said turn around! Turn around!

811
01:18:29,790 --> 01:18:34,060
车辆请调头转回去
Make arroyo, Jack, walk to arroyo, turn around.

812
01:18:37,610 --> 01:18:39,730
好像是遇到一个路障了
Looks like a road block.

813
01:18:41,680 --> 01:18:45,300
怎么了 大卫 告诉我
What is it, David? What? Tell me!

814
01:18:46,560 --> 01:18:49,760
- 现在轮到我了  - 不
- It's happening to me now.  - No.

815
01:18:50,630 --> 01:18:52,700
好了 快出去
All right, we gotta get out of here,

816
01:18:52,740 --> 01:18:55,020
- 我们必须要尽快找到朗斯特博士  - 好
- I gotta find Longstreet now.  - Okay, okay.

817
01:18:55,030 --> 01:18:57,800
- 风暴太强了 现在不能通行  - 这里怎么了
- The storm's front got everything tied-up.  - What's goin' on?

818
01:18:57,910 --> 01:19:00,360
道路封闭 直到风暴过去
The road's blocked 'til the storm's over.

819
01:19:00,360 --> 01:19:02,160
我明天必须赶到盐湖城
I've got to be in Salt Lake tomorrow!

820
01:19:02,240 --> 01:19:06,050
- 那你可能就要找其他的路了  - 该死
- I guess you just gotta find another way to go.  - Damn!

821
01:19:08,380 --> 01:19:09,860
那是我的车啊
What the hell.

822
01:19:11,040 --> 01:19:12,910
嘿 那是我的拖车
Hey, that's my rig!

823
01:19:13,530 --> 01:19:16,010
那是我的车啊 该死
That's my god damned rig!

824
01:19:17,130 --> 01:19:18,290
大卫
David!

825
01:19:19,330 --> 01:19:21,690
不许开走我的拖车
That's my god damned rig!

826
01:19:24,330 --> 01:19:25,470
该死
What the hell...

827
01:19:27,460 --> 01:19:29,350
这是我的拖车
That's my damn rig!

828
01:19:30,190 --> 01:19:33,700
- 会在下一个路口 设立路障拦截他们的  - 该死
- They'll get 'em at the next roadblock.  - Damn!

829
01:19:49,770 --> 01:19:52,930
- 先靠边停下来吧  - 好
- Must be on your side.  - Yeah.

830
01:20:01,850 --> 01:20:04,670
- 在这等我一下  - 不 我要跟你一起去
- You better wait here.  - No, I'm coming with you.

831
01:20:27,250 --> 01:20:29,650
进来吧 大门是开着的
Come in, the door's open.

832
01:20:33,380 --> 01:20:34,920
从壁炉旁边开始
Drop it over there by the fireplace.

833
01:20:36,070 --> 01:20:37,500
哦 我以为是基地来的人
Oh, I thought you were from the Base.

834
01:20:37,510 --> 01:20:38,750
朗斯特博士在这吗
Dr. Longstreet here?

835
01:20:38,750 --> 01:20:40,330
不 有什么我可以帮你的吗
No, can you help you?

836
01:20:41,100 --> 01:20:44,410
这就是那个城镇 我们以为是个沙漠
This is the town! This is place in the desert I was telling you about.

837
01:20:44,470 --> 01:20:47,260
这就是我和吉米首次出现的地方
This is close to where Jimmy and I first showed up.

838
01:20:47,370 --> 01:20:49,040
抱歉 我想你们得离开了
I'm sorry, but you're gonna have to leave.

839
01:20:49,060 --> 01:20:50,620
- 朗斯特博士在那里  - 这是私人住宅
- Where is Longstreet?  - This is a private residence!

840
01:20:50,730 --> 01:20:52,400
不见到他我们不走
We're not leavin' 'til we see him.

841
01:21:00,410 --> 01:21:02,060
当心 这枪上膛了
Be careful of that, it's loaded!

842
01:21:02,120 --> 01:21:04,460
- 他在那里  - 在基地
- Where is he?  - He's on the base.

843
01:21:04,500 --> 01:21:07,640
- 带我去  - 那地方保安严密 不会让你进去的
- Take me to him.  - It's a secured area, they'll never let you in.

844
01:21:07,890 --> 01:21:09,790
走这瞧
We'll see about that!

845
01:21:27,410 --> 01:21:29,100
- 好了 趴下来  - 这样行不通的
- All right, get down.  - You're never gonna make it.

846
01:21:29,310 --> 01:21:31,150
闭嘴 趴下
Shut up and get down!

847
01:21:33,770 --> 01:21:36,370
停下来 停下来
Halt! Halt!

848
01:21:42,300 --> 01:21:45,220
注意所有安全人员冲破门
Attention all security personnel breach at gate!

849
01:21:45,220 --> 01:21:48,050
- 他人在那里  - 在控制室
- All right, where is he?  - The control room.

850
01:21:48,050 --> 01:21:50,600
未经授权车辆接近控制区
Unauthorized vehicle approaching control area.

851
01:21:55,600 --> 01:21:58,430
低下头 我们走
Get down! Let go! C'mon, let's go!

852
01:22:04,280 --> 01:22:05,470
低下头
Get down!

853
01:22:08,040 --> 01:22:09,390
下车 快出去
Let's go! C'mon, get out!

854
01:22:12,410 --> 01:22:16,580
- 快 快  - 你们这群疯子
- Come on! Let's go!  - We're not gonna god damned make it!

855
01:22:22,520 --> 01:22:23,810
大卫
David!

856
01:22:24,350 --> 01:22:27,580
没事吧 好 我们继续走 快
You all right? C'mon, c'mon, move it! Let's go!

857
01:22:58,190 --> 01:22:59,650
下面有一名警卫
There'll be a guard.

858
01:22:59,780 --> 01:23:02,150
- 让我和他们谈谈吧  - 闭嘴
- Why don't you just let me talk to him.  - Shut up!

859
01:23:10,210 --> 01:23:13,310
- 好啦 站住 水手  - 我会打爆他的头
- That's it, sailor.  - I'll blow his head off.

860
01:23:13,350 --> 01:23:15,670
我再给你一次机会
At this point, you'll have to chance that.

861
01:23:15,940 --> 01:23:18,590
- 放下枪  - 行了 少校
- Put the gun down.  - All right, Major.

862
01:23:18,630 --> 01:23:20,310
别伤害他
Don't hurt him.

863
01:23:22,660 --> 01:23:24,490
放开他
Let him through.

864
01:23:37,210 --> 01:23:39,340
你究竟干了些什么事 朗斯特博士
What the hell have you done, Longstreet?

865
01:23:44,140 --> 01:23:46,370
重放探测器的录影画面
Replay the probe.

866
01:23:55,880 --> 01:24:02,020
认出来了吗 你的船和我们的城镇 它们被困在一起了
Recognize 'em? Your ship and our town... trapped together?

867
01:24:02,700 --> 01:24:05,320
- 怎么会那样的  - 我们也不清楚
- How did it happen?  - We don't know exactly.

868
01:24:05,360 --> 01:24:09,120
不知何故 两次试验所产生的电磁场
But somehow the electromagnetic fields created in two experiments,

869
01:24:09,120 --> 01:24:11,120
也就是一九四三年那次 以及最近这次
one in 1943 and the other now...

870
01:24:11,260 --> 01:24:14,070
它们户相联结了 创造了一个漩涡
cross-connected, they created a vortex,

871
01:24:14,070 --> 01:24:18,070
形成虫洞 产生了时空联结 而你们掉了进去
a hole in the space-time continuum, and you fell through it.

872
01:24:19,360 --> 01:24:21,010
你到底在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?

873
01:24:21,320 --> 01:24:22,630
一九四三年那次
In 1943,

874
01:24:22,630 --> 01:24:25,260
“爱尔德里奇号”回来后那个洞就关上了
when the Eldridge came back, the hole closed behind it.

875
01:24:25,350 --> 01:24:27,900
但这次它持续敞开着
This time it stayed open,

876
01:24:27,900 --> 01:24:30,900
就好像一个真空磅埔 把一切东西都吸进去
it's like, it's like a giant vacuum, sucking everything into it.

877
01:24:31,040 --> 01:24:34,180
我们无法阻止 但我们认为你能
Now, we can't stop it, but I believe that you can.

878
01:24:34,220 --> 01:24:36,750
- 怎样  - 大卫 别听他胡说
- How?  - Don't listen to him, David.

879
01:24:38,810 --> 01:24:40,930
强力漩涡能量源仍然活跃
The source of energy explosion in the vortex

880
01:24:40,930 --> 01:24:43,540
能量来自“爱尔德里奇号”的发电机
is the generators on the Eldridge.

881
01:24:44,200 --> 01:24:46,760
大卫 你必须回去关掉它
You have to go back and shut them down, David.

882
01:24:46,930 --> 01:24:50,700
- 我不会为你做事的  - 我恐怕你别无选择了
- I'm not doin' anything for you.  - I'm afraid you've no alternative.

883
01:24:51,390 --> 01:24:54,450
这听起来似乎很奇怪 但你已经那样做过了
You see, in the very real sense, you've already done it.

884
01:24:54,610 --> 01:24:57,390
我会见“爱尔德里奇号”船员的时候
You see, when I interviewed the survivors of the Eldridge,

885
01:24:57,390 --> 01:24:58,170
他们告诉我
they told me that

886
01:24:58,210 --> 01:25:00,050
是你关掉了发电机
you were the one that shut down the generators.

887
01:25:00,070 --> 01:25:03,100
- 但我没有  - 现在还没有
- But I didn't.  - Not yet.

888
01:25:03,130 --> 01:25:05,790
但我们知道 你最终还是会关掉它的
But we know that eventually you will.

889
01:25:06,450 --> 01:25:10,760
大卫 你的身体仍然和多重空间联结着 你的手
You're still multiply-connected, David. Your hand.

890
01:25:10,870 --> 01:25:13,820
分子仍然不稳定
The molecules still drift.

891
01:25:13,830 --> 01:25:16,830
所以只要那个洞在 你的状况还是会恶化
As long as that hole stays open, you'll continue to deteriorate,

892
01:25:18,060 --> 01:25:24,190
直到你回到一九四三年 去救你的朋友吉米
until you return to 1943, same as your friend, Parker.

893
01:25:24,410 --> 01:25:27,080
他在撒谎 大卫 一个字都不要相信他
He's lying, David, don't listen to anything he says.

894
01:25:27,140 --> 01:25:31,290
- 真希望我是在撒谎  - 别来烦我们 让他走
- I wish to God I were.  - Leave him alone, just leave him alone.

895
01:25:32,520 --> 01:25:34,200
他说的对 艾莉森
He's right, Allison.

896
01:25:37,360 --> 01:25:39,240
我能感觉的到
I can feel it.

897
01:25:41,260 --> 01:25:43,680
说什么好呢 大卫 对不起
What am I to say to you, David, "I'm sorry."?

898
01:25:44,550 --> 01:25:46,660
为那件事 我内疚了整整四十年
I've lived with this thing for 40 years,

899
01:25:46,660 --> 01:25:48,410
没有一天我不是在悔恨中度过的
there's not a day I didn't feel it.

900
01:25:48,720 --> 01:25:52,420
但这一切 那个试验 你又再做了一次
What of all this? A new experiment? You did it again!

901
01:25:52,950 --> 01:25:57,220
是啊 是啊
Yes... yes.

902
01:26:07,660 --> 01:26:09,420
那些缠绕的电阻线圈
The copper coils in the suit should protect

903
01:26:09,420 --> 01:26:11,820
可以防止你受到船上电磁场的影响
from the electromagnetic forces.

904
01:26:11,830 --> 01:26:13,690
- 他在干么  - 装氧气瓶
- What is he doing?  - It's oxygen.

905
01:26:13,730 --> 01:26:15,400
那对我有帮助吗
Is any of this stuff really gonna help me?

906
01:26:15,440 --> 01:26:18,080
不 没有 但不管怎么样
Well, if it doesn't help, it won't matter,

907
01:26:18,080 --> 01:26:21,080
有总比没有好吧
cause nothing's going to be left here anyway.

908
01:26:26,280 --> 01:26:29,860
- 给我几分钟的时间吗  - 你只有这点 快去
- Can you give me a couple of minutes?  - That's about all you got.

909
01:26:39,030 --> 01:26:41,720
不敢相信 事情会变成这样
I can't believe it's gonna end like this.

910
01:26:42,700 --> 01:26:44,950
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it!

911
01:26:46,070 --> 01:26:48,010
接下来会发生什么
What's gonna happen?

912
01:26:49,850 --> 01:26:52,470
我不知道 没有人会知道
I don't know, nobody knows.

913
01:26:59,710 --> 01:27:02,810
或许我会变老四十岁 成为一个糟老头
Shoot! Maybe in 40 years I'll...

914
01:27:03,280 --> 01:27:05,070
回来让你吓一跳
come back and surprise you again.

915
01:27:05,070 --> 01:27:07,400
所有非必要在人员
All non-essential personnel are to evacuate

916
01:27:07,400 --> 01:27:09,740
七百小时撤离基地
the base before oh-seven-hundred hours.

917
01:27:15,520 --> 01:27:18,700
大卫 我们得走了
David, we gotta go.

918
01:27:37,310 --> 01:27:39,050
我得走了
I gotta go!

919
01:27:43,840 --> 01:27:46,430
- 还要多少时间  - 准备好了 通讯系统已经就绪
- How are my sound men?  - We're ready, communications are in.

920
01:27:46,430 --> 01:27:47,890
希望一切在运作
Just hope it's all working.

921
01:27:47,970 --> 01:27:50,570
一但你进入那个漩涡通讯就会中断
I'm gonna put "communication ceases" when you entry the vortex.

922
01:27:51,080 --> 01:27:54,240
- 我们就什么忙也帮不上你了  - 我要开这个吗
- We won't be able to help ya.  - Am I supposed to drive this?

923
01:27:54,330 --> 01:27:55,820
- 不  - 我来
- No.  - I am.

924
01:27:58,380 --> 01:27:59,980
我们走吧 水手
Let's go, son.

925
01:28:52,660 --> 01:28:56,750
- 你觉得一九八四年怎么样  - 电视节目很棒
- So, what did you think of 1984?  - Television's great.

926
01:28:57,580 --> 01:29:03,070
- 呵 没看够吗  - 一切都还没看够
- You didn't see enough of it.  - I didn't see enough of anything.

927
01:29:05,890 --> 01:29:10,510
五象限的读作十点五度 你懂我的意思吗
Quadrant 5 reading at ten point five degrees, do you read me?

928
01:29:10,510 --> 01:29:11,150
是的
Yes, I do.

929
01:29:12,920 --> 01:29:16,820
向量三 响应操作 给我们你的PRD 完毕
Vector 3, response is operational, give us your P.R.D., over.

930
01:29:17,130 --> 01:29:20,210
PRD 十一点四八
P.R.D. eleven point four eight.

931
01:29:48,030 --> 01:29:53,110
- 准备好发射进去了吗  - 我以前到过那里
- Are you ready for this?  - I've been there before.

932
01:29:54,620 --> 01:29:57,740
准备上路了 控制中心
Here we go! Control?

933
01:29:58,060 --> 01:30:00,790
我们已经就发射位置 马上准备发射
We're on the station and almost ready.

934
01:30:09,680 --> 01:30:12,280
记住我告诉过你的位置
Remember what I told you about position,

935
01:30:12,280 --> 01:30:14,240
一定要保持在正中间
be sure you're directly in the center.

936
01:30:17,850 --> 01:30:21,330
我一按下这个 就会把你直射上天
When I blow this thing, it's gonna pull you straight up into the air.

937
01:30:22,210 --> 01:30:25,320
- 准备好了吗  - 上路吧
- Are you ready?  - Let's go!

938
01:30:26,570 --> 01:30:28,520
祝你好运 水手
All right, good luck, sailor.

939
01:32:45,040 --> 01:32:50,550
- 大卫 发生了什么事了  - 我们回到船上了
- Davey, what happened?  - We're back on the ship.

940
01:32:52,140 --> 01:32:56,100
- 那医院呢  - 都结束了 你不会再有事了
- But the hospital?  - It's all over, you're gonna be all right now.

941
01:32:56,160 --> 01:33:00,470
- 伙伴 我得走了  - 你打算回那里去吗
- But I gotta go, buddy.  - You're gonna go back?

942
01:33:02,820 --> 01:33:05,570
不知道 我就是觉得不能留在这里
I don't know, I just can't stay here.

943
01:33:05,570 --> 01:33:07,170
我以后再也见不到你了
Will I ever see you again?

944
01:33:09,530 --> 01:33:13,850
总有一天会在见面的 我保证
One of these days... I promise you that.

945
01:33:16,950 --> 01:33:20,510
我得走了 别担心 伙伴
Look, I gotta go now, take it easy, buddy.

946
01:33:47,190 --> 01:33:50,640
急救医疗队报告双吊湾一号
Emergency medical team report to Hanger Bay 1 on the double!

947
01:33:50,640 --> 01:33:53,640
挂湾一号传递报告
Report to Hanger Bay 1 for transfer.

948
01:34:14,700 --> 01:34:17,090
布拉沃的旁边 还有
Bravo's along side, there are,

949
01:34:17,090 --> 01:34:19,660
还有的是火 它仍然有部分在燃烧
there's been fire, it's still burning at some points

950
01:34:19,710 --> 01:34:21,820
到处都是烧灼过的肢体
There are men moving about on the deck,

951
01:34:21,820 --> 01:34:24,810
甲板上有人在动 似乎都快被烤焦了
they, they appear to be pretty badly burned.

952
01:34:25,520 --> 01:34:27,370
天啊
My God, there's a man...

953
01:34:27,370 --> 01:34:32,480
我看到有人被嵌在甲板里
buried... he's in the steel, he's buried in the deck.

954
01:34:35,120 --> 01:34:37,320
我无法用语言形容它
I can't describe it!

955
01:34:39,330 --> 01:34:41,510
他还活着 还活着
He's alive! He's al...

956
01:35:07,440 --> 01:35:10,660
他成功了 我的上帝 他做到了
He did it! He... God damn it, he did it!

957
01:35:17,520 --> 01:35:22,490
他做到了
He did it! Lord, Almighty, he did it!

958
01:35:27,600 --> 01:35:29,690
上帝保佑 真的难以置信
The damn thing worked great!

959
01:36:50,710 --> 01:36:52,540
大卫
David?

960
01:37:05,900 --> 01:37:08,730
天哪 我不相信
My God, I don't believe it.

961
01:37:18,970 --> 01:37:21,480
- 你知道吗  - 什么
- Ya know what?  - What?

962
01:37:22,390 --> 01:37:24,390
我算过了
I got it all figured out...

963
01:37:24,500 --> 01:37:27,640
海军现在欠我四十年的薪资
the Navy owes me 40 years back pay.

