1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
字幕翻译/校对：101eagle [陆战SASUSMC]

2
00:00:10,010 --> 00:00:15,000
字幕转制：天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者

3
00:01:10,800 --> 00:01:16,950
丹麦　1945年5月
德国的五年占领期结束了
译者注：丹麦于1940年4月9日向德国投降

4
00:02:01,910 --> 00:02:05,080
那边那个，停下！对，就是你！
You there! Stop! Yes you!

5
00:02:06,710 --> 00:02:10,250
这名德军士兵手里拿的是丹麦国旗
这是什么？这不是你的，你为什么拿着这个？
What is it? It's not yours. Are you following?

6
00:02:13,880 --> 00:02:17,390
这是什么？你有问题吗？啊！
What is it? Do you have a problem?

7
00:02:17,550 --> 00:02:21,390
你想要这个？还是回家去吧！滚！
Do you have? So take home! Get out!

8
00:02:27,900 --> 00:02:30,570
这不是你的国旗！
It's not your flag!

9
00:02:33,440 --> 00:02:35,860
停手，别打了！
Stop it!

10
00:02:42,790 --> 00:02:47,040
站起来听我说！
Get up! Up, I said!

11
00:02:49,590 --> 00:02:52,960
从这里给我滚开
Here. Take your cap. Get away with you.

12
00:02:53,130 --> 00:02:55,170
给我闪开！
Slip!

13
00:02:55,340 --> 00:02:58,550
我说给我滚开听见没有！
Run! Running, I said!

14
00:02:58,720 --> 00:03:01,680
这是我的国家！滚出去！
This is my country! Get out!

15
00:03:04,770 --> 00:03:07,060
这里不欢迎你们！
You're not welcome here!

16
00:03:09,190 --> 00:03:13,320
你们应该滚出去！这是我的国家！这是你们的错！
Slip with you! It is my country! Understood?

17
00:03:14,360 --> 00:03:17,950
- 带他们离开这里！ - 是的，军士长！
- Get them out of here, man.  - Yes, sir. Sergeant.

18
00:05:05,350 --> 00:05:13,000
地雷区

19
00:05:58,980 --> 00:06:03,200
我是来自丹麦先锋部队的埃贝·岩森上尉
I am captain Ebbe Jensen from the Danish pioneer troops.

20
00:06:03,360 --> 00:06:06,620
需要说一下我们为什么会在这里
For those of you who do not know why you are here

21
00:06:06,780 --> 00:06:13,290
我来到丹麦，是为了清理战争遗留下的东西
I have been brought to Denmark to clean up after the war.

22
00:06:15,000 --> 00:06:20,090
丹麦不是你们的朋友，你们应该明白
Denmark is not your friend. It should understand.

23
00:06:20,250 --> 00:06:26,010
不要指望丹麦会张开双臂欢迎你们
Do not expect that Danes receive you with open arms.

24
00:06:27,300 --> 00:06:30,970
没有人想看见这里有德国人
There is no one who wants to see Germans here.

25
00:06:31,140 --> 00:06:35,270
这只是我来这里的原因之一
I'm only here for one reason.

26
00:06:35,440 --> 00:06:40,110
我必须清除丹麦西海岸被德国埋下的地雷
I must clear the west coast of Denmark for German landmines.

27
00:06:40,270 --> 00:06:44,200
雷区我已经贴在这了
Miner, I have posted here.

28
00:06:44,360 --> 00:06:50,080
大约有二百二十万颗地雷沿着丹麦西海岸分布
There are approximately 2.2 million mines along the Danish west coast.

29
00:06:51,450 --> 00:06:56,710
它比其他所有欧洲国家都多
That is more than in all European countries.

30
00:06:56,870 --> 00:07:02,210
一些人认为盟军会在这里登陆
Someone must have thought that the Allied invasion would take place here.

31
00:07:02,380 --> 00:07:06,050
可惜的是谁会有在这登陆的主意
What a shame for him, who had the idea.

32
00:07:06,220 --> 00:07:09,260
但是这对你们来说也十分糟糕
And too bad for you.

33
00:07:10,600 --> 00:07:15,350
你们谁埋过雷或见过埋雷？
Who has seen or handled a landmine before?

34
00:07:17,100 --> 00:07:21,570
有没有人尝试过拆除地雷？
Has anyone tried to disarm one?

35
00:07:24,530 --> 00:07:28,820
谁在之前见过这种地雷？
Who has seen one before?

36
00:07:30,410 --> 00:07:33,200
这是最常见的地雷
It is the most common mine.

37
00:07:33,370 --> 00:07:36,330
为了获得最大的杀伤效果
For maximum effect ??

38
00:07:36,500 --> 00:07:42,210
通常把它埋在十五到二十厘米深的沙子下面
the mines are dug 15 to 20 centimeters into the sand.

39
00:07:42,380 --> 00:07:45,760
这样就比较容易找到它们
This makes them relatively easy to find.

40
00:07:49,720 --> 00:07:52,300
你刚刚把你的手丢掉了
You just lost your hands.

41
00:07:54,010 --> 00:07:59,150
接着来吧，我们没有时间自怜
Come on. We have no time for self-pity.

42
00:08:03,070 --> 00:08:05,480
你会死的！
You're dead.

43
00:08:05,650 --> 00:08:09,740
在这里我们已经有第一个人显示死掉了
Here we have shown our first death.

44
00:08:09,910 --> 00:08:12,950
如果你不想再看到你的家人
If you do not see your family again?

45
00:08:13,120 --> 00:08:16,250
谁将会第一个送死
Will you be the first to die?

46
00:08:16,410 --> 00:08:20,290
- 不  - 我听不见你说什么
- No.  - I can not hear you.

47
00:08:20,460 --> 00:08:23,170
我不会是第一个死的人
I will not be the first to die.

48
00:08:23,340 --> 00:08:26,210
我很高兴听到这个，再来一遍吧！
I am happy to hear that. Again.

49
00:08:29,510 --> 00:08:31,590
你又死了
Death again.

50
00:08:35,850 --> 00:08:39,440
拆雷时最重要的是避免出现差错
Of undermining her er ikke   catch him.

51
00:08:39,600 --> 00:08:43,270
如果出现一点差错
If I do something wrong ??

52
00:08:43,440 --> 00:08:48,030
你会受重伤或者死的很难看
you will either die or be seriously injured.

53
00:08:48,190 --> 00:08:51,570
- 都清楚了吗？ - 是的，上尉！
- Is that understood?  - Yes, sir. Captain!

54
00:08:51,740 --> 00:08:54,950
你，到这来
Well. Come here.

55
00:08:55,120 --> 00:08:57,950
- 你是第一个  - 是的，上尉
- You are the first man.  - Yes, sir. Captain.

56
00:08:58,120 --> 00:08:59,580
去吧
Not.

57
00:09:03,170 --> 00:09:05,380
下一个
Next.

58
00:09:35,280 --> 00:09:40,700
很好！做得很快，下一个
Excellent. That was fast. Next.

59
00:10:00,720 --> 00:10:02,270
快！
Faster!

60
00:10:16,700 --> 00:10:18,990
下一个
Next.

61
00:10:38,510 --> 00:10:40,390
很好
Excellent.

62
00:10:41,930 --> 00:10:43,270
下一个
Next.

63
00:10:57,410 --> 00:10:59,200
下一个
Next.

64
00:11:13,050 --> 00:11:15,050
下一个
Next.

65
00:11:33,400 --> 00:11:35,780
下一个
Next.

66
00:11:36,570 --> 00:11:38,740
很好
Excellent.

67
00:12:06,560 --> 00:12:08,390
快点！
Faster!

68
00:12:16,070 --> 00:12:18,320
现在出来！
Come now!

69
00:12:18,490 --> 00:12:22,870
其他人不会像你这么久还没完成
The other would long ago have done all mine now.

70
00:12:24,330 --> 00:12:26,830
你睡着了吗？
Have you fallen asleep?

71
00:12:28,500 --> 00:12:31,960
上尉，请允许我帮他一下
Sir. Captain, request permission to retrieve him.

72
00:12:32,130 --> 00:12:34,670
在任何情况下都不行
Under no circumstances.

73
00:12:37,300 --> 00:12:39,680
他妈的！
Fuck you.

74
00:12:40,630 --> 00:12:42,140
我进来了
I come in.

75
00:12:48,520 --> 00:12:51,675
- 别让我说谎  - 我可以做到
- Let mine be.  - I can.

76
00:12:51,680 --> 00:12:56,685
- 快起来！士兵  - 不！我能做到
- Get up, soldier.  - No. I can.

77
00:12:56,690 --> 00:13:01,660
- 快起来！士兵  - 不！我知道我可以拆除它
- Get up, soldier!  - No. I know I can handle it.

78
00:13:08,600 --> 00:13:11,580
捂住你的耳朵
Cover your ears.

79
00:13:24,520 --> 00:13:26,850
下一个
Next.

80
00:13:34,110 --> 00:13:37,440
当我把地雷拆除时
When the mine is disarmed ??

81
00:14:23,500 --> 00:14:26,245
伊丽莎白，进来吧
Elisabeth. Come on.

82
00:14:26,250 --> 00:14:28,780
来吧，宝贝
Come on, baby.

83
00:15:06,050 --> 00:15:08,740
你们是军人？
Are soldiers?

84
00:15:12,920 --> 00:15:16,085
回答我，你们这些白痴！你们是军人？
Answer me, you dirty swine! Are soldiers?

85
00:15:16,090 --> 00:15:18,215
是的，军士长
Javel, hr. sergent!

86
00:15:18,220 --> 00:15:22,170
快！站成一排
Fall in on one rank! Full speed!

87
00:15:23,390 --> 00:15:27,335
快！快点！
Cruise on! Come on!

88
00:15:27,340 --> 00:15:31,430
站成一排，快点！
Onto one rank! Come on!

89
00:15:32,010 --> 00:15:34,230
立正！
Attention!

90
00:15:36,680 --> 00:15:39,595
- 你没有听见“立正”吗？ - 是的…
- Do not you understand "give heed"?  - Yes ...

91
00:15:39,600 --> 00:15:42,940
所以要站得像个男人
So stand like a man!

92
00:15:45,850 --> 00:15:47,860
稍息！
Tube!

93
00:15:52,980 --> 00:15:57,475
- 姓什么？ - 马克林，军士长
- Surname?  - Marklein, hr. sergent.

94
00:15:57,480 --> 00:16:01,055
- 名字？ - 赫尔曼，军士长
- First name?  - Hermann, sir. Sergeant.

95
00:16:01,060 --> 00:16:04,515
- 鲁道夫·塞尔克，军士长  - 弗里德里希·施努尔
- Rodolf Selke, hr. Sgt.  - Schnurr Friedrich.

96
00:16:04,520 --> 00:16:06,765
- 沃尔夫什么？ - 约翰·沃尔夫
- Wolff what?  - Johann Wolff.

97
00:16:06,770 --> 00:16:09,055
- 克鲁格  - 姓名？
- Kluger.  - First?

98
00:16:09,060 --> 00:16:11,850
奥古斯特·克鲁格
August Kluger.

99
00:16:12,850 --> 00:16:16,105
你们两个看起来像兄弟一样
And you two? You look like brothers.

100
00:16:16,110 --> 00:16:21,190
- 我们是双胞胎，军士长  - 这样啊！
- We s Tvillinger, hr. Sergent.  - Ferment?

101
00:16:21,400 --> 00:16:23,105
叫什么名字？
Name?

102
00:16:23,110 --> 00:16:26,185
沃纳和恩斯特·莱斯纳，军士长
Werner og Ernst Lessner, hr. sergent.

103
00:16:26,190 --> 00:16:28,645
- 我问你了吗？ - 没有
- I asked you?  - No.

104
00:16:28,650 --> 00:16:31,490
所以闭上嘴
So shut up.

105
00:16:32,400 --> 00:16:35,700
- 对不起  - 什么？
- Pardon.  - What?

106
00:16:36,860 --> 00:16:39,485
- 你说什么？ - 对不起
- What did you say?  - Pardon.

107
00:16:39,490 --> 00:16:43,815
- 你为什么要道歉？ - 因为我提到了我弟弟的名字
- Why are you apologizing?  - Because I mentioned my brother's name.

108
00:16:43,820 --> 00:16:46,960
- 对你道歉？ - 是的
- Are you apologizing?  - Yes.

109
00:16:48,570 --> 00:16:53,315
把你的道歉去见鬼去吧，我不会用这些词的，明白吗？
To hell with your excuse! I can not use it. Understood?

110
00:16:53,320 --> 00:16:56,270
是的，军士长！
Javel, hr. sergent.

111
00:16:59,280 --> 00:17:03,405
- 对了还有你，小家伙  - 威廉·莱本，军士长
- And you, little guy?  - Wilhelm Lebern, sir. Sergeant.

112
00:17:03,410 --> 00:17:08,325
- 你是一个军人吗？ - 是的 军士长
- Er soldier?  - Javel, hr. sergeant.

113
00:17:08,330 --> 00:17:13,035
- 路德维希·汉克，军士长  - 塞巴斯蒂安·舒曼，军士长
- Ludwig Haffke, hr. sergent.  - Sebastian Schumann, hr. sergent.

114
00:17:13,040 --> 00:17:16,790
你要看着我说话
Look at me when you talk to me.

115
00:17:23,290 --> 00:17:27,325
- 赫尔穆特·莫尔巴赫，军士长  - 多好的制服啊！
- Helmut Morbach, hr. sergent.  - Sikken fin uniform.

116
00:17:27,330 --> 00:17:31,535
- 你作战很久了？ - 是的，军士长！
- Have you been at war?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant.

117
00:17:31,540 --> 00:17:35,180
- 你在哭吗？ - 不，军士长
- Are you crying?  - No, sir. Sergeant!

118
00:17:37,210 --> 00:17:40,825
- 这是什么？你在哭什么？ - 没有，军士长
- What is it? Are you crying?  - No, sir. Sergeant!

119
00:17:40,830 --> 00:17:44,770
- 你在害怕吗？ - 没有，军士长！
- Are you afraid?  - No, sir. Sergeant!

120
00:17:45,040 --> 00:17:49,990
- 你想家吗？ - 没有，军士长！
- Have you homesick?  - No, sir. Sergeant!

121
00:18:32,260 --> 00:18:37,700
- 所有人都能看见在那的黑旗帜吧？ - 是的，军士长
- Can everyone see the black flag out there?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant.

122
00:18:37,800 --> 00:18:44,080
在那旗帜标注的范围内埋着四万五千颗地雷
Between the flag and the path is that 45,000 mines buried.

123
00:18:44,720 --> 00:18:48,305
我必须把它们都清除掉
Shall disarm and remove them all.

124
00:18:48,310 --> 00:18:52,300
当你们完成时，我就可以允许你们回家
When you have finished, you may be allowed to go home.

125
00:18:52,520 --> 00:18:55,765
- 清楚了吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Is that understood?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant!

126
00:18:55,770 --> 00:18:59,265
除非你能回家，明白了吗？
Not until you can get home! Is that understood?

127
00:18:59,270 --> 00:19:02,175
是的，军士长！
Javel, hr. sergent!

128
00:19:02,180 --> 00:19:08,135
如果你每个小时可以拆除六个地雷，如果你可以的话
If I disarm six mines in hours and do not blow yourself in the air ??

129
00:19:08,140 --> 00:19:11,725
你在三个月后就可以回家
you can go home in three months.

130
00:19:11,730 --> 00:19:15,185
- 都清楚了吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Is that understood?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant!

131
00:19:15,190 --> 00:19:19,555
- 你，还想说点什么吗？ - 没有了，军士长
- You! Want to say something?  - No, sir. Sergeant.

132
00:19:19,560 --> 00:19:23,700
- 你确定吗？ - 很确定，军士长
- Are you sure?  - Quite sure, sir. Sergeant.

133
00:19:24,270 --> 00:19:27,355
- 地图在谁那？ - 路德维希，军士长
- You card.  - Ludwig, sir. Sergeant.

134
00:19:27,360 --> 00:19:29,840
给我地图
Give me the map.

135
00:19:30,610 --> 00:19:33,935
- 我在这上面都能看到？ - 是的
- Can I see all see it?  - Oh well!

136
00:19:33,940 --> 00:19:36,395
每个地方都有一个编号
Each field has a number.

137
00:19:36,400 --> 00:19:40,485
这些点标注了地雷的类型和区域
The star and the dot shows the type of mine it is.

138
00:19:40,490 --> 00:19:44,895
我可以肯定你都标注清楚了
Those of you who counts mines must ensure ??

139
00:19:44,900 --> 00:19:47,815
那我的地图会不断更新的
that my card is always updated.

140
00:19:47,820 --> 00:19:52,445
这个任务非常重要 我们要拆除他们
This task is as important as defusing mines.

141
00:19:52,450 --> 00:19:56,570
- 都清楚了吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Is that understood?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant!

142
00:19:57,660 --> 00:20:04,250
从这里开始我们要清出一个安全区
From the stone to mark the water we create a safety zone.

143
00:20:05,160 --> 00:20:09,365
我需要知道你们之中有想退缩的吗？
Do I need to tell you what happens to those who try to escape?

144
00:20:09,370 --> 00:20:12,960
没有，军士长！
No, sir. Sergeant!

145
00:20:41,250 --> 00:20:45,700
一，二，三，四…
En, to, tre, fire.

146
00:20:59,710 --> 00:21:03,455
一，二…
En, to ??

147
00:21:03,460 --> 00:21:07,220
一，二…
three four.

148
00:21:09,550 --> 00:21:14,320
一，二，三，四…
En, to, tre, fire.

149
00:21:17,420 --> 00:21:20,610
我找到一个
I have one.

150
00:22:21,630 --> 00:22:23,730
我找到一个
I have one!

151
00:22:24,840 --> 00:22:29,100
- 我找到一个  - 我也找到一个
- I have one!  - So have I!

152
00:22:40,900 --> 00:22:45,960
在这里并没有那么糟糕
It is not so bad it here.

153
00:22:52,280 --> 00:22:56,220
当你回家的时候你会做什么？
What will I do when I get home?

154
00:22:57,240 --> 00:22:59,905
我要成为一个技师
I have to be a mechanic.

155
00:22:59,910 --> 00:23:04,105
我父亲的一个朋友有一个很好的工厂
One of my father's friends have a good plant.

156
00:23:04,110 --> 00:23:07,195
当我回家时他会雇佣我的
He hires me when I get home.

157
00:23:07,200 --> 00:23:11,865
- 难道你忘记了什么？ - 管好你自己的事吧
- Have not you forgotten something?  - Mind your own business.

158
00:23:11,870 --> 00:23:17,275
当然他应该知道这只是幻想，未来只是一个该死的幻想
Surely he should know that his fine future is a damn illusion.

159
00:23:17,280 --> 00:23:21,785
这不是不抱任何希望的，他已经答应我了
It's no illusion. He has already promised me.

160
00:23:21,790 --> 00:23:24,870
- 如果…  - 别说了
- And if now ...  - Stop.

161
00:23:31,910 --> 00:23:36,865
我应该问，他会雇一个学徒吗？
Should I ask if he will employ an apprentice?

162
00:23:36,870 --> 00:23:40,285
是呀，那将是美好的
Yes. That would be nice.

163
00:23:40,290 --> 00:23:45,705
- 然后我们可以一起工作  - 是呀
- Then we can work together.  - Yes.

164
00:23:45,710 --> 00:23:49,665
你也可以问我，威廉
You can also ask for me, Wilhelm?

165
00:23:49,670 --> 00:23:52,785
- 别说了  - 那是多么美好啊
- Stop.  - That would be nice.

166
00:23:52,790 --> 00:23:55,285
- 我们三个…  - 赫尔穆特
- You three ...  - Helmut.

167
00:23:55,290 --> 00:23:58,490
- 闭嘴！ - 别说了
- Shut up!  - Stop.

168
00:23:58,710 --> 00:24:02,160
我们三个人，携手共进
The three of us, hand in hand.

169
00:24:07,130 --> 00:24:10,250
为什么？
What!?

170
00:24:23,510 --> 00:24:27,390
看那，我觉得她有一些食物
See. I think she has some food.

171
00:24:29,050 --> 00:24:32,310
她那有一些面包
She has some bread.

172
00:24:38,800 --> 00:24:41,820
你好
Hi there.

173
00:24:42,350 --> 00:24:45,950
她叫什么名字？
What is her name?

174
00:24:48,510 --> 00:24:51,710
你懂德语吗？
Do you understand German?

175
00:24:54,350 --> 00:24:57,960
可以帮我解决一下吗？看这里
She has settled. See.

176
00:25:04,020 --> 00:25:08,350
一个士兵必须时刻施与帮助
A soldier must always be ready to help.

177
00:25:12,020 --> 00:25:18,280
我没有一个娃娃作为一个孩子，我是一个男孩，所以我有一辆汽车
I did not have a doll as a child. I am a boy, so I had a car.

178
00:25:21,190 --> 00:25:24,055
这看起来不错
That was better.

179
00:25:24,060 --> 00:25:25,935
谢谢
So.

180
00:25:25,940 --> 00:25:28,015
不客气
You are welcome.

181
00:25:28,020 --> 00:25:32,000
伊丽莎白
Elisabeth.

182
00:25:32,360 --> 00:25:34,185
伊丽莎白
Elisabeth.

183
00:25:34,190 --> 00:25:36,475
你最好回去
You'd better go.

184
00:25:36,480 --> 00:25:39,605
你会过来吗？当我对你说的时候？
Will you come when I say it to you?

185
00:25:39,610 --> 00:25:43,090
你在那做什么？
What are you doing over there?

186
00:25:46,440 --> 00:25:49,315
不，你知道你干吗？
No, you know what?

187
00:25:49,320 --> 00:25:54,980
我告诉过你了，不要在外面玩过家家，对不对？
I told you, you do not have to be over by the fishing house, right?

188
00:25:55,950 --> 00:25:59,440
什么，你不明白吗？
What is it that you do not understand?

189
00:26:00,700 --> 00:26:06,450
你不明白我在说什么吗？我厌倦了你的散漫
Do not you understand what I'm saying? I'm tired of you roam.

190
00:26:09,240 --> 00:26:12,565
现在我要尿尿
It is now, if I have to pee.

191
00:26:12,570 --> 00:26:15,565
你们都回到床上躺着
No? Then it's into bed.

192
00:26:15,570 --> 00:26:19,680
走！快！
Departure! Faster!

193
00:26:21,050 --> 00:26:24,590
- 你们都在这里？ - 是的，军士长
- Er her I alle sammen?  - Javel, hr. sergeant.

194
00:27:12,310 --> 00:27:15,520
你不能和他说话知道吗
Can not you talk to him?

195
00:27:18,100 --> 00:27:22,480
- 我也有两天没怎么吃  - 抱怨是不好的
- I have not eaten in two days.  - It does no good to complain.

196
00:27:24,240 --> 00:27:27,820
饿着肚子怎么排雷
How do I defuse mines on an empty stomach?

197
00:28:00,390 --> 00:28:04,305
- 是我，塞巴斯蒂安  - 你想干什么？
- It is me. Sebastian.  - What will you?

198
00:28:04,310 --> 00:28:08,660
你知道我们什么时候有东西吃？军士长
You know when we get something to eat, sir. Sergeant?

199
00:28:09,560 --> 00:28:14,160
- 如果我们不得到一些食物…  - 那又怎么样呢？
- If we do not get some food ...  - So what?

200
00:28:16,640 --> 00:28:20,670
你觉得我不为你们感到难过吗？
Do you think I feel sorry for you?

201
00:28:21,020 --> 00:28:25,265
- 不，军士长  - 我是他妈的关心你们
- No, sir. Sergeant.  - I fucking do not care about you.

202
00:28:25,270 --> 00:28:29,265
- 我不在乎我是否会死  - 我知道，军士长
- I do not care whether I kreperer.  - I know, sir. Sergeant.

203
00:28:29,270 --> 00:28:35,060
我不知道食物什么时候送来，德国人不是优先配给的
I do not know when the food comes. The Germans are not ahead of the game.

204
00:28:44,820 --> 00:28:47,990
晚安！塞巴斯蒂安
Good night, Sebastian.

205
00:28:50,150 --> 00:28:52,780
回到你们的床上睡觉去
Into bed with you.

206
00:28:53,240 --> 00:28:57,500
快回到床上！睡觉！
Put you to sleep! In bed with you!

207
00:29:46,290 --> 00:29:50,220
- 你要去哪里？ - 现在是睡觉时间
- Where are you going?  - Sleep now just.

208
00:29:50,660 --> 00:29:55,050
- 你想离开？ - 我想找一些吃的
- Will you walk away?  - I will find something to eat.

209
00:30:12,670 --> 00:30:16,205
他不会说谎的，我知道我的兄弟
He can not. I know my brother.

210
00:30:16,210 --> 00:30:21,205
我总是看见他早上呕吐
I have seen him all morning. He threw up constantly.

211
00:30:21,210 --> 00:30:24,960
你要看着我说话
Look at me when you talk to me.

212
00:30:26,510 --> 00:30:29,970
- 恩斯特？ - 这是对的，军士长！
- Ernst?  - That's right, sir. Sergeant.

213
00:30:30,140 --> 00:30:34,270
- 看着我！ - 是的时间符合，我感觉不舒服
- Look at me!  - It fits. I am not feeling well.

214
00:30:34,430 --> 00:30:37,730
如果给我一个小时可以恢复好
If only I had to put me in an hour.

215
00:30:37,900 --> 00:30:42,110
恩斯特，你知道的，我不能允许
Ernst, you know, that I can not allow.

216
00:30:42,280 --> 00:30:46,360
- 我感觉很不好  - 他这样完全不行，军士长
- Well I feel bad.  - May he not be enough, sir. Sergeant?

217
00:30:51,700 --> 00:30:56,330
你有一点发热，但你可以正常工作，对不对？
You are a little warm, but you can work anyway, right?

218
00:30:56,500 --> 00:30:58,460
军士长…
Hr. sergent ...

219
00:31:03,210 --> 00:31:07,930
你说什么，奥托，我们应该给他一个小时，是吗？
What do you say, Otto? Should we leave them one hour? Shall we?

220
00:31:08,090 --> 00:31:11,890
我们应该让他们休息吗？我们可以考虑
Should we let them rest? We could pass.

221
00:31:12,970 --> 00:31:16,180
你认为他们在骗我们？是吗？
Do you think they're trying to cheat us? What?

222
00:31:21,770 --> 00:31:25,280
不，他们不敢
No, they do not dare.

223
00:31:25,440 --> 00:31:28,610
嗯，对 他们不敢
Well? No, they do not dare.

224
00:31:28,780 --> 00:31:31,240
看着我，孩子
Look at me, boys.

225
00:31:32,830 --> 00:31:36,160
- 去工作  - 军士长…
- Back to work.  - Sir. Sergeant ...

226
00:31:36,330 --> 00:31:40,460
你听到了吗？回去工作，我说！现在！
Did you hear me? Back to work, I said! Now!

227
00:31:42,380 --> 00:31:44,670
快去！
Speed ​​up!

228
00:33:44,680 --> 00:33:48,210
威廉！威廉！
Wilhelm? Wilhelm?

229
00:34:19,350 --> 00:34:22,830
出了一点问题，把我的钢盔摘掉
There is something wrong. Take my helmet.

230
00:34:24,940 --> 00:34:28,015
把这该死的钢盔拿掉
Take the shit helmet.

231
00:34:28,020 --> 00:34:30,250
救命！
Help!

232
00:34:33,600 --> 00:34:38,510
- 我想回家  - 安静些
- I want to go home.  - Quiet now.

233
00:34:38,900 --> 00:34:41,555
你会没事的
You'll be all right.

234
00:34:41,560 --> 00:34:46,270
- 赫尔穆特，帮我  - 把他抬离海滩
- Helmut, help me  - get him away from the beach.

235
00:34:49,820 --> 00:34:54,275
- 救我  - 你会没事的，放轻松
- Help me.  - It will be OK. Take it easy.

236
00:34:54,280 --> 00:34:56,315
放轻松
Take it fun.

237
00:34:56,320 --> 00:35:00,990
- 快来帮我！ - 你为什么不去帮他？
- So help me out!  - Why do you help him?

238
00:35:02,440 --> 00:35:05,500
帮帮我！
Help me!

239
00:35:07,070 --> 00:35:11,550
- 我要回家！ - 你会没事的
- I want to go home!  - It should probably go.

240
00:35:14,070 --> 00:35:16,630
救救我！
Help me!

241
00:35:20,450 --> 00:35:23,640
- 救救我！ - 安静
- Help!  - Calm.

242
00:35:36,160 --> 00:35:41,785
- 救命！ - 军士长！我们需要帮助
- Help!  - Sir. Sergeant! We need help!

243
00:35:41,790 --> 00:35:47,445
- 我想回家！ - 不要担心，看着我
- I want to go home!  - Just quiet. Look at me.

244
00:35:47,450 --> 00:35:51,115
- 你会没事的  - 你要这样做
- It should probably go.  - You manage it.

245
00:35:51,120 --> 00:35:56,090
- 妈妈！妈妈！ - 军士长，帮帮我们！
- Mother! Mother!  - Sir. Sergeant, help us!

246
00:35:56,540 --> 00:36:00,075
做点什么！帮帮我们！
Do something! Help us!

247
00:36:00,080 --> 00:36:02,955
军士长，帮帮我们！
Sir. Sergeant, come on!

248
00:36:02,960 --> 00:36:07,350
- 军士长！ - 妈妈！
- Hr. sergent!  - Mor!

249
00:36:07,960 --> 00:36:10,495
妈妈！我要回家！
Tender! I want to go home!

250
00:36:10,500 --> 00:36:16,705
看着我，你会回家的，相信我
Look at me. You're going home. It should probably go. Trust me.

251
00:36:16,710 --> 00:36:20,320
我不想再这样了！
I do not want to anymore!

252
00:36:22,090 --> 00:36:25,085
我要回家！
I want to go home!

253
00:36:25,090 --> 00:36:29,000
我想…想回…
I will ... I will ...

254
00:36:38,340 --> 00:36:41,470
谢谢你！军士长
Thank you, sir. Sergeant.

255
00:37:16,560 --> 00:37:20,845
- 你的错？ - 这是我的错，我们都…
- Your fault?  - It's my fault. We were ...

256
00:37:20,850 --> 00:37:24,845
- 看着我！ - 我们昨晚是太饿了
- Look at me!  - We were so hungry last night.

257
00:37:24,850 --> 00:37:30,635
我去农场偷饲料吃，这就是我们为什么生病了
I stole something fodder on the farm. That's why we have become ill.

258
00:37:30,640 --> 00:37:35,055
每个人都应该得到食物，作为一名军官这是我的责任
As an officer, it is my responsibility to ensure that everybody gets some food.

259
00:37:35,060 --> 00:37:39,190
你没有责任在这里
You have no responsibility here.

260
00:37:46,690 --> 00:37:49,580
你的妈妈在哪里？
Where is your mother?

261
00:37:59,110 --> 00:38:03,435
当我说没有，可事情却不是这样
When I say there is nothing to eat in here, there is not.

262
00:38:03,440 --> 00:38:05,435
这是什么？
What is this?

263
00:38:05,440 --> 00:38:08,525
如果你吃了，就会生病
If they eat it, they have become sick.

264
00:38:08,530 --> 00:38:12,275
这里充满了鼠粪，你看这里
It is full of rat shit. Look here.

265
00:38:12,280 --> 00:38:14,695
有什么好笑的？
What is it that's so funny?

266
00:38:14,700 --> 00:38:19,110
然后却让一些德国人生病了
Then I got anyway ram on some Germans.

267
00:38:23,570 --> 00:38:27,775
- 她笑什么？ - 听着，孩子！
- What she laughed at?  - Listen, kid.

268
00:38:27,780 --> 00:38:31,315
我们两个都别说话了，明白了吗？
We two do not talk. Is that understood?

269
00:38:31,320 --> 00:38:35,695
你别跟我说！我问你你再回答
You do not talk to me! I ask and you answer.

270
00:38:35,700 --> 00:38:40,800
- 并且称呼“军士长” - 是的，军士长
- And always with "Mr. Sergeant."  - Yes, sir. Sergeant.

271
00:38:43,370 --> 00:38:49,180
- 你为什么说那些？ - 我没有提供任何东西
- Why did you say something?  - I was not offered anything.

272
00:39:01,330 --> 00:39:04,240
扔了！
Cabinet on!

273
00:39:05,920 --> 00:39:10,665
喝，喝，喝！打倒它！来吧！
Drink, drink, drink! Down with it! Come on!

274
00:39:10,670 --> 00:39:14,330
- 水！ - 你想死吗？
- Water!  - Would you like to die?

275
00:39:16,460 --> 00:39:20,590
好吧，孩子，喝吧！
All right, boys. Drink.

276
00:39:27,300 --> 00:39:30,300
清洗自己
Wash yourselves.

277
00:39:33,460 --> 00:39:36,085
洗干净些，把头发也洗干净
Wash yourselves. Down with the head.

278
00:39:36,090 --> 00:39:41,165
洗干净的，后面也是
Wash yourselves. Fine. Down with the head.

279
00:39:41,170 --> 00:39:47,150
很好！很好！来吧，坐这，对！
It was good. You are good. Come on. Here, come on. Come on. Sit.

280
00:40:13,560 --> 00:40:16,300
快回床上睡觉！
Into bed with you.

281
00:40:17,060 --> 00:40:20,885
我可以给你看些什么吗？军士长！
May I show you something, sir. Sergeant?

282
00:40:20,890 --> 00:40:24,730
- 快去床上睡觉！ - 我想给你看样东西
- Then go to bed.  - I want to show you something.

283
00:40:28,930 --> 00:40:33,935
有了这个框架，就变得更容易排雷了
With this frame makes it easier to clear the mines.

284
00:40:33,940 --> 00:40:40,435
现在是有限区域，所以你可以找我
Now is the area bounded, so you can look for mine.

285
00:40:40,440 --> 00:40:43,895
当然，我理解，我又不傻
Fine. I understand it. I'm not stupid.

286
00:40:43,900 --> 00:40:49,305
- 我知道  - 把你的玩具带上床睡觉吧！
- I know.  - Take your toys and go to bed.

287
00:40:49,310 --> 00:40:51,975
我知道你恨我们
I know that you hate us ??

288
00:40:51,980 --> 00:40:56,645
并不在乎我们是否炸伤或因饥饿而死
and do not care whether we get blown up or die of hunger.

289
00:40:56,650 --> 00:40:58,225
对
Correctly.

290
00:40:58,230 --> 00:41:03,180
但这不是最好的，我们因清除海滩上的地雷而死？
But it is not the best we die while we clear the mines on the beach?

291
00:41:04,480 --> 00:41:08,685
我不在乎，把你的玩具带上床睡觉
I do not care. Take your toys and go to bed.

292
00:41:08,690 --> 00:41:12,645
海滩上的地雷必须被清除，不是吗？军士长
The beach must be cleared of mines. Not, sir. Sergeant?

293
00:41:12,650 --> 00:41:17,395
是的，我理解你，你可以答应你应该去睡觉了吗？
Yes, I understand you. Why do you understand, that you should go to bed now?

294
00:41:17,400 --> 00:41:21,275
我只是想跟你说这些
I ask you just to listen to me.

295
00:41:21,280 --> 00:41:24,235
- 所以赶紧去吧  - 你听到我的话了吧？
- So hurry.  - Do you understand me?

296
00:41:24,240 --> 00:41:27,195
我理解，你明白我的话吧！
I understand you? Do you understand me?

297
00:41:27,200 --> 00:41:30,945
- 是的，军士长！ - 然后把你的玩具带上床睡觉
- Yes, sir. Sergeant.  - So take your toys and go to bed.

298
00:41:30,950 --> 00:41:33,380
快去
Come on.

299
00:41:38,240 --> 00:41:40,630
晚安！军士长
Good night, sir. Sergeant.

300
00:42:27,560 --> 00:42:30,280
- 早安！ - 早安！
- Good morning.  - Good morning.

301
00:42:31,570 --> 00:42:34,860
- 这个是威廉·莱本？ - 是的
- En Wilhelm Lebern?  - Ja.

302
00:42:35,860 --> 00:42:38,660
他来这几天了
He came in for a couple of days ago.

303
00:42:42,410 --> 00:42:45,580
威廉昨天死了
Wilhelm died yesterday.

304
00:42:47,420 --> 00:42:51,050
他还在这里，如果你想见他
He is still here, if you want to see him.

305
00:42:51,210 --> 00:42:55,220
不，不需要了，谢谢！
No. No, it is not necessary. Thanks.

306
00:43:51,150 --> 00:43:54,110
起床吧！孩子们！
So it's up, boys!

307
00:43:59,570 --> 00:44:01,780
快起来！
Stand up!

308
00:44:03,570 --> 00:44:05,830
快起来！
Stand up!

309
00:45:17,370 --> 00:45:19,990
列队！
Fall in!

310
00:45:27,750 --> 00:45:30,620
稍息！
Tube!

311
00:45:31,460 --> 00:45:35,625
我有一个好消息和坏消息
I have good and bad news.

312
00:45:35,630 --> 00:45:39,335
好事是我刚刚看望了威廉
The good thing is that I just visited Wilhelm.

313
00:45:39,340 --> 00:45:42,720
他感觉好多了
He has the better.

314
00:45:43,380 --> 00:45:48,125
他们好好地照顾他，他活了下来
They take good care of him, and he survives.

315
00:45:48,130 --> 00:45:53,770
我应该跟你们打声招呼，他很快就会回家
I would greet jer. He'll be home soon.

316
00:45:56,220 --> 00:45:59,715
坏消息是我们是落后的
The bad news is that we are backward.

317
00:45:59,720 --> 00:46:04,135
本周我们的任务应该是每人每小时解除八颗地雷
The rest of the week we should disarm eight mines per hour.

318
00:46:04,140 --> 00:46:07,505
- 都清楚了吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Is that understood?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant.

319
00:46:07,510 --> 00:46:11,175
- 我没有听清你们说什么！ - 是的，军士长！
- I can not hear jer!  - Javel, hr. sergent!

320
00:46:11,180 --> 00:46:13,540
不错
Well.

321
00:46:14,220 --> 00:46:20,630
十分钟后出发，把早饭吃完
Departure ten minutes. See to get eaten finished.

322
00:47:13,360 --> 00:47:18,605
如果我回到家，我一定要啤酒和女孩
As soon as I get home, I should have beer and girls.

323
00:47:18,610 --> 00:47:24,190
- 你有女朋友等你回家？ - 不，我去找一个
- Do you have a girlfriend back home?  - No. I go straight out and get one.

324
00:47:24,860 --> 00:47:28,775
- 你不去看望你的父母吗？ - 你需要等一等
- Are not you visit your parents?  - They must wait.

325
00:47:28,780 --> 00:47:31,195
你有什么打算？
What is your plan?

326
00:47:31,200 --> 00:47:35,605
- 去赚一些钱，对吧？ - 对呀，我的朋友
- Make a lot of money, right?  - Namely, my friend.

327
00:47:35,610 --> 00:47:38,775
- 去做什么工作？ - 当然是建筑工人了
- How?  - As masons, of course.

328
00:47:38,780 --> 00:47:43,485
德意志需要重建，这将是我们的任务
Empire gotta be rebuilt. It will be our task.

329
00:47:43,490 --> 00:47:47,275
- 沃纳，恩斯特和他儿子  -“他儿子”？
- Werner, Ernst and sons.  - "And the sons"?

330
00:47:47,280 --> 00:47:50,025
我们的儿子接管这个公司
Our sons to take over the company.

331
00:47:50,030 --> 00:47:53,655
这听起来不错，当我们使用“和儿子”时
It sounds better when we use "and sons".

332
00:47:53,660 --> 00:47:58,485
我们会拥有自己的公司，将来会把家业传给儿子
We own the company. There is no one who realizes that there are no sons.

333
00:47:58,490 --> 00:48:02,285
- 好主意！路易斯和儿子  - 听起来不错，对吗？
- Good idea. Ludwig and Sons.  - Sounds great, right?

334
00:48:02,290 --> 00:48:06,655
是的，几乎一样好，沃纳，恩斯特和儿子
Yes. Almost as good as Werner, Ernst and sons.

335
00:48:06,660 --> 00:48:10,160
闭嘴，这太重了
Shut up, it's heavy.

336
00:48:25,770 --> 00:48:28,070
嘿，我说！
Gently, I said!

337
00:48:30,990 --> 00:48:34,700
- 这里有多少反坦克地雷？ - 四十四颗，军士长！
- How many anti-tank mines are there?  - 44 hr. Sgt.

338
00:48:34,870 --> 00:48:39,200
- 重新计算！ - 二、四、六、八、十、十二
- Count again.  - 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12th

339
00:48:39,370 --> 00:48:43,920
十四、十六、十八、二十、二二、二四、二六…
14, 16, 18, 20, 22, 24, 26 ...

340
00:48:44,080 --> 00:48:46,750
- 四十四颗 军士长！ - 那么S型地雷呢？
- 44, hr. sergent.  - Og Sminer?

341
00:48:46,920 --> 00:48:51,220
- 十六颗 军士长！ - 再算一次
- 16 hr. Sgt.  - Count them again.

342
00:49:03,600 --> 00:49:07,770
- 我们应该叫它什么？ - 本尼，它叫做本尼
- What shall we call it?  - Benny. It's called Benny.

343
00:49:09,900 --> 00:49:12,610
本尼，本尼，本尼
Benny, Benny, Benny.

344
00:49:13,650 --> 00:49:16,410
- 不，它应被称为提米  - 不
- No, it shall be called Timmy.  - No.

345
00:49:16,570 --> 00:49:19,910
- 因为颜色关系  - 提米是黑色的怎么办？
- Because of the color.  - What Timmy with black to do?

346
00:49:20,080 --> 00:49:22,960
这听起来只是黑色
It sounds just black.

347
00:49:23,960 --> 00:49:26,290
本尼就很好
Benny is fine.

348
00:49:27,630 --> 00:49:29,880
我们把它叫做…
We call it ...

349
00:49:31,800 --> 00:49:35,300
提米本尼，提米是它的名字
Tim Benny. Tim is its first name.

350
00:49:35,470 --> 00:49:40,510
- 本尼是它的名字  - 不，不，我的朋友
- Benny is its name.  - No. No, my friend.

351
00:49:43,310 --> 00:49:46,480
来这里，提米本尼
Kom her, Tim Benny.

352
00:49:46,650 --> 00:49:50,400
看这是紫色的
Look at the purple color.

353
00:49:50,570 --> 00:49:53,240
一个漂亮的生物
A beautiful animal.

354
00:49:54,200 --> 00:49:58,910
- 这是什么昆虫？ - 有六条腿而已
- What is such an animal?  - A seksbener.

355
00:49:59,080 --> 00:50:02,580
- 黑甲壳虫  - 不
- A bark beetle.  - No.

356
00:50:02,750 --> 00:50:06,210
本尼提米，树皮甲虫
Benny Tim, barkbillen.

357
00:50:06,370 --> 00:50:11,000
- 本尼提米，六条腿的树皮甲虫  - 是的
- Benny Tim, seksbener  - barkbillen.  - Yes.

358
00:50:11,170 --> 00:50:14,840
本尼提米，六条腿的树皮甲虫
Benny Tim, seksbenerbarkbillen.

359
00:50:19,430 --> 00:50:22,180
所以要去睡觉了，可爱的男孩们
So it is in bed, boys.

360
00:50:25,560 --> 00:50:27,230
塞巴斯蒂安
Sebastian.

361
00:50:30,860 --> 00:50:33,230
都在这里
The spears are here.

362
00:50:34,650 --> 00:50:39,240
- 你们都在这里？ - 是的，军士长先生！
- Er her I alle sammen?  - Javel, hr. sergeant.

363
00:51:21,030 --> 00:51:24,035
- 住手！ - 看看他！哈！
- Stop!  - Look at him!

364
00:51:24,040 --> 00:51:27,710
- 闭上你的嘴！ - 住手！
- Close your mouth up!  - Stop!

365
00:51:30,580 --> 00:51:35,920
- 住手！ - 闭上你的嘴！
- Hold on!  - Luk så din mund on!

366
00:51:37,000 --> 00:51:41,550
住手！停下！
Hold on! Så Hold on!

367
00:51:44,250 --> 00:51:49,585
- 开枪射死这个混蛋！ - 先生们…
- Shoot the bastard right between the eyes!  - Gentlemen ...

368
00:51:49,590 --> 00:51:53,610
瞧，这些纳粹男孩互相照顾
See how Nazi boys care of each other.

369
00:51:56,550 --> 00:52:00,820
- 一，二…  - 抬起你的头！
- One two ...  - Up with the head!

370
00:52:01,170 --> 00:52:06,290
先生们，就到这吧，我需要这些孩子
Gentlemen, look here. I need the boys.

371
00:52:08,800 --> 00:52:12,215
- 你是谁？ - 卡尔·拉斯穆森军士长
- Who the hell are you?  - Sergeant Carl Rasmussen.

372
00:52:12,220 --> 00:52:15,585
这是我的人，我必须清除海滩上的地雷
It is my device. I must clear the beaches of mines.

373
00:52:15,590 --> 00:52:19,510
我需要所有的男孩
I need all the boys.

374
00:52:28,640 --> 00:52:33,980
我们进展的好好的，该死的丹麦佬来坏事儿
We progresses. Fucking Danes.

375
00:52:43,810 --> 00:52:46,910
往里走，男孩们
Go inside, boys.

376
00:52:55,770 --> 00:52:58,250
过来吧，路德维希
Come, Ludwig.

377
00:53:00,690 --> 00:53:04,340
路德维希，你去把自己洗干净
Ludwig. Go and wash you.

378
00:53:08,610 --> 00:53:11,685
嘿！
Hey!

379
00:53:11,690 --> 00:53:15,975
你他妈的到底在做什么，埃贝？我刚刚才让他们稳定下来
What the hell are you doing, Ebbe? Now I just got them up and running.

380
00:53:15,980 --> 00:53:18,895
你知道吗，我不认为这是命令
You know what, I do not think is in order?

381
00:53:18,900 --> 00:53:22,275
你为德国人在厨房拿食物
That you download food to the Germans in the kitchen.

382
00:53:22,280 --> 00:53:25,990
我只是给我和我的狗
I'll get myself and my dog.

383
00:53:26,900 --> 00:53:31,395
- 虽然他们是人们的眼中钉  - 你不是这样做的吗？
- People talk and get pain in the ass.  - Is not it you who makes it?

384
00:53:31,400 --> 00:53:34,775
不，但是奇怪的是，你还给他们偷拿食物
No. But it is strange, you have to pick up food, ??

385
00:53:34,780 --> 00:53:38,195
当我们付出农场，还要为你的食宿时
when we pay the farm for your room and board.

386
00:53:38,200 --> 00:53:42,670
你听见我对你说什么了吗？当我和你说时，你要看着我
Do you hear what I'm saying to you? Look at me when I talk to you.

387
00:53:43,820 --> 00:53:47,865
你可以告诉我，这些小男孩为什么会被侮辱
You could have told it was small boys, I got up.

388
00:53:47,870 --> 00:53:51,695
- 这情况有点变化  - 我不认为有什么问题
- It changes the situation a little.  - I do not think it does.

389
00:53:51,700 --> 00:53:56,575
你在战争中是否有资格？你觉得够了，你需要收拾干净
Are you old enough to go to war, you are old enough to clean up.

390
00:53:56,580 --> 00:53:59,275
男孩们不知道到底发生了什么事情
The boys have no idea what is going on.

391
00:53:59,280 --> 00:54:03,990
不，但你必须教他们什么，卡尔，这就是为什么你在这里！
No, but you must teach them that, Carl. That's why you're here.

392
00:54:05,990 --> 00:54:10,160
你像他们一样还没有开始，对吗？
You have not started to like them, right?

393
00:54:13,200 --> 00:54:15,325
不
No.

394
00:54:15,330 --> 00:54:18,615
记住你所做的
Remember what they have done.

395
00:54:18,620 --> 00:54:21,920
他们比我们更好
Better them than us.

396
00:54:24,290 --> 00:54:30,140
你能帮我找一些有经验的人到我的排里吗？
Can you help me get some more experienced men in my platoon?

397
00:55:31,850 --> 00:55:33,870
诱雷？
Pis.

398
00:55:34,820 --> 00:55:37,280
路德维希，停下！
Ludwig, stop!

399
00:55:38,450 --> 00:55:43,040
路德维希！有两颗雷连在一起！
Ludwig! There are two mines on top of each other!

400
00:55:43,200 --> 00:55:46,370
停下！有两颗雷连在一起！
Stop! There are two mines on top of each other!

401
00:55:46,540 --> 00:55:48,500
沃纳！住手！
Werner! Stop!

402
00:55:50,880 --> 00:55:54,670
我找到你了，你这个小东西
I got you now, you little bugger.

403
00:55:54,840 --> 00:55:57,840
沃纳！停下！
Werner! Stop!

404
00:56:09,150 --> 00:56:13,320
沃纳！沃纳！你在哪里？
Werner! Werner, where are you?

405
00:56:13,480 --> 00:56:15,150
沃纳
Werner!

406
00:56:18,700 --> 00:56:22,330
沃纳，你在哪里？
Werner, where are you?

407
00:56:22,490 --> 00:56:26,330
- 恩斯特，坐下！ - 沃纳？
- Ernst, sit down.  - Werner?

408
00:56:26,500 --> 00:56:29,170
沃纳，你在哪里？听到了吗？
Werner, where are you? Say something!

409
00:56:30,670 --> 00:56:35,300
- 沃纳，你在哪里？ - 恩斯特，现在放松
- Werner, where are you?  - Ernst, relax now.

410
00:57:09,250 --> 00:57:12,420
- 放开我！ - 别紧张！
- Slip me!  - Take it fun.

411
00:57:12,580 --> 00:57:14,670
我们一定要去找他！
We must look for him!

412
00:57:14,840 --> 00:57:18,260
- 放开我！ - 把他摁住
- Let go of me.  - Hold him fast.

413
00:57:20,720 --> 00:57:24,930
- 沃纳！ - 抓紧他
- Werner!  - Hold ham fast.

414
00:57:25,100 --> 00:57:28,310
安静，别紧张，孩子！
Calm. Take it easy, kid.

415
00:57:29,980 --> 00:57:31,520
好的
Well.

416
00:57:41,060 --> 00:57:43,400
出去吧！男孩们
In addition, boys.

417
00:57:46,690 --> 00:57:48,820
塞巴斯蒂安，好好休息！
Sebastian, out.

418
00:57:53,990 --> 00:57:56,330
你需要休息
You have to sleep.

419
00:58:03,330 --> 00:58:07,630
- 不，放轻松  - 我们必须找到沃纳
- No. Take it easy.  - We must look for Werner.

420
00:58:07,800 --> 00:58:11,630
我们明天再找沃纳，现在你需要好好休息
We're looking for Werner tomorrow. Now you need to sleep.

421
00:58:11,800 --> 00:58:15,010
来吧！我会先找到沃纳的
Come on. I will find Werner first.

422
00:58:15,180 --> 00:58:21,060
我们必须到海滩，我想救他，但他消失了
We must get down to the beach. I would save him, but he ran away.

423
00:58:21,230 --> 00:58:24,190
我们一定要找到他
We must find him.

424
00:58:24,360 --> 00:58:26,650
他坐在那里
He sleeps there.

425
00:58:26,820 --> 00:58:31,320
没有他我不能入睡
I can not fall asleep without him.

426
00:58:31,490 --> 00:58:34,660
- 让我起来  - 不，你现在需要睡觉
- Come on.  - No. You have to sleep.

427
00:58:34,820 --> 00:58:37,660
我们明天再找他
We're looking for him tomorrow.

428
00:58:37,830 --> 00:58:41,000
明天？听起来不错
Tomorrow? It sounds good.

429
00:58:47,800 --> 00:58:52,010
当我们发现沃纳时
When we find Werner ??

430
00:58:52,180 --> 00:58:55,930
我会和他一起回德国
I take him to Germany...

431
00:58:56,100 --> 00:59:01,180
我们建立了这一切，又一次打造了这一切
and build it all up again. We build it all up.

432
00:59:01,350 --> 00:59:07,230
这个国家已成废墟，这一切都需要重建
The country is in ruins. It all needs to be rebuilt.

433
00:59:08,860 --> 00:59:12,820
泥瓦匠…我们要成为画家
Masons ... We have to be masons.

434
00:59:12,990 --> 00:59:15,070
这是一个好工作
It's a good job.

435
00:59:15,240 --> 00:59:19,620
军士长先生…他们不可能拥有他们
Hr. Sergent ... They must not goodbye him.

436
00:59:19,790 --> 00:59:25,170
- 我也不会做  - 他们可能没有他们
- I do not either.  - Do not hate him.

437
00:59:28,750 --> 00:59:33,970
不，躺下来，放轻松，现在你必须睡觉
No. Lie down. Relax. You have to sleep now.

438
00:59:34,130 --> 00:59:38,430
如果你知道他为我做的
If you knew him as I do ??

439
00:59:38,600 --> 00:59:41,640
你会帮忙的
They would help.

440
01:00:40,030 --> 01:00:42,830
我对你说了谎
I have lied to you.

441
01:00:46,250 --> 01:00:49,380
威廉并没有活着
Wilhelm did not survive.

442
01:00:51,920 --> 01:00:54,170
我知道，军士长
I know, sir. Sergeant.

443
01:00:55,170 --> 01:00:57,930
但这也是最好的方式
But it was best that way.

444
01:00:58,090 --> 01:01:01,300
所以我们可以继续排雷了
So we could continue with mine clearance.

445
01:01:02,510 --> 01:01:06,390
总有一天我们可以回家
So we can come home one day.

446
01:01:06,560 --> 01:01:08,690
也许吧
Perhaps.

447
01:01:19,490 --> 01:01:22,740
别担心，你会没事的
Do not worry. I do not take it from you.

448
01:01:26,160 --> 01:01:28,620
十字架会帮你渡过难关的
Helps the cross you?

449
01:01:43,100 --> 01:01:47,230
- 你也可以尝试一下，军士长  - 不用了
- They can try it, sir. Sergeant.  - No.

450
01:01:47,390 --> 01:01:51,940
就试试吧！军士长
Come on, sir. Sergeant. Just try.

451
01:01:52,110 --> 01:01:56,570
- 不用  - 我的意思是尝试，军士长
- No.  - I mean it, sir. Sergeant. Try.

452
01:02:03,660 --> 01:02:05,620
嘣
boo

453
01:02:16,290 --> 01:02:18,580
我从父亲那拿到了这个
I got it from my father.

454
01:02:21,040 --> 01:02:25,880
他总喜欢这么做，我每次都吓一跳
He always did this, and I got a shock every time.

455
01:02:29,300 --> 01:02:32,390
这就是为什么我有它
That is why, I have it on.

456
01:02:35,100 --> 01:02:37,310
这是你爸爸的？
Deliver your father?

457
01:02:46,860 --> 01:02:49,280
我不知道
I at not.

458
01:04:35,510 --> 01:04:38,260
- 塞巴斯蒂安  - 赫尔曼
- Sebastian.  - Hermann.

459
01:04:40,220 --> 01:04:43,350
- 鲁道夫  - 奥古斯特
- Rodolf.  - August.

460
01:04:44,940 --> 01:04:46,860
- 约翰  - 约翰
- Johann.  - Johann.

461
01:04:47,020 --> 01:04:49,940
- 过来，弗里德里希  - 赫尔穆特，你在我们队里
- Come, Friedrich.  - Helmut, you're on our team.

462
01:04:50,110 --> 01:04:52,860
过来，赫尔穆特！清醒一下吧！
Come, Helmut! Wake up!

463
01:05:01,540 --> 01:05:05,790
好，赫尔穆特！就是这样！
Well, Helmut! Such!

464
01:05:09,840 --> 01:05:12,260
传球！
Shoot!

465
01:05:24,810 --> 01:05:29,190
- 奥古斯特！ - 我一个人做不到！
- August!  - I can not do it alone!

466
01:05:29,360 --> 01:05:32,070
不会有下一次的，你个白痴！
Not again, you idiot!

467
01:05:32,230 --> 01:05:36,200
这是足球，不是手球，请用脚踢，谢谢！
It's football, not handball. Down to earth, thank you.

468
01:05:37,660 --> 01:05:40,830
路德维希，去那里看看！
Ludwig, kom her!

469
01:05:45,330 --> 01:05:47,420
来我们接着玩！
We play on!

470
01:05:47,580 --> 01:05:50,340
- 那是谁？ - 新来的
- Who is it?  - The new.

471
01:05:54,340 --> 01:05:56,010
你好
Hi.

472
01:05:58,220 --> 01:06:02,600
我们必须加入这个单位，拉斯穆森军士长在哪？
We must join the unit. Where is Sergeant Rasmussen?

473
01:06:03,560 --> 01:06:07,440
在那里，但我可以和你们一起去，我的名字叫路德维希
There. But I can join you with me. My name is Ludwig.

474
01:06:07,600 --> 01:06:11,520
- 约瑟夫·贝克尔  - 阿尔伯特·布劳尔
- Josef Becker.  - Albert Brauer.

475
01:06:11,690 --> 01:06:14,320
过来吧！我们有一天假
Come on. We have the day off.

476
01:06:53,020 --> 01:06:56,900
你叫什么名字？告诉我
What's your name? Tell me.

477
01:06:58,950 --> 01:07:00,860
放轻松
Take it fun.

478
01:07:05,620 --> 01:07:07,500
待在这
Stay here.

479
01:07:11,830 --> 01:07:14,090
这很好
It was good.

480
01:07:15,460 --> 01:07:18,800
一，二，三！快跑！
One two Three! Run!

481
01:07:36,360 --> 01:07:40,200
莫尔巴赫击打破了世界纪录！
Morbach has beaten the world record!

482
01:07:42,360 --> 01:07:44,450
看这里！
Se her!

483
01:07:53,040 --> 01:07:55,840
第一个进球真精彩
The first goal was fantastic.

484
01:07:56,000 --> 01:07:58,170
下次我们会赢
Next time we win.

485
01:07:59,260 --> 01:08:01,430
加油！加油！
Come on. Come on.

486
01:08:01,590 --> 01:08:04,340
你认为呢？
Do you think?

487
01:08:07,010 --> 01:08:10,520
这里，奥托，来吧！来吧！
Here, Otto. Come on. Come on.

488
01:08:10,680 --> 01:08:15,770
这里，奥托，来吧！来吧！
Here. Hopti. Come. Come.

489
01:08:15,940 --> 01:08:19,280
水是可爱的
The water was lovely.

490
01:08:19,440 --> 01:08:23,910
- 这是一些美丽的沙丘  - 是的，你必须去探索
- It has some beautiful dunes.  - Yes. You must explore.

491
01:10:08,010 --> 01:10:12,850
士兵路德维希·汉克，你是负责七号区域，对吗？
Soldat Ludwig Haffke. You were in charge of field 7, not?

492
01:10:13,010 --> 01:10:16,310
是的，军士长，所有的东西都标记了
Yes, sir. Sergeant. Everything has been posted.

493
01:10:16,480 --> 01:10:21,690
共一千两百颗地雷，一千两百颗被找到并被解除和标记
1,200 mines were buried, 1200 was found, disarmed and posted.

494
01:10:21,860 --> 01:10:27,240
- 但是你说错了，对吧？ - 没有，我数两遍
- But you have spoken wrong, right?  - No. I've counted them twice.

495
01:10:27,400 --> 01:10:31,370
一千两百颗地雷埋在那里，我们拆除了一千两百颗地雷
1,200 mines were buried, and 1,200 mines were removed.

496
01:10:44,550 --> 01:10:47,470
把球捡回来！
Get the ball.

497
01:10:47,630 --> 01:10:49,720
把球捡回来！
Get the ball!

498
01:10:50,220 --> 01:10:53,510
像狗那样！用嘴叼回来！
As a dog! With your mouth!

499
01:10:58,220 --> 01:11:01,810
真是一条好狗！一条非常好的狗！
Good dog. Very good dog.

500
01:11:03,310 --> 01:11:06,440
把球叼回来，快！
Get the ball. Quickly!

501
01:11:07,230 --> 01:11:09,860
不能用手！用你的嘴！
Without hands! Use your mouth!

502
01:11:17,350 --> 01:11:20,055
好狗
Good dog.

503
01:11:20,060 --> 01:11:23,475
好狗 真是好狗
Good dog. Good dog.

504
01:11:23,480 --> 01:11:26,210
好狗 坐下！
Good dog. His!

505
01:11:31,150 --> 01:11:32,725
学狗叫！
Bark!

506
01:11:32,730 --> 01:11:35,315
- 学狗叫！ - 汪汪…军士长
- Bark!  - Dare, sir. Sergeant.

507
01:11:35,320 --> 01:11:38,015
- 什么？ - 汪汪…
- What?  - Dare.

508
01:11:38,020 --> 01:11:39,895
大声点
Higher.

509
01:11:39,900 --> 01:11:42,900
狗叫！大声点！
Bark! Higher!

510
01:11:47,940 --> 01:11:51,485
你有什么想说的吗？什么？有没有？
Is there anything you want to say? What? Is there?

511
01:11:51,490 --> 01:11:54,870
想说点什么？
Want to say something?

512
01:11:55,780 --> 01:12:00,290
- 也许…  - 请停下来 军士长！
- Maybe ...  - Please stop, sir. Sergeant.

513
01:12:04,320 --> 01:12:06,630
白痴！
Idiot!

514
01:12:07,360 --> 01:12:09,775
你们都是白痴！
In're all idiots!

515
01:12:09,780 --> 01:12:15,220
我有一群德国白痴！听到了吗？每个人！
I have a bunch of German idiots! Hear? Each and every one!

516
01:12:15,570 --> 01:12:20,485
我怎么能保证海滩是安全的呢？告诉我！
How can I now guarantee that the beach is safe? Tell me!

517
01:12:20,490 --> 01:12:26,825
军士长，我们可以再数一数，看数量是否匹配
Sir. Sgt. We can count them again to see if the number fits.

518
01:12:26,830 --> 01:12:32,285
正确的数量？我们现在需要这些数字吗？
About the number fits? What do we need the number for now?

519
01:12:32,290 --> 01:12:36,075
- 我们应该怎么办呢？ - 什么？
- What should we use it?  - What?

520
01:12:36,080 --> 01:12:39,785
你能保证海滩是安全的吗？
Can you guarantee that the beach is safe?

521
01:12:39,790 --> 01:12:44,170
- 不能，军士长！- 所以就请闭上你的嘴！
- No, sir. Sergeant!  - So keep your mouth shut!

522
01:12:46,330 --> 01:12:50,380
我一直对你们太好了
I've been too kind to you.

523
01:12:53,040 --> 01:12:57,300
这就是问题所在，我已经用它犯了错误
That's the problem. And I have used it!

524
01:13:35,720 --> 01:13:40,545
你们从现在开始
From now on you go along.

525
01:13:40,550 --> 01:13:44,135
手挽手，彼此相依
Arm in arm. Next to each other.

526
01:13:44,140 --> 01:13:47,965
通过所有已经清除的区域
Through all the cleared fields.

527
01:13:47,970 --> 01:13:53,465
我必须保证我自己没有错误！
I must make sure that there will be no mistakes!

528
01:13:53,470 --> 01:13:57,070
信任你们是一个错误
It was a mistake to trust you.

529
01:13:57,760 --> 01:14:02,305
但现在一切都结束了，明白吗？
But it's over now. Is that understood?

530
01:14:02,310 --> 01:14:06,920
- 清楚了吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Is that understood?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant!

531
01:14:08,450 --> 01:14:12,450
他还不如把我们推到墙边，射杀我们
He might as well put us up against the wall and shoot us.

532
01:14:14,830 --> 01:14:18,210
你有话要说吗，士兵？
Do you have something to say, soldier?

533
01:14:25,970 --> 01:14:27,890
笑什么？
Laughing?

534
01:14:34,600 --> 01:14:38,060
好笑？你觉得我好笑吗？
Griner you? Do you think I'm funny?

535
01:14:41,320 --> 01:14:45,280
你觉得我很好笑吗？你好笑吗，士兵？
Do you think I'm funny? Nagging you, soldier?

536
01:14:45,450 --> 01:14:49,830
- 没有，军士长！ - 你为什么笑？
- No, sir. Sergeant!  - Why are you laughing so?

537
01:14:51,240 --> 01:14:53,750
你笑什么？
Why are you laughing?

538
01:14:55,750 --> 01:14:58,330
- 你是一个男人吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Are you a man?  - Yes, sir. Sergeant!

539
01:14:58,500 --> 01:15:00,790
- 你是一个军人吗？ - 是的，军士长！
- Er soldier?  - Javel, hr. sergeant!

540
01:15:00,960 --> 01:15:04,090
所以要像一个军人！你是吗？
So act like a soldier! Are you following?

541
01:15:04,260 --> 01:15:06,680
是的，军士长！
Javel, hr. sergent!

542
01:15:07,930 --> 01:15:11,640
- 还觉得我很好笑吗？ - 不，军士长！
- Still think I'm funny?  - No, sir. Sergeant.

543
01:15:11,810 --> 01:15:14,390
振作起来！
Pull yourself together!

544
01:15:17,140 --> 01:15:19,770
像一个男人一样！
Behave like a man!

545
01:15:31,740 --> 01:15:34,910
还有谁有话要说吗？
Is there anyone who has something to say?

546
01:15:37,870 --> 01:15:40,630
所以现在告诉我
So it now.

547
01:15:40,790 --> 01:15:44,050
谁有什么话要说吗？
Is there anyone who has something to say?

548
01:16:05,150 --> 01:16:08,740
很好！向前走
Excellent. Forward march!

549
01:16:10,410 --> 01:16:13,950
快！向前行进！
Come on! Forward march!

550
01:16:15,540 --> 01:16:19,870
通过所有清除区域，一丝一毫都不要错过
Through all the cleared fields! Centimeter by centimeter!

551
01:16:20,040 --> 01:16:23,420
直到我们有绝对把握！
Until we are absolutely sure!

552
01:17:52,400 --> 01:17:56,180
在我们死之前，让我们跑吧
Let's run away before we all die.

553
01:18:02,930 --> 01:18:07,720
你们聋了？你们没在那里？
Are you deaf? Do you find you just in it?

554
01:18:07,890 --> 01:18:11,440
我宁愿被英国人射杀也比这个强
I would rather be shot by the English than this.

555
01:18:11,600 --> 01:18:15,360
我们会坚持到我们做完的，然后我们就可以回家
We will be until we're done. Then we take home.

556
01:18:15,520 --> 01:18:19,030
军士长说我们完成了，我们就可以回家
The sergeant said that we are coming home when we're done.

557
01:18:19,190 --> 01:18:24,530
军士长？你觉得呢！军士长不是对你朋友的事说了谎吗？
The sergeant? You might think that your friend the sergeant keep your word?

558
01:18:27,490 --> 01:18:32,330
所以你到这里，要继续这个死亡行军
If you want to continue on this death march, so here you go.

559
01:18:32,500 --> 01:18:35,580
所以别告诉我，我该做什么！
But do not tell me what to do!

560
01:18:35,750 --> 01:18:39,550
当他意识到你消失了，我们会发生什么？
And what happens to us when he realizes you're gone?

561
01:18:40,920 --> 01:18:45,340
- 我不能答应  - 这不是你能决定的！
- I can not allow it.  - It's not your decision!

562
01:18:45,510 --> 01:18:48,970
- 我要离开这里！ - 你就待在这吧！
- I am out of here!  - You stay here!

563
01:18:52,310 --> 01:18:57,480
然而无论如何，他恨你，正如他恨我们所有人！
Fat, however. He hates you, just as he hates us all!

564
01:18:57,650 --> 01:19:01,400
让军士长在这里，因为他喜欢我们吗？
Make sergeant maybe it here because he likes us?

565
01:19:01,570 --> 01:19:03,820
抓住他！把他绑起来！
Tag ham! Bind ham!

566
01:19:05,410 --> 01:19:09,790
- 我说，把他绑起来！ - 放开我！
- Tie him up, I said!  - Let go of me!

567
01:19:13,670 --> 01:19:16,130
该死的叛徒！
Damned traitors!

568
01:19:16,300 --> 01:19:19,510
放开我！放开我！
Let go of me! Let go of me!

569
01:19:25,180 --> 01:19:27,100
你为什么不闭上你的嘴？
Holder of mund go?

570
01:19:28,020 --> 01:19:30,480
闭上你的嘴
Holder of mund go?

571
01:20:26,410 --> 01:20:29,290
卡尔！卡尔！
Carl! Carl!

572
01:20:31,580 --> 01:20:34,590
军士长在哪里？军士长在哪里？
Where's the sergeant? Where's the sergeant?

573
01:20:34,750 --> 01:20:36,960
救命！救命！
Help! Help!

574
01:20:37,130 --> 01:20:40,090
我的小女孩！帮帮我！
My little girl! Help me!

575
01:20:40,260 --> 01:20:43,640
救命！我的小女孩！
Help! My little girl!

576
01:20:59,320 --> 01:21:02,240
伊丽莎白！伊丽莎白！
Elisabeth! Elisabeth!

577
01:21:03,910 --> 01:21:08,200
坐下来，亲爱的！现在会有人来帮助你
Sit down, honey. Now comes someone to help you.

578
01:21:31,020 --> 01:21:33,230
快起来！
Wake up!

579
01:21:33,400 --> 01:21:36,400
恩斯特，其他人都到哪儿去了？
Ernst, where are the others?

580
01:21:36,570 --> 01:21:38,860
快起来，孩子！
Wake up, kid!

581
01:21:39,900 --> 01:21:43,240
其他人在哪儿？你们逃跑了吗？
Where are the others? Are they run away?

582
01:21:55,170 --> 01:21:59,300
你必须坐下，对不对？坐下
You must be seated, right? Be seated.

583
01:22:02,220 --> 01:22:05,050
你必须安静地坐着，对吗？
You must sit still, tax, right?

584
01:22:05,220 --> 01:22:08,100
待会儿这个男孩就会过来
Soon comes one of the boys out to you.

585
01:22:24,200 --> 01:22:25,320
恩斯特！
Ernst!

586
01:22:27,910 --> 01:22:30,290
恩斯特！
Ernst!

587
01:22:34,210 --> 01:22:36,130
你好
Hi there.

588
01:22:39,710 --> 01:22:42,380
她好了吗？
Has she turned up?

589
01:23:06,530 --> 01:23:08,160
是这里？
Of?

590
01:23:12,580 --> 01:23:14,540
还是这里？
Of?

591
01:23:20,170 --> 01:23:23,050
你知道沃纳吗？
Do you know Werner?

592
01:23:23,210 --> 01:23:26,430
他是个好兄弟，他看起来像是一颗子弹
He's a good brother. He looks like me on a bullet.

593
01:23:28,840 --> 01:23:31,060
我愿意为他做任何事
I would do anything for him.

594
01:23:35,890 --> 01:23:37,690
不要担心
Just quiet.

595
01:23:43,440 --> 01:23:45,900
恩斯特，给她给我
Ernst, give her to me.

596
01:24:08,130 --> 01:24:10,930
恩斯特，你要做什么？
Will you, Ernst?

597
01:24:14,060 --> 01:24:18,100
- 恩斯特，过来  - 恩斯特，到这里来
- Ernst, kom nu.  - Ernst, kom her.

598
01:24:18,270 --> 01:24:21,060
恩斯特，来这里！
Ernst, kom her!

599
01:24:21,230 --> 01:24:24,320
- 恩斯特  - 你在做什么？到这儿来！
- Ernst.  - What are you doing? Come here!

600
01:24:24,480 --> 01:24:29,320
恩斯特，回来！过来，恩斯特！
Ernst, came back. Come on, Ernst.

601
01:24:29,490 --> 01:24:32,830
- 你在做什么？ - 回来
- What are you doing?  - Come on.

602
01:25:22,580 --> 01:25:25,130
擦干眼泪
Dry eyes.

603
01:25:26,960 --> 01:25:30,970
- 重复一遍“很快就会过去了” - 很快就会过去了
- "It will soon be over."  - It will soon be over.

604
01:25:31,130 --> 01:25:34,850
-“我马上就要回家了” - 我马上就要回家了
- "I'm coming home soon."  - I'll be home soon.

605
01:25:36,720 --> 01:25:38,720
- 好多了对吧？ - 是的
- OK?  - Yes.

606
01:25:38,890 --> 01:25:41,230
别哭了
Stop crying.

607
01:25:44,520 --> 01:25:48,820
我需要你，其他人也需要你，知道吗？
I need you. The other needs you. Okay?

608
01:25:49,820 --> 01:25:55,370
- 要坚强，你能做到吗？ - 是的，我能做到！
- Be strong. Are you able to do it?  - Yes. I can do that.

609
01:25:55,530 --> 01:25:58,240
- 你要坚强  - 我很坚强！
- You are   strong.  - I am strong.

610
01:25:58,410 --> 01:26:01,000
- 再说一遍！ - 我很坚强！
- Say it again.  - I am strong.

611
01:26:01,160 --> 01:26:04,540
-“我马上就要回家了” - 我马上就要回家了
- "I'm coming home soon."  - I'll be home soon.

612
01:26:07,500 --> 01:26:09,920
很快就会过去了
It will soon be over.

613
01:26:10,090 --> 01:26:12,840
谢谢
So.

614
01:27:48,600 --> 01:27:51,180
- 古斯塔夫  - 是的
- Gustav?  - Yes.

615
01:27:51,350 --> 01:27:54,480
当你回家时你打算做什么？
What should you do when you get home?

616
01:27:54,640 --> 01:27:57,400
开个餐馆，我只想多吃点儿
Eat. I'll just eat.

617
01:27:57,560 --> 01:28:02,360
我的母亲是柏林最好的厨师，我厌倦了丹麦的食物。
My mother is the best cook in Berlin. I'm tired of the Danish pigswill.

618
01:28:02,530 --> 01:28:04,950
你必须邀请我们到你家
You must invite us to your home.

619
01:28:05,110 --> 01:28:08,870
当然！到柏林奥拉宁堡大街找我就行
Yes. Kom til i Oranienburgerstrasse Berlin ??

620
01:28:09,030 --> 01:28:13,540
你们将会得到丰盛的土豆泥、香肠和肉汤
and ye shall receive potatoes, meat and sauce.

621
01:28:13,710 --> 01:28:15,870
- 真好啊  - 当然
- The best.  - Yes.

622
01:28:59,130 --> 01:29:01,250
这简直是地狱！
Hell.

623
01:29:44,050 --> 01:29:46,300
出发吧！
Here we go.

624
01:30:23,460 --> 01:30:25,670
- 坐下  - 你想要干什么？
- Sit down.  - What will you?

625
01:30:26,670 --> 01:30:29,840
我们需要更多的有经验的人到斯凯灵恩半岛
We need more experienced people at Skallingen.

626
01:30:30,010 --> 01:30:32,510
是的，但我需要休假
Yes, but I need to Ringkøbing.

627
01:30:32,680 --> 01:30:36,810
是的，当然，这不是你的问题，这就是我说的
Yes, please. It's not you, I'm talking about.

628
01:30:38,520 --> 01:30:40,810
我们在谈论什么呢？
What are we talking about?

629
01:30:42,100 --> 01:30:45,610
你的德国男孩们
Your German boys.

630
01:30:45,770 --> 01:30:50,030
我们需要他们在那里，人们希望他们死得像苍蝇一样
We need them down there. People, they die like flies.

631
01:30:53,410 --> 01:30:56,580
雷区已经改变，这是一个混乱的地方
The mines have budged. It is a place of chaos.

632
01:30:56,740 --> 01:30:59,290
我们需要有经验的德国人
We need experienced Germans.

633
01:30:59,450 --> 01:31:03,380
我希望我能帮助你，但他们将被批准送回家
I wish I could help you, but they are sent home.

634
01:31:03,540 --> 01:31:05,670
我听说了
That I heard.

635
01:31:05,840 --> 01:31:10,050
- 他们在这已经超过十四周了  - 但是他们不会被送回家
- Four out of 14 made it.  - But they will not be sent back.

636
01:31:11,260 --> 01:31:16,140
我已经承诺，他们完成时就可以回家，我们现在完成了
I have promised, they came home when we were finished, and we're done.

637
01:31:16,300 --> 01:31:20,480
所有德国士兵都必须把所有的地雷清除才行
All German troops to remain until all mines are cleared.

638
01:31:20,640 --> 01:31:23,100
我的意思是每个人
And I mean everyone.

639
01:31:26,110 --> 01:31:28,190
埃贝
He had.

640
01:31:36,780 --> 01:31:40,250
我想告诉你，送孩子们回家
I would like to ask you to send the boys home.

641
01:31:40,410 --> 01:31:43,580
让他们现在就走，否则你就死在这里
Let them now just go. They die down there.

642
01:31:46,130 --> 01:31:48,920
我能理解你，卡尔
I can understand you, Carl.

643
01:31:49,090 --> 01:31:52,220
但我不能这么做，这是上面的命令
But I can not. The order is completed.

644
01:31:52,380 --> 01:31:56,430
- 这是关于这四个男孩的未来  - 现在，你应该听到我说什么了
- It is about four boys.  - Now, you hear what I say.

645
01:31:56,600 --> 01:31:59,220
如果我听到更多关于男孩们回家的消息
If I hear more about the boys ??

646
01:31:59,390 --> 01:32:03,230
我会把他们一个接一个的射杀
I take yourself down and shoot them one by one.

647
01:32:03,390 --> 01:32:08,190
这些德国人不是好人，他们只能这样
They are not good people. You do not know what they have on their conscience.

648
01:32:08,360 --> 01:32:12,400
你骗了我，你从一开始就没想让他们回家
You have lied to me, and you've done it right from day one.

649
01:32:12,570 --> 01:32:16,240
这些小男孩…小男孩…为他们的母亲而流泪
It's little boys. Little boys who yell at their mother ??

650
01:32:16,410 --> 01:32:20,660
他们害怕被炸掉胳膊和腿
when they get scared or get blown arms and legs.

651
01:32:23,370 --> 01:32:28,000
这是命令，这些德国人只能这样，卡尔
The Germans, Carl. The order is completed.

652
01:32:28,170 --> 01:32:30,840
如果你要尽自己最大努力？
If you find yourself out?

653
01:32:31,880 --> 01:32:35,970
- 谢谢你今天的谈话，卡尔  - 闭上你的嘴！
- Thank you for today, Carl.  - Shut up!

654
01:32:39,390 --> 01:32:41,720
埃贝
He had.

655
01:32:42,350 --> 01:32:44,980
就是这样，卡尔
It was all, Carl.

656
01:33:00,200 --> 01:33:05,210
我们认为还有七万两千颗德制地雷
We assume that there are 72,000 German mines ??

657
01:33:05,370 --> 01:33:08,750
埋在斯凯灵恩半岛
buried here at Skallingen.

658
01:33:08,920 --> 01:33:12,670
你们中有些人排雷的经验很丰富
Some of you have had the luxury ??

659
01:33:12,840 --> 01:33:17,680
之前可以有详细的雷区标记图可以用
to have detailed my cards available.

660
01:33:17,840 --> 01:33:22,760
在斯凯灵恩半岛，我们没有这样详细的雷区标记图
Here at Skallingen we do not have such cards.

661
01:33:40,820 --> 01:33:44,410
- 赫尔穆特·莫尔巴赫？ - 是的
- Helmut Morbach?  - Javel.

662
01:33:44,580 --> 01:33:47,580
- 鲁道夫·塞尔克？ - 是的
- Rodolf Selke?  - Javel.

663
01:33:47,750 --> 01:33:50,500
- 路德维希·汉克？ - 是的
- Ludwig Haffke?  - Bleach.

664
01:33:50,670 --> 01:33:52,460
塞巴斯蒂安·舒曼？
Sebastian Schumann?

665
01:33:52,630 --> 01:33:56,590
过来，来吧！上车！
Stig on. Come now! Stig on!

666
01:34:15,190 --> 01:34:18,650
都出来吧！下车！出来！
Get out. Come on. Out!

667
01:34:25,990 --> 01:34:28,120
走那个方向
I must go this way.

668
01:34:28,290 --> 01:34:31,540
这里，离边境大约有五百米
The limit is about 500 meters from here.

669
01:34:31,710 --> 01:34:34,590
所以你们可以回德国了
So are you in Germany.

670
01:34:34,750 --> 01:34:36,840
快跑！
Run.

671
01:34:38,300 --> 01:34:41,430
快跑！
Run!

672
01:35:33,900 --> 01:35:40,360
二战结束后，2000多名德国战俘清除了丹麦西海岸150多万颗地雷

673
01:35:41,400 --> 01:35:45,660
几乎有一半死亡或受伤

674
01:35:46,620 --> 01:35:49,870
他们中的许多人都是非常年轻的男孩

675
01:35:53,400 --> 01:35:57,650
罗兰·穆勒

676
01:40:32,850 --> 01:40:42,630
地雷区

