He is the kind of....
Why are you talling under the trees in PE class?
Get up and join the class.
Are you mad? Why did you run so many rounds just now?
Don't you want to know who is my husband?
Who?
He took around round beside me just now.
The most handsome one.
That one. What?
My husband. He is in a colorful shirt.
Zhang Shihao, class 975.
Blue summer love
Let's have a bet.
What?
3 scores ball?
Then 5 scores ball.
You are so boring.
Hey.
How about we bet which one of us walk dog in the night?
Ok. How much?
100.
You are so cheeseparing.
Are you an idiot? Then you do it yourself.
I bet....You pay the class fee for me.
OK. How much is it?
1200.
Hey. Let's see it.
Someone is walking his dog.
Let's see it.
I got it.
You played basketball again.
I played sometimes.
Hey. What are you doing?
I'm reading English.
So leat.
No.
I'll be the happiest man in the world.
I am stay with my classmate.
I'll go now.
I'm wearing shoes.
Where are you?
I'll pass the traffic lights.
Be quick.
Please tell me where we will go.
Bring back the milk for me.
Hey. It's going dark and you should get up.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
You come at last.
It's so late. Where will you go?
Guess.
I guess.
Go to watch Zhang Shihao, OK?
I will not.
Go....Please.
Go....
You beg me.
I beg you.
Do you Beg me?
Go.
Go, Go, quick.
Go. Please go with me.
Zhang Shihao swims everynight.
He is in the swimming team.
I can't see anything.
You can listen.
You really love him.
Yes.
But I don't know whether he has girlfriend.
Of course he has.
I don't know whether he loves me.
Of course not.
You ask for me.
No.
Please.
Zhang Shihao, do you have a girlfriend?
Zhang Shihao, my friend wants to meet you.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Zhang Shihao, do you hear me?
My friend wants to meet you.
Zhang Shihao, do you have a friend?
Zhang Shihao
Please don't shouting so loudly.
If the drillmaster come and find us here.
I will be punished.
Hey!
Did you shout just now?
My friend wants to meet you.
Who?
Who wants to meet me?
She will know your idea first.
Who is she?
What's your idea?
I really want to know who she is.
Who is she?
Hey.
Yuezhen, Yuezhen
Yuezhen!
Yuezhen£¬please go out.
Yuezhen£¬go out.
Lin Yuezhen, Lin Yuezhen
There isn't a Lin Yuezhen, right?
You want to meet me.
Yuezhen, go out.
Lin Yuezhen
There isn't a Lin Yuezhen, right?
You want to meet me.
Hey!
My name is Zhang Shihao. Scorpio. Blood type is O. I am in the swimming team and the guitar college.
Be quick.
Ok.
Let me see it.
Zhang Shihao's basketball.
I picked it up that day.
Zhang Shihao's shoes.
His shoes is in a big size.
Size 26.5.
You have his diary.
His writting is poor.
He deceived me to hand in homework and I got it without difficulty.
What's this?
It's love heart made by myself.
He drank.
YOu even keep the bottles he drank.
Don't throw it anyway.
His blinkers.
His ball pens.
I have been loving him for a long time.
But I only can take his photo slinkingly.
Pick up his waster.
Am I very timid?
I'll go home.
No.
I'll make friend with you.
Meng Kerou
What?
Hand it over.
No.
Please.
I won.
It's for you.
My present?
My name is Zhang Shihao. Scorpio. Blood type is O. I am in the swimming team and the guitar college.
Zhang Shihao, hello.
I'm your classmate.
I can't help watching you when in school.
I want to see you everyday in shcool.
I think you are a good boy.
I hesitated for a long time and then wrote to you.
Education office is reporting.
Zhang Shihao, 975 class.
Meng Kerou, 968 class.
Please go to the education office quickly.
I'll wait for your reply.
Be sure to reply.
Sorry.
It's not me. It's Ahmian.
I didn't write this letter. It's Lin Yuezhen.
There isn't a Lin Yuezhen, right?
You want to meet me.
My name is Zhang Shihao. Scorpio. Blood type is O. I am in the swimming team and the guitar college.
I'm pretty good.
Read this, follow me: housewife.
Good. Notice this plural form's change.
fe tuens to ves£¬and knife turns to knives.
Why do you write letter with my name?
Good, now read follow me: ambition.
Often we remember the ending of a word.
ion is an ending of a noun.
Meng Kerou,what are you doing?
Why do you write letter with my name?
Pick up the books. What's happen to you?
Meng Kerou, do you want to have meal?
Meng Kerou
20 boiled dumplings,please.
Ok.
Our boiled dumplings are big. I think 15 is enough for you.
Any soup?
We have many kinds.
Acid-spicy soup
I think greengrocery-Tofu soup is ok.
Boys don't like greengrocery.
Ok.
Do you study in the affiliated school
Yes.
My daughter is study there too. Her name is Meng Kerou.
Do you hear about her?
Yes. Her name is unique. She is quite well-known in our school.
Her name is not good. She is not mild as a girl should be.
Do you find out her name?
No. Her father.
Quite good.
Disgusting.
What about today's eaxm?
Which pages will the exam cover?
58¡ª67.
58¡ª67....
So much.
The teacher said that this chapter is finished.
So many words.
Don't you remember them?
Many not.
How do you pronounce this word?
develop, develop.
What about this?
Communication.
Be quick. The exam is near.
What do you want to do?
I am in the swimming team and the guitar college.
I'm pretty handsome. I'm not bad.
What do you want to do?
I'm going after you.
Ok. Thanks.
I will cook for you sometime.
Ok. Thanks. Bye.
I'm full and I'll go home. Hey?
What do you want to do?
I'm going after you.
I'm full of troubles.
Me too.
The girl of love.
Come to the center quickly.
Come beside me.
I'll take care of you.
Then sing the farewell songs.
We'll never cry again.
Do you like this music?
I like it too.
Do you know what he is singing?
I understand.
I understand too.
Is it boring goingout with me?
In fact I'm not so boring usually.
if you are more more familiar with me, I would be very interesting.
You konw.
Hey.
What?
Do you want to kiss me?
So quick.
Here?
Aren't girls shy?
I am, too.
Let's swim.
Ok?
Can you?
No.
I'll teach you.
No. Go.
Go.
No.
Quick.
I'm going ti see Lin Yuezhen.
I run to here everyday.
Drink and then run back.
Come.
Teacher, Are we kissing in this way?
We are dirnking like this.
Of course it isn't kissing.
DO you wang to kiss me?
You students are still underage.
Don't think about these.
Do you want to kiss me?
It is not allowed shaking hands in school.
Zhang Shihao, teacher wants to speak to Meng Kerou solely.
He's so strange.
What's going on?
Why did you look for me that day?
Nothing
I know who wrote "disgusting" on your desk
Who?
That one.
I thought you were gonna beat him.
Loser.
Do you know why he wrote that on your desk?
How can I know.
Because he likes Zhang Shihao
Then it should be her wrote that.
How are you with Zhang Shao?
We are just friends.
Then all I heard are only rumors?
Yeah,all rumors.
What rumors?
I've gotta go.
Bye
Bye,ride slowly.
Okay.
Hey,I'm full. I have to go home now.
Zhang Shihao
Zhang Shihao,please don't follow me after school.
Don't go to Dumpling Shop for dinner.
and don't come for me anymore.
Okay?
What do you mean by this?
It's impossible for me to like you.
What's wrong with me?
Why did you want me to kiss you?
Don't you understand?
It's just impossible for me to like you.
Why did you hold my hands?
Why?
Why?  Hey?
No reason.
How is you and the P.E teacher?
We have nothing.
But,but why did you want me to kiss you?
Stop bugging me.
Hey,why?
Tell me.
Why?
Why did you want me to kiss you?
Tell me.
Tell me a secret.
What?
Come on.
Tell me a secret.
A secret.
You really wanna know?
Actually I hate swimming.
You see my in the swimming pool everyday.
Actually it's boring alone in there.
Which sport else is for one man?
Many.
But swimming feels cool.
But,I want to get first place in the game,
and recommended to college.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about the secret.
It's a mess.
not a secret.
It's not?
It's not,think of another one.
I'm still a virgin.
Many people are still virgin.
Who?
Those who say they are,think of another one.
I have no idea.
What on earth you want me to say?
A secret.
Secret.
Let me tell you another one.
I scatter.
What?
I scatter when pissing.
Like a sprinkler.
Not linear.
I don't know why.
Maybe the hole is too big.
Don't tell anybody.
Fair.
I tell you a secret of mine too.
Where are you going?
Don't come here.
I can only tell you like this.
I think Yuezhen is very nice.
There is no Yuezhen,isn't it?
There is,she likes you.
And?
I'm very kind to Yuezhen,
help her a lot.
Went to swimming pool for you with her.
Sent letter for her.
Took the consequences for her.
I was always helping her.
Because I really like her.
So I think,I like girls.
It's impossible for me to like you.
You are a really nice person.
I don't wanna hurt you.
It's the worst excuse I've ever heard.
What excuse?
To refuse someone.
Next time I meet Yuezhen,
I'll tell her I'm gay too.
Belive or not,as you want.
I don't believe this.
Why did you still date wih me?
Why did you still hold my hand?
Why did you still want me to kiss you?
I always thought if i kissed a boy,
then i wasn't a lesbian.
How about you and the P.E teacher?
He just had bad luck.
I asked him if he want to kiss me too.
Yeah
Maybe,after kissed a boy,
you won't feel you are a lesbian.
Then do you want to kiss me?
Do you have feeling?
Want another kiss?
Are you still a lesbian?
Are we done like this?
Zhang Shihao...
Are you really not dating with Zhang Shihao?
I am not,really.
Okay,let me show you one thing.
What are you doing?
If keep writing his name using his pen,
he'll love me until the ink used out
You are so smart.
The ink is almost used out.
You are really not dating with Zhang Shihao?
I've told you many times.
Then....introduce me to him.
No
You know him.
Just introduce me to him,no big deal to you.
No.
Come on.
Come on,you know him....
Okay?
Will he like me?
No.
Really?
Yeah.
Zhang Shihao
Zhang Shihao,this is Lin Yuezhen.
She wants to date with you.
Come on.
Okay,my job is done,I've to go.
Wait,what should I do now?
What do you want to do?
What do you mean?
Okay,I wait for a while.
I'll call you.
It's here.
Bye.
Zhang Shihao.   Um?
Can you date with me?
Sorry.
Meng Kerou
Meng Kerou!
Who is there?
Are you looking for Meng Kerou?
You...
Where is Yuezhen?
She is cute,isn't she?
What do you mean?
What do you really mean?
You walked her home,didn't you?
What?
Boys love girls,girls love boys.
What else meaning?
What do you mean?
What do you really mean?
Don't you like Lin Yuezhen?
I can't love Lin Yuezhen.
I really can't love Lin Yuezhen.
I can't love girls.
No use. I have kissed.
Have you kissed Lin Yuezhen?
No.
Does Lin Yuezhen know?
If I were you, I will tell her.
Tell her.
If I told her,we may not be able to be friends.
No everyone in this world is like you.
This world is actually not fair.
Sorry
For what?
If you were 17,all you think about is if you can go to college or not.
If losing virginity can make it linear when pee
What a happy kid you will be
Zhang Shihao...
That's a very luxury restaurant.
I've never been in there.
The light is dark,feels so romantic.
And there are piano playing.
And there's a kind of lavender smell floating in the air.
And good waiters there,in black suits,
Walking around
We were there until 9 o'clock.
Yuezhen.
Zhang Shao said he want to go to my house.
So I took him home.
He sat on my bed just after entering.
Yuezhen
What?
My mom came back after.
Yuezhen,I....
I'm a girl,I should like boys.
Hey,don't bother my friends.
They are not bad.
I don't know your name yet.
Then what kind of boys you like?
Depends on my feeling.
Then how do you feel about me.
I...
Hey...
Hey!Me
Um...It's nothing actually.
The swimming team will have a game on next Wednesday.
I hope you can come to watch it.
Um...and
and...and I wanna say...
What are you doing?
Don't cry.
How about we going out together,okay?
Come on,don't cry.
Hey!Go!Hurry!
Are you crazy?Come back so late.
Can I sleep beside you?
What's going on?
Nothing.
Come on,tell me.
When dad passed away,
How did you come through?
I've said that,you are lovelorn.
Is he the boy comes here to have dumpling everyday?
It's doesn't metter,everyone has been lovelorn.
How did you come through?
I don't know,just come through like this.
I don't really know.
Just come through like this.
I wish to see that day soon.
Zhang Shihao,come on!
Channel 3,Zhang Shihao from the high school attached to normal university.
Channel 4, Liu Ziqiang from Dong Shan School.
Ready!
1,2,3
Come on,smile
A,B
C
What's so funny?
Give us a smile.
Why didn't you come?
How did you swim?
Sucks,but it's good for you to not come.
I don't wanna give up.
The summer is almost gone,i've done nothing.
Yeah,just hanging around
and do nothing
Haven't won any game,nothing at all.
What are you thinking?
But at least it'll leave something.
What kind of adult we'll be depends on what it'll leave us.
Where did you steal this sentence from?
I'm going home.
Me too.
I win.
I win again.
Still win.
I win.
You win.
Hey,um...actually...
That day on the phone,what I wanted to say is
if there was one day...
maybe after 1 year,or 3...
maybe you become to like boys.
You must tell me first
What the fuck are you laughing at?
I'm serious.
Xiao Shi,look,your colored shirt is flying away.
I'm thinking,
after 1 year,3 years,5 years
What will we become?
You are kind,unclouded and free
you'll become more handsome.
So,I seem to see after many years
You are standing at one blue gate...
Sunshine of 3PM...
You have some pimples
You are smiling,I run to you to ask you if you are good.
You nod
After 3 years,5 years or maybe even longer.
What kind of adults will we become?
P.E teacher? Or my mom?
Though,I can't see myself with eyes closed.
I can see you.
I'm a girl,I love boys.
Zhang Shihao was here.