Rainie Yang (Jade)
Isabella Leong (Takeko)
Spider Lilies/ Tattoo
I am only the illusion in your dreams.
you are also alive only in my dreams.
Do you wanna possess me privately tonight?
I'm Jade.
Why do people wanna get tattooed?
Are they dressed?
...or naked?
If I tell you that I have a tattoo somewhere on my body...
where do you expect it will be?
dress off, let me have a look.
So, my tattoo is very sexy.
It is so late, why don't you go to sleep?
Alright, I'm going to sleep soon.
You go first.
Hurry up, you little girl.
Alright, I'll go to bed in ten mins.
So, you wish where it will be?
I have been turned on by you.
If you wish to explore more...
Please buy my private declaration.
Grandma!
Hello, cam video lover
Do you wanna possess me privately tonight, my love.
Hello, is it Jade?
Ms. Jade, please...
you got off line suddenly yesterday again...
??????????????????
I tell you! there will be no customers if you still behave like this.
Could you please notice this situation!
alright! alright!
and...I'll get tattooed and perform live, is it feasible?
[August, 19 customers in total
they want to symbolize themselves with the tattoos.]
Miss, Miss?
You have been waiting for me?
come on, tell your sister how many sweet candies you made today.
these children made over ten JIN(half a kilogram) candies today, they are tasty.
alright alright
brother, how is it going today?
there is one thing, Takeko...
everybody call me Ching...but why only you call me "brother"?
Because I'm your sister.
I don't understand.
[Search: Dissociative Disorders
Dissociative fugue, inert and indolent]
Ching?
have a look at what I've done today.
I did it really.
How about this drawing?
Oh, a fierce face.
But that guy...he never paid you.
[Customer number079: Adong
tattoo needs: a lucifer head]
but, he do paid today.
where do you want to go? hum?
Fuck you!
?????
give me your money
you don't have? you lie to me?
Fuck!
My tattoo master told me, one tattoo had one secret behind.
As a tattoo master, you must know the secret.
I did pay you!
But you can't speak it out.
hey, Takeko, could you give me a tattoo...on my belly...tattoo...
a lucifer head, please. Takeko, Takeko!
You don't have any aesthetic feeling.
no one understand that.
or...or...here...here...
On my belly, a panther? alright? a panther! Yahoo! panther!
No.
you can't?
if you tattoo this...
I decide to tattoo a pair of knives on his arms
He will box far more strongly in this way.
In fact, Adong is a self-contempuous person.
He needs tattoos to bring him strength.
Takeko, where is your tattoo?
it's still here.
#@$!$#!$@%#$%^$#^#%^%^@%@%$#%
(Sorry, I can't understand Japanese)
@#$@$$!@#!
%@#%@#%@#%
$#$!$!@!@#~!#@
%@%@$@#$
%@%@#%@%#@
%@%@%^@^@$#!#$!
you like this tattoo?
It's a real body tattoo.
Takeko! you have a customer!
Wait. Wait. Wait.
Are you already 18 years old?
What's that?
If you haven't reached 18 years old, you can't get  a tattoo from Takeko.
which means that you are already 18 years old?
I am exactly 18 years old.
Can you have a tea with me later?
How about it? Come with me? come on.
please sit here.
Did you get tattooed before?
No, I just want to see it first.
give this to me, carry it by yourself. call us if you really want to get one.
Hey, Takeko, please do me a favor.
a very little favor.
do me a favor, give me a tattoo, whatever it is, please, please!
Takeko, Takeko!
Takeko.
please give me a tatoo on my belly...
a lucifer head, please!
You still have no aesthetic feeling.
Takeko, please!
%@#$!#$#!???
[It is told that those who can't sleep will not distinguish reality from dream]
[Jade has a break today
p.s. accompany grandma who can't sleep]
water melon or pineapple?
pineapple.
Grandma, I have something to ask you...
I met a neighbor today.
Her name is Takeko.
Do you remember?
Takeko.
hum...don't remember.
You don't remeber? it donesn't matter.
and...I had a green wig before.
where is it now?
wig?
the wig on the model when you sold clothes years ago.
ouch...it's not here.
Let me help you.
Did you throw it away?
Grandma!
You just can find it in such a dark place!
it's fluorescent, so different from other materials.
Grandma, I love you.
you're...stupid.
We can stop here.
It's over?
Why it is so fast today?
We can stop here today.
Is it a tatoo knife?
It's not a knife, but tattoo tool.
and... if I become plumpy, will my tattoo distort because of it?
will it distort like this?
and...
I wanna this golden flower.
How is it?
Sorry.
Why not?
this flower, it's on the way to hell.
hell?
It's Manjusaka.
(Manjusaka: Buddhism word, kinda means "the connection between the real world and the nether world")
But...
I saw one frind of mine...had one.
Really?
When?
When I was 9 years old.
9 years old? You can't trust you 9 year-old memory!
but it's true!
you have to think about why you want to get tattooed.
How about you?
Me? about what?
You should have tattoos.
Why do you want to get tattooed?
I...I forget...
my business card.
Jade?
Yeah, it's my name.
That's my Blog, where you can find my photos and diaries...
you will know better when you browse it. Bye.
[Jade's Blog]
[today, I met my first love in tattoo shop. I was only 9 years old then;
If you want to know my first love experience, please log in at 23:00 tonight.]
Hello, cam video lovers, do you wanna possess me privately tonight, my love?
Jade's coming!
you sit here.
Where is Takeko?
[5 people on line: Xiong, King, Mark, QiangSheng, Silence]
Will she come?
[Xiong: are you going to discuss your first love experience here?]
Yes.
Do you want to hear the love story of a little girl?
[I want to hear the first sex experience of a little girl.]
I wasn't even 10 years old when I first fell in love.
[Silence: such a liar.]
It's true!
I was just over 9 years old at that time.
I used to sitting in the threshold of alley.
Waiting for a neighbor to pass by.
I am Jade.
am I beautiful?
That is a very beautiful wig.
like this...
[That's not beautiful at all, lol...]
who said it was not beautiful!
????
I am vey beautiful when I dress it up well.
Am i beautiful?
huh, you are beautiful.
You accent makes you sound like a foreigner
Are you local?
No, I lived in Japan when I was young.
My mom is Japanese.
Japan? I have never been to Japan before.
I feel dull and lonely.
Do you wanna come to my house?
Isn't your mom at home?
I don't have mom.
There are only me and my grandma.
Why don't you have mom?
My mom...She...
When the earthquake happened...
mom carried me outside...
and...my mom herself...died when the house collapsed.
Alright...and...May I send the beauty Jade home?
Ok.
I will always remember...that beautiful dusk
and the sound he hummed when he drove the bicycle.
Little jasmine...
Will you forget me?
Please remember...I am still here.
[You slept with somebody when you only 9 years old? Did you feel painful for the first time?]
Little jasmine, please remeber. I am still here.
[Xiong: you fucked with your neighbor, was it high?
Mark: How much will you do it with me, just tell me.]
[King: Tell us the point! were you high?]
it's not high!
???
In...in...in fact...I...just...just...
just..just...start to record...then...then...you...you catch me.
So you haven't recorded anything... you can laugh out?!
Do you have some problem? Speaking slowly is acceptible, but you act slowly, too.
You can't just wait here, you must use some techniques.
Ask her whether she need some money or help form the cuties.
You can't even use such a simple techique?
You make me upset.
???????????
Hello, cam video lover.
do you wanna possess me privately tonight?
What's the hell?
Hey! I'm Jade.
What's on the letter?
Mom, I send you 3,000 Yuan, you can send me back if you are free. Be safe.
It's over?
It's very short.
She didn't mention Jade?
No.
Who's that?
Jade's mom!
Jade's mom?
I thought...
Her mom did...
She is supposed to be at Taipei.
but...in the earthquake...her mom...
After the earthquake, her mom brought her son out here, leaving Jade home.
Her father has been in jail for many  years!
Hello?
OK.
My house-moving truck is coming.
Oh, I hope everything will be ok on your way.
Thanks for your chocolate.
I will give it to Jade.
[Customer number091: Jade
Tattoo needs: unclear]
Ching?
It's time to sleep.
you have no story today?
not many customer came today.
But, there was a wierd girl.
She kept asking something.
And asked about my tattoo.
She ask for stories from you?
Not really.
I don't care, I have to listen to your story.
you tell me one.
Ching?
%@#%@#$!$!@
#@%@%@^@$@%@#
#@$#@$
@%$^#^#$&%^&%*&^*^(^(^&(^&$^#$%@
Your brother still can't recover from the earthquake.
But...
I'm getting closer to him.
But...you're a girl...
%$@%@%#!@#$!@$
I am not a coward.
^#%@%^@^$&^&^%^*%*
%^*^%&#^#$@$
ok.
^$%^%#$%@$#
%^&$%&^&%#^%@%@%#
Do you design tattoo patterns for each customer like this?
Change your type?
No. I think this uniform is pretty.
Did you browse my Blog?
I'm busy these days. No time to get on line.
such a busy guy.
If you have spare time, you should view it.
If you will, you can find some time.
frankly speaking, I don't like internet.
alright.
But I have to say, after you see my Blog, we will discuss tattoos together.
if you're impatient
you can find other tattoo masters.
[Silence: Hello, what's your story today?]
I am in no mood.
my lovers, if you want, you possess me directly, don't be wordy.
[300 points, private possession, ok?]
when she starts to dresses off, you press these two buttons to record.
don't forget to ask her if she needs?????? and how many times.
trap her quickly, don't waste time.
don't waste time.
65464556
[Wait!]
What's up?
[Don't dress off, chatting is ok.]
But 300 points are not cheap.
Don't you wanna see something?
[alright, can you show me your smile?]
Hello.
[Hello, are you upset today?]
it's ok now.
[I love the story you told yesterday.]
huh? you listened to my story?
Do you have cam video? pick up your mic and talk with me.
What's wrong? catch cold?
[I...have difficulty in talking...sorry]
That's fine. Then what do you want to chat?
[what kind of person are you?]
I...
I am...easy-going, happy...
sometimes upset...
but I feel lucky...
because I can do whatever I love to do, no one could interupt me.
[So, you want to do this cam video business yourself?]
That's right! I like to do this.
[Aren't you afraid of meeting some evil guys on line?]
Tt's impossible!
I'm here at home, it's impossible to meet evil guys.
and internet is virtual and false. I like here,then I get on line;
If I don't like, then I will get off.
But sometimes I was reproved by Sister Chong.
And Sister Chong is also false. I never see her.
[Sister Chong?]
Sister Chong is the web manager and my boss.
[and, am I false?]
If...
you remember me and I remember you...
and then it should not be false.
[Does your first love remember you?]
certainly!
It is so hard to meet him.
Let me tell you...
He designed a tattoo for me.
and he told me...he would tattoo that pattern on my body...
and I will show it to you, ok?
[you always...have day dreams like this?]
day dreams?
it's not a day dream! I remember it clearly.
[9 year-old memory is not trustworthy.]
It's true!
9 years old? You can't trust you 9 year-old memory!
it's true!
who...who are you?
why don't you trust me?
[memory often cheats people, especially yourself.]
What do you mean?
[because You...]
[look so lonely]
bad dad.
you promised me to come home evrytime, but you never really returned.
ok, and when you return, what presents will you give to me?
it's ok, Snoopy pencilbox?
It's nice.
Takeko.
Jade?
Remember my name this time?
Your hair...
Isn't it beautiful?
It's beautiful.
And then?
You look different from the images on net.
Oh...you browsed my Blog?
I...I didn't.
whatever, it's ok.
I'm here to tell you...
I made the decision.
Huh?
Didn't you ask me why I wanted to get tattooed?
I want to keep the memory of love.
so...I still need that one.
Because of your 9 year-old memory?
How about 9 year-old memory?
those who really forget somebody...
are adults, not children.
anyway...
I truely need a tattoo to remember my love.
I mean it seriously.
[early September 11 customers in total
male needs: strength
female needs: memory of love]
Wow...Takeko!
you are the fucking best artist in the whole world!
I love you so much!
you bastard.
why don't you accept elder sister-younger brother love?
(he means Takeko and him)
Is it true that you never really loved someone?
It happened long ago and it's over.
and...
was your lover a girl?
Aha! that's it!
we have same sex orientation!
Is it Ok...
if we can't become lover, we can be brother and sister.
is it ok?
you're a jerk.
but...my sister...
why I didn't see you have any girlfriend?
seriously, why not?
Why not? sister.
[Customer number091: Jade
Tattoo needs: unclear]
Anyway...
I truely need a tattoo to remember my love.
I mean it seriously.
When will you come?
after dinner.
earthquake!
Takeko.
Are you tired?
No.
it's alright.
I tattooed for Adong today...
It lasted many hours.
My eyes are tired a little bit.
but the effect is perfect.
Does he like that?
He loves it so much.
He asked me to be his elder sister.
No.
I am kiddding.
will you be here all the time?
I will.
But sometimes, you are late to catch me home.
cause the drawings need to be completed in a rush.
I don't want be alone at night.
I promise not.
I will pick you up everyday.
is it ok?
obviously, she's on line!
[5 people on line:Silence, J, Long, Johnson, Hao]
Which one is she?
[Jade, I...]
Hello, thank you all to come here.
Today, I will send a free chance for private possession.
If you have tattoos on your body, please show them to me.
I will perform only for you.
a very special show!
[Jade, I...]
[Jade, is it ok to possess you privately? 500 points!]
Show me your tattoos!
If you don't show me your tattoos, I will perform for someone else!
[Hao: I have tattoos]
Congradulations! Hao.
[It's private time]
you see...
these young women...
@#$@#$#?
????????
pretend to be an innocent girl.
they are all flirty and snobbish inside.
They cheat money out of men...
to buy famous brands.
to buy drugs, or sleep with some cuties.
They are all evil!
how...how...how...how...
...do you know?
why can't I know?
you are doing your job, don't you understand?
let me tell you.
these women...
needs men to teach them lessons.
Hao, what's your opinion for my privat show?
please share your experiences with others.
[Hao: damned high! Jade is so sexy]
Remember to possess me privately next time!
[can we have a talk?]
I know it's you!
show me your tattoo, I/????
[why do you want to see tattoos?]
what?
[why do you exhaust yourself like this?]
and you exhaust your money the same way.
spending money for private possession is really high, huh?
[I don't want to see you like this]
like what?
[you are wasting your youth]
What do you mean!
If you look down upon me, you can get off.
@#@$@#$@#$@#$@#?
[You will hurt yourself badly]
If you really look down on me, you just go away!
why do you come and teach me something here?
Who you think you are!
@#%@#$@#$@#?
dfsaWEWERW
[I am not conceited, but...]
you did this and you can't admit! And you wanna teach me morals here?
fdafasfdsa
[Xiong: Hello, stop quarrelling!]
[dickman: accept the truth that you are only a prostitute.]
[Langzi: let it go, we will get off if you're not going to perform.]
Jade is so tired today.
She wants to say good night to you all.
[J: private possession, please.]
Alright.
300 points.
The last private show tonight.
I want to keep the memory of love.
so...
I still need that one.
you are supposed to have tattoos.
why do you want to get tattooed?
I...I forget
viridescent moonlight
the haze covers little jasmine
I gaze at you
never wanna lose you
viridescent moonlight
the haze covers little jasmine
I am waiting for you
to enter my dreams
little jasmine
please remember I am still here
on the branch, blooms natrually
little jasmine
please remember me
do never forget me
Takeko.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
it's nothing.
Ching...
If someone wants this tattoo...
What's your opinion?
What's your meaning?
why do he want the same one?
If...He keeps begging for this...will you agree?
Then his tattoo is fake!
I hate the fake tattoo.
it's different from yours.
Even if it's fake...
it can comfort him.
sister...
you didn't say a word today.
it's painful!
I can't distract myself from the agony.
Even if you can abuse me or something.
Takeko!
it's me! I am the top master of knives -lucifer head Adong!
[Police Office]
You have been investigating this site for nearly a month...
Why don't you have any final decision?
I....I....I think....she...she...
is...is...not guilty as this shows.
Fuck you! what's your definition of guilt?
%@$@#$!#@$#!#?(taiwanese...)
I...I...I...
You what!...Fuck you!
if you cannot do this, you will never be a senir police! you are junor policeman for ever!
Out of my office!
[Silence: possess! possess!]
You despised me, then why are you on line again?
[I come here to say goodbye]
[I come here to say sorry]
[I am so sorry]
You shouldn't abuse me like that.
I didn't mean that, but...
but what?
[please, as soon as possible...]
[go away from your business.]
why do you keep saying this?
I am worried...
you are worried about me?
you are worried about what?
[traps are everywhere on the internet.]
[I have to admit that I have been noticing you]
[But I can't tell who I am.]
I can't bear you, you sucks!
you are shy and mysterious
[I care about you.]
So...you were jealous!
[sometimes...]
[it's my last request]
[please leave this business.]
then...why should I have to obey your words.
[because I...]
[I really love Jade, I hope you can be happy.]
because...
I really love you...
I hope you can be happy!
Wow...cool knives!
Aren't they cool?
Takeko is such a genius!
I'm finding some time to try these kniveies!
Isn't she here?
She told me not to bother her.
Do you have anything?
Yeah, I come here to make sure...something.
make sure... whether she will do the tattoo for me.
She has been working on the picture all day. She is very easy to get upset!
What picture?
Some...some damned boring flowers
Really?
To be honest, she is easy to lose temper these days.
I thought she didn't have periods.
you bet! She's totally a tomboy, extremely serious when she's working on her pictures.
She doesn't have femininity at all.
She is not tough and she still pretends to be cool like that.
and she is unsociable and eccentric.
She just think she is a real man!
yeah!
stop the noise!
Jade...
are you busy now? Adong said you were working on the drawings.
yes, it's yours.
Wow...really?
it's my picture!
you do not understand that. Tattoo is painful, I am telling you.
generally speaking, men get scared to pain more easily than women.
it's not true.
and when should I come? tomorrow?
it's that urgent. It's Firday ok for you?
ok, then I will come on Friday.
Friday...
you come late today and yesterday.
You didn't show up until the head called us to sleep.
Sorry, because of the drawings.
Is it?
Wow, it's so nice.
I think I have new story to listen to.
A customer wanted my tattoo...
But you didn't agree with it.
So...I alter to draw this jasmines pattern.
I want you stories, whatever it is.
You haven't told me story for a long time.
I tell you something about your childhood?
I have no story.
Everyone has his story.
Only if you forget yours.
Why are you waiting here? Go to sleep now.
I am afraid. I don't want to sleep by myself.
Ching is grwon up. Please be courageous, ok?
No. you can't leave me alone.
I am not leaving you alone.
I just...study in my classmate's
No...No...
You always say no.
Ching is not a good child. I don't like you any more.
I will not spoil you like mom!
bad sister...bad sister...
bad sister.
why don't you talk with me?
that night...
what happened between us is false?
Takeko, look at me.
That night...
I shouldn't leave my brother alone.
He can't recognize me now.
It's not your fault!
If I was with him, the result would be different.
It's accident. You shouldn't say this.
it's not our fault!
Why?
I can't understand your story...
why...why the story you tell today is so wierd?
It's only a story.
Don't think of it.
My head hurts.
Takeko.
why...I feel...
you are angry with me.
No, i'm not.
Don't think too much.
go back to sleep.
Jade.
is it mine?
yes, it's yours.
it's jasmine!
so it's not that Manjusaka.
This is for you specially.
This drawing is for me only?
I understand.
This should be my tattoo of love.
It's only a tattoo.
No. it's love.
I told you before, I need a tattoo of love.
After I said that, you draw this jasmines for me.
It's only a tattoo.
you have too many illusions!
What's your meaning?
Is it my illusion?
Or you conceal yourself too much!
Otherwise I will speak it out.
You thought you log in my Blog anonymously, and I don't know who you are.
That's you, why don't you admit the truth?
I can't understand.
Whether you despise me, or you just become a coward when you face your true feelings.
I'm sorry.
Why can you remember all these things?
How about you?
You choose to forget?
I don't.
Tell me the story of your tattoo...
the tattoo on the wall, isn't it real?
This is...my dad...when he was dead...
my brother lost his memory of anything...
All he can remember is this tattoo.
the doctor said my brother lost his memory of all things.
Please, give me the same tattoo pattern as my dad had.
So...this is the reason that you had this tattoo?
They are the most important people in my life.
Where is your mom?
did she return home?
she will never return.
Are you still mad at her?
Rreally? mom! Do you really miss me?
When you come home next time, where will you bring me to go.
Tokyo? Is it Disney land?
ok!ok!
She doesn't remember me.
just like you.
So...
I always have illusions.
people are all around me.
Will you remember me?
hug me.
Hello, cam video lovers.
Do you wanna possess me privately tonight, my love.
[off-line]
[Thank you for accepting my suggestion, don't come back...goodbye...
I love Jade.]
Sir, it's...it's done.
it is raining in the early morning
dew moistens little jasmine
its white leaves, chaste and fresh
I covertly kiss your breath
evening wind is breezing over grassland
sunset dyes little jasmine
smile bursts, silently and soundlessly
Takeko!
Adong! Adong!
Adong!
Ching!
Ching! Ching!
Should Ching be upstairs?
Ching!
Sorry, I am the police of XZ district.
as his case, he's in a coma, the point is  5...
belongs to deep coma.
I can't say whether he will wake up.
Takeko!
They are false!
why they are false!
Dad!
I didn't mean to leave brother alone.
I didn't!
You thought you tattooed this flower on your body, then I would wake up?
[I can't finish the tattoo, please forgive me, bye, Takeko]
[All I know is your false tenderness
and the existence of that unfinished tattoo]
[I can feel it...it's still...painful]
I have no other choice.
I can only live in virtual world.
I will be waiting for you here day and night.
[Silence: Jade! Jade!]
You come at last.
[Get off line immediately!]
[Get away from the internet!]
No, I won't!
You ignore me. I am drowning.
[Jade! please listen to me...]
[I...am a police]
what are you talking about!
Ja...Jade...
it's...it's....I...am...a police...
We..we..decide to...to... search your website tonight...
[we have been investigating this website for a long time.]
[The whole course of search and arrest will be recorded.]
[If you are still on line...]
[You will appear to be one part of the evidence]
Actually...
the one who loves me is not Takeko...
evening wind is breezing over grassland
sunset dyes little jasmine
smile bursts, silently and soundlessly
I cannot see your secret
viridescent moonlight. the haze covers little jasmine
little jasmine
please remember me
do never forget me
I will get on line to wait for you.
This is my last request...
Please...remember me.
A computer can make you cry like this...
Don't cry...don't cry...
alright...don't think of the computer.
34234234
Brother.
sister!
why can you remember all these things?
And you?
Do you choose to forget?
[Sorry, I will wait for you in the tattoo shop...]
the background of this movie is the 921 Taiwan earthquake(21th, Sep,1999), many people lost their families during the earthquake.