This is a latte
Taipeipeople'sfavorite coffee
Dorisdoesn'tlike
decorating the eurteoo
Itthere'se beDere...
youcan'tsee how the cream blends
with the mild teem
It'sdifferent each time
These are ecleire
Doris'sbest dessert
Look...
Each one is slightly different
Because food is much lidsd¡ã¡ãd'¡ã
Not all the same
If you fancy tastingDoris'saclaira...
you'llneed to come
toDoris'sCafe on a Wedneodoy
Dee, tde deeeeD menu odeedee doily
This is Doris
The owner ofDoris'sCofo
She'slong dreamt
of having an elegant coffee Shod
A year ago...
when her aunt emigrated to Shanghai...
she knew the moment had come
She told her former hone
she was quitting
This thing is really not bad
And really expensive
Many people want one
You want to see?
You...
Look closely at the joints
It'sso well made
Take a look
Take a good look
Explain to her, Ah Kuo!
Now watch...
its best feature!
One, two, three...
The Flying Fist!
This isDoris'sCafe
Now you see it...
Not all that elegant
Why does the coffee shop look like thisy
Betere wed¡ãee with the steW...
lets just listen in for a moment
These are Dories leteet thoughts
As I see if, a beautiful cup...
is woAh more
than a baseball aibeab by a afar
I'mtelling you
The pictureisn'tworth that much
In that customers mind...
the picture is worth more
thee the eotiee toy
If wehadn'tlived here before...
Iwouldn'tswap if
And in my sisters mind...
the pictureisn'twoAh
the price of two coffees
That'senough talk
Another coffee,
please
I'llhave another toe
Okay...
If you really want it that much...
I'llswap with you
Really?
What matters most is
its inner value
She'sexhausted.
Take a rest yourself too.
Oh absolutely, thank you.
I'mcome back hors
tomorrow moraiab at b:bh.
Let me show you how to lock the door.
It'scow cow oooy.
Just...
Of course, of course.
I'mnot bothering you anymore.
Good night.
Have a nice dream.
Thank you.
Bye.
One Year Earlier
Tastes good!
It'schocolate
Really good!
Look howyou'reeating it!
Great!
Not bad,today'sisn'tbad
Idon'tlike cheesecake
Lots of people do, though
Everywhere sells cheesecake
Then why ask me?
I'mjust asking
Idon'tlike cheesecake
Must have a sofa
A really soft and comfy one
Nope,that'dgive you less loading
¡°Loading¡±?
Customer loading
But look,
there'llbe a huge table at the her
Thatli have really high loading
Ever been to a shade-adobe p1000?
¡°Loading¡±?
Refills
This is Josie
Refills?
Wewon'tdo refills
Did you really major
in Business Studies?
It Doris could modu nr dur own mind,
shewouldn'tget Jonie involved
ButJooie'omother ended her
to ho nomothieg ooeotreotivo
AndDoris'smother told her
she'dneed a helbied hoed
As it debbees,
their mothers ore the some person
So even if Doris h000et really want
Jeeie working in the veto...
it'snot her call
Doris'sdream finally came tree
From now on...
there'sa place
where she can make all the decisions
She sees hereelt...
taking a step towards freedom
Hello?
Swontin!
I'min the mountains,reception'slousy
I'mbuying some cello lilies
Don'tyou remember?
My cafe is ebeet to oboe!
Come, and bring a gift!
You absolutely have to coma
Young lady,
don'tyou know how to drive?
You kit my trnok!
Mister, you hit me first!
Look at the state of my bembor!
Come on,
you know how much it will cost to fix it?
-Cou'cohoutok my truck, too
-My koohligk?o okoCorok!
Mister, I was going uphill
and you were going downhill!
I hod the right at way
Says who?
My ex-boyfriend
Uphill? Downhill?
Hello, is that Mr. Hsu?
I cant deliver the flowers today
Ito pouring with rein up here
There'sbeen a muhelihe,
theroad'sblocked
Nethieb oheebeh after this oellieiee
Neither of their wallets
got fafter or thieeer
The oelle iliac that were as their way
downhill kept going downhill
But now inDorin'nonr
Sic, put this vase on the bar table
WhatlI webs with all these tlewere?
Idon'tknow either
This one?
Uh-huh
Listen, all of you,Doris'sCafe opens
the day after tomorrow
Wdot'IIwe do odoet gifto?
Send one big one together?
Sr all do our own?
Gifts?
Better ask Hugo
Ask me?
Sure,aren'tyou the¡®creative'one here?
I'dsay...
Send something useless,
doesn'tmatter what
Hello, hello, friends arriving!
Hello
Hello, Auntie
Hi, Erock, have a flower
Thank you!
Hi there, ceegreteletiene
Hi, Eggie
Is the dog a gift too?
No,he'sjust here for fun
This is for you
Thank you!
Come in, welcome
Doris is inside
-Auntie...
-Hello, welcome
Congratulation
Nice to have you here
This place is beautiful!
And you are...?
Tora
Okay,let'schat later
Okay
Why did no-one bring anything normal?
Hugo, what on earth is that?
Weighs a tan...
Welcome,
Hugo
Help me with this
Ito not heavy at all!
You'rejnot showing off, goon in!
Welcome the boss
ofDoris'sCafe... Doris!
Speech, speech!
Give her a big hand
Thank you all for coming today
Can'thear you!
Turn on the mic!
Louder!
Hello.., is that better?
Can'thear you!
Okay, okay,fhof'IIdo
Thank you all for oomiad fokoy
I hopeI'llbe running thisCaf¨¦
for years and yearn
Can naih that
sheet warhieg in aer aCioa!
Yeah, you did!
This is different
This timeit'smy passion
You said art was yssr psasias tss
And playing deAn!
-And being a ntrnnt noint!
-Okay, abny
Doris has so many friends...
Enough to¡ã¡ãbthis bl000 going
for yosro
That'sright,
come here for your coffees!
We come here for the cello lilies!
Calla lilies...
Don'tbe embarrassed
You guys brought so many gifts,
I feel blessed
Don'tmoetios it...
Didn'thave space
at home for all that juah
When Dana aahah tan diDa an DDD...
it was because
she had too many oalla lilies
Too many ta heal with
So she invited her friends...
to her epeeie hey
Made her feel popular
Now she has a new problem
Surveying all the junk they brought...
she wieheh ahab heewe
they'htehe her at her werh
What she should have put on MSN was...
¡°Ihave a treohlash at veilslilies¡±
¡°Ifyou want some
and would like to seeme...¡±
bring some superfine flour
erArabica beans in exchange
Of all your friends...
Hugo sounded the most oiuooro
Ma, you must be kidding!
He'sso glib!
But hedidn'tskiD the issue
¡°Didn'thave space
at hems tar all thatjeeD'
Shouldn'tyou have
jeof asked for money?
Why all fhooo voile lilioo?
Just shut up
Shut up
¡°Ifit were you,
would you have taken cash? Or callalilies?¡±
I'ddefinitely take the lilies
With calla lilies...
you can use some
to decorate your home
And give the root to your triouho
Cash, of course!
What use are all fhaaa flawara?
l'hfaha tha calls l!l!aa
I could set up a market stall!
I'dsell all the calls l!l!aa...
and use the money to fix my car
I'dtake half sad halt
First see how much cash
he has on him
Thee tehe the beleece is Fewere
I guessI'dprefer him
to pay me off in cash
Whet could I do
at home with cello lilies?
¡°Gatherye rosebuds while ye mey,
old time is stilla-flying¡±
Calla lilies are good
Cash
Give'emto your friends orseII'em
Because I need to get my car fixed
Well, Id go for the cells lilies
How many kilos in one catty?
Welcome!
Sorry,I'mjust here for my friend
Thanks
What are you doing?
Throwing it away
Throwing it away?
Three eggs: NT$15,
sugar: NT$18,
cocoa powder: NT$7...
Haifa pack
of iahfffngere aione is NTPt2h!
Not tergeffing the powdered coffee,
the coffee oak the oreem!
You know how much
I spend making tiromion?
Yronnh NTPdbb!
Then what shall I do with it?
Give itto Unola
He already has some cheesecake
Then give it to that gay as the third tlser
He'sabroad
Then eat it yourself!
I thought all your friends
were coming here?
Not one of them hoe ehewe ad
At least I have some friends,
unlike you
It'sactually knife deed
Bin it
The problemisn't
the tiramisu
The problem is all that junk
I'llget rid of if all tomorrow
Hey, Borough Chief!
Need a hand with that?
No, thanhe,we'redee
Come on in
Sorry about the mess
It just opened, nice coffee smell
-Have a seat
-Thanks
I'msorry...
Let'ssit here
Sowhat'syour latest recommendation?
Keaholi is Soisload Chiso
Kundali? Where is it?
Exit junk, enter customers!
We can lose that wooden horse too
Sie, how ooe yea odd ee?
oleir to the bill?
Hewon'tmind
A Thai cookbook
What'sa Thai cookbook doing here?
Search me
There'sa lot of weird stuff here
Is this far esleT
I'llask her
Miss...
Can you come over?
Is this book for sale?
Wedidn'tpay for if, so wecan'tsell if
Youcan'taellit'f
It'snot for sale
Why do you want it?
It'sin Chinese too
Whywon'tyou sell it?
Why not?
You can exchange something for if
Exchange?
It'sfor exchange only
That'sa pity
What do you want in 000handaT
Well?
Our backyard drain is blocked
My sister is asking me to unblock it
But it I go ask be tkst...
there'llbe no-one to serve you
Unblock the brainy
In 000hoebo tsr thioy
My son can do it,it'seasy
Is it a deal?
I'llsee to your drain...
end you give us tdu deed
Fine
So we have a deal?
Just take it
I'llsort out the drain
Hello,
Madam...
I'llgive you this
Thanks, take one of these
Boss!
I'llgive you this
What is it?
¡°Exchangegoods atDoris'sCafe¡±
That'shard ward!
VisitDoris'sCafe!
VisitDoris'sCots!
Oh, yes...
Everything'sup for exchange?
-Mm, you can look around
-Okay, Thanks
There are too many ooooo adobe
We need to stand out
You'reso oeeoyied
Idon'twant to gaddam stand ant
Yaar Cat? is ndnOial,
tall at strands tdiadn
Mr. Lin,I'mthe one who called you
Hello,I'mJosie
Don'tyou want a set of bone china?
Not tar ma, i?o tar Do
Give me a few months andI'llget a set
The reason I veiled yen ia..
we want to make a wabaita
for exchanging thinga
I'meat apanhing money an any wahaita
Itdoesn'tdove to doe wodoito
A died wiii do deed oeoedd
Why this exchanging thing?
Because I need some bose ohiee?
Yup
And?
AndI'dlike a car
My family used to run a pawn adap
The house was always
crammed with paweah doaha
I heaw how to gica thom a hoahooha,
maha thom haaitata...
You'regiving me a headache already
Sowhere'sthe eteS eawy
What stuff?
The pawned goods
You know what people do
when they need to atop end thiehy
Whety
Your sisterwon'tlike this!
They order another ooffoo!
Sis...
I think we need an extractor vent
There'sair pollution
What about the palletian
stall Taur junk?
All these things are exchangeable?
Have you brought anything?
There'sno light bulb
Doesn'tmefter,
just put one in subit'llworb
What can I swap for if?
Youdidn'tbring anptding?
No, butI'mthinking...
At home,
I have another lomb I oonlh bring
Exchange one lamp for another?
Yes, and mine hone bald in if
It'snot working out
as well as Josie said it would
Lots atd¡ã¡ãd1¡ãosmo and look around
But not many of them exchanged things
The been chine end the oar
ore etill nowhere in night
Idon'twant another lamp
Idon'tdnow...
One lamp for another!
Jeeie defends her pee!f!en
She says people are still looking for
the right pleoee te pet this stuff
They just havent found them yet
It'sgood
You like it?
What? Too bitter?
I like it bitter
I like espresso, too
None of these things is for sale?
Only for exchange?
It'smy sisters idea
I like the baSer system
Do you know Sofa Guests?
I'ma member
Everyone has a sofa at home, right?
You just offer it
to a backpacker guest
Maybe someone
from Europe or America
He gets to ooco Os the coot of o betel
And next time you go abroad...
you get to abed tar tree
on someoneelse'ssofa
In a way,that'sa kinh of osohongo too
III add some water for you
The exchanges hihef set eeythieg
valuable for Jeeie...
but if definitely helped the beeieeee
Isn'tthat
what Doris wanted at the ostoot?
Than why is ohs shoot sow?
It'sa question of skills
People care about their skills
Doris heeent like her skills
taken for greefek
Whilek¡ã¡ãk'¡ãkosher
where thekIl 0 lomb...
theydon'tnotice her skills
You said you woutod
to study oft duoidu
And you?
You said you wanted
to study duoiuooo trodo
Later you said
that art designwasn'tfor yen
And yanL
You said business trade
wasn'tfor you oifdor
I fdiud dofd of you
lack staying power
You give
up
No strength!
You want stronger moooogo?
No,I'mtalking to my daughter
The one at the oeh!
You took a hootry-mohieg oboe...
Then a coffee-making class
And what did yen aayT
¡°Ifit'sgood,
we'llget lots of repeatbusiness¡±
And sow? Are yes is prodt?
You'veeven otorted a sideline
I had nothing to do with that!
That wasJoaia'aidea
I spend all day daiad myjad...
making coffees and dooooffo
She told me to unblock the drain
Same old thing
Business tradewasn'tfor you
Unbloohing drainsisn'tfor you either
Sowhat'sthis thied
shout rassiad Os osohosgo?
Doesn'tif sound like another
form of business treks?
Desk morning
Aren'tyou rather early?
We'renot open yet
I'vebrought some things to exchange
Take a look...
See if you want any of it
don'tthink
theree anything here I want
So I goat know what exchange to make
How about this...
I'llleave these here
And you help me decide
what to exchange them for
I decide for yen?
They'reall soaps!
It nobody wants a bar at soap...
I can throw in a story with each one
A atary?
Throw in how?
You'llwrite it down?
Where'sMehegeecer?
Off the eceth-eset ceest et Atrice
It'san island
I sort of remember...
Deep in the forests there...
you can find the Decil Tree
Why'sit called that?
They say that it yaa small its tradraaca...
They say a group of people
set out to find the Devil Tree
They were determined
to smell this unique fragrance
Nothing in their whole licee
meNereh mere
to them than this
So...
I guess you could call it...
the inner value
This cafe isverf'interesting
Come on,it'scool insihe
Come in, all of you
Come on,
come on
Let me explain
This cafe is really interesting
Of course if sercee ceffee...
which you can pay for
with NT$or Mainland Chinese yuan
But acarything elan you can nan...
Just look at all this stuff!
Youcan'tbuJ it,
scan with US$or¡ãb¡ã¡ã¡ã¡ãJ05
You have to bring something
of your own onh ooohongo it
You'retram...?
They'respecial guests
from Mainland China
Anything yen went te heew, ash me
Feel free to look around
Okay, thanks
Two cappuccinos
Take a seat
What'sgoing on?
Sic...
We could give these dumplings
to the thirh-tleer guy
He'shad plenty
Really?
He gets them every time
Fourth floor?
Why did you make so many?
I'mstuffed
You know what?
That stewardess with short hair...
She has a pug strap on her mobile
The kind I telh yen sheet haters
The one youcouldn'tfind in Taiwan?
Yen, I really wont cnn
Excuse me, can we have some water?
Thank you
I'llcheck if out for you
Ito oo great that you got to ky ocory hay
It'snot so great, just makes you old
Really?
But you get to visit so many places
My sister osys...
youcan'tbuy those in Taiwan
This?
I bought it in France
See?That'sso cool!
Could you buy her one
next timeyou'rethere?
Your oiotor lihee them?
Thenit'shers
Icouldn'ttake yours
Could I take a look at it?
Nice to see a real aaa at loot
It'sso cute
I used to have a pug
Then you can have it
Oh, Icouldn'tdo that
It'sairight, take it
Let me buy it from you!
No way
All we sell here is coffee
Everything else you can see here...
Like all that stuff on the choices...
That'sall for exchange
Exchange?
How about telling her a stew
in exchange?
Heeb ihee
You have no other customers right sow
Moho yoeroolt a cab at coffee...
and tell us a story
Ihaven'theard a story in ages
I'mnot that great at telling eteriee
Never mieh
heat mehe her teal ewhwerh
If exchange is the rule here...
how about giving me eeether ceffee?
That would be an exchange, right?
Not such a tair exchange...
Three coffees, then?
Okay, okay
I'lltell a etory on her behalf
And you give if to her when I tieieh
I only finished junior high school
Dad dish when I
woo obonf fogs on fo senior high
He left us some money
Anyhow, Ma made out two slips ot popor
One said:¡°Travelround theworld¡±
The other said:¡°StehT¡±
We two kids drew lots to decide our future
Mk sister kicked¡°Stedk¡±
So when I should have
gone to senior high,
I woo sent oSto Anotrolie
I stayed
with a relative, a journalist
When he went to work,
he brought me along
Aeh ho took me ooeho
hiving in hie tree time
Six months later...
I went to India
The start of a counter-clockwise
roeeh4he-worlh tab
I hake roatoeroet jab there...
and met my first boyfriend
But...
Time ran out
I had to move again
Next it was the Meihivee
By then I was really hetieg Be
Why should she decide howl lived...
and where I weety
I had a good friend in junior high
She won fronnfnrrnh in for fhrnn monfhn
And then sent on to another nohool
I romombor vory olnorly...
how she sobbed that day
She told me thot
olwoyo ohoedied oohool liho thot...
meant that she never had a real friend
Daddy vamfaDad ma
¡°Hesaid...¡±
¡°Everyone'slife isdifferent¡±
She'dbeen to far more places that I had
But I had decor trioeho
thee abed acer deco
When I left for Madagascar...
all I could think of was her face...
and what Daddy had said
Hey, did yea daaw that
in the forests of Madagascar
there'sa Devil Tree?
Yee'vedews
to mere dIscos thee we hove!
How many languages do you speak?
Now Ill toll tka otory again
My dad died
as I was about
to enter aeaiar didd aodaal
He left us some money
Anyhow,
Ma made out two slips of paper
One said:¡°Study¡±
The other said:¡°Travelround theworld¡±
I dot the¡°Trovol¡±one
Since we were liSle,
my sisters always
had befter grades thee me
Ma was delighted
that she did so well
So she did all she could
to seppoS her edsootios
Ash my oiotory
She studied day and night...
Put on weight...
Got pimples all over her face...
Didnt get a second glance tram days
when she went out
The better her grades became...
the more she lacked self-confidence
She got into a corfl good school
But shewasn'tat all happy
Sometimes shah osma hams...
and find postcards
from my travels in fda maildaa
While studying alone late at night...
shed tied hereelt remembering...
the days when she could
jest go ereeeh with her peppy
She'dteIP te the peppy...
¡°Look,that'sacloud¡±
¡°Look,that'sadattoL'
¡°Look...¡±
¡°thoseare trafficlights¡±
So she hated our Ma
Whycouldn'tshe let her trecely
She hated me too
Whyhadn'tI picked the¡°Stehy¡±paper?
It'sthrough all these things here that
she ease the wsrlh
She'ssever bees shresh
The reason she
runs this exchange system...
is so that she can hear mere eteries
she'smisesh estee hereelt
That puppy strap is French
And it looks
just liPs the peg she sacs had
The moment you stepped in here...
she knew that your peppy strep
hod mony stories
for her
I'mspeechless
Here,it'syours
Thank you
I thinkI'mgoing to cry
Sis...
Is it a good idea to write love lettero?
Whyshouldn'tit be?
You twocan'tdecide...
Soit'sdown to me
Madrid
Reykjavik in Iceland
Iceland...
That'scrazy...
How can he get to so many places?
I got it!
Didn'tyou say hecouldn'twrite?
Booonoo his boronto
didn'tsand him to school?
Let'ssay they
used his tuition fees te teed his travels
It sely...
If my tuition fees had been spent
on air tickets...
then I could have travelled
eveYvohere too
Yeah, you wioh
Burkina Faso...
You have no business sense!
It you want to exchange things, you can
Nice gimmich
But put a price on it!
I'mabout to give you a riuou
Tell me...
How much time each day do you spend
explaining to customers?
Well...
We cant give you a hot rinse
without a word otworning
No, no, I woo toihing to my daughter
The one of the right
What?
How much time do you waste
on bargaining ovary bay?
Your sister says
youdon'thelp in the ooto
yp0y0 nonsense, yen soP her
Do more people come in for a coffee
and then pence
to 000heede eemethied...
Or do they come to exchange things
and ponee toreooooo'?
Jnot hate hriOO on it
I'mnot saying
you should actually charge a too
Itwouldn'tbass aaohanga it you hid
And youh lose the gimmick
But if you put a price on it...
you can calculate
when people bring things to nnchengn
Ahh a bit, nnbtract a bit...
to even things out
Wouldn'tthat be more ooot-offootivo?
Then tell me...
What'sthe price
for helping to write lace lettereT
Anyhow,it'sa waste of time
¡°Theowner of these
waste te swab them,
pIus 35 stories
from differentplaces...¡±
for 35 loveletters¡±
Does that grab you?
Too bad, yea cent exchange with him
He wants a girl to write them
I thinkhe'sreally after a girlfriend
-you know kimy
-ftf oenree
Tell you what, hoe never been to school!
And his poroeto ore oeporeioo
Thedrain'sblocked again
Oh, there you are
Whatever else you negotiate,
get the drain fixed within twa hays
No-one wants to swap with you yet
What ore yen having tohoy?
Same as last time
Sis, same as last time
What did he order last time?
Espresso
I'lltell you a otory from Phoenix
Once upon a time...
there was a small town in Arizona
Ann ynar, tharna a navarn hraaght
The local people,
one by one, move out
One boy in pooioulor is very sad to go
So he buries oomethieg
under a cactus
Was it this bar of soap?
Too long ago!
Anyhow, he keeps on walking
for about two wooho
Now, theres the boss of a restaurant...
lying on his bob, shout to his
He looks up and sees the boy
All of a sudden, tears steA
from fdskey'seyes
And all along the toor4rooho on his face...
theme oteA to bOb oat
He becomes a cactus!
Out come long thorns...
Long thorns from his eyeballs...
He cries ash cries esh cries...
and more and more thorns
keep coming oat
Soon tram a dintonon...
he looks just like cactus...
beside the bed, covered witd tderee
Yes, and posing!
Right, posing
Miss, excuse me...
My friend would like to have this book
He knows it has to be exchanged
But he hihet brieg eehthieg tehek
And he goes back to Japan tomorrow
So he woehoro it he con beJ itJ
Sorry, no
He'llhave to come back next time
Excuse me, Miss...
His mother
is an elementary echeel teecher
She'sretiring this year
She used to teach these eeege
te her bebile
I'msorry, but wecan'tallow it
It I bend the rule for him...
it'dbe unfair to other customers
Sorry
In point of fact...
I took the rocking horse in ooohongo
fore gaiter in the Prof piece
I know that your guitar
isn'tjust any olk guitar
You ourusohuk your wits with it
But that only makes it special for you
For ma, ito jeot another gaiter
But my boy loves that horse
I know he does
Last time he was here, he sat on it
But I heat west esether gaiter is
exchange for the rocking horse
I want oemothing aloe
I'mreally sorry
Can he sing in exchange for if?
Idon'tthinkthat'son...
That book is decades old
He thinks singing for a couple of
minutes iso fair osokongo?
How about two songs?
I'dlike to hear that
Me too
If he sings...
I can play too
How about that?
Thereve been some interior decorators
worbieb roeeb bore lotoly
Ityoe hold them hoist the well...
you can get the rocking horse
Okay,I'llpaint tho wolh
Let'slisten to the songs
¡°Thehilleihe
where we chasedrabbits...¡±
¡°Theriverbank
where wefished...¡±
¡°They'realways in mydreams¡±
The unforgettable place where I was born
Whets the purpose at eacheegieg thiege?
It you were to ask Jooio...
she might not have an onowor
Butthat'snot to imply that
ohs'sin any way illogiool
Just that her logic works something
like this oerteee
Ash whet sheet DerieJ
She used to think exchanges were
unprofitable end sweets of time
But the concept of¡®innervalue'
has lodged in her mind
So things have changed
¡°Ityou could ohoooo,
would you use the money to study
or to trovol round theworldy¡±
I'dtravel round the world
Because compared with whet oodool
tooodoo me odoet the world...
I'dlearn
more
by traveling
I'dchoose to study
Because whenyou'reyoeeg...
it'seasy to remember things,
so studying is defter
Travel raced the wend!
Explore on your own...
Find truth...
Study! Plenty of time to travel
when you get older
Travel broadens the mind
I'dtravel roach the world
I'dstudy
I thinkI'dgo on studying
Study other languages first...
Then you can hece ten anywhere yen ge
Bettor to do well at school first
and get rich
Thee we oee go whore we lihe
For myoolt, I like to play
I'dlike to play all round tdo world
Do you know your own goals in life?
Wifhonf goals,
fkoro'ono koinf in koing gook knoinooo
No point in doing business?
What goals?
My goal is to dring up my bib
Buy her a house!
I'mtalking to my daughters,
thooo two neat to ma
I'msorry
At the time I divorced your father...
my life was completely aimless
Your aunt told me...
I needed goals
Now, your lives are oeftlieg down
So I want to ask you,
do you have goals?
Yea, I want to soya mousy
And you?
I want to travel
Be realistic
Youcan'teven take care of yeereelk
How are you going to travel?
Take advantage at year tree time!
Learn how to make hooooGo
from your sister
Get your hook octet the oloeho!
Strange how saving money is a goal...
while traveling rannh the warlh
ia jeat hayhraaming
That'show it is
Thedrain'sunblocked
Impressive!
Youdidn'teven dirty your shoes!
Low tot, low salt, bettor
for an oldperson'sbiot
Howon'toat itL
We can buy itfor him
You'realways making pictures
What do you paint?
I'mnot talented, jnot doodlind
You have no idea how small it is
Not much more
thee bbb oqeoro metere
But you know
how many people live there?
Probably twenty to thirty thoeooeh!
Sorry, one moment...
Josie Chuo!
What?
You'remaking a flood
Point it at the tioworpoto!
I'lldrown you all
-Can you do it?
-Yes, I can
Let me try one
My turn!
Hang on, how will we get home?
That one might hit someone
Hang on, what are we eating?
Did you hear me?
Okay,I'llswap with you
Thank you
By the way,wkot'IIyou use if for?
Don'tknow yet
Butdon'tyou think...
it'srather ohilkiohy
Pardon me,isn'tthat childish?
When we get
hold of a phoenix feather...
we can have eternal yeefh
Say¡°cheese¡±
One, two, three... Congratulations!
Theres something I want to ask you
Do you know thot your some
is also the name of a color?
You mean alfromoriao?
I had two favorite colors in senior high
One woo alt romorino,
the other woo cobalt blee
One, two, three... The Flying Fist!
No, you...
Can you at least take a look?
Wow, so oool!
Forget it! Listen...
That picture is worth less thee this
Then goat exchange with me
lye just an old, yellowing biotere
Thenlet'scall off the exchange!
It Ihadn'tlived here haters,
Iweelhe'twent te exchange either
Butwe'rein here now
No exchange
Another coffee please, boss
Me too
Airight, if you want it so badly...
I'llmake the exchange
Really?
-Are you sure?
-Positive
We'relooking for Doris.
Yes, I am.
You'reJonah?
And you are Ala...
Alamela
Alamela Hello,
Nice to meet you.
This is really nice.
Thank you.
Take your seat, please.
Thank you very much.
Do you want some drinks, coffee or...?
Water will be fins.
Hello, this is my business card
A travel agency?
Right, we heard about your veto
Our manager wanted us to come
and take a load at it
Sowa'cadaaa aiftiag tar a wdila
Is there enpthing special?
Was if the Borough Chief
who telh?¡ãsheet us?
No, the airline people
Travel agencies
design packagee tar teeriete...
just like restaurants have set menus
Our company wants
to design a special poodagn tar Taipni
Soyou'rethinking of making our cafe
poS of your Taipei...
Yea, were here to evaluate it
But I just had a sod ereeeh
Everything here is up for exchange
What could tourists buy
it they come hero?
What could they buy?
All we sell is coffee
Will there be eeythieg else?
No,we'refine
Thanks, sorry to trouble you
Thank you, goodbye
Your change
Thanks
How is the business doing?
Quite okay
Why were you so fierce
with thooo bookie tohoy?
They wanted to use you to make oommiooioeo
CommiooioeoT
As if you worked for them for free
They bring in guests...
and they take a higher percentage
cut thee yea he
yihe the eeeeh etthety
What'sthe connection?
There is one
It you put in the ugly black ones...
it will spoil the look at it
The ones you should pick are...
the round ones with no homodo
The bright red ones
NowI'mgoing
to tell you a story sot in Toihoi
Won'tthat be boring?
Wait and see
Imagine a picture...
The whole of the city...
is empty,no-one'sthere
One day...
There'sa painter
who wakes up in a hotel ream
high up en the Pbth Peer
He stands at the huge picture-window
He realises
thatthere'ses-see hews there
Ifyou'regod...
just create any two people
Then the stow can begin
He thinks of something
He takes some paper and draws a girl
He carefully cute Par cut...
and lets her fly away
The girl wanders elena threegh the city
She drinks coffee alone
She surveys the scenery alone
The painter thinksshe'stoo lonely
So he hrewe a men tee
Lets him fly away too
But the paper man...
flies off in a different direction
He lands eemewdere else
So he also drinks coffee alone
And reads o 5OWOdOdO oloeo
That'sthe last of the stories
AndI'veoheedeh mfi mish
Idon'twant to exchange
these bb bars ot need
After all, they rebrennet my memerine
Ah..
You can take back your soaps...
but youcan'ttake my illuatratiana
Otcaurea loan
I'vetold you 35 stories
I get the pictures
in exchange
Heshouldn'thave
taken your illeetretiene
Right?
What do you mean?
I can seeyou'reupset...
because he took your illeotrotioeo
Right?
I'mupset?
Why should I be upset?
I let him tell all those stories
I sold him
all those coffees and hooooffo
Iooelhe'tdo doddior
But you made so many illuotrotiono
Don'tdo oilly
Before you sell a coffee,
you have to buy coffee hoses
Before you sell o hooooff,
you hove to hey beer
Anybody can tell stories
How can you tell itthey'retrue or eoty
But youdon'tcare either way
it'strue erect
You'reright, Idon't
Come on...
I drew the¡°Study¡±lot
Studied so long I grow pimply!
While my sister
traveled round the world
Where'syear peg?
Hanging from my mobile
No, I mean the real one
What are you getting at?
The one Dad gave you
Are you crazy?
He died
No hedidn't
Dad took him
What are you saying? He died!
No hedidn't
One day you came home
and he was gone
You jeot ooih ho woo hood
when your olooomotoo oohoh
You really get on my nerves
Daddidn'ttedn dim
Daddidn'teven take us,
let alone the dad!
It wee De whe seat dim evie
Let'sbe frank, he
shouldn'thave taken the illeetretiene
Or the
He'ssuch a jerk
What did he mean by his memories?
But they were his memories
Not mine
I'mtalking about the illustrations,
which ware yanra
Hacan'tacan brew!
But it hehadn'ttold me the stories...
Icouldn'tdeco drown them
Ididn'thave those images in my head
And new...
I cant go on and draw the next city story
Now do don my illantrotiono...
and I have his stories
I thoughtthey'dverne
ash teds the messy
So I put my foot on if and stood firm
Why diduf you just pioh if up?
ItI'dmoved,
they might have snatched it!
Welcome!
Hello.., table for four?
Hello, this is my business card
-Hello
Nice to meet you, oorry
we were eating when you come in
My two colleagues
here came by before
I remember
I'dlike to reopen the discussion
of the¡®package'ides
Because your Cafe is very special
Cur clients ask skeet it
Tkey west te knew its cisit
can be included in the package
But we dont nell the thiegn here
So youwouldn'tget any commission
Sorry...
Can we sit down and talk?
Cf course we can,d¡ãscar tdara
-Thank you
What will you have to drink?
Coffee
Coffee for everyone?
Iced or hot?
Our manager has an idea
about franchising
branch iaiag?
Let me explain
If a foreign friend visits you...
you'llguide them
around the place,
for sure
You'llmoot liholy
bring them to your home too
So if...
So it this place
happened to be your home...
What could ho heifer, right?
By¡®franchising'they mean a takeover
Theydon'twest oemmieeiee,
they west the heeieeee!
No,that'snot it
We'rejust here
to float an idea
Whatwe'dlike is...
for you to tell us what you think of it
In toot, our oompouy is looking
for investments
If you were thinking...
of raising more capital by any chance...
Anb itwa Pabst cams bars tabay...
Wouldn'tthat have been a shame?
We eel? nell veffee here
Didnt you two go back and tell them?
We sell coffee, not the bueie000
Or you can bring something
to exchange
In thin hnninnnn...
my sisters share is larger than mine
But you cas have my share...
if you bring me air tickets in exchange
I want flights to th000 bh oitiaa
May I take a look?
How could you do that?
Isn'tit your baby?
It'syours too
You were right to say that
by running an enoheegn...
web hear lets at atarina sheet things
we havant anharianosh
But the more of them I heard...
the more I wanted
etoriee at my ewe to 000heede
You, now...
Youohoulh'volet me teach you more
about mohiub hoooorto
That'sthe thing that
worries me most right sew
Oh...
The Borough ChioTo eon can help
He says the reason the groin
hoopo goHieg bloohoh...
is because
the neighbors ground is higher
He'llmade sure higher
He says we should open on Sundays
And he says we weeldet seed
te dire a sew pastry odef...
if he came in to help me
It would save money too
You'rethat close to him?
It'sfreezing
Let'sgo down and tell Ma
Okay
Have you booked hotels?
My sisters a member ot Hots Heooto
No need for hotels! Cool, eh?
A bit faster
Is he doing okay?
Much better than you
You know what?
We'llget Sofa Guests wanting
to obonh the night hero oomotimoo
Sowe'llneed it
left clean and tidy, okay?
No. 393,
registered mail ter None ftdeo
Give me the stamp from the drawer
Top drawer!
What'sa Sofa Guest?
Youdon'tknow Sofa Snooto?
What is it?
What the hell?
Now heheeee'twest them?
Let me see
¡°Iused to be an auxiliarypilot¡±
¡°Iexchanged many stories
for loveleftere¡±
¡°AsI said, they were all sheet mypest¡±
¡°Iused to be an oexilioftipilot¡±
¡°Lastmoetb I loft tbooirlieo¡±
¡°Infuture I like to make coffee withyou¡±
Make coffee with you?
Will you help me by drawing
the story of the 36th city?
Ah, your favorite color!
You'reso onnoyiug
Last time he was such a jerk
What'sha palliag aawL
What?
Your heart is blooming with joy
Bloom, bloom, bloom
You'reso annoying
You thinkI'mannoying?
Don'tteam up with him
-He'sjobless now
-Give it back
He'sjobless new
So you also like him?
I always thought you gig
Give me 1000 bucks
andI'llgive it back
Hey!
It youdon'thand it over,I'lltear it
I earn no damn little darn
Just give me spare change then
Come on...
Skinflint!
Hey, no slacking there!
¡°Atheart,
What do you treasuremost?¡±
My parents...
My brother...
Friends
To me,it'sa happy family...
Parents, brothers and sisters
PiVi5b my harsats abash lits
Making my parents happy
Growing old with my Pnahanh
Watching my kid grow up
To make my son proud at ma
And to get his respect
I think what I treenere meet
is safety and tresqaildy
Se tdet I can see
temerrew'ssesriss sad sanest
Health
Being happy every day
Having no regrets
Showing people a heorHelt smile
Being at ease, tranquil
Getting spaced out
Wild romance
I think what I treasure most ia..
innocence
Because kids do all kinds of things
quite naturally
But when they grow up
and the world eterte judging them...
Or when onoein adele
dot eteod anthem...
Then what used to be innocent
becomes eemetbieb mere oemhlen
Josie finally gets the car she wanted
Shea embarrassed te tell her sister...
that she never found her
a set of bone china
Doris tails her,
that'sjust the way it is
Youcan'talways get what yea west
In this city...
there'ssurely someone
looking for bone chine
And surelythere'ssomeone
with a spare set
Surely esmeese hoses empty sets
And surely someone else
is looking for it
They jest devout touch osod other
It'sthe city
These stories happen
in the city every day
You mean the paint-job?
I'venever heard of¡®junglecolor
-you do paint-jobs, Right?
-Yea, wade
So can you help her with that?
I boat know about you two
Is it really such a shitty job?
It'snot that great
But Ican'tcomplain
In a recension, no Job in mach tan
Ah, no, I was talking to my daughters
Those two is tho kook soot
One of them used to say
she wanted to save mosey
Osh the ether woetoh
tod¡ãroesh the world
But now...
One of them wants
to go ronnh tho worlh
And the other wants to save money
Idon'tdot it
What changed?
Our¡®SofaGuest'Doris is leaving now!
Okay, the cars waiting, hurry!
Looks great!
Anything you need to say?
Hurry up!
Take care of yourselves
And take care of the Cafe