1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\an5}m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8

2
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\an5}m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8

3
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\an5}{\pos(145,227)}m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8

4
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(67,223)}m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0

5
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(67,223)}m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35

6
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(58,213)}m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60

7
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(84,223)}m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172

8
00:00:00,500 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(99,242)}原創翻譯  雙語字幕

9
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:05,000
{\pos(235.108,242)}最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利

10
00:00:06,220 --> 00:00:36,220
{\an9}m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1

11
00:00:05,720 --> 00:00:36,220
{\an2}{\pos(26,248)}m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1

12
00:00:06,730 --> 00:00:11,730
{\an4}{\pos(35,235)}翻譯     白DORA

13
00:00:11,730 --> 00:00:16,730
{\an4}{\pos(35,235)}翻譯     白DORA

14
00:00:16,730 --> 00:00:21,730
{\an4}{\pos(35,235)}校對     毛絨絨

15
00:00:21,730 --> 00:00:26,730
{\an4}{\pos(27,235)}時間軸     姜姜

16
00:00:26,730 --> 00:00:31,730
{\an4}{\pos(35,235)}后期     魚骨頭

17
00:00:31,730 --> 00:00:36,730
{\an4}{\pos(35,235)}總監     haoyang112

18
00:19:00,660 --> 00:19:30,660
{\pos(327.159,28.927)}m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0

19
00:19:00,660 --> 00:19:30,660
{\pos(327.159,28.927)}m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35

20
00:19:00,660 --> 00:19:30,660
{\pos(321,24)}m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60

21
00:19:00,660 --> 00:19:30,660
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172

22
00:19:00,660 --> 00:19:30,660
最新海外影視劇下載

23
00:00:04,730 --> 00:00:08,990
在英國每年發生約600宗兇殺案
There are about 600 murders in the UK each year.

24
00:00:09,250 --> 00:00:11,570
基本上是一天兩起
That's around two a day.

25
00:00:13,980 --> 00:00:17,620
全球范圍內每小時有五十人被殺
And, globally, about 50 people are murdered every hour.

26
00:00:21,390 --> 00:00:23,800
兇殺讓我們又害怕又厭惡
Murder appals and repels us.

27
00:00:23,810 --> 00:00:25,780
但也讓人好奇
But it also fascinates.

28
00:00:26,390 --> 00:00:28,760
那么到底人們為何會殺人
So, what makes people murder?

29
00:00:28,800 --> 00:00:30,210
我感覺自己是上帝
I felt like God.

30
00:00:30,210 --> 00:00:33,200
那種凌駕于凡人之上的神的力量
The power of God over a human being.

31
00:00:33,270 --> 00:00:37,000
我走進廚房把一碗冰淇淋放下
I went into the kitchen and put my bowl of ice cream down.

32
00:00:37,000 --> 00:00:39,600
從料理臺上拿了把刀
I grabbed a knife from the counter,

33
00:00:39,980 --> 00:00:42,120
捅了勞瑞和我媽
and I stabbed Larry and my mom.

34
00:00:43,300 --> 00:00:45,540
有些人天生就是殺人犯嗎
Are some people born to kill?

35
00:00:45,610 --> 00:00:48,490
還是受到了環境的驅使
Or are they driven to it by circumstance?

36
00:00:49,590 --> 00:00:52,170
五十年來  《地平線》欄目組和BBC
For 50 years, Horizon and the BBC

37
00:00:52,170 --> 00:00:54,250
不斷跟進科學家們的研究
have been following the work of scientists,

38
00:00:54,250 --> 00:00:57,540
這些科學家試圖一窺殺人犯的內心世界
as they struggle to delve into the minds of murderers,

39
00:00:57,540 --> 00:01:00,570
想要弄明白為何有人會殺人
to try to understand why people kill.

40
00:01:02,440 --> 00:01:04,610
我們希望通過了解
The hope is that by understanding

41
00:01:04,610 --> 00:01:06,820
人們的殺人動機
what makes people into murderers,

42
00:01:07,030 --> 00:01:10,000
可以有一天阻止謀殺
we might, one day, be able to prevent it.

43
00:01:17,380 --> 00:01:26,380
{\pos(224,175)}謀殺之謎

44
00:01:19,780 --> 00:01:26,380
{\pos(289,175)}地平線指南

45
00:01:29,260 --> 00:01:32,760
1997年12月21日
On the 21st December, 1997,

46
00:01:33,640 --> 00:01:37,590
俄亥俄州安靜郊區的某處發生了一起駭人的謀殺案
a chilling murder took place in a quiet suburb in Ohio.

47
00:01:40,520 --> 00:01:43,400
迪翁·桑德斯闖進了他祖父母家
Dion Sanders had broken into his grandparents house,

48
00:01:43,400 --> 00:01:44,830
想要偷錢
looking for money.

49
00:01:45,860 --> 00:01:49,110
但他們提早回家當場把他抓住
But they came home early and caught him in the act.

50
00:01:49,110 --> 00:01:51,610
結果雙方發生了激烈的爭吵
It ended up in a big argument.

51
00:01:51,310 --> 00:01:56,030
{\an8}《殺人犯心理：殺人者》（2001年）

52
00:01:51,610 --> 00:01:53,050
爭執非常嚴重
A bad argument.

53
00:01:54,260 --> 00:01:57,070
接下來我只知道自己在毆打他們
Next thing I know, I'm beating on them.

54
00:01:57,390 --> 00:01:59,140
我是說  我在  我在
I mean, I'm...I'm...

55
00:01:59,140 --> 00:02:01,510
我記得我當時極度憤怒
I remember I was in such a rage...

56
00:02:02,850 --> 00:02:04,370
他們沒辦法阻止我
..That they couldn't stop me.

57
00:02:05,330 --> 00:02:07,220
手上多了一個平底鍋
A frying pan came into it.

58
00:02:09,540 --> 00:02:12,320
至今為止我仍不知道到底是自己拿的鍋
To this day, I have no idea whether I grabbed it,

59
00:02:12,320 --> 00:02:15,260
還是他們拿來阻止我的
or if they grabbed it to try to stop me.

60
00:02:20,200 --> 00:02:23,520
迪翁的祖父母在面對升級的瘋狂襲擊時
Dion's grandparents had to defend themselves

61
00:02:23,520 --> 00:02:26,360
不得不進行自衛
against an increasingly frenzied attack.

62
00:02:27,920 --> 00:02:30,270
我知道祖父家里有把獵槍
I knew grandpa had a shotgun in the house.

63
00:02:30,870 --> 00:02:32,600
我記得我朝門那邊望去
I remember looking through the door,

64
00:02:35,130 --> 00:02:38,050
看見祖母從地上撿起槍
and seeing grandma picked the gun up off the floor.

65
00:02:38,810 --> 00:02:41,070
結果我把槍從她那奪了過來
I ended up getting the gun away from her.

66
00:02:47,810 --> 00:02:49,640
我記得自己最后轉到了她后面
I remember ending up behind her.

67
00:02:51,910 --> 00:02:53,400
我記得給槍上膛
I remember loading the gun.

68
00:02:56,510 --> 00:02:58,530
然后指向她并開火
And I pointed at her and shot.

69
00:03:04,980 --> 00:03:06,820
我記得她倒在地上
I remember her falling to the ground.

70
00:03:10,510 --> 00:03:12,850
我記得我重新裝彈
I remember reloading it.

71
00:03:12,850 --> 00:03:14,360
跑進車庫
I ran into the garage,

72
00:03:14,360 --> 00:03:17,240
朝祖父開了火
I pointed at my grandpa and fired.

73
00:03:19,830 --> 00:03:21,710
我不知道打到了哪里
I don't know where I hit him.

74
00:03:23,530 --> 00:03:25,060
只知道自己射中了
I know I shot him.

75
00:03:38,120 --> 00:03:40,460
對我們大部分人來說
For most of us, the idea of violently killing

76
00:03:40,460 --> 00:03:41,880
殘忍地殺害他人
another human being,

77
00:03:41,880 --> 00:03:44,900
尤其是自己的祖父母是很可怕的事
particularly your grandparents, is so abhorrent,

78
00:03:44,900 --> 00:03:46,940
我們認為能干出這種事的人
we assume that anyone who is capable of it

79
00:03:46,940 --> 00:03:48,890
一定有哪里不正常
must have something wrong with them.

80
00:03:49,200 --> 00:03:50,560
但真的是這樣嗎
But is that right?

81
00:03:50,560 --> 00:03:54,320
殺人犯真的和我們其他人不同嗎
Are murderers really that different to the rest of us?

82
00:03:58,330 --> 00:03:59,650
在十九世紀七十年代
In the 1870s,

83
00:03:59,650 --> 00:04:03,000
人們開始慢慢嘗試用科學
science began to take its first faltering steps

84
00:04:03,000 --> 00:04:04,920
來解釋這一疑問
towards answering this question.

85
00:04:05,940 --> 00:04:10,370
切薩雷·隆布羅索醫生是科學犯罪學之父
Dr Cesare Lombroso, the father of scientific criminology,

86
00:04:10,370 --> 00:04:14,640
他曾研究過都靈和帕維亞監獄內的囚犯
was studying criminals imprisoned in Turin and Pavia.

87
00:04:21,750 --> 00:04:24,350
1871年11月的一個早晨
One November morning in 1871,

88
00:04:22,720 --> 00:04:27,110
{\an8}《繩之以法：犯罪心理分析》（2001年）

89
00:04:24,550 --> 00:04:28,430
隆布羅索研究了臭名昭著的意大利盜賊
Lombroso made what he thought was a great scientific discovery,

90
00:04:28,510 --> 00:04:32,000
比耶拉的頭骨時  自認取得了一個
when he studied the skull of the famous Italian thief

91
00:04:32,000 --> 00:04:33,600
重大的科學發現
known as Villela.

92
00:04:37,880 --> 00:04:39,930
"我在枕骨上
"I found in the occipital part,

93
00:04:39,930 --> 00:04:43,390
即普通頭骨連接脊椎的地方
exactly on the post where the spine is found in a normal skull,

94
00:04:43,530 --> 00:04:46,660
發現了一個特殊印記
a distinct impression, as an inferior animal's.

95
00:04:46,760 --> 00:04:48,480
與低等動物  特別是嚙齒類相同
In particular, rodents.

96
00:04:48,910 --> 00:04:53,230
就如星空照亮原野一般  我突然看見了
I suddenly saw, lit up as a vast plain under the flaming sky,

97
00:04:53,440 --> 00:04:55,300
罪犯的本質
the nature of the criminal.

98
00:04:55,350 --> 00:04:58,700
即一個返祖的人重演
An atavistic being who reproduces the ferocious

99
00:04:58,710 --> 00:05:03,110
人類的殘暴本能和低等動物的行為"
instincts of humanity and of the inferior animal."

100
00:05:08,220 --> 00:05:10,490
隆布羅索確信自己發現了
Lombroso believed he had found evidence

101
00:05:10,500 --> 00:05:14,090
犯罪者與非犯罪者大腦不同的證據
that a criminal's brain is different to that of a noncriminal.

102
00:05:14,420 --> 00:05:16,640
進化上的一種倒退
A step back in evolution.

103
00:05:17,270 --> 00:05:19,280
他宣稱這一特點清楚地表現在
He claims that this was clearly displayed

104
00:05:19,280 --> 00:05:21,650
罪犯的臉型上
in the shape of a criminal's face.

105
00:05:23,850 --> 00:05:26,620
"罪犯的耳朵一般較大
"A criminal's ears are often of a large size,

106
00:05:26,790 --> 00:05:28,540
鼻孔經常外翻
and the nose is frequently upturned,

107
00:05:28,540 --> 00:05:31,540
小偷通常有扁鼻子
or of a flattened character in thieves.

108
00:05:32,100 --> 00:05:34,190
而殺人犯則是鷹鉤鼻
In murderers, it is often aquiline,

109
00:05:34,190 --> 00:05:36,260
狀似肉食鳥類的喙"
like the beak of a bird of prey."

110
00:05:40,910 --> 00:05:43,920
隆布羅索的研究很快就被推翻了
Lombroso's approach was soon discredited,

111
00:05:43,920 --> 00:05:47,080
但它卻是一個偉大想法的雛形
but it was the beginning of a big idea.

112
00:05:47,100 --> 00:05:49,590
即犯罪者  特別是殺人犯
That criminals, and in particular murderers,

113
00:05:49,590 --> 00:05:52,350
與我們其他人的大腦不同
have different brains to the rest of us.

114
00:05:52,700 --> 00:05:55,040
他于十九世紀開展的研究
The studies he conducted back in the 1800s,

115
00:05:55,040 --> 00:05:57,120
在今天看來可能很可笑
by today's standards might be laughable,

116
00:05:57,120 --> 00:05:59,270
但同時這也是一切的開始
but, at the same time, it was a beginning.

117
00:05:59,530 --> 00:06:01,890
隆布羅索打開了一扇大門
And what Lombroso did was open the door.

118
00:05:59,580 --> 00:06:03,950
{\an8}羅伯特·雷斯勒
聯調局行為科學小組  1974-1990年供職

119
00:06:01,900 --> 00:06:04,940
他為后人的研究奠定了基礎
He built a foundation for others to build on.

120
00:06:08,530 --> 00:06:10,710
但這之后近一百年
But it was almost 100 years

121
00:06:10,710 --> 00:06:13,320
科學才研究出
before science was able to provide the tools

122
00:06:13,320 --> 00:06:17,280
可以探索殺人犯大腦的技術
to really start exploring the mind of a murderer.

123
00:06:26,670 --> 00:06:28,320
重要的第一步是
The first crucial step

124
00:06:28,320 --> 00:06:32,270
二十世紀五十  六十年代的動物研究
was research with animals, in the 1950s and '60s.

125
00:06:32,820 --> 00:06:34,350
科學家試圖弄清楚
Scientists wanted to know

126
00:06:34,350 --> 00:06:39,130
大腦中是否有區域負責人的攻擊性
if there were specific parts of the brain responsible for producing aggression.

127
00:06:40,500 --> 00:06:42,380
在一次史無前例的研究中
In one ground-breaking study,

128
00:06:42,380 --> 00:06:44,710
科學家給貓植入了電極
cats were implanted with electrodes,

129
00:06:44,710 --> 00:06:47,300
從而可以用電流刺激
and these were used to electrically stimulate

130
00:06:47,300 --> 00:06:49,660
它們大腦的不同部分
different parts of their brains.

131
00:06:49,580 --> 00:06:53,520
{\an8}《地平線：該隱之子》（1967年）

132
00:06:50,690 --> 00:06:52,890
接受這種手術的動物
The animals, after such an operation,

133
00:06:52,890 --> 00:06:56,500
表現得很自在
are perfectly at ease,

134
00:06:55,510 --> 00:07:00,070
{\an8}西德尼·希爾頓教授  伯明翰大學

135
00:06:56,500 --> 00:06:58,810
它們沒有感到任何不適
and they suffer no discomfort.

136
00:06:58,880 --> 00:07:02,330
我們繼續這樣養了它們很長時間
And we can keep them like this for a long period of time.

137
00:07:02,640 --> 00:07:05,360
但當我們開始刺激實驗時
But, when we stimulate, the first thing we see,

138
00:07:05,360 --> 00:07:08,090
哪怕用的是最小的電流
with the smallest amount of current we can use,

139
00:07:08,090 --> 00:07:10,050
它們行為上的變化也是顯而易見的
is this alerting behaviour.

140
00:07:10,160 --> 00:07:12,980
瞳孔放大  耳朵豎起
The pupils are dilated, the ears are pricked,

141
00:07:12,980 --> 00:07:14,660
頭部微微抬高
and the head might be raised a little.

142
00:07:14,660 --> 00:07:18,690
心臟跳動得更加猛烈  肌肉保持緊張
The heart is working much harder, ready for the muscular exertion

143
00:07:18,690 --> 00:07:21,650
我們接下來觀察加大電流會怎樣
which we soon see if we stimulate a little bit harder.

144
00:07:21,650 --> 00:07:23,570
"結果當電流打開時
"Then, when the current is switched on,

145
00:07:23,570 --> 00:07:26,330
貓就攻擊了它所見的第一個物體
the cat attacks the first object it sees.

146
00:07:26,330 --> 00:07:28,410
如正這只假貓"
In this case, a dummy cat."

147
00:07:33,630 --> 00:07:37,330
這類動物研究給我們提供了可靠證據
Animal experiments like these provided strong evidence

148
00:07:37,330 --> 00:07:38,880
證明大腦的某些部分
that specific parts of the brain

149
00:07:38,880 --> 00:07:41,100
負責暴力行為
are involved in producing violent

150
00:07:41,100 --> 00:07:43,830
及攻擊性情緒反應
and aggressive emotional reactions.

151
00:07:44,780 --> 00:07:47,730
關鍵部位稱為杏仁核
The key area is called the amygdala.

152
00:07:48,610 --> 00:07:49,960
那么杏仁核是否
So, might the amygdala

153
00:07:49,960 --> 00:07:53,080
與人為暴力甚至兇殺相關呢
play a part in human violence and even murder?

154
00:07:59,870 --> 00:08:02,520
1969年在一個名為朱莉的病人
In 1969, the dramatic case

155
00:08:02,520 --> 00:08:04,950
身上發生的一件戲劇性的案件
of a patient known only as Julie

156
00:08:04,960 --> 00:08:08,180
為科學家提供了一個寶貴的機會
gave scientists a rare opportunity to measure activity

157
00:08:08,180 --> 00:08:10,850
讓他們得以研究
directly from the amygdala of someone

158
00:08:10,850 --> 00:08:14,010
一名差點成為兇手的人的杏仁核
who had come close to committing a murder.

159
00:08:15,330 --> 00:08:17,360
朱莉身患癲癇
Julie suffered from epilepsy.

160
00:08:17,360 --> 00:08:20,260
她發作時常常感到恐懼
During her fits, she often experienced fear

161
00:08:20,260 --> 00:08:21,850
和恐慌
and a sense of panic.

162
00:08:22,620 --> 00:08:25,830
各種奇怪的感覺向我襲來
Then all the strange feeling would come over me.

163
00:08:26,850 --> 00:08:31,780
可怕的感覺  無比奇特強烈
Frightening feeling. Strange and stronger than hell.

164
00:08:33,130 --> 00:08:36,730
有一天在電影院朱莉犯了病
One day, while at the cinema, Julie was overcome by a fit

165
00:08:37,220 --> 00:08:40,610
病發中她用刀刺傷了一個年輕女孩
and during that fit, she stabbed a young girl.

166
00:08:41,660 --> 00:08:43,370
幸運的是那女孩沒死
Luckily, the girl survived,

167
00:08:43,370 --> 00:08:48,330
但是否是朱莉的癲癇導致了這次暴力襲擊
but could Julie's epilepsy have been responsible for this violent attack?

168
00:08:51,850 --> 00:08:55,810
弗農·馬克醫生在這之后開始治療朱莉
Dr Vernon Mark treated Julie after the incident.

169
00:08:56,390 --> 00:08:58,520
實驗內容是
What we did was to

170
00:08:56,960 --> 00:09:01,440
{\an8}《大腦機器：暴力心理》（1988年）

171
00:08:58,520 --> 00:09:01,550
在對她實施全身麻痹后
put a special guiding machine on to her skull,

172
00:09:01,550 --> 00:09:03,380
將一個特制引導器放入她顱內
under general anaesthesia.

173
00:09:03,860 --> 00:09:07,940
我往她的顳葉內杏仁核附近
And I inserted a needle inside her temporal lobes,

174
00:09:08,000 --> 00:09:12,550
插入一根針
very close to the amygdala, and once we did this,

175
00:09:12,920 --> 00:09:16,510
然后我們開始記錄電流活動
we then recorded the electrical activity,

176
00:09:16,570 --> 00:09:18,120
試圖確定
trying to determine

177
00:09:18,520 --> 00:09:22,730
當她犯病時哪個區域活躍起來了
what site was firing off when she had her ordinary seizures.

178
00:09:23,480 --> 00:09:26,690
利用最新動物實驗的成果
Using a technique newly developed in animal research,

179
00:09:26,690 --> 00:09:30,130
神經病學家可以接收到
the neurologists received signals transmitted by radio

180
00:09:30,140 --> 00:09:33,150
植入朱莉大腦深處電極發出的無線電信號
from electrodes implanted deep in Julie's brain.

181
00:09:33,810 --> 00:09:37,250
他們觀察她在日常活動
They monitored her brainwaves during normal activity,

182
00:09:39,100 --> 00:09:40,700
和睡眠時的腦電波
while she was resting,

183
00:09:42,000 --> 00:09:44,300
也觀察她癲癇時的腦電波
and also during her seizures.

184
00:09:45,350 --> 00:09:47,740
此外更有爭議的是
And then, more controversially,

185
00:09:47,740 --> 00:09:50,500
弗農·馬克的團隊將信號反轉
Vernon Mark's team reversed the signal.

186
00:09:50,500 --> 00:09:54,330
所以他們不再記錄活動而是刺激她的大腦
And so, instead of recording activity, stimulated her brain.

187
00:09:55,050 --> 00:09:58,030
在刺激了幾秒鐘之后
Some seconds after the stimulation was initiated,

188
00:09:58,200 --> 00:10:01,360
病人變得沒有反應然后開始注目凝視
the patient became unresponsive and she began to stare

189
00:10:01,720 --> 00:10:06,320
之后開始面部扭曲
and then she had facial grimacing,

190
00:10:06,820 --> 00:10:09,960
基本呈現出了憤怒反應的特征
almost characteristic of a primitive rage response.

191
00:10:10,550 --> 00:10:11,440
在這期間
And during this time,

192
00:10:11,440 --> 00:10:16,010
我們發現病人杏仁核產生的電流活動
we noticed that the patient was producing electrical activity

193
00:10:16,010 --> 00:10:19,770
與其在犯癲癇時一樣
that looked like a seizure coming from the amygdala

194
00:10:20,750 --> 00:10:23,000
之后突然
and quite suddenly,

195
00:10:23,710 --> 00:10:26,420
在面部扭曲幾秒后
after some seconds of grimacing,

196
00:10:26,940 --> 00:10:29,330
朱莉突然進行攻擊
Julie launched herself against the wall

197
00:10:29,330 --> 00:10:31,580
她沖向了墻壁
in a sudden attack behaviour,

198
00:10:31,780 --> 00:10:33,880
并用拳頭擊打墻壁
smashing her fists against the wall.

199
00:10:39,480 --> 00:10:42,070
刺激杏仁核后朱莉的反應
Julie's response to stimulation of the amygdala

200
00:10:42,070 --> 00:10:45,130
同貓異常相似
was strikingly similar to that of the cat's.

201
00:10:47,340 --> 00:10:50,160
她的案例證明
Her case proved there could be a direct relationship

202
00:10:50,160 --> 00:10:53,550
暴力行為與杏仁核的活動間有直接聯系
between a violent act and activation of the amygdala,

203
00:10:53,550 --> 00:10:55,770
而杏仁核是大腦的情緒終端
the emotional centre of the brain.

204
00:11:01,170 --> 00:11:05,250
另一個不同尋常的醫學案例
Another unusual clinical case, that of Ted Bledsoe,

205
00:11:05,250 --> 00:11:07,910
特德·布萊索的案例則揭示了大腦的另一部分
was to implicate a totally different part of the brain

206
00:11:07,910 --> 00:11:09,550
與謀殺行為的關系
in murderous behaviour.

207
00:11:10,430 --> 00:11:11,420
很好
Perfect.

208
00:11:11,420 --> 00:11:13,530
特德·布萊索是一名醫生
Ted Bledsoe was a doctor,

209
00:11:13,950 --> 00:11:17,380
他是一名沒有任何暴力記錄的模范市民
a model citizen with no history of violent behaviour.

210
00:11:19,260 --> 00:11:21,980
79 72
79, 72...

211
00:11:22,030 --> 00:11:23,610
{\an8}丹佛外科手術協會  賓夕法尼亞大學醫院

212
00:11:22,130 --> 00:11:24,200
但突然間  他變了
But then, he changed.

213
00:11:24,350 --> 00:11:26,900
在十年中  沒有任何明顯的原因
Gradually, over a ten year period,

214
00:11:28,620 --> 00:11:32,990
他逐漸變得暴虐
he became increasingly violent for no apparent reason.

215
00:11:34,870 --> 00:11:37,240
我打了
I hit the child

216
00:11:34,900 --> 00:11:39,400
{\an8}《殺人犯心理：創傷》（2001年）

217
00:11:37,240 --> 00:11:39,810
密友的孩子
of some dear friends

218
00:11:41,040 --> 00:11:42,210
當時
who, at that time,

219
00:11:42,210 --> 00:11:45,110
那孩子才五歲
was about five years old.

220
00:11:45,110 --> 00:11:49,930
他跟我鬧著玩我就狠狠地揍了他的臉
He was teasing me and I hurled off and hit him in the face.

221
00:11:49,930 --> 00:11:51,880
我還襲擊了我妻子
And I attacked my wife.

222
00:11:51,990 --> 00:11:53,590
把她打倒在地
I knocked her down,

223
00:11:53,860 --> 00:11:58,150
壓在她身上用拳頭打她
got on top of her and beat her with my closed fists.

224
00:11:59,900 --> 00:12:02,310
我想如果當時手上有武器
I know that had I a weapon in my hand,

225
00:12:02,320 --> 00:12:04,070
我有可能殺了她
I probably would have killed her.

226
00:12:10,420 --> 00:12:14,980
特德終于一無所有  并接受了大腦掃描
Finally, after losing everything, Ted was sent for a brain scan.

227
00:12:16,040 --> 00:12:20,050
結果發現他前額皮質上有個巨型腫瘤
This revealed a massive tumour in his prefrontal cortex.

228
00:12:20,800 --> 00:12:22,200
而這里是大腦
This is the part of the brain

229
00:12:22,200 --> 00:12:24,790
讓我們對杏仁核產生的情緒沖動
that allows us to control our reactions

230
00:12:24,790 --> 00:12:28,360
進行遏制的地方
to the emotional impulses produced in the amygdala.

231
00:12:28,360 --> 00:12:30,930
你能看到那里沒有大腦
You can see that there is just no brain there.

232
00:12:31,490 --> 00:12:33,530
本來應該有  但沒有
There's supposed to be, but there isn't.

233
00:12:35,590 --> 00:12:39,700
特德的例子證明  前額皮質的損傷
As Ted's case demonstrates, damage to the prefrontal cortex

234
00:12:39,700 --> 00:12:43,500
導致人們較難掌控自己的情緒
makes people less able to control their emotional reactions.

235
00:12:43,590 --> 00:12:46,620
沒有人能拍著胸脯保證
There's no way that somebody can say with a straight face

236
00:12:46,510 --> 00:12:51,500
{\an8}喬納森·平卡斯  神經學家  喬治城大學

237
00:12:46,620 --> 00:12:47,940
一個人
that this fella,

238
00:12:47,940 --> 00:12:49,850
缺失了額葉
the absence of his frontal lobes has not had

239
00:12:49,850 --> 00:12:51,350
其行為舉止不會受到影響
any behavioural effect on him.

240
00:12:51,350 --> 00:12:54,350
這種說法是  是站不住腳的
That would be... That's untenable.

241
00:12:55,550 --> 00:12:57,890
由于他的沖動控制機能受阻
By disrupting his impulse control,

242
00:12:57,890 --> 00:13:00,930
腫瘤差點把特德變成了殺人犯
the tumour almost made Ted a murderer.

243
00:13:01,900 --> 00:13:03,600
特德和朱莉這樣的案例
Cases like Ted and Julie's

244
00:13:03,600 --> 00:13:06,820
顯然揭示了前額皮質
certainly suggest that the prefrontal cortex

245
00:13:06,820 --> 00:13:08,660
與大腦情緒中樞
and the emotional centres of the brain

246
00:13:08,660 --> 00:13:10,930
都與謀殺行為相關
are both involved in murder.

247
00:13:11,370 --> 00:13:15,780
然而在審謀殺案時沒人考慮腦腫瘤和癲癇
Yet, brain tumours and epilepsy rarely feature in murder trials.

248
00:13:16,110 --> 00:13:18,800
那還有其它證據表明
So, is there other evidence that murders

249
00:13:18,800 --> 00:13:21,320
大腦這兩個區域與謀殺相關嗎
involve these two brain areas?

250
00:13:23,760 --> 00:13:27,330
二十世紀八十年代發明的大腦功能性掃描
The invention of functional brain scanning in the 1980s

251
00:13:27,330 --> 00:13:30,480
終于可以讓心理學家精確檢測
finally allowed psychologists to precisely measure

252
00:13:30,480 --> 00:13:34,240
任一殺人犯的腦內活動了
the activity going on inside the brain of any murderer.

253
00:13:34,850 --> 00:13:37,280
首個掃描殺人犯大腦的研究
The first brain scanning study of murderers

254
00:13:37,280 --> 00:13:40,800
是英國神經科學家
was carried out in California by British neuroscientist

255
00:13:40,800 --> 00:13:42,770
艾德里安·雷恩醫生在加州進行的
Dr Adrian Raine.

256
00:13:44,110 --> 00:13:48,480
{\an8}《殺人者心理：創傷》（2001年）

257
00:13:45,390 --> 00:13:49,380
加州的一大吸引力是
One of the attractions in coming to California is that

258
00:13:50,140 --> 00:13:54,950
{\an8}艾德里安·雷恩  精神科學家

259
00:13:49,380 --> 00:13:51,970
你可以在這里找到大量的
one can obtain large samples of

260
00:13:51,970 --> 00:13:54,790
殘暴且有殺人傾向的人做研究對象
very violent and homicidal individuals.

261
00:13:58,310 --> 00:14:00,860
唐塔·佩奇便是這樣一個殺人犯
Donta Page was one such murderer.

262
00:14:01,550 --> 00:14:05,840
年僅21歲時  他殘暴地強奸并殺害了
Aged just 21, he brutally raped and murdered 24-year-old

263
00:14:05,840 --> 00:14:07,130
24歲的佩頓·塔特希爾
Peyton Tuthill

264
00:14:07,170 --> 00:14:10,610
她回家時撞見他在偷盜
when she came home to find him committing a burglary.

265
00:14:12,100 --> 00:14:14,170
"我當時在后面  后門
"I was in the back, by the back door,

266
00:14:14,170 --> 00:14:15,820
聽見了前門的動靜"
when I heard the front door."

267
00:14:17,660 --> 00:14:18,940
當時
At that time,

268
00:14:17,690 --> 00:14:22,200
{\an8}帕特·塔特希爾  佩頓的母親

269
00:14:19,390 --> 00:14:22,720
她撞見了兇手
she encountered the murderer,

270
00:14:23,330 --> 00:14:27,380
他們發生了激烈的搏斗
and there was quite a physical battle that ensued after that

271
00:14:27,380 --> 00:14:30,300
之后她試圖自保并掙脫了出來
with her trying to protect herself and she got away.

272
00:14:30,740 --> 00:14:31,970
"我追向她"
"I chased her."

273
00:14:34,780 --> 00:14:37,150
但他沒有就此停手
But he didn't stop.

274
00:14:40,850 --> 00:14:44,060
他趕上去用刀不停地扎她
He proceeded to stab her many, many times.

275
00:14:48,690 --> 00:14:51,840
唐塔·佩奇為何如此殘暴
What made Donta Page such a violent killer?

276
00:14:55,120 --> 00:14:58,630
為尋找答案雷恩醫生掃描了他的大腦
Looking for answers, Dr Raine scanned his brain.

277
00:15:00,390 --> 00:15:04,130
這是一個正常非暴力的人的大腦
This is the scan of a normal, non-violent person's brain.

278
00:15:04,910 --> 00:15:06,800
暖色  紅和黃
The warm colours, reds and yellows,

279
00:15:06,800 --> 00:15:09,310
代表正常大腦活動
indicate normal brain function.

280
00:15:10,310 --> 00:15:11,970
而唐塔·佩奇的掃描圖顯示
Donta Page's scan shows

281
00:15:11,970 --> 00:15:14,710
他的大腦活動異常
that his brain is not functioning properly.

282
00:15:14,820 --> 00:15:16,520
顏色冷上許多
The colours are much cooler.

283
00:15:17,240 --> 00:15:20,050
通過底下這個掃描圖我們可以看出
What we can see in this lower scan

284
00:15:20,050 --> 00:15:23,090
唐塔·佩奇的前額皮質
is that Donta Page's prefrontal cortex

285
00:15:23,090 --> 00:15:26,940
比起非暴力的正常人來說
is functioning much more poorly than that of normal people

286
00:15:26,940 --> 00:15:28,480
工作能力要弱許多
who are non-violent.

287
00:15:30,670 --> 00:15:34,430
雷恩醫生及其團隊掃描了41名兇手
Dr Raine and his team scanned 41 murderers

288
00:15:34,430 --> 00:15:36,710
所有的掃描結果都顯示
and all of them showed reduced functioning

289
00:15:36,710 --> 00:15:38,850
他們的前額皮層功能較弱
of the prefrontal cortex,

290
00:15:38,860 --> 00:15:43,420
而前額皮層負責控制我們的情緒沖動
the area which controls our response to our emotional impulses.

291
00:15:44,190 --> 00:15:47,310
他還發現大腦的情緒制造中樞
He also found that the emotion-producing centres of the brain,

292
00:15:47,310 --> 00:15:48,440
如杏仁核
like the amygdala,

293
00:15:48,440 --> 00:15:51,230
即產生攻擊沖動的地方
which generates our aggressive impulses,

294
00:15:51,230 --> 00:15:53,890
在殺人犯腦內都過度活躍
were overactive in the murderers.

295
00:15:55,480 --> 00:15:57,910
因此看來殺人犯的大腦
So, it seems that murderers have brains

296
00:15:57,910 --> 00:16:00,790
讓他們更容易憤怒
that make them more prone to rage and anger,

297
00:16:01,070 --> 00:16:02,140
而與此同時
while at the same time,

298
00:16:02,140 --> 00:16:05,350
令他們自控能力更差
making them less able to control themselves.

299
00:16:08,690 --> 00:16:10,510
但事實要復雜許多
But it's more complicated than that

300
00:16:10,510 --> 00:16:13,030
因為殺人犯有很多種
because there are different types of murderer.

301
00:16:13,090 --> 00:16:15,920
雷恩醫生所研究的對象
The ones in Dr Raine's study were mainly

302
00:16:15,920 --> 00:16:18,920
主要是應激行兇的沖動性殺人犯
reactive, impulsive, hot-blooded.

303
00:16:19,140 --> 00:16:21,360
此外還有冷酷的殺人犯
Then, there are the cold-blooded ones,

304
00:16:21,360 --> 00:16:23,990
這類人一絲不茍地計劃謀殺
who planned everything in meticulous detail

305
00:16:23,990 --> 00:16:26,650
并可能一犯再犯
and may kill again and again.

306
00:16:26,830 --> 00:16:30,670
那連環殺人犯的大腦是怎樣的呢
So, what goes on inside the mind of a serial killer?

307
00:16:40,510 --> 00:16:43,970
大衛·克魯格是名典型的連環殺人犯
David Krueger is a typical serial killer.

308
00:16:44,310 --> 00:16:46,200
與90%的連環殺人犯相似
Like 90% of serial killers,

309
00:16:46,200 --> 00:16:50,410
他呈現出精神變態的心理癥狀
he displays the psychological characteristics of a psychopath.

310
00:16:50,900 --> 00:16:54,890
年僅17歲時  他殘忍殺害了三名幼童
Aged just 17, he brutally murdered three young children.

311
00:16:55,540 --> 00:16:59,460
事發于1956年9月16日
It all began on the 16th of September 1956.

312
00:16:56,310 --> 00:17:00,820
{\an8}《殺人者心理：瘋狂的面具》（2001年）

313
00:16:59,770 --> 00:17:01,570
一個叫韋恩·馬利特的小男孩
A little boy called Wayne Mallette

314
00:17:01,570 --> 00:17:04,450
前往多倫多看望祖母
had gone to 'visit his grandmother in Toronto.

315
00:17:06,080 --> 00:17:08,080
他當時在前院玩耍
He was playing in the front yard,

316
00:17:08,400 --> 00:17:11,570
但當他母親來找他時  他不見了
but when his mother went to look for him, he had vanished.

317
00:17:19,880 --> 00:17:22,370
韋恩著迷于火車
Wayne was fascinated by trains.

318
00:17:22,880 --> 00:17:24,490
臨近傍晚的某個時刻
At some point in the late afternoon,

319
00:17:24,490 --> 00:17:26,460
他遇見了大衛·克魯格
he met with David Krueger.

320
00:17:26,900 --> 00:17:29,470
克魯格引誘他到了一個偏僻處
Krueger lured him to a secret place,

321
00:17:29,470 --> 00:17:31,990
對他說他們可以在那里等火車
where he said they could wait for trains together.

322
00:17:40,110 --> 00:17:44,610
而六歲的韋恩不知道死神正一步步逼近
Six-year-old Wayne was led unsuspecting to his death.

323
00:17:49,440 --> 00:17:53,010
幾小時后人們發現他被殘忍地殺害了
He was found a few hours later, brutally murdered.

324
00:17:55,600 --> 00:17:59,210
盡管有大規模的搜捕  克魯格還是逃脫了追捕
Despite a huge manhunt, Krueger escaped detection.

325
00:17:59,610 --> 00:18:00,520
不到三個星期
Within three weeks,

326
00:18:00,520 --> 00:18:02,030
他誘騙了一個九歲的孩子
he persuaded nine-year-old

327
00:18:02,030 --> 00:18:05,610
蓋里·莫瑞斯搭乘他的自行車
Gary Morris to accept a ride on his bike.

328
00:18:08,130 --> 00:18:11,920
他把他帶到多倫多碼頭附近的一個空灘
He led him to an empty waterfront area by Toronto Docks.

329
00:18:18,200 --> 00:18:20,750
那晚人們發現了死去的蓋里
When Gary was found dead later that night,

330
00:18:20,750 --> 00:18:23,690
他被掐死并遭受惡性襲擊
he had been choked and viciously attacked.'

331
00:18:24,440 --> 00:18:27,400
很遺憾兩個男孩死了
It is too bad that the two boys died,

332
00:18:27,840 --> 00:18:30,410
但我感覺自己成了神
but I felt like God,

333
00:18:30,410 --> 00:18:33,380
擁有凌駕于凡人之上的神的權利
with the power of God over a human being.

334
00:18:33,480 --> 00:18:35,540
在扼殺孩子的時候
In the strangling of children,

335
00:18:35,540 --> 00:18:38,920
我感到了某種程度的快感
I found a degree and sensation of pleasure

336
00:18:38,920 --> 00:18:43,090
一種我從未體會過的成就感
and of accomplishment that I didn't feel anywhere else.

337
00:18:44,030 --> 00:18:46,880
大衛·克魯格在被捕前
David Krueger went on to kill four-year-old

338
00:18:46,890 --> 00:18:49,940
又殺了四歲的卡羅爾·沃耶斯
Carole Voyce before finally being arrested.

339
00:18:50,750 --> 00:18:54,480
假如我當時想到
Now, had I for one instance thought,

340
00:18:55,160 --> 00:18:56,830
這是個活生生的人
This is a human being,

341
00:18:57,010 --> 00:19:00,950
我正在殘忍傷害這個人
this is somebody who is been badly hurt by me,"

342
00:19:00,950 --> 00:19:01,950
我想我會住手的
I think I would have stopped.

343
00:19:04,050 --> 00:19:06,380
而我沒有這么想說明
The fact that I didn't shows

344
00:19:06,380 --> 00:19:08,720
我真的沒有那種感覺
that those feelings were really secondary.

345
00:19:13,750 --> 00:19:15,400
顯然大衛·克魯格
It's clear that David Krueger

346
00:19:15,400 --> 00:19:18,660
對他的受害者漠不關心
had no concern whatsoever for his victims.

347
00:19:20,410 --> 00:19:23,700
而這是精神變態的主要特點
And this is the key hallmark of a psychopath.

348
00:19:25,750 --> 00:19:28,500
精神變態的主要特征包括
The essential features of psychopathy

349
00:19:28,600 --> 00:19:31,040
缺乏同理心
would include a lack of empathy.

350
00:19:30,780 --> 00:19:35,030
{\an8}羅伯特·黑爾博士  不列顛哥倫比亞大學

351
00:19:31,040 --> 00:19:32,510
我不是說一般性的缺乏
I don't mean just a general...

352
00:19:32,510 --> 00:19:34,790
我是指嚴重缺乏同理心
I mean a profound lack of empathy.

353
00:19:35,010 --> 00:19:37,890
對他人的麻木不仁
A general callousness towards other people.

354
00:19:38,370 --> 00:19:40,320
這種人沒有良心
These are people without a conscience.

355
00:19:41,770 --> 00:19:45,330
我當時沒感到任何后悔或內疚
I didn't feel any sense of remorse or guilt at the time,

356
00:19:45,330 --> 00:19:47,060
我只想創造平衡
I just wanted to create a balance.

357
00:19:47,060 --> 00:19:49,990
死了兩個男孩  也許還該死個女孩
Two boys had died, so maybe now a girl should die.

358
00:19:54,580 --> 00:19:57,130
為了解為何
To try to understand why they have

359
00:19:57,130 --> 00:19:59,810
他們如此缺乏同情心
this extreme lack of empathy for others,

360
00:19:59,940 --> 00:20:03,710
羅博·黑爾開始研究精神變態者的大腦
Rob Hare began to explore the brains of psychopaths.

361
00:20:13,670 --> 00:20:17,690
我們給實驗對象看了一系列圖片
We actually showed our subjects a series of pictures

362
00:20:17,690 --> 00:20:18,930
其中有些圖片
and some of these pictures are

363
00:20:18,930 --> 00:20:20,870
是中性無害的
neutral and rather innocuous,

364
00:20:20,870 --> 00:20:22,860
而有些是恐怖的
others are horrific, appalling,

365
00:20:22,860 --> 00:20:25,110
那些圖片會使大部分人感到不適
would make most people extremely upset.

366
00:20:25,110 --> 00:20:26,890
那些圖片很嚇人
They were very distressing.

367
00:20:28,120 --> 00:20:31,240
黑爾在精神變態者觀看圖片時
Hare looked at the psychopaths' emotional brain,

368
00:20:31,520 --> 00:20:33,550
觀察他們的大腦情緒
while they were looking at the images.

369
00:20:34,080 --> 00:20:35,810
結果令人震驚
The results were striking.

370
00:20:38,530 --> 00:20:42,420
這是正常人看到暴力圖片時的大腦掃描
This is a scan of a normal person looking at violent images.

371
00:20:42,550 --> 00:20:45,930
紅色區域顯示杏仁核很活躍
The red shows a great deal of activity in the amygdala.

372
00:20:46,590 --> 00:20:50,650
相比之下  精神變態者的基本沒有活動
By contrast, the psychopath has almost no activity.

373
00:20:51,160 --> 00:20:54,360
他們的大腦在觀看中性圖片
There was no difference in the way they processed neutral

374
00:20:54,360 --> 00:20:56,410
與刺激性圖片時沒有什么區別
and emotional images.'

375
00:20:57,790 --> 00:21:00,730
當它們看到他人受苦時
This lack of emotional activity in the amygdala

376
00:21:00,730 --> 00:21:03,020
杏仁核缺乏情緒活動
in response to seeing others' suffering

377
00:21:03,030 --> 00:21:05,090
可以解釋為何精神變態者對其受害人
explains the chilling lack of empathy

378
00:21:05,090 --> 00:21:07,680
缺乏同理心這一可怕現象
psychopaths have for their victims.

379
00:21:08,260 --> 00:21:12,810
我記得自己在山丘上興奮地跳動
I remember jumping on the hillside, up and down, with excitement,

380
00:21:12,810 --> 00:21:16,440
她躺在那等死時我歡呼  死  死
chanting, "Die, die, die," As she was lying there dying.

381
00:21:20,320 --> 00:21:24,040
大腦掃描還顯示與應激型殺人犯不同
Scans also revealed that unlike reactive killers,

382
00:21:24,040 --> 00:21:27,690
精神變態者的前額皮質工作正常
the prefrontal cortex functioned normally in psychopaths.

383
00:21:27,800 --> 00:21:30,730
他們可以控制自己的攻擊沖動
They can control their aggressive impulses.

384
00:21:32,080 --> 00:21:35,630
擁有自控力  但缺乏同理心
And it's this combination of self-control with no empathy

385
00:21:35,630 --> 00:21:37,900
使他們尤其危險
that makes them so dangerous.

386
00:21:38,110 --> 00:21:41,750
他們可以小心翼翼地謀劃襲擊
They can carefully plan their attacks without being held back

387
00:21:41,750 --> 00:21:43,820
又不會因同情受害者而卻步
by concern for their victims.

388
00:21:52,210 --> 00:21:55,440
科學家們揭示了
So, scientists had uncovered what is different about the brains

389
00:21:55,440 --> 00:21:58,620
應激型殺人犯與精神變態者大腦的不同
of reactive killers and psychopaths.

390
00:21:59,660 --> 00:22:02,220
然而還有另一種殺人犯
But there is another type of killer -

391
00:22:02,850 --> 00:22:05,500
他們是精神分裂癥患者
those who suffer from schizophrenia,

392
00:22:05,540 --> 00:22:08,660
他們只在陷入瘋狂時犯罪
and only kill while in the grip of madness.

393
00:22:11,030 --> 00:22:14,730
在西方  每年百分之五到十的兇案
In the Western world, 5-10% of murders each year

394
00:22:14,730 --> 00:22:17,630
是精神分裂癥患者犯下的
are committed by someone with schizophrenia,

395
00:22:17,930 --> 00:22:20,510
科迪·米滕便是其中一例
as was the case with Cody Mitten.

396
00:22:34,340 --> 00:22:38,710
{\an8}《殺人者心理：瘋狂的面具》（2001年）

397
00:22:34,870 --> 00:22:39,390
科迪小時候是個很好的弟弟
As Cody was growing up, he was a really good little brother -

398
00:22:39,390 --> 00:22:43,390
有愛心且精力充沛
loving and energetic and he just...

399
00:22:40,230 --> 00:22:44,550
{\an8}塔米·雷

400
00:22:43,600 --> 00:22:45,050
他是個好孩子
He was a great kid.

401
00:22:47,420 --> 00:22:50,910
我為科迪驕傲  沒有比他更好的兒子了
I was very proud of Cody. You couldn't ask for a better son.

402
00:22:51,420 --> 00:22:55,950
長大后他也有愛心  善解人意助人為樂
Even growing up, he was very lovable, understanding and helpful.

403
00:22:53,800 --> 00:22:57,460
{\an8}吉姆·米滕

404
00:22:55,950 --> 00:22:58,820
在你需要幫助時他定會伸出援手
You need some help? He'd help you.

405
00:22:59,130 --> 00:23:00,700
他是最棒的兒子
He was number one son.

406
00:23:04,820 --> 00:23:07,060
他同他母親關系很親密
He had a real close relationship with his mother.

407
00:23:07,060 --> 00:23:09,470
他非常愛自己的母親
He loved his mother very true.

408
00:23:11,020 --> 00:23:14,840
我是說誰都知道他很愛她
I mean, there was no doubt in nobody's mind that he loved her.

409
00:23:18,710 --> 00:23:23,000
但1997年科迪開始舉止異常
But in 1997, Cody started acting strangely.

410
00:23:25,600 --> 00:23:27,860
那天晚上  他突然來到我家
That night, he just shows up at my place.

411
00:23:28,230 --> 00:23:30,860
他捂著肚子  說自己病了
He's holding his stomach, he's saying that he's sick

412
00:23:30,860 --> 00:23:33,140
他以為自己要死了
and he thinks he's going to die.

413
00:23:34,510 --> 00:23:36,940
他以為自己是耶穌基督
And that he thought he was Jesus Christ.

414
00:23:39,230 --> 00:23:42,000
他會突然說
Out of the blue, he would come out and say that

415
00:23:42,420 --> 00:23:46,300
自己是半人半猿
he was half man and half ape.

416
00:23:46,380 --> 00:23:50,760
他開始自言自語  說些怪話
He started talking and saying weird...things,

417
00:23:47,010 --> 00:23:51,110
{\an8}瑪麗·卡羅  科迪的姨母

418
00:23:51,050 --> 00:23:53,320
他漸漸變得不像自己了
which was not becoming to Cody.

419
00:23:54,990 --> 00:23:59,700
我被他的巨大變化嚇壞了
I was scared because there was such a drastic change in him.

420
00:24:03,690 --> 00:24:06,420
盡管大多精神分裂癥患者并不暴力
Though most schizophrenics are not violent,

421
00:24:06,420 --> 00:24:09,850
但患精神分裂使男性的殺人幾率提高三倍
having schizophrenia makes men three times

422
00:24:09,850 --> 00:24:13,820
女性則是二十二倍
and women 22 times more likely to murder.

423
00:24:15,220 --> 00:24:18,480
而科迪的病情驅使他殺了自己的母親
In Cody's case, his illness drove him to kill his mother

424
00:24:18,480 --> 00:24:20,120
和她的男友拉里
and her boyfriend Larry.

425
00:24:22,930 --> 00:24:24,950
我們正坐在客廳
We're all sitting in the living room and stuff

426
00:24:24,960 --> 00:24:28,240
我聽見電視傳來了聲音
and I was hearing voices come out of the TV,

427
00:24:28,240 --> 00:24:29,200
好像在跟我說話
like they were talking to me,

428
00:24:29,200 --> 00:24:31,790
跟我說有人要謀害我的家人
telling me that people were trying to kill my family,

429
00:24:31,790 --> 00:24:32,900
要殺掉我
trying to kill me and stuff.

430
00:24:32,900 --> 00:24:36,030
這些完全說不通  我當時非常恐懼
None of this made sense to me at all. I was just really fearful.

431
00:24:37,420 --> 00:24:39,330
盡管我母親是我的一切
Even though my mother was everything to me,

432
00:24:39,330 --> 00:24:42,440
當時我認為她和別人沆瀣一氣
at this time, I thought she was in cahoots with everybody else,

433
00:24:42,440 --> 00:24:45,910
想要殺我  要傷害我
trying to kill me, trying to do harm to me and stuff.

434
00:24:45,910 --> 00:24:47,790
我走進廚房
So, I went into the kitchen

435
00:24:47,790 --> 00:24:51,310
把手上的那碗冰淇淋放下
to put my bowl of ice cream down and...

436
00:24:52,430 --> 00:24:53,810
放到水槽里
In the kitchen sink.

437
00:24:53,840 --> 00:24:58,360
我從料理臺上抓起一把刀捅了拉里
And I grabbed a knife from the counter and I stabbed Larry

438
00:24:58,360 --> 00:25:00,260
還有媽媽
and my mom and...

439
00:25:07,600 --> 00:25:09,380
我不明白為什么
I don't know why... I don't know.

440
00:25:11,820 --> 00:25:15,060
-我不明白  -好的
- I don't know... - OK.

441
00:25:16,690 --> 00:25:18,840
我捅了拉里和媽媽
I stabbed Larry and my mom...

442
00:25:20,610 --> 00:25:23,580
我不明白為什么  完全不明白
I don't know why. I have no idea why.

443
00:25:29,910 --> 00:25:32,430
為了解為何精神分裂癥
To try and understand how schizophrenia

444
00:25:32,430 --> 00:25:34,830
令人更可能殺人
could make someone more likely to kill,

445
00:25:34,930 --> 00:25:37,830
科學家們掃描了精神分裂癥患者的大腦
scientists scanned the brains of schizophrenics.

446
00:25:39,560 --> 00:25:42,850
掃描顯示他們的情感中樞
The scans revealed that the emotional centres of their brains

447
00:25:42,850 --> 00:25:46,310
不能對他人的情緒做出正常反應
did not respond normally to the emotions of others.

448
00:25:46,380 --> 00:25:50,340
他們的前額皮質也沒有正常工作
And their prefrontal cortex did not function properly either.

449
00:25:51,620 --> 00:25:54,240
精神分裂型殺人犯
Schizophrenic murderers seem to combine

450
00:25:54,240 --> 00:25:56,600
似乎既像精神變態一樣缺乏同理心
the lack of empathy of a psychopath

451
00:25:56,610 --> 00:25:59,980
也同應激性殺人犯一樣缺乏自控力
with the lack of impulse control of a reactive killer.

452
00:26:02,110 --> 00:26:03,780
大腦掃描允許我們
The use of brain scans has allowed us

453
00:26:03,780 --> 00:26:06,110
找出了大腦中的兩塊區域
to identify two areas of the brain.

454
00:26:06,160 --> 00:26:07,820
一是產生情緒的
One that produces emotion

455
00:26:07,820 --> 00:26:10,490
一是控制我們的情緒反應的
and one that controls our response to emotions,

456
00:26:10,500 --> 00:26:13,910
殺人兇手大腦中的這兩塊區域都工作失常
which appear to malfunction in the brains of murderers.

457
00:26:14,130 --> 00:26:17,520
除此之外  科學家們還研究了
Alongside this, scientists have also studied the biochemistry,

458
00:26:17,520 --> 00:26:20,900
與這些失常相關的生物化學
which seems to underline these malfunctions.

459
00:26:23,850 --> 00:26:25,000
他們試圖了解
They wanted to see

460
00:26:25,010 --> 00:26:27,190
是否是化學物質的不平衡
if there were any chemical imbalances

461
00:26:27,200 --> 00:26:29,400
影響了殺人犯的大腦
affecting the brains of murderers.

462
00:26:29,990 --> 00:26:31,710
首要且最明顯的研究對象
The first and most obvious target

463
00:26:31,710 --> 00:26:34,400
便是雄性激素睪丸素
was the male hormone testosterone.

464
00:26:34,700 --> 00:26:37,530
因為關于謀殺的最驚人事實可能就是
Because perhaps the most striking about murder

465
00:26:37,530 --> 00:26:40,670
百分之九十的殺人犯都是男人
is that 90% of murderers are men.

466
00:26:43,480 --> 00:26:47,520
那么睪丸素是否參與塑造了兇手的大腦呢
So, might testosterone play a part in creating a killer brain?

467
00:26:49,580 --> 00:26:53,050
1980年代康乃迪克州
An important clue came from a notorious serial killer

468
00:26:53,060 --> 00:26:55,790
有名臭名昭著的連環殺手可提供重要線索
in Connecticut in the 1980s.

469
00:26:57,210 --> 00:27:00,070
邁克爾·羅斯說他隨時隨地都可能產生
Michael Ross says a powerful 'and irresistible urge

470
00:26:58,590 --> 00:27:02,980
{\an8}《殺人者心理：殺手的性》（2001年）

471
00:27:00,070 --> 00:27:02,680
傷害女人的強烈而不可抑制的沖動
to hurt women could come over him at any time

472
00:27:02,680 --> 00:27:06,980
這種沖動來得毫無預兆且沒有任何理由
and at any place, for no apparent reason and with no warning.'

473
00:27:09,670 --> 00:27:13,940
"你很難想象
"You cannot imagine what it is like

474
00:27:14,460 --> 00:27:17,850
殺人這個念頭
to be excited and to be stimulated

475
00:27:17,850 --> 00:27:19,360
所激發的興奮感
by thoughts of killing somebody,

476
00:27:19,360 --> 00:27:21,160
強奸  殺害和羞辱他人
by raping and killing and degrading.

477
00:27:21,160 --> 00:27:24,460
這些想法在短期內
They are extremely stimulating

478
00:27:24,460 --> 00:27:27,170
非常令人興奮與滿足
and satisfying in the short term,

479
00:27:27,790 --> 00:27:30,040
但它們又令人作嘔
but they're disgusting as hell

480
00:27:30,040 --> 00:27:32,770
我真希望自己沒有這些想法"
and I wish that I didn't have them."

481
00:27:37,070 --> 00:27:39,390
經診斷邁克爾·羅斯
Michael Ross was diagnosed as having

482
00:27:39,390 --> 00:27:42,760
有遠高于正常水平的睪丸素
abnormally high levels of testosterone.

483
00:27:43,370 --> 00:27:46,110
那么高睪丸素水平
So, could there be a link between high testosterone

484
00:27:46,110 --> 00:27:47,860
是否與暴力犯罪相關
and violent crimes?

485
00:27:48,700 --> 00:27:51,370
這一疑問讓詹姆斯·達布斯教授
This question led Professor James Dabbs

486
00:27:51,370 --> 00:27:55,860
收集并檢驗了上百名罪犯的唾液樣本
to collect and test saliva samples from hundreds of prisoners.

487
00:27:56,400 --> 00:27:59,320
我們檢驗了獄囚的睪丸素水平
We examined prison inmates and looked at the testosterone level

488
00:27:59,320 --> 00:28:00,900
并與它們所犯的案件相聯系
and related it back to the crimes

489
00:28:00,910 --> 00:28:03,670
我們發現具有較高睪丸素水平的獄囚
they had committed and found that the higher testosterone inmates

490
00:28:03,670 --> 00:28:06,410
更有可能暴力犯罪
had more often committed violent crimes.

491
00:28:03,290 --> 00:28:05,840
{\an8}詹姆斯·達布斯教授  心理學家

492
00:28:07,410 --> 00:28:11,160
當然不是所有睪丸素含量高的人都是兇手
Of course, not everyone with high testosterone is a killer.

493
00:28:11,540 --> 00:28:14,810
但含量高確更易導致暴力行為
But high levels of it do make violence more likely.

494
00:28:15,860 --> 00:28:19,270
最新研究表明
And the very latest research has found that giving normal men

495
00:28:19,270 --> 00:28:21,850
提高正常人的睪丸素水平
extra testosterone increases

496
00:28:21,850 --> 00:28:24,370
他們的杏仁核會變得更活躍
the reactivity of their amygdala,

497
00:28:24,640 --> 00:28:27,720
許多殺人犯的大腦掃描顯示
the emotional centre of the brain which scanning had revealed

498
00:28:27,720 --> 00:28:30,680
殺人時這一情緒中樞過度活躍
was overactive in many murderers.

499
00:28:32,140 --> 00:28:36,530
這可以解釋睪丸素與暴力之間的關系
This could explain the link between testosterone and violence.

500
00:28:40,810 --> 00:28:43,460
與此同時科學家們
Meanwhile, scientists were also investigating

501
00:28:43,460 --> 00:28:47,970
還調查了另一種可能與兇殺相關的化學物質
another chemical that they suspected might be implicated in murder

502
00:28:47,970 --> 00:28:49,340
血清素
serotonin.

503
00:28:52,140 --> 00:28:54,700
這是一種神經遞質
It's a neurotransmitter that is important

504
00:28:54,700 --> 00:28:57,420
對保證前額皮質的工作來說至關重要
for the functioning of the prefrontal cortex,

505
00:28:57,510 --> 00:28:59,540
而前額皮質是大腦中
the area of the brain that is crucial

506
00:28:59,540 --> 00:29:02,480
控制情緒沖動的關鍵區域
for regulating our emotional impulses.

507
00:29:03,240 --> 00:29:06,570
最早的線索來自于猴子實驗
The first clues came from studies with monkeys.

508
00:29:09,400 --> 00:29:12,320
通過觀察低血清素的猴子
If you look at monkeys who have low serotonin,

509
00:29:11,070 --> 00:29:15,390
{\an8}迪伊·希格利博士  行為生物學家

510
00:29:12,730 --> 00:29:13,920
你可以發現它們
then what you see are monkeys

511
00:29:13,920 --> 00:29:17,850
具有所謂反社會人格
that have what we call an antisocial personality.

512
00:29:17,860 --> 00:29:20,070
其它猴子不愿與這些猴子交往
These are monkeys that nobody wants to associate with

513
00:29:20,070 --> 00:29:23,130
因為它們傾向于毆打別的猴子
because they're likely to beat up other monkeys,

514
00:29:23,130 --> 00:29:27,680
或是會做另其他猴子不快的舉動
or likely to do the kinds of things that really are an unpleasant

515
00:29:27,680 --> 00:29:29,640
使社交關系無法維持
kind of relationship to have.

516
00:29:30,530 --> 00:29:34,010
因此科學家們懷疑這情況也同樣適用于人
So, scientists wondered if the same might be true of humans.

517
00:29:38,260 --> 00:29:41,110
通過研究海軍陸戰隊員
Striking evidence came from a study of Marines

518
00:29:41,110 --> 00:29:43,100
科學家得到了驚人的證據
who'd 'served in Vietnam,

519
00:29:43,350 --> 00:29:45,980
這些曾在越南服役的人的異常舉止引起了關注
but whose behaviour was causing concern.

520
00:29:46,760 --> 00:29:49,790
弗雷德·古德溫醫生
The clue to their overtly aggressive behaviour

521
00:29:49,790 --> 00:29:53,160
通過研究數百名陸戰隊員
was 'discovered for the first time by Dr Fred Goodwin

522
00:29:53,340 --> 00:29:56,540
濫用職權的暴力行為最先發現了
when he studied hundreds of Marines whose violent behaviour

523
00:29:56,540 --> 00:29:59,000
導致過激攻擊行為發生的線索
went 'well beyond the call of duty.'

524
00:30:01,640 --> 00:30:04,150
我們研究了他們的履歷表
We dug into their charts

525
00:30:04,150 --> 00:30:08,440
{\an8}弗雷德里克·古德溫醫生  神經科學家

526
00:30:04,240 --> 00:30:06,550
發現他們中的很多人
and found that there was lots of histories

527
00:30:06,550 --> 00:30:11,360
有暴力和攻擊行為的記錄
of violent and aggressive behaviour in many of these individuals.

528
00:30:12,600 --> 00:30:15,810
他發現這些暴力分子有一個共通點
He found the violent men shared a key characteristic -

529
00:30:15,810 --> 00:30:19,850
其腦內化學物質血清素的含量都很低
unusually low levels of the brain chemical serotonin.

530
00:30:20,310 --> 00:30:23,960
血清素是調節器和剎車機制
It's a modulator, a dampener, and it is a brake.

531
00:30:24,110 --> 00:30:27,860
因此低血清素會使人喪失這種剎車機制
It's a brake and so low serotonin seems to take the brakes off.

532
00:30:28,340 --> 00:30:31,980
低血清素會導致暴力行為的增加
His discovery that low serotonin can increase violent behaviour

533
00:30:31,980 --> 00:30:34,220
他的這一發現是科學研究的轉折點
was a scientific turning point.

534
00:30:34,540 --> 00:30:38,310
會不會是低血清素含量導致人殺戮
Could a lack of serotonin allow some men to kill?

535
00:30:41,260 --> 00:30:45,910
殘忍殺害年邁祖父母的迪翁·桑德斯
The case of Deion Sanders, who had brutally murdered his elderly the grandparents,

536
00:30:45,910 --> 00:30:47,660
為血清素在殺人行為中起作用
 provided further evidence

537
00:30:47,660 --> 00:30:50,240
提供了進一步的證據
that serotonin could play a part in murder.

538
00:30:51,130 --> 00:30:52,220
桑德斯
Sanders.

539
00:30:55,410 --> 00:31:00,040
獄中保羅·羅斯醫生量了迪翁的血清素量
In prison, Dr Paul Ross measured Deion's serotonin levels.

540
00:31:00,750 --> 00:31:03,080
異常低的血清素水平
A very abnormally low level of serotonin

541
00:31:02,620 --> 00:31:06,820
{\an8}保羅·羅斯醫生  神經生物學家

542
00:31:03,080 --> 00:31:06,680
與許多沖動性失調癥相關
has been linked to many impulsive disorders

543
00:31:06,680 --> 00:31:08,980
比如攻擊性
including aggression,

544
00:31:08,980 --> 00:31:11,150
無抑制攻擊性以及狂暴
unopposed aggression, or rage.

545
00:31:12,130 --> 00:31:14,130
至于迪翁·桑德斯
In the case of Deion Sanders,

546
00:31:14,130 --> 00:31:17,390
他的血清素含量異常低
his serotonin level was very abnormally low,

547
00:31:17,390 --> 00:31:19,410
超乎尋常的低
extremely abnormally low.

548
00:31:19,910 --> 00:31:21,890
血清素的異常低含量
Extremely low levels of serotonin

549
00:31:21,890 --> 00:31:24,250
導致迪翁與不知多少其他人一樣
put Deion amongst an unknown number of men

550
00:31:24,250 --> 00:31:26,960
處在脾氣失控的邊緣
with a heightened risk of losing their temper,

551
00:31:27,320 --> 00:31:30,750
他們可能突然采取放肆的暴力行為
capable of sudden and unrestrained violence,

552
00:31:31,000 --> 00:31:32,820
甚至會殺人
capable of murder.

553
00:31:39,360 --> 00:31:41,950
過去五十年
Over the last 50 years, we've discovered a number

554
00:31:41,950 --> 00:31:43,940
我們發現了一系列
of biological differences

555
00:31:43,940 --> 00:31:45,630
兇手大腦
between the brains of murderers

556
00:31:45,630 --> 00:31:49,480
與我們其他人的不同之處  但成因是什么
and the rest of us, but what causes of those differences?

557
00:31:49,570 --> 00:31:53,100
是基因所致還是全由環境決定
Is there a genetic component or is it entirely environmental?

558
00:31:53,390 --> 00:31:56,140
殺人犯是天生的還是后天的
Are murderers born or are they made?

559
00:31:59,170 --> 00:32:02,610
起初科學家們著重研究教養因素
Initially, scientists focused on the role of upbringing.

560
00:32:03,550 --> 00:32:08,310
二十世紀五十年代末六十年代初
Experiments with monkeys in the late 1950s and early 1960s

561
00:32:08,310 --> 00:32:11,090
在猴子實驗表明母愛對于
revealed the importance of motherly love

562
00:32:11,090 --> 00:32:14,950
幼猴的正常心理成長的重要性
for the normal psychological development of baby monkeys.

563
00:32:15,550 --> 00:32:17,120
在一些具有爭議的實驗里
In controversial experiments,

564
00:32:17,120 --> 00:32:22,020
哈利·哈洛把幼猴隔離達一年之久
Harry Harlow put baby monkeys in isolation for up to a year.

565
00:32:22,820 --> 00:32:26,020
所有這些猴子都變得嚴重失常
All the monkeys came out severely disturbed.

566
00:32:27,470 --> 00:32:29,480
缺乏父母的關照
Lack of normal parental care

567
00:32:29,480 --> 00:32:32,310
很明顯影響了它們的情感發育
had clearly affected their emotional development.

568
00:32:34,140 --> 00:32:37,180
而這似乎在人類身上也同樣適用
And it looked like the same was true of humans.

569
00:32:37,560 --> 00:32:39,450
人們早就知道
Certainly it had been known for some time

570
00:32:39,460 --> 00:32:43,660
許多殺人犯都有充滿暴力而不快的童年
that murderers often had violent and disrupted childhoods.

571
00:32:46,930 --> 00:32:50,910
史蒂夫·帕克斯便是糟糕童年影響人格的
Steve Parkus is a classic case of what a terrible childhood

572
00:32:50,910 --> 00:32:52,430
一個典型案例
can do to someone.

573
00:32:53,240 --> 00:32:54,660
史蒂夫與其弟弟
Steve and his brother were abused

574
00:32:54,660 --> 00:32:57,660
被酗酒的父母長期忽視并虐待
and neglected by their alcoholic parents.

575
00:32:59,170 --> 00:33:02,300
{\an8}《殺人者心理：創傷》

576
00:33:00,200 --> 00:33:02,750
她待史蒂夫比待我更壞
She was harder on Steve than she was on me,

577
00:33:02,980 --> 00:33:04,850
可能因為我是最小的
cos I was the youngest, probably.

578
00:33:04,190 --> 00:33:09,670
{\an8}切斯特·帕克斯  史蒂夫的弟弟

579
00:33:06,650 --> 00:33:08,170
我總是躲在他后面
I always hid behind him

580
00:33:08,360 --> 00:33:10,250
因為他比我高大一些
cos he was bigger than I was, right?

581
00:33:10,300 --> 00:33:13,940
她一發作我就躲他后面
She started swinging, I just ducked behind him, right?

582
00:33:15,070 --> 00:33:18,060
由于沒有看護  當琳達外出喝酒時
In lieu of a baby-sitter, when Linda went out drinking,

583
00:33:15,760 --> 00:33:21,010
{\an8}肖恩·奧布賴恩  史蒂夫·帕克斯的律師

584
00:33:18,060 --> 00:33:21,280
她就把孩子們鎖在廁所  鎖上門
she would just lock the kids in the bathroom, lock the door.

585
00:33:21,490 --> 00:33:26,060
有一次  史蒂夫和切斯特從廁所窗戶溜出來
One time, Steve and Chester sneaked out, out the bathroom window,

586
00:33:26,550 --> 00:33:28,680
他們被警察發現并帶了回來
and the police found them and brought them home

587
00:33:28,680 --> 00:33:30,990
等警察走后
and after they left,

588
00:33:31,020 --> 00:33:34,120
她在爐子上燒熱了一把刀
she heated up a knife over the stove

589
00:33:34,120 --> 00:33:36,940
然后用燒的滾燙的刀刃
and started burning them on bare buttocks

590
00:33:36,940 --> 00:33:39,040
來烙他們裸臀
with the hot blade of the knife

591
00:33:39,040 --> 00:33:41,700
之后未成年保護機構
and that was the point at which the juvenile authorities

592
00:33:41,700 --> 00:33:43,630
便介入了
became involved in the case.

593
00:33:46,200 --> 00:33:49,020
兩位男孩被他們的舅舅泰勒
The two boys were taken in by their uncle Taylor

594
00:33:49,020 --> 00:33:50,690
和舅媽柏妮絲收養
and aunt Bernice.

595
00:33:51,980 --> 00:33:53,370
但對史蒂夫來說不幸的是
Unfortunately for Steve,

596
00:33:53,370 --> 00:33:56,750
他才出虎口又入狼窩
it was like out of the frying pan and into the fire.

597
00:33:56,750 --> 00:33:59,670
他從一名患精神分裂的母親身邊被帶走
He was taken away from a schizophrenic mother

598
00:33:59,670 --> 00:34:02,050
卻又被送入了
and put in the home

599
00:34:02,050 --> 00:34:04,810
一個虐待狂戀童癖的家里
where he was raised by a sadistic paedophile.

600
00:34:05,480 --> 00:34:09,340
史蒂夫·帕克斯遭受了
Steve Parkus is a very good example of a combination

601
00:34:09,340 --> 00:34:12,290
各種你所能想象的
of some of the most horrendous abuse

602
00:34:12,290 --> 00:34:14,380
最可怕的虐待
that you can possibly imagine,

603
00:34:15,340 --> 00:34:16,870
性上的與身體上的
sexual and physical,

604
00:34:16,870 --> 00:34:21,190
導致他變成一個孤僻的人
leading to a completely unsocialised individual.

605
00:34:18,510 --> 00:34:23,780
{\an8}喬納森·平卡斯  神經學家  喬治城大學

606
00:34:21,540 --> 00:34:24,860
他是在完完全全沒有愛
He was a person who was raised absolutely and totally

607
00:34:24,860 --> 00:34:29,060
沒有關懷和照顧的情況下長大的
without any love, without any affection, without any caring.

608
00:34:29,780 --> 00:34:32,370
自他出生至今
He was used as a thing

609
00:34:33,300 --> 00:34:36,560
他一直被當物品對待
from the time that he was born until today.

610
00:34:39,260 --> 00:34:42,650
十七歲時  史蒂夫·帕克斯進了監獄
Aged 17, Steve Parkus ended up in prison.

611
00:34:43,640 --> 00:34:45,290
他入獄后第一天
The first day that he got to prison,

612
00:34:45,290 --> 00:34:47,450
看守把他扒光
the guards stripped him naked

613
00:34:47,530 --> 00:34:49,910
讓他在監獄內來回走動
and marched him up and down the cell block

614
00:34:50,160 --> 00:34:52,630
將他拍賣
and auctioned him off to the highest bidder.

615
00:34:54,630 --> 00:34:58,510
他以六十美元的價格被賣作了性奴
He was sold as a sex slave for $60.

616
00:35:03,360 --> 00:35:06,720
1985年11月  還在獄中時
In November 1985, while still in prison,

617
00:35:06,720 --> 00:35:10,920
史蒂夫殺了唯一的朋友馬克·史蒂芬哈根
Steve murdered Mark Steffenhagen, his only friend.

618
00:35:11,860 --> 00:35:14,690
我把他的手  我綁了他的手腳
I put his hands... tied his hands and tied his feet...

619
00:35:14,690 --> 00:35:17,750
{\an8}帕克斯的自白錄音

620
00:35:16,010 --> 00:35:17,830
然后我趴在了他的背上
and I laid him over on his back

621
00:35:17,830 --> 00:35:20,740
我告訴他我要干什么  為什么干
and I told him what I was going to do and why.

622
00:35:21,460 --> 00:35:24,080
然后我開始掐他
And I just started choking him, you know.

623
00:35:24,080 --> 00:35:27,350
我用手勒緊他的喉嚨
I had my hand around his throat.

624
00:35:35,110 --> 00:35:38,740
很顯然充滿暴力沒有愛意的童年
It seemed obvious that a violent, unloving childhood

625
00:35:38,740 --> 00:35:41,710
是制造殺人犯的重要因素
played a crucial part in creating a killer,

626
00:35:42,180 --> 00:35:44,360
但問題是為什么會這樣
the question was how?

627
00:35:47,720 --> 00:35:51,950
1961年一項開創性實驗
In 1961, a groundbreaking experiment revealed the effect

628
00:35:51,950 --> 00:35:55,460
解釋了暴力對幼童產生的影響
that exposure to violence could have on young children.

629
00:35:58,310 --> 00:35:59,420
這個四歲的兒童
This four-year-old

630
00:35:59,420 --> 00:36:02,310
第一次得到了氣球娃娃
given a Bobo doll to play with for the first time

631
00:36:01,220 --> 00:36:05,630
{\an8}《地平線：該隱之子》（1967年）

632
00:36:02,310 --> 00:36:04,370
沒有任何襲擊它的意向
shows no tendency to attack it.

633
00:36:07,730 --> 00:36:09,630
他根本沒有這種想法
The idea doesn't seem to occur to him

634
00:36:09,630 --> 00:36:11,340
即使他跟娃娃玩了很長時間
and he didn't do so even though

635
00:36:11,350 --> 00:36:14,520
他也沒那么做
he was allowed to play with the doll for a considerable period.

636
00:36:16,300 --> 00:36:17,440
在這些實驗里
In the experiments,

637
00:36:17,440 --> 00:36:18,490
孩子們被安排看到了
the children were allowed

638
00:36:18,490 --> 00:36:22,030
一名成年人暴力攻擊玩具的樣子
to watch an adult attack the doll violently.

639
00:36:23,140 --> 00:36:24,750
而這名四歲孩童
This particular four-year-old

640
00:36:24,750 --> 00:36:26,880
不僅沒有什么暴力傾向
was not only generally unaggressive,

641
00:36:26,880 --> 00:36:29,570
他也從未學過拳擊
but he hadn't previously learnt to punch.

642
00:36:42,340 --> 00:36:44,930
但當再次給他娃娃玩時
But when given a second chance to play with the doll,

643
00:36:44,930 --> 00:36:47,940
他不僅迫不及待地攻擊了它
he not only attacked it eagerly and without prompting,

644
00:36:47,940 --> 00:36:49,790
而且還出人意料地準確模仿了
but copied with surprising accuracy

645
00:36:49,790 --> 00:36:52,380
他剛才看到的攻擊方式
the techniques of attack he'd just witnessed.

646
00:36:52,490 --> 00:36:53,880
這種行為模仿
This behaviour parallels...

647
00:36:53,880 --> 00:36:56,280
現在的人可能覺得這理所當然
This may seem obvious to us now,

648
00:36:56,280 --> 00:36:59,530
但當時是一項革命性的發現
but at the time it was a revolutionary finding.

649
00:36:59,860 --> 00:37:03,860
見證暴力會導致孩童行為更暴力
Witnessing violence made children behave more violently.

650
00:37:07,650 --> 00:37:11,720
但這不僅僅是兒童對成年人行為的模仿
But it's not just a case of children copying adult behaviour.

651
00:37:12,060 --> 00:37:15,420
我們現在知道童年經歷
We now know that childhood experiences actually affect

652
00:37:15,420 --> 00:37:17,310
真的會影響
the development of the brain areas

653
00:37:17,310 --> 00:37:19,560
大腦有關控制攻擊性的區域的發育
involved in controlling aggression.

654
00:37:21,050 --> 00:37:24,660
{\an8}《地平線：你有多暴力》（2009年）

655
00:37:21,380 --> 00:37:25,140
彼得·史密斯教授是兒童心理學的專家
Professor Peter Smith is an expert on child psychology.

656
00:37:26,060 --> 00:37:29,270
他正在研究早期侵略性行為的發展
He's studying the development of early aggressive behaviour.

657
00:37:29,410 --> 00:37:32,110
他們都知道彼此想要滑板車
They know that they each want the scooter... Yeah.

658
00:37:32,110 --> 00:37:35,210
但他們還無法抑制這種沖動
..But they're not able to really inhibit those impulses yet.

659
00:37:32,370 --> 00:37:34,930
{\an8}彼得·史密斯教授  倫敦大學金斯密斯學院

660
00:37:35,250 --> 00:37:37,240
這是因為與大些的孩子相比
That's because of a lack of brain development,

661
00:37:37,240 --> 00:37:38,770
他們的大腦發育得還不完全
compared to older children.

662
00:37:41,020 --> 00:37:44,890
三歲以前  我們放縱沖動
Until the age of three, our impulses run riot.

663
00:37:46,810 --> 00:37:48,420
我們情緒中樞產生的這些欲望
There's no stopping the urges

664
00:37:48,420 --> 00:37:50,550
沒辦法被阻止
which come from the emotional centre,

665
00:37:52,490 --> 00:37:55,850
之后我們才發育了
but then we start to develop the part of the brain

666
00:37:55,850 --> 00:37:58,230
大腦中負責控制攻擊性的部位
that allows us to the control our aggression,

667
00:37:58,680 --> 00:38:00,530
即前額皮質
the prefrontal cortex.

668
00:38:04,170 --> 00:38:05,350
然而重要的是
Yet, crucially,

669
00:38:05,520 --> 00:38:10,250
這一抑制機制工作如何取決于我們的經歷
how well this control mechanism works depends on our experiences.

670
00:38:11,320 --> 00:38:15,280
-我們在托兒所做什么  -我們分享
- What do we do at the nursery? - We share.

671
00:38:15,990 --> 00:38:18,450
里昂  開爾文  當沙漏漏完以后
Leon, Kelvin, when the sand timer finishes

672
00:38:18,460 --> 00:38:19,830
就告訴我
tell me when it's finished

673
00:38:19,830 --> 00:38:22,350
我們就可以輪流用車了  好嗎
and we can take turns on the bikes, yeah?

674
00:38:22,350 --> 00:38:26,120
神奇的是  學習分享和輪流使用
Incredibly, being taught to share and take turns

675
00:38:26,120 --> 00:38:29,150
會切實改變大腦的物理結構
actually changes the physical structure of the brain.

676
00:38:31,330 --> 00:38:34,360
這種學習會加強情緒中樞
It strengthens the connections between the emotional centre

677
00:38:34,690 --> 00:38:36,470
與前額皮質的聯系
and the prefrontal cortex.

678
00:38:38,820 --> 00:38:41,860
這就導致我們攻擊性降低
This is what makes us less aggressive.

679
00:38:43,590 --> 00:38:45,830
通常兩歲大的兒童
It's actually children as young as two

680
00:38:45,840 --> 00:38:49,250
是最具攻擊性的  動手動腳
who are the most frequently aggressive, physically aggressive,

681
00:38:49,250 --> 00:38:51,880
之后他們逐漸學會
and they're gradually learning not to

682
00:38:51,880 --> 00:38:55,130
通過社交過程變得不那樣有攻擊性
be aggressive in that way through a socialisation process.

683
00:38:57,610 --> 00:38:59,310
因此童年經歷
So childhood experiences

684
00:38:59,310 --> 00:39:02,150
實際上會改變
actually shape the very parts of the brain

685
00:39:02,150 --> 00:39:06,360
殺人犯大腦掃描顯示工作異常的部位
that scanning had revealed don't function properly in murderers.

686
00:39:07,190 --> 00:39:10,300
如果一個人在成長時只經歷過暴力
If someone grows up experiencing only violence,

687
00:39:10,300 --> 00:39:13,900
他大腦的這些區域就很可能不會正常發育
these brain areas are unlikely to develop normally

688
00:39:14,100 --> 00:39:17,810
而他們很可能變得暴力
and it is more likely that they too will become violent.

689
00:39:20,980 --> 00:39:25,150
除了大腦區域的正常連接受阻
As well as disrupting the normal wiring up of the brain,

690
00:39:25,170 --> 00:39:27,080
二十世紀九十年代的研究還發現
studies in the 1990s

691
00:39:27,080 --> 00:39:30,980
童年受到虐待還有可能使大腦受創
suggested that childhood abuse might also be creating killers

692
00:39:30,990 --> 00:39:34,240
從而制造殺人犯
by actually causing physical damage to the brain.

693
00:39:33,710 --> 00:39:36,230
{\an8}《殺人者心理：創傷》

694
00:39:34,690 --> 00:39:38,150
這些孩子中很多人被扔下樓梯
A lot of these kids have been just thrown downstairs

695
00:39:37,450 --> 00:39:42,530
{\an8}桃樂茜·路易斯醫生  司法精神病學家  耶魯大學

696
00:39:38,190 --> 00:39:41,130
撞在墻上  受到毆打
and battered against walls, punched, hit,

697
00:39:41,190 --> 00:39:45,280
因此他們的大腦受傷
and so the brain itself is damaged.

698
00:39:45,340 --> 00:39:46,430
給我們讓條路
Let's get a path for the...

699
00:39:46,430 --> 00:39:49,550
前額皮質是很脆弱的
The prefrontal cortex is especially vulnerable.

700
00:39:49,560 --> 00:39:53,120
如果父母使勁地搖晃嬰兒
If you're an infant and your parent vigorously shakes you

701
00:39:52,290 --> 00:39:55,500
{\an8}艾德里安·雷恩教授  神經科學家  南加州大學

702
00:39:53,120 --> 00:39:55,850
導致嬰兒的頭顱前后晃動
and your head rocks backwards and forwards,

703
00:39:55,860 --> 00:39:58,180
那么顱骨內的大腦
the brain inside the skull

704
00:39:58,180 --> 00:40:00,680
假設這是顱骨而這是大腦
if this is the skull and this is the brain

705
00:40:00,700 --> 00:40:04,150
大腦會撞上顱骨的硬部
it will bang on the bony part of the skull

706
00:40:04,160 --> 00:40:07,810
而大腦的前面這部分會受損
and this frontal part of the brain here will get damage

707
00:40:07,810 --> 00:40:11,120
因為它在顱骨內前后晃動
as it's rocked backwards and forwards inside the skull.

708
00:40:14,210 --> 00:40:17,790
1999年殘忍殺害佩頓·塔特希爾的
Donta Page who had brutally murdered Peyton Tuthill

709
00:40:17,790 --> 00:40:21,590
唐塔·佩奇就是個典型
in 1999 is a textbook example.

710
00:40:22,310 --> 00:40:25,030
他在嬰兒時代總是被母親劇烈搖晃
As a baby, he was frequently shaken by his mother

711
00:40:25,080 --> 00:40:28,280
他大一些后時虐待變得更嚴重
and as he got older, the abuse got worse.

712
00:40:28,280 --> 00:40:30,440
你在干什么  過來
What are you doing? Come here!

713
00:40:30,920 --> 00:40:33,700
他母親開始拿東西打他
His mother began to use objects to hit him with,

714
00:40:33,700 --> 00:40:36,850
包括用電器延長線
including, um, electrical extension cords,

715
00:40:34,310 --> 00:40:38,350
{\an8}吉姆·卡斯爾  唐塔·佩奇的律師

716
00:40:37,230 --> 00:40:39,110
還有鞋子  什么順手就用什么
shoes, whatever was handy.

717
00:40:39,130 --> 00:40:42,480
對他的毆打不是偶爾為之
These were not once-a-year beatings,

718
00:40:42,490 --> 00:40:45,260
他母親基本上
they were beatings that occurred

719
00:40:45,260 --> 00:40:48,360
每天都打他
almost...daily.

720
00:40:52,620 --> 00:40:55,590
這種身體上的虐待
This physical abuse could help explain

721
00:40:55,590 --> 00:40:58,970
有可能解釋唐塔前額皮質的失常
the malfunctioning of Donta's prefrontal cortex.

722
00:40:59,570 --> 00:41:02,320
我比較贊同
I would tend to be persuaded by the notion

723
00:41:02,320 --> 00:41:06,700
早期身體的虐待
that the early physical abuse, amongst other things...

724
00:41:07,330 --> 00:41:11,400
比起其它可能導致大腦受損的因素
..Could likely have led to the brain damage which could likely

725
00:41:11,400 --> 00:41:15,840
更有可能導致他的這種暴力行為
have led to him committing this violent act.

726
00:41:18,180 --> 00:41:21,710
隨著證據越來越多
As the evidence mounted, it seemed clear that killers

727
00:41:21,710 --> 00:41:25,420
顯然殺人犯是他們暴力成長環境的產物
were largely being created by their violent upbringing.

728
00:41:32,070 --> 00:41:35,720
但童年不幸的人中
But only a small proportion of those who have terrible childhoods

729
00:41:35,720 --> 00:41:37,630
只有一小部分變成了殺人犯
grow up to become murderers.

730
00:41:37,950 --> 00:41:40,520
如今通過研究雙胞胎和被收養的兒童
Now, studies with twins and adopted children

731
00:41:40,520 --> 00:41:45,240
人們發現暴力可能是遺傳的
had already suggested there is a hereditary component to violence.

732
00:41:45,240 --> 00:41:49,880
是否有某些基因讓人天生就傾向于謀殺呢
Could it be that there are genes that predispose us to murder?

733
00:41:54,150 --> 00:41:58,150
1993年對一個荷蘭家族的研究獲得了突破
The breakthrough came in 1993 with a family in Holland

734
00:41:58,150 --> 00:42:01,060
這個家族里所有的男子都有暴力記錄
where all the men had a history of violence.

735
00:42:01,650 --> 00:42:04,160
長達十五年艱辛的研究揭示
15 years of painstaking research

736
00:42:04,170 --> 00:42:07,510
他們全都缺乏某種基因
revealed that they all lacked the same gene.

737
00:42:07,920 --> 00:42:11,680
{\an8}《地平線:善惡溯源》（2011年）

738
00:42:09,800 --> 00:42:12,460
他們缺乏一種基因
There was one gene that was missing and...

739
00:42:12,460 --> 00:42:15,790
{\an8}吉姆·法隆教授  神經學家  加利福尼亞大學歐文分校

740
00:42:12,460 --> 00:42:16,050
而所有的這些人都很暴力
in the men and all these men were violent...

741
00:42:17,940 --> 00:42:19,390
因此這支持了
..So that kind of supported the idea that

742
00:42:19,390 --> 00:42:22,280
有種基因控制某種行為的想法
one gene really controlled a behaviour.

743
00:42:26,430 --> 00:42:30,960
而這種基因產生名為單胺氧化酶A的酶
This gene produces an enzyme called MAOA.

744
00:42:31,780 --> 00:42:34,280
這種酶調節與控制沖動相關的
It regulates the levels of neurotransmitters

745
00:42:34,290 --> 00:42:36,440
神經遞質水平
involved in impulse control.

746
00:42:37,150 --> 00:42:40,960
如果你缺乏單胺氧化酶A基因
It turns out that if you lack the MAOA gene

747
00:42:40,960 --> 00:42:44,760
或你擁有的是所謂"低活性變體"
or have what is known as the "Low activity variant",

748
00:42:44,760 --> 00:42:47,570
你就天生暴力
you are predisposed to violence.

749
00:42:48,150 --> 00:42:51,410
而這一變體被稱作斗士基因
This variant became known as the warrior gene.

750
00:42:54,620 --> 00:42:57,140
不久后人們發現了
And soon after, a gene was discovered

751
00:42:57,150 --> 00:42:59,910
一種控制血清素水平的基因
that controls the levels of serotonin.

752
00:43:00,460 --> 00:43:01,940
就是這種神經遞質
This was the neurotransmitter

753
00:43:01,940 --> 00:43:04,490
導致了猴子  海軍陸戰隊員
linked to violent behaviour in monkeys,

754
00:43:04,490 --> 00:43:08,070
和迪翁·桑德斯這類罪犯的暴力行為
marines and criminals, like Deion Sanders,

755
00:43:08,880 --> 00:43:10,840
但擁有斗士基因
but is having the warrior gene

756
00:43:10,850 --> 00:43:14,980
或是低血清素基因就會讓你成為殺人犯嗎
or the gene for low serotonin enough to make you a killer?

757
00:43:16,940 --> 00:43:18,570
對吉姆·法隆教授來說
For Professor Jim Fallon,

758
00:43:18,570 --> 00:43:22,090
這可以是個很私人的問題
this question was about to become deeply personal.

759
00:43:22,670 --> 00:43:26,340
吉姆研究殺人犯大腦異常
Jim had been researching the brain abnormalities of murderers

760
00:43:26,340 --> 00:43:28,700
長達十一年之久  然后有天
for 11 years, when, one day,

761
00:43:28,710 --> 00:43:30,970
他與母親閑談時
a casual conversation with his mother

762
00:43:30,970 --> 00:43:34,230
發現自己家族有殺人史
revealed a history of murder in his own family.

763
00:43:35,510 --> 00:43:39,560
我們在聊這個話題還有各種大腦時
As we were discussing this, and different brains,

764
00:43:39,620 --> 00:43:43,230
我對他說  你該查查自己的家族史
I said to him, "You should look into your own history."

765
00:43:43,760 --> 00:43:45,090
我是說這真的很嚇人
I mean, it was really pretty startling,

766
00:43:45,090 --> 00:43:46,370
但我知道這是事實
but, you know, I knew it was true

767
00:43:46,370 --> 00:43:48,330
因為她從不撒謊
because she doesn't make things up.

768
00:43:48,340 --> 00:43:51,140
那家族里有不少殺人犯
Yeah, there were quite a few murderers in that family.

769
00:43:53,490 --> 00:43:58,100
家族里至少十六個人是殺人犯
At least 16 murderers in the one line.

770
00:44:00,500 --> 00:44:04,060
得知此事吉姆做了一個大膽的決定
Hearing this, Jim took the bold decision to run a check

771
00:44:04,070 --> 00:44:05,760
他要查一查整個家族
on the entire family

772
00:44:06,110 --> 00:44:09,520
尋找與心理變態行為相關的基因
for the genes linked to violent psychopathic behaviour.

773
00:44:11,810 --> 00:44:13,530
結果出來了
Back came the results.

774
00:44:14,300 --> 00:44:16,860
我家人都有各種相關基因
Everybody had a mix of things in our family.

775
00:44:16,870 --> 00:44:21,570
看上去大家各有各的
It looked like an average sort of mix of these different genes

776
00:44:21,570 --> 00:44:24,670
與侵略性和其它行為相關的基因
that have to do with aggression and all sorts of behaviours,

777
00:44:24,810 --> 00:44:27,050
然而有一個人
except now and again there was this one

778
00:44:27,050 --> 00:44:29,910
擁有所有危險基因
that showed all of these high-risk genes

779
00:44:29,910 --> 00:44:31,130
而那個人是我
and it was mine.

780
00:44:32,310 --> 00:44:36,540
基因上比我危險性小得多的人
People with far less dangerous genetics become killers

781
00:44:36,540 --> 00:44:38,820
變成了殺人犯和心理變態者
and are psychopaths than what I had, you know.

782
00:44:38,820 --> 00:44:40,350
而我擁有幾乎所有這些基因
I had, like, almost all of them.

783
00:44:40,350 --> 00:44:41,700
直到
It was right up...

784
00:44:42,260 --> 00:44:44,370
但他家人的反應
But the reaction from his family

785
00:44:44,420 --> 00:44:46,830
讓他更緊張
was to unsettle him even further.

786
00:44:48,770 --> 00:44:50,540
我一直覺得他有些不對勁
I knew there was always something off.

787
00:44:51,320 --> 00:44:55,390
{\an8}兒子  詹姆斯·法隆

788
00:44:51,330 --> 00:44:54,380
現在弄清楚了
It makes more sense now that

789
00:44:54,860 --> 00:44:55,990
很顯然
it's clear that

790
00:44:55,990 --> 00:44:58,710
他的確擁有心理變態的大腦和基因
he does have the brain and genetics of a psychopath.

791
00:44:59,380 --> 00:45:01,620
現在都說得通了
It all falls into place, as it were.

792
00:45:02,640 --> 00:45:03,870
那些是
Those are...

793
00:45:04,600 --> 00:45:06,780
我有些性格或特質
I have characteristics or traits,

794
00:45:06,780 --> 00:45:10,050
與心理變態類似
some of which are, you know, that a psychopath...yeah.'

795
00:45:10,800 --> 00:45:12,870
我可以不去姨母的葬禮
I could blow off an aunt's funeral

796
00:45:13,050 --> 00:45:14,720
而去參加當天舉行的派對
if I thought there was a party that day

797
00:45:14,930 --> 00:45:18,560
我可以就那么一走了之  而那是不對的
I would just take off and that's not right.

798
00:45:19,220 --> 00:45:21,810
問題在于我明白但我不在乎
The thing is I know that now but I still don't care

799
00:45:22,590 --> 00:45:27,450
我知道有什么不對  但我不在乎
and so I know something's wrong, but I still don't care.

800
00:45:29,940 --> 00:45:31,730
而且
And, er, you know...

801
00:45:31,740 --> 00:45:32,870
我不知道還該怎么說
I don't know how else to put that.

802
00:45:32,870 --> 00:45:35,440
就好像你覺得  "那樣不對
It's just you are in a position where, "Oh, that's not right

803
00:45:35,440 --> 00:45:38,470
我才不在乎呢"  就是這樣
"And I don't give a shit," And that's the truth.

804
00:45:39,830 --> 00:45:43,420
但吉姆不是殺人犯  他是受尊敬的教授
But Jim isn't a murderer, he's a respected professor.

805
00:45:43,980 --> 00:45:48,590
事實上百分之三十的男性都有斗士基因
It turns out that about 30% of men have the warrior gene

806
00:45:48,790 --> 00:45:51,900
而百分之十六有低血清素基因
and 16% have the low serotonin gene

807
00:45:52,210 --> 00:45:55,220
顯然大部分都不是殺人犯
and clearly most of them are not killers.

808
00:45:56,310 --> 00:45:59,830
為什么不是所有有殺手基因的人都犯案
So why isn't everyone with killer genes a murderer?

809
00:46:01,560 --> 00:46:04,530
答案是基因是否被激活
The answer is that whether the genes are triggered or not

810
00:46:04,530 --> 00:46:07,890
取決于你的童年經歷
will depend on what happens in your childhood.

811
00:46:09,940 --> 00:46:11,800
如果你有所謂的高危基因
If you have the so-called high risk form of the gene

812
00:46:11,800 --> 00:46:14,760
而你早年受到虐待
and you're abused early on in life,

813
00:46:14,760 --> 00:46:17,570
你有更高幾率走上犯罪的道路
your chances of spending a life of crime are much higher.

814
00:46:17,660 --> 00:46:20,020
而如果你有高危基因
If you have the gene, the high risk gene,

815
00:46:20,030 --> 00:46:23,320
但沒受過虐待那么就沒什么危險
but you weren't abused then there really wasn't much risk,'

816
00:46:23,380 --> 00:46:26,060
因此單基因本身  或者其變體
so just the gene by itself, the variant,

817
00:46:26,060 --> 00:46:28,350
不會對行為產生重要影響
doesn't really dramatically affect behaviour,

818
00:46:28,350 --> 00:46:31,390
但在特定環境下  會有巨大影響
but under certain environmental conditions, a big difference,

819
00:46:31,390 --> 00:46:34,380
而這是一項重要發現
and that was a very profound finding.

820
00:46:36,790 --> 00:46:40,170
那吉姆所處環境的什么因素
So what was it about Jim's environment that cancelled out

821
00:46:40,170 --> 00:46:42,140
導致他的不幸基因失效了呢
his unlucky genes?

822
00:46:45,410 --> 00:46:48,900
因為我擁有非常美好的童年
It turns out that I had an unbelievably wonderful childhood.

823
00:46:52,020 --> 00:46:54,900
如果我回頭看錄像和照片
I'd go back and look at old movies and old pictures

824
00:46:54,900 --> 00:46:57,070
我就忍不住微笑并無比快樂
and I'm smiling and I'm as happy as a lark

825
00:46:57,070 --> 00:47:00,110
而我的人生一直保持著這種快樂
and you can see it all the way through my life.

826
00:47:01,400 --> 00:47:03,760
因此有很大幾率抵消掉
You know, there's a good chance that that offset

827
00:47:03,940 --> 00:47:05,160
這些基因要素
all these genetic factors,

828
00:47:05,160 --> 00:47:06,910
隨著大腦發育
the brain development and everything

829
00:47:07,340 --> 00:47:09,210
危機就被清除了
and it washed that away.

830
00:47:15,280 --> 00:47:18,770
因此暴力傾向的基因與受虐待的童年
So it seems that a genetic tendency towards violence

831
00:47:18,770 --> 00:47:23,570
兩者合在一起會創造殺人犯
together with an abusive childhood are a killer combination.

832
00:47:23,970 --> 00:47:26,840
殺人犯既是天生的也是后天形成的
Murderers are both born and made.

833
00:47:28,500 --> 00:47:31,060
我們現在更深入地了解
We now have a far more sophisticated understanding

834
00:47:31,060 --> 00:47:35,790
社會與生物因素之間復雜的關系
of the complex interactions between the social and the biological factors

835
00:47:35,790 --> 00:47:38,410
正是這二者相結合  讓人傾向于殺人
that predispose people to murder.

836
00:47:39,060 --> 00:47:41,030
那我們該如何運用這種知識呢
But what can we do with that knowledge?

837
00:47:41,130 --> 00:47:45,410
我們是否可以降低殺人犯再犯罪的風險
Can we use it to reduce the risk that murderers will reoffend

838
00:47:45,420 --> 00:47:49,030
或是預防他們殺人
or perhaps even prevent them from killing in the first place?

839
00:47:53,670 --> 00:47:55,700
早在二十世紀五十年代
As far back as the 1950s,

840
00:47:55,700 --> 00:47:58,220
我們就可以利用藥品
we had the ability to use drugs

841
00:47:58,220 --> 00:48:01,280
來治療潛在殺人犯
to treat some types of potential murderer

842
00:48:01,280 --> 00:48:03,910
降低他們犯案的風險
and reduce the chances of them killing.

843
00:48:04,330 --> 00:48:06,130
特別是精神分裂癥
Schizophrenia, in particular,

844
00:48:06,130 --> 00:48:09,900
可以通過抗精神病藥物有效控制病情
can be successfully treated with anti-psychotic medication.

845
00:48:10,540 --> 00:48:14,880
科迪·米滕在產生幻覺時殺了他的母親
Cody Mitten had killed his mother while suffering from delusions

846
00:48:14,880 --> 00:48:17,000
他被判無期徒刑
and he was sentenced to life in prison.

847
00:48:17,460 --> 00:48:20,240
現在回頭來看他當時肯定患有精神病
Cody was obviously psychotic because when you went back

848
00:48:20,240 --> 00:48:23,060
回想起來  事發兩周前
and looked back at the past, two weeks prior to the incident,

849
00:48:23,060 --> 00:48:25,830
他展現出典型精神病癥狀
he started to have definite psychotic symptoms,

850
00:48:24,630 --> 00:48:28,750
{\an8}安東尼·亨佩爾醫生  司法精神病學家

851
00:48:25,830 --> 00:48:27,480
他相信
believing that...

852
00:48:27,550 --> 00:48:29,530
幻聽和幻像
auditory and visual hallucinations

853
00:48:29,530 --> 00:48:31,260
并伴有幻覺
along with delusions.

854
00:48:31,260 --> 00:48:33,990
他相信電視機傳來聲音
He believed that voices were coming out of the TV

855
00:48:33,990 --> 00:48:35,090
讓他去傷害別人
telling him to hurt

856
00:48:35,090 --> 00:48:39,250
他相信有人要害他
and he believed that others were trying to hurt him.

857
00:48:40,250 --> 00:48:40,910
在獄中
While in prison,

858
00:48:40,910 --> 00:48:44,250
他因精神分裂癥接受治療
he has been receiving treatment for his schizophrenia

859
00:48:44,530 --> 00:48:46,570
隨著病癥的好轉
and as his symptoms have receded,

860
00:48:46,570 --> 00:48:49,580
他開始陷入悔恨
the enormity of what he did has sunk in.

861
00:48:50,340 --> 00:48:52,080
老天
Oh, man, erm...

862
00:49:00,210 --> 00:49:02,450
我多么希望一切都沒發生
Oh, I just wish everything was the way it used to be,

863
00:49:02,450 --> 00:49:03,900
但不可能
but it's not, no.

864
00:49:12,360 --> 00:49:14,990
因病情得到控制
While his illness is being kept at bay,

865
00:49:14,990 --> 00:49:17,220
科迪不太可能再殺人了
Cody is unlikely to kill again.

866
00:49:17,650 --> 00:49:20,670
但也許他母親的死
But perhaps his mother's murder could have been avoided

867
00:49:20,670 --> 00:49:22,080
本可以避免
in the first place.

868
00:49:22,510 --> 00:49:24,500
我可以從他的眼神看出來
I could see it in his eyes,

869
00:49:24,500 --> 00:49:28,110
我認為科迪該去見醫生
I felt like Cody needed to go to the doctor

870
00:49:28,110 --> 00:49:30,290
我們當天就該帶他去
and we needed to take him today.

871
00:49:31,020 --> 00:49:33,430
科迪的母親帶他去了醫院
Cody's mother took him to the hospital,

872
00:49:33,440 --> 00:49:35,870
但可悲的是他被送回家了
but tragically they sent him home.

873
00:49:37,240 --> 00:49:42,230
他們說一切正常  而我說  不可能
They said everything was normal and I said, "That can't be."

874
00:49:45,460 --> 00:49:48,880
當晚他殺了母親及她的男友拉里
That night, he killed his mother and her boyfriend Larry.

875
00:49:50,190 --> 00:49:52,960
如果醫生診斷出精神分裂
Had the doctors detected his schizophrenia

876
00:49:52,960 --> 00:49:54,980
讓他留院治療
and kept him in hospital for treatment,

877
00:49:54,980 --> 00:49:57,370
他們本可以活著的
they might still be alive today.

878
00:50:06,310 --> 00:50:08,140
大腦中化學成分
The discovery that brain chemistry

879
00:50:08,140 --> 00:50:10,100
與某些兇殺相關的這一發現
was involved in certain murders

880
00:50:10,100 --> 00:50:12,810
也促進了藥物的研發
has also led to the development of drugs

881
00:50:12,810 --> 00:50:15,500
來治療這種化學物質不平衡
to treat these chemical imbalances.

882
00:50:16,730 --> 00:50:18,200
該怎么形容
How do you admit that you

883
00:50:17,120 --> 00:50:21,190
{\an8}《殺人者心理：殺手的性》（2001年）

884
00:50:19,450 --> 00:50:22,450
自己在殺人時產生的性刺激
are sexually stimulated by killing someone?

885
00:50:24,560 --> 00:50:27,800
藥物治療似乎
In particular, drug treatment appears to be effective

886
00:50:28,360 --> 00:50:31,560
在與睪丸素相關的犯罪方面特別有效
when testosterone is implicated in the crime.

887
00:50:32,780 --> 00:50:37,000
就好像我體內有只怪物
It's, er, it was like a monster inside me.

888
00:50:41,700 --> 00:50:45,940
很想讓人就這樣隨它去了
It's so tempting just to give into it.

889
00:50:48,340 --> 00:50:51,790
邁克爾·羅斯在二十世紀八十年代早期
Michael Ross had abnormally high levels of testosterone

890
00:50:51,790 --> 00:50:55,490
殺掉八名女性時體內的睪丸素水平異常的高
when he killed eight women in the early 1980s.

891
00:50:57,850 --> 00:51:01,670
在美國  像邁克爾這樣的男性罪犯
In America, male offenders like Michael are given drugs

892
00:51:01,670 --> 00:51:04,110
會用藥物抑制其睪丸素水平
to lower their testosterone levels.

893
00:51:04,570 --> 00:51:07,340
這就是所謂化學閹割
It's known as chemical castration.

894
00:51:08,960 --> 00:51:13,750
邁克爾的睪丸素降為大部分男性的百分之五
Michael's testosterone levels fell to 5% of that of most men.

895
00:51:14,000 --> 00:51:15,820
為科學期刊撰文時
Writing for a scientific journal,

896
00:51:15,820 --> 00:51:18,560
他如下描述治療的效用
he described the effect of the treatment.

897
00:51:21,290 --> 00:51:25,770
我那些念想  欲望和幻想開始消失
My obsessive thoughts and urges and fantasies began to diminish.

898
00:51:26,420 --> 00:51:28,260
但問題還在
The problem is still there.

899
00:51:28,670 --> 00:51:30,390
現在比較好應付了
It's easier to deal with

900
00:51:30,390 --> 00:51:32,600
因為那種沖動不再總是涌現了
because it isn't always in the foreground,

901
00:51:32,600 --> 00:51:34,780
它不再打擾到我的日常生活
Intruding on my everyday life.

902
00:51:36,270 --> 00:51:38,820
但體內的怪物還在
The monster within is still present

903
00:51:39,110 --> 00:51:41,890
然而藥物導致他陽痿
But the medication has rendered him impotent.

904
00:51:42,480 --> 00:51:46,140
如果我十五年前
Had I begun receiving just a 1cc injection

905
00:51:46,140 --> 00:51:48,490
每月就注射一毫升的藥
once a month 15 years ago,

906
00:51:49,060 --> 00:51:51,900
那八名婦女就能幸免于難
eight women would be alive today.

907
00:51:56,180 --> 00:51:58,290
對暴力性侵犯者的研究
Studies of violent sex offenders

908
00:51:58,290 --> 00:52:00,510
表明化學閹割
have shown that chemical castration

909
00:52:00,510 --> 00:52:04,010
將再犯的比例降低至百分之五
cuts reoffending rates to below 5%.

910
00:52:05,770 --> 00:52:07,740
除了藥物干預
As well as pharmaceutical interventions,

911
00:52:07,740 --> 00:52:10,660
科學家們還使用心理治療
scientists also use psychological therapies

912
00:52:10,660 --> 00:52:13,300
來嘗試治療殺人犯
to try and rehabilitate murderers.

913
00:52:13,320 --> 00:52:17,950
這的確讓許多罪犯減少了暴力行為
Now, it certainly reduces violent behaviour in many offenders,

914
00:52:18,000 --> 00:52:21,250
但對精神變態的治療卻讓人警惕
but psychopaths provide a cautionary tale.

915
00:52:22,590 --> 00:52:27,750
{\an8}橡樹嶺醫院  佩內坦吉申  安大略省

916
00:52:23,930 --> 00:52:27,490
二十世紀七十年代加拿大一群心理學家
In the 1970s, a group of psychologists in Canada

917
00:52:27,490 --> 00:52:30,570
正在治療精神變態者
were using therapy to treat psychopaths.

918
00:52:31,930 --> 00:52:35,630
當我1975年到醫院時
When I arrived at this hospital in 1975,

919
00:52:33,690 --> 00:52:37,190
{\an8}《殺人者心理：瘋狂的面具》（2001年）

920
00:52:35,630 --> 00:52:37,990
醫院當時很為
the pride of the hospital at that time

921
00:52:37,990 --> 00:52:40,170
治療精神變態的這一項目而驕傲
was this programme for psychopaths

922
00:52:40,170 --> 00:52:43,510
當時在橡樹嶺的四間病房里開展了這一項目
that was run on four wards of Oakridge.

923
00:52:44,180 --> 00:52:47,920
當時所有人都認為
And it was considered by everyone at the time

924
00:52:47,920 --> 00:52:50,850
這是一個了不起的項目
to be an excellent, excellent programme

925
00:52:48,230 --> 00:52:52,490
{\an8}瑪麗安·賴斯  心理學家

926
00:52:50,860 --> 00:52:54,080
并認為這個項目對精神變態者特別有益
that would be especially beneficial for psychopaths.

927
00:52:55,580 --> 00:52:58,940
大衛·克魯格是其中一名項目治療對象
David Krueger was one of the psychopaths on the programme.

928
00:53:05,660 --> 00:53:09,060
大家認為克魯格明顯好轉
Krueger himself was deemed greatly improved.

929
00:53:10,160 --> 00:53:13,960
三十年的精神病院治療上限后
After over 30 years in a maximum security mental hospital,

930
00:53:13,960 --> 00:53:17,560
他被送去了布洛克維爾安保較松的機構
he was sent away to a less secure institution at Brockville.

931
00:53:21,200 --> 00:53:24,330
瑪麗安·賴斯和同事跟進了受治病人
Marnie Rice and her colleagues followed up treated patients

932
00:53:24,330 --> 00:53:26,990
來判斷治療項目是否成功
to check on the treatment programme's success...

933
00:53:28,130 --> 00:53:30,220
但當她比較了
..But when she compared re-offence rates

934
00:53:30,220 --> 00:53:32,330
被治療的心理變態者
of psychopaths who had been treated

935
00:53:32,330 --> 00:53:33,860
與監獄收押過
with psychopaths from prison

936
00:53:33,860 --> 00:53:35,970
沒受過任何治療的心理變態者的再犯率后
who had received no treatment at all,

937
00:53:36,530 --> 00:53:38,120
大家大吃一驚
there was a surprise.

938
00:53:41,700 --> 00:53:45,520
我們看了結果發現
When we looked at the results and what we saw was

939
00:53:45,520 --> 00:53:49,630
項目事實上讓心理變態者病情更重
the programme actually made the psychopaths worse,

940
00:53:49,640 --> 00:53:50,790
我們震驚了
we were astounded.

941
00:53:50,800 --> 00:53:52,670
我是說  我當時看著數據
I mean, I looked at these data

942
00:53:52,670 --> 00:53:55,770
就想  肯定哪里搞錯了
and I thought, "There's got to be a mistake here."

943
00:53:55,770 --> 00:54:00,020
我們又重新檢查了好幾次
You know, we went back and we checked and checked and checked

944
00:54:00,020 --> 00:54:03,340
確定結果是真實的
and sure enough, the effect was real.

945
00:54:03,340 --> 00:54:05,500
毫無疑問
It was absolutely the case

946
00:54:05,500 --> 00:54:08,830
項目讓心理變態者病情加重
that the programme made the psychopaths worse.

947
00:54:08,330 --> 00:54:11,840
{\an8}不要摘花

948
00:54:10,610 --> 00:54:13,650
許多心理變態者將治療項目
Many psychopaths have described the therapy programmes

949
00:54:13,650 --> 00:54:17,060
比喻成完成他們磨煉技巧的課業
as finishing schools where they honed their skills.

950
00:54:17,220 --> 00:54:19,700
我確實學會了更好地操縱別人
I did learn how to manipulate better...

951
00:54:23,270 --> 00:54:26,290
我學會了如何控制
..I did learn how to get control

952
00:54:27,050 --> 00:54:29,960
自己情緒的表露
of expressing my feelings

953
00:54:29,960 --> 00:54:32,860
控制得更好了
inappropriately...better...

954
00:54:33,930 --> 00:54:37,390
我學會了更好地隱藏
and keep the more outrageous feelings

955
00:54:37,400 --> 00:54:40,490
我的憤怒
under wraps...better.

956
00:54:43,230 --> 00:54:46,270
三十五年來的第一天
On his first day pass in 35 years,

957
00:54:46,280 --> 00:54:50,140
大衛·克魯格殘忍地殺害了獄友
David Krueger brutally murdered a fellow inmate.

958
00:55:00,560 --> 00:55:01,500
目前看來
For the time being,

959
00:55:01,500 --> 00:55:03,770
我們無法治愈精神變態者
it seems we cannot treat the psychopaths'

960
00:55:03,770 --> 00:55:06,030
這種缺乏同理心的本性
underlying lack of empathy.

961
00:55:12,040 --> 00:55:14,720
科學家們現在著重使用一些療法
Scientists are now focusing on using therapy

962
00:55:14,720 --> 00:55:18,510
來嘗試從一開始阻止兇手的產生
to try and prevent murderers being created in the first place.

963
00:55:19,530 --> 00:55:22,440
他們非常清楚殺人行為產生的原因
They know enough about the causes of murderous behaviour

964
00:55:22,450 --> 00:55:24,850
可以發現早期表征
to spot early warning signs,

965
00:55:24,860 --> 00:55:28,020
并可以在事情不可挽回前介入
and attempt to intervene before it's too late.

966
00:55:29,620 --> 00:55:31,620
同時大家希望治療法可以消除
The hope is that therapy will undo

967
00:55:31,620 --> 00:55:34,210
一些因童年虐待而產生的
some of the psychological damage being caused

968
00:55:34,210 --> 00:55:35,910
心理創傷
by an abusive childhood

969
00:55:35,910 --> 00:55:39,080
從而防止兒童成長為殺人犯
and prevent children from turning into killers.

970
00:55:43,020 --> 00:55:46,290
比如賈斯丁和其哥哥科迪這樣的兒童
Children, like Justin and his brother Cody,

971
00:55:46,300 --> 00:55:49,520
他們早期在充滿暴力的家庭長大
who spent their first few years in a violent home.

972
00:55:50,320 --> 00:55:53,940
當賈斯丁兩歲時  他的母親被殺
When Justin was only two years old, his mother was murdered.

973
00:55:55,190 --> 00:55:56,290
當時她母親和她的男友
There was a verbal argument

974
00:55:56,290 --> 00:55:58,300
發生了口角
that started between the boyfriend and the mother

975
00:55:56,400 --> 00:56:00,470
{\an8}《殺人者心理：創傷》（2001年）

976
00:55:57,360 --> 00:56:02,670
{\an8}布魯斯·佩里醫生  兒童精神病醫生

977
00:55:58,750 --> 00:56:02,960
口角上升為肢體沖突
and it led to physical confrontation when they were shoving

978
00:56:02,960 --> 00:56:06,350
他們互相推搡然后男友暴怒
and pushing at each other and then the boyfriend got enraged

979
00:56:06,350 --> 00:56:09,830
他開始毆打她  然后她踢他
and started to beat her and she kicked at him

980
00:56:09,830 --> 00:56:13,320
然后他拿起刀捅入了她胸膛
and he picked up a knife and apparently stabbed her in the chest.

981
00:56:13,720 --> 00:56:15,390
小心  科迪
Be careful, Cody.

982
00:56:16,000 --> 00:56:18,050
母親被殺時賈斯丁就在場
Justin was there when his mother was murdered.

983
00:56:18,050 --> 00:56:20,090
他目睹了一切
He's seen everything

984
00:56:20,880 --> 00:56:23,130
他當時真的嚇壞了
and he was real devastated.

985
00:56:22,850 --> 00:56:27,300
{\an8}伯納德·蘭德爾  賈斯丁的祖父

986
00:56:23,130 --> 00:56:26,330
他總是哭
You know, he'd just cry a lot

987
00:56:26,330 --> 00:56:29,460
害怕上樓進自己的房間
and scared to go upstairs to his room,

988
00:56:29,460 --> 00:56:31,150
晚上不敢睡覺
scared to sleep at night.

989
00:56:31,150 --> 00:56:35,910
他必須跟我們睡  他再也不是賈斯丁了
He had to sleep with us, er, he just wasn't Justin again.

990
00:56:35,910 --> 00:56:39,290
他不是個快樂的孩子  完全不是
He wasn't a happy child at all, nothing like that again.

991
00:56:41,240 --> 00:56:42,450
站直了
Stand up straight.

992
00:56:43,120 --> 00:56:45,830
賈斯丁被帶去見布魯斯·佩里醫生
Justin was sent to see Dr Bruce Perry

993
00:56:45,830 --> 00:56:48,270
他治療暴力家庭出身的孩子
who works with children from abusive families.

994
00:56:48,270 --> 00:56:50,420
你比上次來的時候高了
You're taller than you were last time you were here.

995
00:56:51,640 --> 00:56:55,440
{\an8}1999年2月

996
00:56:53,530 --> 00:56:57,620
事情發生后不久我見到了他
I saw him very soon after the event

997
00:56:57,660 --> 00:57:01,600
讓他進了我們的辦公室
and had him come into our office...

998
00:57:02,680 --> 00:57:06,110
只要講到
..And just getting at

999
00:57:06,110 --> 00:57:08,520
甚至提到母親
or even mentioning mother

1000
00:57:08,900 --> 00:57:12,540
就會引發他劇烈的爆發性的行為
resulted in this tremendous, explosive,

1001
00:57:12,880 --> 00:57:15,470
我認為是重演行為
what I would consider, re-enactment behaviour.

1002
00:57:19,590 --> 00:57:20,620
我認為在許多方面
And I think in many ways,

1003
00:57:20,620 --> 00:57:23,950
他的行為并不一定在重演謀殺
his behaviours were not necessarily re-enactment of the murder,

1004
00:57:23,950 --> 00:57:25,400
但我認為那些是重演
but they were re-enactment, I think,

1005
00:57:25,400 --> 00:57:29,820
他曾經歷的家庭暴力
of the kinds of domestic violence that he had seen prior to that.

1006
00:57:33,100 --> 00:57:34,580
賈斯丁是幸運的
Luckily for Justin,

1007
00:57:34,580 --> 00:57:38,020
他得到幫助得以平復創傷
he's receiving the help he needs to reverse the damage.

1008
00:57:38,510 --> 00:57:41,780
在接受佩里醫生治療的十八個月間
In the 18 months he's been attending Dr Perry's clinic,

1009
00:57:42,160 --> 00:57:43,920
他取得了巨大的進步
he's made great progress.

1010
00:57:45,410 --> 00:57:46,770
他又回歸正常生活了
Back on track.

1011
00:57:46,780 --> 00:57:48,590
治療是一個緩慢的過程
It's going to be a slow process

1012
00:57:48,600 --> 00:57:53,030
但他的未來將是美好的  我確定
but his future is going to be real bright, I can see that.

1013
00:58:07,080 --> 00:58:09,840
我們對被捕兇手的大腦
We know a huge amount about what happens inside the minds

1014
00:58:09,850 --> 00:58:12,680
以及他們大腦的運作有豐富的知識
and brains of murderers that have been caught,

1015
00:58:12,780 --> 00:58:14,990
但我們尚不能預測
but we are still some way off being able to predict

1016
00:58:14,990 --> 00:58:16,480
誰會變成殺人犯
who will become a murderer.

1017
00:58:16,480 --> 00:58:18,920
誘因太多了
There are far too many factors involved.

1018
00:58:19,170 --> 00:58:22,940
但有一點可以確認  接下來我們在將會繼續
One thing, however, is certain, we will continue to be fascinated

1019
00:58:22,940 --> 00:58:27,380
被他們可怕的罪行所吸引并深受震撼
and appalled by their terrible crimes for many years to come.

