1
00:00:34,930 --> 00:00:39,930
艾洛斯精神病院是密西根州
威斯特蘭市最大的精神病院

2
00:00:39,950 --> 00:00:45,930
從1832年最初的一棟發展為78棟大樓，
佔地面積達110萬坪

3
00:00:45,980 --> 00:00:52,000
謠傳精神病院的主治醫生格萊斯
給病人施行殘忍的醫學試驗治療

4
00:00:52,050 --> 00:00:59,400
據傳由於發生嚴重火災，醫院於1982年關閉
如今只剩下四棟大樓

5
00:01:06,210 --> 00:01:07,760
早安，醫生
Good morning, Doctor.

6
00:01:10,010 --> 00:01:12,470
我不會再害怕了
I'm not afraid anymore.

7
00:01:12,510 --> 00:01:14,390
我很好
I'm good.

8
00:01:14,430 --> 00:01:15,850
它起作用了
It worked.

9
00:01:17,600 --> 00:01:21,020
我感覺比昨天好多了
I feel so much better
than even yesterday.

10
00:01:21,060 --> 00:01:23,360
睡得更好了，身體感覺好多了
Sleeping better and
feeling a lot better.

11
00:01:25,650 --> 00:01:30,650
再次回我家的感覺一定很棒
It will be great to join
up with my family again.

12
00:01:30,700 --> 00:01:32,910
下週就是我女兒的生日
Next week's my daughter's birthday.

13
00:01:32,950 --> 00:01:34,950
回家正是時候
It would be quite a great homecoming.

14
00:01:34,990 --> 00:01:37,540
我想對你說
格萊斯醫生我感覺好多了
I just want to say, Dr. Greiss,
that I'm feeling a lot better

15
00:01:37,580 --> 00:01:39,710
我今天比昨天好多了
today than I was yesterday,
and yesterday I was feeling

16
00:01:39,750 --> 00:01:42,920
昨天比之前也好很多
我身體以後會好起來的
better than before that and
tomorrow I'm gonna feel better.

17
00:01:42,960 --> 00:01:46,920
醫生，求你！你已經幫到我了，
格萊斯醫生，我現在沒事了！
Doctor, please! You already helped me,
Dr. Greiss, I'm fine!

18
00:01:59,310 --> 00:02:01,060
各路媒體報導
Multiple sources reporting

19
00:02:01,100 --> 00:02:03,480
艾洛斯精神病院發生火災，
造成了嚴重的...
that a fire has broken out
at Eloise causing significant...

20
00:02:03,520 --> 00:02:05,440
據報導目擊者在昨晚10點後
Witnesses reported seeing

21
00:02:05,480 --> 00:02:07,690
看見煙霧並聽到叫喊聲
smoke and hearing screams
a little after 10:00 o'clock

22
00:02:07,730 --> 00:02:09,820
消防隊員隨即趕到火災現場...
last night as firefighters
rushed to the scene...

23
00:02:09,860 --> 00:02:11,150
報導稱火災
Reportedly broke out

24
00:02:11,190 --> 00:02:13,200
發生時間為昨晚十點之後
just after 10:00 PM last night.

25
00:02:13,240 --> 00:02:15,820
火災發生原因至今未知，
但是案件調查人員..
The cause of the fire is not
yet known but investigators

26
00:02:15,870 --> 00:02:17,660
認為是有人蓄意縱火...
believe it was intentional...

27
00:02:17,700 --> 00:02:18,990
多人傷亡，在他們之中
Multiple casualties, among them,

28
00:02:19,040 --> 00:02:20,950
格萊斯醫生
Dr. H. H. Greiss,

29
00:02:21,000 --> 00:02:23,460
艾洛斯精神病院主治醫生，
他以爭議性極大的..
Chief physician at Eloise
known for his controversial

30
00:02:23,500 --> 00:02:25,880
殘酷的醫學療法..
and brutal therapies.

31
00:02:25,920 --> 00:02:27,880
以及兇殘的醫學實驗而聞名
And vicious medical experiments.

32
00:02:27,920 --> 00:02:29,500
據說許多病人
It's also believed that
many patients perished

33
00:02:29,550 --> 00:02:31,010
也在這場大火中喪生...
in the fire as well...

34
00:02:31,050 --> 00:02:32,840
消防人員衝到
Firefighters rushed

35
00:02:32,880 --> 00:02:35,340
火災現場，但是還是沒能
to the scene but were too late
for many patients and staff

36
00:02:35,390 --> 00:02:37,300
挽救被困在精神病院頂樓的病人
及醫護人員的生命
who were trapped on
the upper floors of Eloise

37
00:02:37,350 --> 00:02:40,390
他們都被認為死在了這場大火中
and are believed to have
died in the blaze.

38
00:02:43,520 --> 00:02:45,190
自從1982年那場火災之後
In the years since its closing

39
00:02:45,230 --> 00:02:46,900
這所精神病院一直未營業
in 1982 after the fire.

40
00:02:46,940 --> 00:02:49,690
無數的當地人
來這個空蕩的大樓裏探險
Countless locals have explored
the vacant buildings

41
00:02:49,730 --> 00:02:52,530
據傳在這裏有時候能聽到怪聲
of Eloise and reported
chilling tales of hearing voices

42
00:02:52,570 --> 00:02:55,950
在某些情況下，還能看到
or screams and in some cases,
seeing apparitions

43
00:02:55,990 --> 00:02:59,080
死去的病人及醫護人員的幽靈
甚至是鬼魂..
or even ghosts
of deceased patients and staff

44
00:02:59,120 --> 00:03:02,290
遊蕩在精神病院空蕩、破舊的走廊
roaming the asylum's empty,
decrepit corridors,

45
00:03:02,330 --> 00:03:04,290
猶如囚犯一般
prisoners still.

46
00:03:04,330 --> 00:03:06,080
據說之前一個病人
One former patient was reported

47
00:03:06,120 --> 00:03:08,920
說這裏的人一直都想逃出去
as saying,
"People tried to escape all the time."

48
00:03:08,960 --> 00:03:12,260
但是一旦你被送進艾洛斯精神病院，
就不能逃出去
"But once you're committed
into Eloise, you can't leave."

49
00:03:12,300 --> 00:03:14,220
你無法離開
"You can never leave."

50
00:03:36,360 --> 00:03:38,780
你好，皮婭
Hello, Pia.

51
00:03:38,820 --> 00:03:40,580
我是弗雷澤警探
My name is Detective Frazer.

52
00:03:40,620 --> 00:03:45,210
如果你不介意的話，我想問你幾個問題
I'd like to ask you a couple
questions, if you don't mind.

53
00:03:45,250 --> 00:03:49,750
兩天前幾個孩子在精神病院
發現了這個男人的屍體
Some kids found the body of
this man at Eloise two days ago.

54
00:03:51,790 --> 00:03:53,960
在你的陳述中，
你曾經提到過一個叫德爾·理查茲的男人
In your statement, you had
mentioned a Dell Richards.

55
00:03:54,000 --> 00:03:55,090
說的是他嗎？
Is that him?

56
00:03:59,130 --> 00:04:01,550
當我們發現了這具屍體後，
決定搜索精神病院
After we discovered the body,
we decided to scour

57
00:04:01,590 --> 00:04:03,890
尋找你的哥哥 斯科特....
the building and look
for your brother, Scott.

58
00:04:08,090 --> 00:04:12,490
和雅各布·馬丁
事先聲明一下...
And uh, Jacob Martin, prior statement.

59
00:04:13,240 --> 00:04:15,160
我們找到了你哥哥的遺體
We did find your brother's remains.

60
00:04:15,200 --> 00:04:18,580
瓦斯爆炸破壞力非常強大，
我們只能通過牙齒記錄
The gas explosion was so intense
that only dental records

61
00:04:18,620 --> 00:04:22,210
來對死者身份作出肯定的判斷
were able to make the positive ID.

62
00:04:22,250 --> 00:04:25,170
但是我們找不到雅各布·馬丁
But we can't find Jacob Martin.

63
00:04:25,210 --> 00:04:26,960
在我調查期間
During the course of my investigation,

64
00:04:27,010 --> 00:04:29,970
我遇到了一些奇怪的事，我希望
I've come across some things that are
very strange, and I'm hoping that

65
00:04:30,010 --> 00:04:33,390
你能幫我理理頭緒
you can help me wrap
my mind around them.

66
00:04:33,430 --> 00:04:39,310
這是一份關於艾洛斯裡病人的檔案
This is an old case file
from a patient at Eloise.

67
00:04:41,060 --> 00:04:45,440
雅各布·馬丁的出生證明和這些
都在這份檔案裏
In it is Jacob Martin's
birth certificate and these.

68
00:04:57,320 --> 00:05:01,070
你能解釋一下這些嗎？皮婭
Can you explain these, Pia?

69
00:05:06,410 --> 00:05:08,210
皮婭？
Pia?

70
00:05:12,000 --> 00:05:13,460
皮婭？
Pia?

71
00:05:15,040 --> 00:05:17,580
片名：療養怨

72
00:05:27,060 --> 00:05:29,730
好了，現在再試試
All right, try again now.

73
00:05:30,980 --> 00:05:33,480
對，就是這個聲音
Yeah, that's the sound.

74
00:05:33,520 --> 00:05:34,570
應該行了，兄弟
Should be good, buddy.

75
00:05:34,610 --> 00:05:36,940
雅各布，有人給你打電話
Jacob, you got a call inside.

76
00:05:41,030 --> 00:05:43,030
嗯，我是雅各布
Yeah, Jacob here.

77
00:05:43,070 --> 00:05:46,240
雅各布，我用了一個禮拜的時間
Jacob, finally, I've been trying

78
00:05:46,290 --> 00:05:48,500
終於聯絡到你了
to reach you for a week.

79
00:05:48,540 --> 00:05:50,620
我是阿倫·戴維斯，你爸爸的律師
It's Arlen Davies, your father's lawyer.

80
00:05:50,670 --> 00:05:53,170
嗯，這些年我都沒和我爸爸說過話
Yeah, well, I haven't spoken
to my father in years.

81
00:05:53,210 --> 00:05:56,210
我知道!
I see, well,

82
00:05:56,250 --> 00:05:59,220
我很不想告訴你
I hate to be the one to tell you

83
00:05:59,260 --> 00:06:00,550
但是你爸爸已經去世了
but your father has passed.

84
00:06:00,590 --> 00:06:02,220
等等，什麼？
Wait, what?

85
00:06:02,260 --> 00:06:04,890
我知道這一定嚇到你了
I realize this must be a shock.

86
00:06:04,930 --> 00:06:06,810
因為你是他僅存的繼承人
Since you are his only surviving heir,

87
00:06:06,850 --> 00:06:09,390
關於財產方面的一些重要細節
there are important details
that need to be discussed

88
00:06:09,430 --> 00:06:11,730
需要討論一下
concerning the estate.

89
00:06:11,770 --> 00:06:15,360
明天下午2點在艾爾伍德墓園舉行葬禮
The funeral's tomorrow
at Elwood Cemetery, 2:00 PM.

90
00:06:15,400 --> 00:06:17,400
- 嗯
- 或許我們可以在那之後談談
Yeah.
Perhaps we can talk afterward.

91
00:06:17,440 --> 00:06:19,490
- 嗯，好的
- 對於你父親的去世我深感抱歉
- Yeah, okay.
- I'm sorry for your loss.

92
00:06:19,530 --> 00:06:20,950
我會參加的
I'll be there.

93
00:06:24,740 --> 00:06:26,700
誰打的電話？
Who was that?

94
00:06:27,450 --> 00:06:29,450
哦，沒什麼事啦
Oh, nobody.

95
00:06:30,580 --> 00:06:33,080
你還好嗎？
You all right?

96
00:06:33,120 --> 00:06:37,090
嗯...我很好
Yeah... I'm fine.

97
00:06:37,130 --> 00:06:40,210
我得去底特律幾天
I just gotta go up
to Detroit for a few days.

98
00:06:40,260 --> 00:06:41,590
為什麼？
Why?

99
00:06:41,630 --> 00:06:43,470
我爸爸死了
My dad died.

100
00:07:01,360 --> 00:07:05,070
我很遺憾你沒能參加你爸爸的葬禮
I was very sorry that
you weren't able to make it
to the funeral.

101
00:07:06,510 --> 00:07:08,850
現場處理的很妥善
It was a lovely service.

102
00:07:08,890 --> 00:07:11,960
我知道對你來說這段時間一定很傷心
I realize this must be a very
emotional time for you.

103
00:07:12,200 --> 00:07:13,800
我們真的不必說這些
We haven't really spoken since he

104
00:07:13,850 --> 00:07:15,510
因為在我16歲的時候
他把我送去少年感化院
sent me to Juvie when I was 16.

105
00:07:15,550 --> 00:07:17,610
那是法院要求把你送去的
Well, it was the court
that sent you to Juvie.

106
00:07:17,610 --> 00:07:19,250
我不會再那麼魯莽了，戴維斯先生
I don't need to be rude, Mr. Davies,

107
00:07:19,250 --> 00:07:21,250
但是如果你願意的話，
開始處理眼前的事吧
but if you please,
just get down to bussiness here.

108
00:07:21,450 --> 00:07:22,710
在最近這兩天..
In the last two days,

109
00:07:22,750 --> 00:07:25,290
我擔心的問題發生了
I'm afraid a small
complication has arisen.

110
00:07:25,330 --> 00:07:27,170
沒剩多少錢了，對嗎？
There's no more money, is there?

111
00:07:27,210 --> 00:07:29,300
不，錢的方面沒問題
No, there's money all right.

112
00:07:29,340 --> 00:07:33,220
你沒有兄弟姐妹，也沒有媽媽，
錢當然都歸你
And with no siblings and no
mother, it all falls to you.

113
00:07:33,260 --> 00:07:39,470
有一個存有120萬美元的帳戶
And then there is an account in
the amount of $1.2 million.

114
00:07:40,710 --> 00:07:42,670
當然那是扣稅之前收益
That's before taxes of course.

115
00:07:42,720 --> 00:07:45,140
上世紀末，你父母投身於
Turn of the last century
your people were pretty big

116
00:07:45,180 --> 00:07:46,220
房地產行業
into real estate.

117
00:07:46,260 --> 00:07:48,180
究竟有什麼問題？
What's the problem exactly?

118
00:07:48,220 --> 00:07:51,680
你爸的妹妹，你的姑姑吉娜維芙·馬丁
His sister, your aunt.
Genevieve Martin.

119
00:07:52,480 --> 00:07:54,140
什麼姑姑？
What aunt?

120
00:07:55,390 --> 00:08:00,560
在上世紀她被送到了艾洛斯精神病院
She was committed to Eloise
Insane Asylum in the late 1960s.

121
00:08:00,600 --> 00:08:04,650
大概在十年之後它就關門了，
但是她沒有出來
A decade or so later it closed,
but she was never released.

122
00:08:04,690 --> 00:08:08,020
當然，最有可能的原因
就是她死在了裡面
Most probable reason, of course,
is that she died there.

123
00:08:08,070 --> 00:08:10,690
所以有了她的死亡證明
So, you are still the sole inheritor

124
00:08:10,730 --> 00:08:12,280
你就是唯一的財產繼承人
with proof of her death.

125
00:08:12,320 --> 00:08:14,950
我們必須得宣佈她已經死亡
If we have to have her declared dead,

126
00:08:14,990 --> 00:08:17,410
否則你在七年內拿不到一分錢
you won't see a dime for seven years.

127
00:08:17,450 --> 00:08:19,240
所以，我該去哪找證明呢？
So, where do I find proof?

128
00:08:19,290 --> 00:08:24,180
和過去一樣，
艾洛斯精神病院有一個行政中心
Well, as a happened. Eloise still
has a small administrative office.

129
00:08:24,220 --> 00:08:26,680
我建議你明天去那一趟
I suggest that you stop
by there tomorrow.

130
00:08:26,720 --> 00:08:30,730
作為親屬，你可以申請查看病歷
As a relative, you can request
the records.

131
00:08:30,770 --> 00:08:32,730
謝謝
Thank you.

132
00:08:32,770 --> 00:08:35,480
有件事你應該知道
There's something you should know.

133
00:08:35,520 --> 00:08:38,450
你爸爸在三年前得了癌症
Your father had cancer
the last three years.

134
00:08:38,490 --> 00:08:41,620
但是他不是死於癌症
But, it wasn't the cancer
that killed him.

135
00:08:41,660 --> 00:08:47,580
在情況變糟時，他決定用剃刀
When things got really bad,
he decided to take his own life.

136
00:08:50,580 --> 00:08:52,580
結束自己的生命
With a straight razor.

137
00:08:55,280 --> 00:08:57,280
我不知道
I didn't know.

138
00:12:53,850 --> 00:12:57,270
在情況變糟時
When things got really bad,

139
00:12:57,310 --> 00:13:00,100
他決定結束自己的生命
he decided to take his own life.

140
00:13:12,820 --> 00:13:14,620
該死！
Holy shit!

141
00:13:14,660 --> 00:13:17,330
你究竟拿著剃刀在幹什麼？
What the fuck are you doing
with that razor?

142
00:13:17,370 --> 00:13:18,790
你嚇死我了
You scared the shit out of me.

143
00:13:18,830 --> 00:13:21,210
你戴著滑雪面罩搞什麼鬼？
What the fuck are you
doing in a ski mask?

144
00:13:21,250 --> 00:13:23,250
聽著，我見燈亮著，決定碰碰運氣
Look, I saw the lights on,
took a chance.

145
00:13:23,290 --> 00:13:25,960
聽著，我理解你了，行了吧？
Look, I was fucking with you, okay?

146
00:13:26,000 --> 00:13:27,710
你聽說過我的老朋友嗎？
Did you hear about my old man?

147
00:13:27,760 --> 00:13:29,300
嗯，我很抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry.

148
00:13:30,420 --> 00:13:33,430
- 別這樣
-哦，老兄
- Don't be.
- Yo, man.

149
00:13:33,470 --> 00:13:35,350
哦，你居然害怕這把小剃刀？
Oh, you scared of a little
straight razor?

150
00:13:35,390 --> 00:13:37,010
拜託！
Come on!

151
00:13:40,230 --> 00:13:41,640
你好啊，兄弟，過得怎麼樣？
What's up, man, how you doing?

152
00:13:41,690 --> 00:13:43,400
很好，兄弟
I'm good, man.

153
00:13:43,440 --> 00:13:45,310
嗯，我知道，
你就像一個處在緊急備戰狀態的罪犯
Yeah, I can see, you're like
the GQ of delinquency.

154
00:13:45,360 --> 00:13:47,940
罪犯也有自己的做事風格...
罪犯也有自己做事風格
Thugs can have style, too...
thugs can have style.

155
00:13:52,570 --> 00:13:54,870
我能為你做點什麼？
What can I get ya'?

156
00:13:54,910 --> 00:13:57,660
我有一句臨終遺言
I will have a Last Word.

157
00:14:00,290 --> 00:14:01,580
等等，如果你不知道怎麼完成它
Wait, if you don't know how to make it,

158
00:14:01,620 --> 00:14:02,830
我想說，我可以展示給你看
I mean, I can show you.

159
00:14:02,870 --> 00:14:05,790
我自己也是個很棒的酒保
I'm a pretty good bartender myself.

160
00:14:05,840 --> 00:14:07,710
啤酒也不錯
Beer is good, too.

161
00:14:07,750 --> 00:14:11,260
呃...那就兩杯阿特沃特啤酒
Uh... just two Atwaters, please.

162
00:14:11,300 --> 00:14:12,930
我需要看看某人的身份證
I'm gonna need to see some ID.

163
00:14:12,970 --> 00:14:15,050
說真的嗎？我像30歲的
Really? I'm like 30.

164
00:14:16,300 --> 00:14:19,310
你就像個嬰兒
Awe, just a baby.

165
00:14:19,350 --> 00:14:21,600
隨便坐，我會找你
Sit anywhere, I'll find you.

166
00:14:27,060 --> 00:14:28,440
這是這邊的傳統
It's a tradition around here.

167
00:14:28,480 --> 00:14:30,900
過生日的男孩給每個人買飲料
The birthday boy buys everyone a round.

168
00:14:30,940 --> 00:14:31,940
哦，該死
Oh shit.

169
00:14:31,990 --> 00:14:33,320
對！
Yeah!

170
00:14:33,360 --> 00:14:36,200
真的嗎？這傳統真是好極了
Really? That's a great tradition.

171
00:14:38,370 --> 00:14:40,830
生日快樂，兄弟，
我都不知道今天是你生日
Happy birthday. Man, I didn't
know it was your birthday.

172
00:14:40,870 --> 00:14:42,710
今天不是，明天才是
It's not, it's tomorrow.

173
00:14:45,170 --> 00:14:47,330
總之，你過得怎麼樣，兄弟？
工作怎麼樣？
Anyway, what's up with
you, man? How's work?

174
00:14:47,380 --> 00:14:49,920
我這兩年來一直循規蹈矩地生活
I've been straight for like,
what? Two years now.

175
00:14:49,960 --> 00:14:51,760
兩年來循規蹈矩地生活？就戴著滑雪面罩
You've been straight for two
years? Running around with

176
00:14:51,800 --> 00:14:53,970
瞎晃蕩，嗯哼？
a ski mask on, huh?

177
00:14:54,010 --> 00:14:56,760
你知道我變聰明了
我不會在酒吧裏戴那個了  你知道嗎？
I got smarter, you know,
I no longer wear them
in bars, you know?

178
00:14:56,800 --> 00:14:59,260
你進化了，真不錯，兄弟
You evolved, that's nice, man.

179
00:14:59,310 --> 00:15:02,220
但是你說對了，我還在幹那行
But you right, I'm still running it.

180
00:15:03,350 --> 00:15:05,020
你知道...
You know...

181
00:15:05,060 --> 00:15:06,730
現在還有些事讓我頭疼
Got something hanging
over my head right now.

182
00:15:06,770 --> 00:15:08,610
比如什麼，錢的事？
Like what, some money shit?

183
00:15:08,650 --> 00:15:11,280
拜託，兄弟，錢一直都是個大問題
Come on, man, it's always a money thing.

184
00:15:11,320 --> 00:15:13,360
多少錢？
How much?

185
00:15:15,360 --> 00:15:16,860
2萬美元
20 G's.

186
00:15:16,910 --> 00:15:20,370
2萬美元？媽的，兄弟，你在做什麼？
20 G's? Holy fuck, man,
what were you doing?

187
00:15:20,410 --> 00:15:23,040
媽的，我現在有很大的麻煩，兄弟
Fuck, I'm in some deep shit, man.

188
00:15:23,080 --> 00:15:26,040
聽著，我可能會得到一筆錢
Well, look, I might be coming
into some money.

189
00:15:26,080 --> 00:15:27,790
這或許能幫你解圍
Might be able to help you out.

190
00:15:27,830 --> 00:15:29,380
什麼，值2萬美元嗎？
What, 20 G's worth?

191
00:15:29,420 --> 00:15:32,920
嗯...更多，比如120萬美元
Yeah... more like 1.2 mil.

192
00:15:32,960 --> 00:15:34,720
- 胡說八道
-不是胡說
- Bullshit.
- No bullshit.

193
00:15:34,760 --> 00:15:37,090
你在家無所事事的就拿到了120萬美元？
You just got 1.2 laying
around the house?

194
00:15:37,130 --> 00:15:39,140
我親愛的白人朋友，你說真的嗎？
Fucking love my white friends.
Are you serious?

195
00:15:39,180 --> 00:15:41,220
至少我聽我爸爸的律師是這麼說的
At least that's what I'm hearing
from my father's lawyer anyway.

196
00:15:41,260 --> 00:15:42,890
所以，你怎麼拿到那筆錢？
So, how do you get it?

197
00:15:42,930 --> 00:15:44,930
我必須得拿到我某個姑姑的死亡證明
I have to get this death
certificate for some aunt...

198
00:15:44,980 --> 00:15:46,440
I didn't know I had.
我不知道我是否能找到

199
00:15:46,480 --> 00:15:48,440
她叫吉娜維芙，給你了看一眼照片
Her name's Genevieve.
Here take a look.

200
00:15:48,480 --> 00:15:51,320
她被關到了那個叫艾洛斯的精神病院
She was locked away in that
mental hospital, Eloise,

201
00:15:51,360 --> 00:15:53,320
離底特律不遠處，你知道嗎？
right outside Detroit, you know?

202
00:15:53,360 --> 00:15:55,030
嗯，我知道，那個地方早在30年前就關門了
Yeah, yeah, that place closed
down like, what, 30 years ago?

203
00:15:55,070 --> 00:15:56,990
它被燒燬了，對嗎？
It burned down, right?

204
00:15:57,030 --> 00:16:00,370
跟我想的一樣，但是那還有一些老舊建築
裏面有一堆檔案
That's what I thought, man,
but there's still a couple
old buildings there,
just a bunch of files.

205
00:16:00,410 --> 00:16:02,410
我明天必須得去一趟那裡
找找死亡證明
All I have do is swing
by there tomorrow, pick it up,

206
00:16:02,450 --> 00:16:03,910
輕鬆一件的事
piece of cake.

207
00:16:03,950 --> 00:16:06,370
你到家了我真的很高興，哦，天吶！
Yo, I'm happy you're home.
Oh my God!

208
00:16:06,410 --> 00:16:08,710
嗯，我敢打賭你也會，打賭你也會的
Yeah, I bet you are. Bet you are.

209
00:16:08,750 --> 00:16:10,040
好了
All right.

210
00:16:12,210 --> 00:16:13,500
給你
Here you go.

211
00:16:15,630 --> 00:16:17,510
她挺漂亮的
She's beautiful.

212
00:16:17,550 --> 00:16:18,680
那是我姑姑
That's my aunt.

213
00:16:18,720 --> 00:16:20,590
她看起來好眼熟
She looks familiar.

214
00:16:20,640 --> 00:16:23,310
皮婭，再來點酒！
Pia, some shots!

215
00:16:26,810 --> 00:16:29,400
皮婭？名字挺好聽的
Pia? That's a pretty name.

216
00:16:29,440 --> 00:16:31,110
嘿，你幾點到？
Hey, what time you got?

217
00:16:31,150 --> 00:16:33,070
拜託，老兄，你知道我平時不戴錶的
Awe, come on, man, you know
I don't carry a watch.

218
00:16:33,110 --> 00:16:37,030
你不戴錶，還在我爸家偷了一個？
Oh, you don't carry a watch
on you like the one you just
pulled from my father's house?

219
00:16:37,070 --> 00:16:39,200
你這"錶"裡不一的混蛋
You profiling motherfucker.

220
00:16:39,240 --> 00:16:40,570
什麼？你想收回你說的話嗎？
What, you want it back?

221
00:16:40,610 --> 00:16:43,370
不...行了，兄弟，你就是那樣
Nah... all good, man.
That's you.

222
00:16:44,990 --> 00:16:46,330
謝謝，安東
Thanks, Anton.

223
00:16:46,370 --> 00:16:49,920
所以你什麼時候出發？
So, when do you get off?

224
00:16:49,960 --> 00:16:54,000
雅各布...祝你好運，
希望你能找到這裏的「臨終遺言」
Jacob... good luck finding
that "Last Word" around here.

225
00:16:55,460 --> 00:16:57,460
生日快樂，雅各布
Happy birthday, Jacob.

226
00:16:57,510 --> 00:16:59,340
很高興看到你還是個話題終結者，兄弟
Yo, it's good to see you're
still a closer, man.

227
00:16:59,380 --> 00:17:00,760
滾蛋！
Fuck off!

228
00:18:07,080 --> 00:18:10,080
你好，我在找行政管理辦事處
Hi, I'm looking for
administrator office.

229
00:18:16,090 --> 00:18:19,720
你好....我就是那個打電話要我姑姑病歷的人
Hi.... I'm the one who called
about my aunt's records.

230
00:18:19,770 --> 00:18:21,930
當然，馬丁，快進來
Of course, Martin.
Come right in.

231
00:18:21,980 --> 00:18:22,940
Thank you. Right here?
謝謝，這邊嗎？

232
00:18:22,980 --> 00:18:25,810
- 嗯
-好的
- Yes.
- Okay.

233
00:18:25,850 --> 00:18:27,560
請坐下，我去幫你找找
Please have a seat, I'll go find them.

234
00:18:27,610 --> 00:18:28,980
謝謝
Thank you.

235
00:18:30,820 --> 00:18:33,780
我看到了外面的畫，那幅畫是怎麼回事？
I noticed that painting outside.
What's the deal with that?

236
00:18:33,820 --> 00:18:35,950
哦，事實上那是年輕時的艾洛斯
Oh, that's actually young Eloise.

237
00:18:35,990 --> 00:18:39,160
在她小的時候，
他們以她的名字來為精神病院命名
They nicknamed the asylum
after her, when she was a child.

238
00:18:39,200 --> 00:18:40,910
幸運的孩子
Lucky kid.

239
00:18:40,950 --> 00:18:44,620
嗯...官方稱大概有7000名前居民
Mm... About 7,000 former
residents were officially

240
00:18:44,670 --> 00:18:47,170
埋進公墓，但是實際上真正的數目
buried in the cemetery but
the real number is actually

241
00:18:47,210 --> 00:18:48,500
要比那個高出十倍
ten times higher.

242
00:18:48,540 --> 00:18:51,710
相信我，要找到它真的很難
This was not very easy to find,
believe me.

243
00:18:51,760 --> 00:18:53,220
But, here you are.
但是，這給你

244
00:18:53,260 --> 00:18:54,470
真的很感激，非常謝謝你
I appreciate it, thank you so much.

245
00:18:54,510 --> 00:18:56,430
別客氣
You're welcome.

246
00:18:56,470 --> 00:18:58,720
- 拜
-拜拜
- Bye.
- Bye, bye.

247
00:19:39,680 --> 00:19:42,060
嗯，這上面寫著它已經被格萊斯醫生
Uh, yeah, it just says here
that it's been remitted

248
00:19:42,100 --> 00:19:45,650
送到了分院區
to the Annex, per Dr. H. H. Greiss.

249
00:19:45,690 --> 00:19:50,110
哦，嗯，分院區是我們保存非公開病歷的地方
Oh yes. The Annex is where we
keep all our nonpublic records.

250
00:19:50,150 --> 00:19:54,070
甚至對我都進行保密，你會需要一個法院指令
Sealed even to me.
You'll need a court order.

251
00:19:54,120 --> 00:19:57,200
呃...那得花多長時間？
Ah... and uh...
How long will that take?

252
00:19:57,240 --> 00:19:59,620
我們現在就能提出申請
We could put in the request right now,

253
00:19:59,660 --> 00:20:04,290
我們會在6、7個月後收到回復...
希望如此吧
we'd hear back in six or seven months...
Hopefully.

254
00:20:04,330 --> 00:20:10,510
我們或許還有別的方法，你知道的
Um... yeah, is there any way we
could maybe just, you know,

255
00:20:10,550 --> 00:20:13,090
這次能通融一下嗎？
bend the rules a little bit
on this just once?

256
00:20:13,130 --> 00:20:16,430
哦，不，不行，不，不行
Oh no. No, no, no.

257
00:20:16,470 --> 00:20:19,140
但是我會盡可能幫你
But here's what I can do.

258
00:20:19,180 --> 00:20:22,140
填一下這個表
Fill this out for you.

259
00:20:29,980 --> 00:20:32,400
J... A...

260
00:20:32,450 --> 00:20:34,530
哦，天吶
Oh, Jesus.

261
00:20:40,260 --> 00:20:40,590
密西根州，威斯特蘭30712密西根街
格萊斯醫生
主治內科醫生

262
00:20:41,840 --> 00:20:43,300
住院通知
特此通知你為雅各布·馬丁作住院安排

263
00:20:44,470 --> 00:20:45,010
晚上10點

264
00:20:45,010 --> 00:20:45,590
5月5日

265
00:20:45,590 --> 00:20:47,590
急性幽閉恐懼症

266
00:20:53,470 --> 00:20:55,220
糟糕
Shit.

267
00:20:55,260 --> 00:20:56,680
該死
Dammit.

268
00:21:01,220 --> 00:21:04,100
什麼鬼？
What the fuck?

269
00:21:04,140 --> 00:21:05,810
哦，天吶
Oh, my God.

270
00:21:14,990 --> 00:21:18,410
哦，老兄...天吶
Oh, man... Jesus.

271
00:21:24,540 --> 00:21:27,170
該死！
Holy shit!

272
00:21:27,210 --> 00:21:30,420
哇，你嚇到我了，老兄！你還好嗎？
Awe, you scared me, man!
Are you okay?

273
00:21:30,460 --> 00:21:34,130
我很抱歉，我只是...撞了你的車子
I'm sorry I just, uh... hit your
cart here.

274
00:21:34,170 --> 00:21:36,130
你還好嗎？
Are you good?

275
00:21:36,180 --> 00:21:37,640
It should be okay.
它應該沒事

276
00:21:37,680 --> 00:21:40,850
我沒撞壞車輪和別的東西
I didn't bend the wheels or anything.

277
00:21:40,890 --> 00:21:43,220
所以...全都在這裡了
So... it's all here.

278
00:21:44,350 --> 00:21:47,230
呃...
Uh...

279
00:21:47,270 --> 00:21:51,070
如果你沒事的話，我得走了
I'm gonna get going if you're good.

280
00:21:51,110 --> 00:21:55,990
你知道...沒事的，反正我也沒受傷
Um, you know... no harm, no foul.

281
00:21:56,030 --> 00:21:58,070
好了，我要走了
Okay, I'm going.

282
00:22:06,540 --> 00:22:09,170
哦，該死
Oh, fuck.

283
00:22:22,510 --> 00:22:24,510
大日子，兄弟，今天是你的大日子
Big day, man. Big day.

284
00:22:24,510 --> 00:22:27,310
好了，我們該為這個好消息好好慶祝一下
Okay, I think we celebrate,
which is good news.

285
00:22:27,320 --> 00:22:29,120
Great fucking news.
超級棒的消息

286
00:22:29,120 --> 00:22:30,620
你拿到證明了嗎？
Did you get the certificate?

287
00:22:30,620 --> 00:22:33,120
我討厭這地方，兄弟，
所以太他媽讓人抑鬱了
I hate this place, man.
So fucking depressing.

288
00:22:33,120 --> 00:22:35,420
- 你拿到證明了嗎？
- 不，我沒拿到
- Did you get the certificate?
- No, I didn't get it.

289
00:22:35,420 --> 00:22:37,420
我查到那份檔案已經轉移到
Found out the file, has been
moved to some other place

290
00:22:37,420 --> 00:22:40,420
知多郡的財產處，得等法院的指令
on property in Chita.
Court order to get to.

291
00:22:40,420 --> 00:22:42,420
那幫該死的分院區的鳥人們
Fucking Annex shit someone tagged.

292
00:22:42,420 --> 00:22:45,420
- 得需要多長時間？
- 6到8個月
- How long this will take?
- 6 to 8 months.

293
00:22:45,420 --> 00:22:48,420
- 該死！
- 嗯，所以...
- Shit!
- Yeah, so...

294
00:22:48,710 --> 00:22:50,880
那就等拿到法院指令，再看看會發生什麼
Just gotta get the court order
and see what happens.

295
00:22:50,920 --> 00:22:52,050
你知道，如果我們一直等法院的話
You know if we wait for the courts,

296
00:22:52,090 --> 00:22:53,340
你絕不會拿到一分錢，對嗎？
you'll never get a dime, right?

297
00:22:53,390 --> 00:22:55,760
你想那樣嗎？
You want that?

298
00:22:55,800 --> 00:22:58,140
你能想像到我們能用那筆錢做什麼嗎？
Can you imagine what we can
do with that money?

299
00:22:58,180 --> 00:23:00,100
我們可以過全新的生活
Yo, we could start our lives over.

300
00:23:00,140 --> 00:23:02,640
該死，我們可以重新開始
Shit, we could start them.

301
00:23:04,520 --> 00:23:07,020
我們以前幹過辣麼瘋狂的事，嗯哼？
We have been through some
crazy shit, huh?

302
00:23:07,070 --> 00:23:10,650
那才是我所認識的雅各布，
那次是我所認識的雅各布
That's the Jacob I know.
That's the Jacob I know.

303
00:23:10,690 --> 00:23:11,950
那裏面有保安嗎？
Any security in there?

304
00:23:11,990 --> 00:23:16,370
不，不見得，說實話
No, not really, to be honest.

305
00:23:16,410 --> 00:23:18,080
所以，那我們還等什麼？
So, what are we waiting on?

306
00:23:18,120 --> 00:23:21,000
聽著，一直有很多人為了找樂子 闖入那個地方
Look, people break in that
place all the time just for fun.

307
00:23:21,040 --> 00:23:23,620
嗯，但是我們怎麼能找遍分院區的所有地方呢？
Yeah but how are we gonna find
the fucking Annex of all places?

308
00:23:23,670 --> 00:23:28,210
兄弟，你讓我瘋狂了，我一直在做研究
Man, you call me crazy.
I've been doing some research.

309
00:23:28,960 --> 00:23:30,380
看看這個
Check this out.

310
00:23:35,890 --> 00:23:37,180
喔噢
Wow.

311
00:23:40,270 --> 00:23:43,730
斯科特·卡特...這傢伙神通廣大
Scott Carter... this guy's got
blueprints and everything.

312
00:23:43,770 --> 00:23:46,690
我們可以進他家，拿到檔案，
然後再溜出來
We get in, get the file
and get the fuck out.

313
00:23:46,730 --> 00:23:50,610
嗯...我們開始干吧
Yeah... let's do it.

314
00:23:50,650 --> 00:23:54,200
他住在謝菲爾區，它就在這條街上
Yo, he lives on Schaefer.
That's right up the street.

315
00:23:54,240 --> 00:23:56,280
嗯，兄弟，咱們趕快去那，快點
Well, dude, let's get
over there, come on.

316
00:23:56,320 --> 00:23:58,410
你在等什麼？打電話讓他上路
What are you waiting for?
Call him on the way.

317
00:23:58,450 --> 00:24:00,410
哦，所以我現在是你的秘書
Oh, so now I'm your secretary.

318
00:24:19,420 --> 00:24:21,970
斯科特！
Yo, Scott!

319
00:24:22,370 --> 00:24:24,290
把手電筒打開！
Get the lights to on!

320
00:24:26,290 --> 00:24:28,370
斯科特！？
Yo, Scott!?

321
00:24:33,910 --> 00:24:35,420
斯科特？
Scott?

322
00:24:41,660 --> 00:24:43,740
這些奇怪的東西究竟是什麼？
What the fuck is all this weird shit?

323
00:24:50,790 --> 00:24:52,330
天吶
Holy shit.

324
00:24:55,570 --> 00:24:56,990
斯科特！
Scott!

325
00:24:58,690 --> 00:25:00,690
這邊沒有
This is ain't right here.

326
00:25:05,430 --> 00:25:07,310
他預料到我們會來，對嗎？
He was expecting us though, right?

327
00:25:07,350 --> 00:25:10,770
嗯，那正是我所擔心的
Yeah, that's what I'm afraid of.

328
00:25:15,200 --> 00:25:18,670
你知道，或許這根本就不是個好主意
You know, maybe this wasn't
a good idea after all.

329
00:25:19,710 --> 00:25:22,380
雅各布？
Yo... Jake?

330
00:25:23,750 --> 00:25:25,510
看看這個
Look at this.

331
00:25:29,340 --> 00:25:31,260
-喔噢！      -該死！
- Whoa!
- Shit!

332
00:25:31,300 --> 00:25:32,300
真的嗎？
Really?

333
00:25:32,350 --> 00:25:34,850
天吶！
Jesus.

334
00:25:38,100 --> 00:25:40,190
你好啊，兄弟
What up, man?

335
00:25:48,840 --> 00:25:50,300
所以你沒穿褲子
So you ain't wearin' no pants.

336
00:25:52,420 --> 00:25:55,840
天吶，你把所有的東西都偷來了嗎？
Jeez. You steal all this stuff?

337
00:25:55,890 --> 00:25:58,390
不...我只是收藏了
No... I collected it.

338
00:25:58,430 --> 00:26:01,220
說得好，我應該用收藏這個好詞
That's a good one, I should
use that one, collected.

339
00:26:01,270 --> 00:26:03,640
你們可以用你們想要的一切，
只要能還回來
You can use anything you want
as long as you return it.

340
00:26:03,680 --> 00:26:06,350
這個就是格萊斯醫生，
This is Dr. Greiss, known for his famous

341
00:26:06,400 --> 00:26:08,190
他的對抗性療法非常出名
confrontational therapy.

342
00:26:08,230 --> 00:26:11,230
對，對！哦，你們想看我最喜歡的收藏嗎？
Yes, yes! Oh, do you want
to see my favorite thing?

343
00:26:13,320 --> 00:26:16,280
醫生，評論者直言不諱地稱它為激進療法
Doctor, your critics have been
extremely vocal

344
00:26:16,320 --> 00:26:18,700
你稱它為什麼呢？
about this radical, what do you call it?

345
00:26:18,740 --> 00:26:21,950
對抗性療法，有人把它視為一種折磨
Confrontational Therapy.
Some liken it to torture.

346
00:26:21,990 --> 00:26:23,660
你對此有什麼看法？
What do you say about that?

347
00:26:23,700 --> 00:26:25,370
我之前就聽過了
I've heard it all before.

348
00:26:25,410 --> 00:26:27,120
他們沒意識到的是
What they fail to realize

349
00:26:27,170 --> 00:26:30,040
我們需要面對自己的恐懼
is that we need to confront our fears.

350
00:26:30,090 --> 00:26:32,420
戰勝它們，而不是任由它們發展
Conquer them, not coddle them.

351
00:26:32,460 --> 00:26:35,260
我們最深的恐懼，
那些讓我們最害怕的恐懼
Our deepest fears, the ones that
terrify us the most,

352
00:26:35,300 --> 00:26:37,510
只是通過把人鎖起來，
麻醉他們進入癱瘓狀態
cannot be alleviated by locking
people up and drugging them

353
00:26:37,550 --> 00:26:40,050
這樣的方法恐懼是不能被緩解的
into catatonia.
It's our moral imperative

354
00:26:40,100 --> 00:26:42,310
只有到達恐懼的根基處，
然後把它們毀掉才是最重要的精神需求
to get to the root of these fears
and destroy them.

355
00:26:42,350 --> 00:26:44,100
對抗性療法的原理就是這樣
Confrontational therapy does this.

356
00:26:44,140 --> 00:26:47,560
嗯，確實有副作用，但是只是
Yes, there are side effects,
but there are side effects

357
00:26:47,600 --> 00:26:49,400
化學療法及外科手術產生的副作用
with chemotherapy and surgery.

358
00:26:49,440 --> 00:26:50,770
我們在一很安全的環境中
We submit our patients

359
00:26:50,820 --> 00:26:53,440
把我們的病人送到他們恐懼的誘發端
to their phobic triggers
in a safe environment.

360
00:26:53,480 --> 00:26:55,740
可以說是將它們進行重編
Reprogramming them, so to speak.

361
00:26:55,780 --> 00:26:58,610
艾洛斯精神病院
曾經是世界上最大的精神病院
Eloise was the biggest asylum
in the world at one time.

362
00:26:58,660 --> 00:27:03,540
它擁有自己的郵政編碼、農場，
消防部門，火車站
It had its own zip code, farm,
fire department, train station.

363
00:27:04,180 --> 00:27:06,680
第一台X光機器是在這研發出來的
The first X-ray machine
was developed here,

364
00:27:06,720 --> 00:27:08,100
被用來給病人檢查身體
tested on patients.

365
00:27:08,140 --> 00:27:09,850
不是你，艾瑪...
Not you, Emma...

366
00:27:09,890 --> 00:27:12,810
哦，你們想聽聽關於那些
腦神經切除術的瘋狂事嗎？
Oh, oh, oh, do you want to
hear about the lobotomy craze?

367
00:27:12,850 --> 00:27:14,350
兄弟，他在摸我
Yo, man, he's touching me.

368
00:27:14,400 --> 00:27:15,980
- 夠了
- 大概不想
- Stop.
- Maybe not.

369
00:27:19,140 --> 00:27:21,980
嘿，兄弟，把相機關了，
老兄，關了相機！
Hey, man, come on, man, cut
the camera off, dude. Cut the camera!

370
00:27:22,020 --> 00:27:25,110
聽著，我打開了紅外濾鏡，
所以它只能拍到紅外線
Look, I took out the IR filter,
so it only shoots infrared.

371
00:27:25,150 --> 00:27:26,980
我太想試試這個了
I've been dying to try this out!

372
00:27:27,020 --> 00:27:28,730
我希望用它能拍到鬼魂
I'm hoping to capture some
ghosts with it.

373
00:27:28,780 --> 00:27:30,860
我只拍了我們三個人中的一個人三秒鐘
I just recorded three seconds,
one for each of us.

374
00:27:30,900 --> 00:27:32,490
好極了，三秒
Good. Three seconds.

375
00:27:34,450 --> 00:27:35,660
漂亮，兄弟
Beautiful, buddy.

376
00:27:35,700 --> 00:27:37,950
嘿，斯科特，我有個提議
Hey, Scott. I have
a proposition for you.

377
00:27:37,990 --> 00:27:42,250
今晚在這裡你想怎麼用你的相機？
How would you like to use your
camera here tonight?

378
00:27:42,290 --> 00:27:45,500
聽著，我需要收集一些文件...
Uh... listen, I need to collect
some papers...

379
00:27:45,540 --> 00:27:47,250
文件
Documents.

380
00:27:47,290 --> 00:27:50,300
文件...關於我姑姑的，它們被藏在了
Documents... on my aunt,
and they're locked away

381
00:27:50,340 --> 00:27:51,720
一個絕密的地方
in a top secret location...

382
00:27:51,760 --> 00:27:53,470
- 分院區
- 什麼？
- Annex.
- What?

383
00:27:53,470 --> 00:27:55,470
- 分院區
- 嗯
- The Annex.
- Yes.

384
00:27:55,510 --> 00:27:57,840
分院區，它就在分院區的5樓
The Annex, it's on
the 5th floor of the Annex.

385
00:27:57,890 --> 00:27:59,720
嗯，我們出發吧！
Yeah, let's go!

386
00:27:59,760 --> 00:28:01,010
分院區，就在分院區的5樓
The Annex, the Annex,
it's on the 5th floor,

387
00:28:01,060 --> 00:28:02,470
我首先得拿到通行證
I need to get permission first.

388
00:28:02,520 --> 00:28:03,600
不！他得先拿到通行證
No! He's gotta get permission first.

389
00:28:03,640 --> 00:28:05,390
但是她逃走了
But she's running away.

390
00:28:05,440 --> 00:28:07,440
嗯，你穿過這裏
Yes, you go in through here,

391
00:28:07,480 --> 00:28:10,520
然後沿著這個走廊，爬上後面的樓梯
then down this corridor,
up the back stairs.

392
00:28:10,570 --> 00:28:12,570
行政管理大樓被鎖得死死的
The administration building
is locked tight,

393
00:28:12,610 --> 00:28:14,440
但是你可以進到發電廠裏
but you can get in
through the power station.

394
00:28:14,490 --> 00:28:15,610
這裏絕對沒鎖
They never lock it.

395
00:28:15,650 --> 00:28:17,860
哦，哦，這將棒極了
Oh, oh, this will be great!

396
00:28:17,910 --> 00:28:20,030
- 這會是一次大冒險！
- 他又在碰我
- This will be, an adventure!
- And he's touching me.

397
00:28:20,170 --> 00:28:21,380
嘿，斯科特，你能幫我
Hey, Scotty, can you help me

398
00:28:21,430 --> 00:28:22,890
with the groceries, please?
整理一下雜物嗎？

399
00:28:22,931 --> 00:28:24,600
There's just a few more bags in the car!

400
00:28:24,640 --> 00:28:25,800
- 是誰啊？
- 我不知道
- Who's that?
- I don't know.

401
00:28:25,850 --> 00:28:29,020
- 是誰啊？
- 我會回來的
- Who's that?
- I'll be back.

402
00:28:29,060 --> 00:28:30,480
不用著急回來，看這個
Keep walking back slow.
Look at this.

403
00:28:30,520 --> 00:28:33,350
不，不，不，絕不，兄弟
No, no, no, hell no, man.

404
00:28:33,400 --> 00:28:34,690
我知道你在想什麼
I know what you're thinking.

405
00:28:34,730 --> 00:28:36,610
我可不打算和一個瘋子
I am not going to Eloise,

406
00:28:36,650 --> 00:28:39,830
去艾洛斯精神病院，
他跳到床上的樣子簡直就像只達菲鴨
with a crazy dude, jumping on
the bed like he's Daffy Duck.

407
00:28:39,970 --> 00:28:41,020
你知道，我快完了，老兄
You know what, I'm done, dude.

408
00:28:41,060 --> 00:28:42,690
聽著，顯然他對所有事都瞭如指掌
Look, he obviously knows all
of this shit like the back

409
00:28:42,730 --> 00:28:44,400
這對我們來說是良機
of his hand, we're golden.

410
00:28:44,440 --> 00:28:45,480
很顯然我不在行
Rain Man's on me.

411
00:28:45,520 --> 00:28:46,650
嗯，你真是太看得起他了
Yeah, you babysit him.

412
00:28:46,690 --> 00:28:48,110
好的
Okay.

413
00:28:48,150 --> 00:28:49,740
就是他們
This is them.

414
00:28:49,780 --> 00:28:54,120
這是德爾，這位是...我也不知道他叫什麼
This is Dell. This is...
I don't know his name.

415
00:28:54,160 --> 00:28:55,620
你們在這裡做什麼？
What the hell are you doing here?

416
00:28:55,660 --> 00:28:57,450
我也想問你同樣的問題
I was just gonna ask you
the same question.

417
00:28:57,490 --> 00:29:00,540
我住在這裡，他是我的哥哥，
在我打911之前
I live here, he's my bro and
you've got 15 seconds

418
00:29:00,580 --> 00:29:02,120
你們還有15秒的時間解釋
before I call 911.

419
00:29:02,170 --> 00:29:03,670
- 喔噢，喔噢
- 我有朋友了！
- Whoa, whoa.
- I have friends!

420
00:29:04,920 --> 00:29:07,500
你在哪裡遇見他們的？親愛的
How did you meet them, sweetie?

421
00:29:07,550 --> 00:29:09,970
不，不是，是我們找到了他，
我們找到了他，好嗎？
No, no, we found him,
we found him, all right?

422
00:29:10,010 --> 00:29:11,170
我們只是想來一次
艾洛斯精神病院之旅
We just want to take a tour of Eloise,

423
00:29:11,220 --> 00:29:12,260
而且斯科特是最佳人選...
and Scott's the best person...

424
00:29:12,300 --> 00:29:13,640
你們是怎麼找到他的？
How did you meet?

425
00:29:13,880 --> 00:29:15,420
- 我們在他的網站上找到他的
- 對
- We met him on his site.
- Yeah.

426
00:29:15,460 --> 00:29:16,510
他建了一個叫"艾洛斯"的人氣網站
He's got a hot, little site @eloise.

427
00:29:16,550 --> 00:29:18,380
我們查到了他，對吧？
We looked him up, right?

428
00:29:18,420 --> 00:29:19,800
我們發現了那個網站，
他的照片和他的所有信息都在那上面
We found the site, his picture's
on there, all the information.

429
00:29:19,840 --> 00:29:21,430
真是好極了
It's great.

430
00:29:21,470 --> 00:29:24,760
好吧，明天我們會叫警察
Okay, well then,
tomorrow we can call the staff

431
00:29:24,810 --> 00:29:26,260
把你們兩個人送回去
and get back to you guys.

432
00:29:26,310 --> 00:29:28,430
不，不，我想用我的新相機！
No, no, I was gonna use my new camera!

433
00:29:28,480 --> 00:29:29,520
他想用他的新相機
He wants to use his new camera.

434
00:29:29,560 --> 00:29:31,020
我只隨便說說
I just said that.

435
00:29:31,060 --> 00:29:32,480
我得和你到外面談一談
I need to talk to you
outside for a minute.

436
00:29:32,520 --> 00:29:33,610
好吧
Okay.

437
00:29:33,650 --> 00:29:35,610
斯科特，你跟德爾待在屋裏
Scotty, you stay with Dill.

438
00:29:35,650 --> 00:29:38,970
雅各布，別，別扔下我...
Jacob, no. Don't leave me...

439
00:29:40,650 --> 00:29:43,900
好了，就讓我從頭給你說一遍，好嗎？
Okay, just let me start
from the beginning, all right?

440
00:29:43,940 --> 00:29:47,150
我爸爸剛剛去世了，好嗎？
My father just passed away, okay?

441
00:29:47,190 --> 00:29:50,280
嘿，兄弟，雅各布嗎，拜託，
兄弟，你這是在搗亂
Hey, man, Jacob, man, come on, man,
y'all playing games.

442
00:29:50,320 --> 00:29:51,780
我想摸你
I wanna touch you.

443
00:29:51,820 --> 00:29:54,530
不，不要不穿褲子就摸我，
穿好你的褲子
No, not with no pants on.
Get your pants on.

444
00:29:55,180 --> 00:29:57,590
我知道這得打聽很多事
但是其他人都沒有
And I know it's asking a lot,
but no one knows

445
00:29:57,640 --> 00:29:59,120
你哥哥對那個地方瞭解得多
that place better than your brother.

446
00:29:59,160 --> 00:30:00,070
穿上你的褲子！
Put your pants on!

447
00:30:00,110 --> 00:30:02,870
我知道，他清楚我想要的定西在哪裡
I know, and he's all I've got
and I won't

448
00:30:02,910 --> 00:30:04,490
我並沒有在利用他
have him taken advantage of.

449
00:30:04,530 --> 00:30:05,950
他很喜歡那個地方
He is obsessed with that place

450
00:30:05,990 --> 00:30:08,450
如果他在那裏和我們走散了
或者發生什麼事的話...
and if he wanders off
or something happens...

451
00:30:08,500 --> 00:30:10,830
我會快去快回的，而且會一直看著他，
我保證!
Quick in, quick out.
I'll watch him, I promise.

452
00:30:10,870 --> 00:30:11,810
你會看著他？
You'll watch him?

453
00:30:11,850 --> 00:30:13,850
- 對
- 在艾洛斯精神病院？
- Yeah.
- In Eloise?

454
00:30:13,890 --> 00:30:17,310
我覺得你一直看著他會忙不過來的
I think you're gonna have your
hands full keeping up with him.

455
00:30:17,360 --> 00:30:18,400
-把你的頭放到裏面
-兄弟
- Put your head here.
- Yo, man.

456
00:30:18,440 --> 00:30:19,460
快點戴上它，戴上它！
Put it there. Put it on!

457
00:30:19,500 --> 00:30:21,080
既然你激起了他的興趣
Now that you got him all riled up,

458
00:30:21,130 --> 00:30:23,210
那麼我也不可能對他說不
it's impossible to say no to him.

459
00:30:25,450 --> 00:30:29,200
好吧，快去快回，我也會去的
Okay, quick in, quick out,
and I'm coming.

460
00:30:29,240 --> 00:30:30,990
好的！謝謝你
Yes! Thank you.

461
00:30:31,040 --> 00:30:33,290
嘿...皮婭也加入了
Hey... Pia's in.

462
00:30:33,330 --> 00:30:35,830
你們想看看有趣的玩意兒嗎？
You guys wanna see something funny?

463
00:30:35,870 --> 00:30:37,920
-斯科特，不要！
-不
- Scott, don't!
- No.

464
00:30:37,960 --> 00:30:39,920
不！
Don't!

465
00:30:40,760 --> 00:30:44,520
不，這一定會很有趣，會是一次大冒險
No, this will be fun,
this will be an adventure.

466
00:30:44,560 --> 00:30:45,430
對，對
Yeah, yeah...

467
00:30:45,470 --> 00:30:47,970
- 一切都準備好了
- 一定會很棒
- It's all good.
- ...it's gonna be something.

468
00:30:48,810 --> 00:30:50,560
別高興得太早
Don't look too happy about it.

469
00:30:50,600 --> 00:30:52,770
說不定會是一場災難，估計就會變成那樣
It's gonna be a disaster,
that's what it's gonna be.

470
00:30:52,820 --> 00:30:53,940
真是可笑
This is ridiculous.

471
00:30:53,980 --> 00:30:55,610
褲子！
Pants!

472
00:30:57,440 --> 00:30:58,490
你需要拿上書包或者...
Do you need like a bag or...

473
00:30:58,530 --> 00:31:00,360
書包！
Bag!

474
00:31:02,450 --> 00:31:05,990
醫生，有誰在這個療法期間死亡嗎？
Has anyone ever died during
this therapy, Doctor?

475
00:31:06,040 --> 00:31:10,370
死傷在所難免
Medicine is not an exact science.

476
00:31:15,670 --> 00:31:18,010
為什麼他對這個地方這麼迷戀呢？
Why is he so fascinated with this place?

477
00:31:18,050 --> 00:31:20,090
小心，小心點，兄弟，小心！
Careful, careful, man, careful!

478
00:31:20,130 --> 00:31:22,550
我媽以前在這裏當護士
Our mom used to be a nurse here.

479
00:31:22,590 --> 00:31:25,430
在我四歲的時候，有一天她去上班了
She left for work one day
when I was about four,

480
00:31:25,470 --> 00:31:27,850
所以斯科特當時六歲
so Scotty was six.

481
00:31:27,890 --> 00:31:29,520
她就再也沒回家
She just never came home.

482
00:31:29,560 --> 00:31:32,480
我們再也沒有收到她的消息
Never heard from her again, either.

483
00:31:32,520 --> 00:31:34,940
有時候我覺得斯科特還認為
Sometimes I think Scott still thinks

484
00:31:34,980 --> 00:31:37,030
她因為某種原因還在這裏面
she's in here for something.

485
00:31:37,070 --> 00:31:39,820
- 所以，你知道我們現在在哪裡嗎？
- 對...我有地圖
- So, you know where we are?
- Yes... I have a map.

486
00:31:39,860 --> 00:31:42,450
你拿了地圖，所以這裡以前是什麼地方？
You got a map. So, what used
to be here, anyways?

487
00:31:42,490 --> 00:31:44,120
這裏一直都是這個，它是個公墓
It's always been this, it's a cemetery.

488
00:31:44,160 --> 00:31:46,120
波特的牧場，他們把病人埋在了這裡
Potter's Field, it's where they
buried the patients.

489
00:31:46,160 --> 00:31:47,750
病人？你的意思是說我們一直
The patients? You mean all this
time we walking

490
00:31:47,790 --> 00:31:49,660
在踩著瘋子的屍體？
on crazy dead people?

491
00:31:49,710 --> 00:31:51,580
不錯，他們是瘋子，這是個精神病院
Of course they're crazy,
it's a mental institution.

492
00:31:51,620 --> 00:31:54,630
我爸和斯科特都瘋了
Our dad went a little nuts
with Scotty needing

493
00:31:54,670 --> 00:31:56,800
他們需要特殊照顧
special attention and all,
so it was pretty much

494
00:31:56,840 --> 00:31:58,760
一旦我們知道我媽再也不會回來
up to me to look out for him
once we realized

495
00:31:58,800 --> 00:32:01,380
照顧斯科特的責任就得由我扛起
she was never coming back.

496
00:32:01,430 --> 00:32:04,010
那對一個四歲的孩子來說真的很難
That's gotta be pretty tough
for a four-year-old.

497
00:32:04,050 --> 00:32:07,180
嗯，但是...我猜這就是生活
Yeah, but... that's life I guess.

498
00:32:07,220 --> 00:32:10,430
所以，沒有媽媽的生活到底是什麼樣的？
So, what was it like living
without a mom?

499
00:32:10,480 --> 00:32:12,520
你不知道
You have no idea.

500
00:32:12,560 --> 00:32:15,810
其實我知道
Actually I do.

501
00:32:15,860 --> 00:32:19,070
我都記不清她的長相
I barely even remember her.

502
00:32:19,110 --> 00:32:21,740
當她走的時候我可能有點生氣
When she left I was probably
a little angry,

503
00:32:21,780 --> 00:32:24,820
所以我想忘了關於她的一切東西
so I tried to just forget all about her.

504
00:32:24,870 --> 00:32:26,450
你呢？
What about you?

505
00:32:26,490 --> 00:32:29,160
我沒有真正見過她，
所以我都不知道我錯過了什麼
Never really met her,
so I don't know what I missed.

506
00:32:29,200 --> 00:32:33,040
我爸爸，他甚至都沒有說過她
My father, he would never even
speak about her.

507
00:32:33,080 --> 00:32:35,330
他們相處得不是很好
He didn't really get along too well.

508
00:32:37,960 --> 00:32:41,170
嘿，你們知道我們正踩著瘋子的屍體，
對嗎？
Hey, y'all know we're walking
on crazy dead people, right?

509
00:32:41,220 --> 00:32:43,840
哦，好把，好吧，你們相愛了，好吧
Oh, okay, okay, y'all in love, okay.

510
00:32:53,440 --> 00:32:55,940
好的，我們穿過這裡，從這邊
Okay, we're gonna go in through
here and from here,

511
00:32:55,980 --> 00:32:57,520
我們從發電廠穿過，要從那邊
we're gonna go through the power
station and from there

512
00:32:57,560 --> 00:32:59,230
我們要去行政管理大樓
we're gonna go to the
administration building.

513
00:32:59,270 --> 00:33:01,820
嘿，兄弟，有...
Hey buddy, is there uh...

514
00:33:01,860 --> 00:33:05,990
除了這條路，還有其他到那個地方的路嗎？
Is there any other way into this
situation besides... this?

515
00:33:06,030 --> 00:33:07,660
沒有
No.

516
00:33:07,700 --> 00:33:09,160
好吧
Okay.

517
00:33:09,200 --> 00:33:11,700
「還有其他的路嗎？」
"Any other way into this situation?"

518
00:33:11,750 --> 00:33:14,250
雅各布，你怎麼不彎下身子？
How you holding up, Jacob?

519
00:33:14,290 --> 00:33:16,290
好吧
Okay.

520
00:33:18,500 --> 00:33:20,250
哦，天吶
Oh, God.

521
00:33:23,340 --> 00:33:24,630
你還好嗎？
You okay?

522
00:33:24,680 --> 00:33:27,510
嗯，我有幽閉恐懼症
Yeah, I'm just a little claustrophobic.

523
00:33:27,550 --> 00:33:29,890
你知道，不是什麼大事
You know, no big deal.

524
00:33:29,930 --> 00:33:33,430
每個人都有害怕的東西，我可不敢打針
Everybody's afraid of something.
I don't do needles.

525
00:33:33,480 --> 00:33:35,020
我又不是必須得說害怕..
I wouldn't say afraid necessarily...

526
00:33:35,060 --> 00:33:36,770
只是，你知道...有點不舒服而已
just, you know... a little
uncomfortable.

527
00:33:36,810 --> 00:33:40,190
- 好吧
-全是廢話，廢話
- Okay.
- That's bullshit. Bullshit.

528
00:33:40,230 --> 00:33:43,650
我不想和說話，蠢貨...媽的
I wasn't talking to you,
dipshit... fuck.

529
00:33:44,860 --> 00:33:47,660
- 好了
-好的
- All right.
- It's okay.

530
00:33:47,700 --> 00:33:50,450
我們走吧
Here we go.

531
00:33:50,490 --> 00:33:51,830
哦，該死
Oh shit.

532
00:34:01,460 --> 00:34:02,960
那是什麼？
Yo, what was that?

533
00:34:03,010 --> 00:34:04,380
是這座樓的墜落物
That's the building settling.

534
00:34:04,420 --> 00:34:07,010
這地方可是以它的污水坑而出名
This area's famous for its sinkholes.

535
00:34:07,050 --> 00:34:08,720
什麼，你害怕嗎？
What, are you scared?

536
00:34:08,760 --> 00:34:10,100
兄弟，當然不，我一點也不害怕
Man, hell no, I ain't scared.

537
00:34:10,140 --> 00:34:11,890
胡說八道
Ah, bullshit.

538
00:34:11,930 --> 00:34:13,430
嗯，胡說八道，別告訴我你不害怕
Yeah, bullshit, don't tell
me that didn't scare

539
00:34:13,470 --> 00:34:15,680
嚇得你都尿褲子了
the piss out of you just a little bit.

540
00:34:15,730 --> 00:34:17,350
看那個，你褲子上是什麼？
Look at that, what's that on your pants?

541
00:34:17,390 --> 00:34:18,690
那是雨水，蠢貨
That's rain, dipshit.

542
00:34:18,730 --> 00:34:20,440
那是某個蠢貨下的雨
That's some pissy-ass rain.

543
00:34:20,480 --> 00:34:23,440
一分鐘前，你還嚷嚷著說你有幽閉恐懼症
A minute ago, you was crying
about being claustrophobic.

544
00:34:23,480 --> 00:34:25,610
這個地方真讓我毛骨悚然
This place gives me the creeps.

545
00:34:25,650 --> 00:34:28,240
謝謝，終於有人肯承認這地方
Thank you. Finally somebody
can admit that this place

546
00:34:28,280 --> 00:34:30,410
讓人毛骨悚然了
gives them the creeps.

547
00:34:30,450 --> 00:34:33,870
這是我最喜歡的地方，這下面是地下墓穴
This is my favorite part.
Down here are the catacombs.

548
00:34:33,910 --> 00:34:36,330
這就是他們過去存放死屍的地方
This is where they used to store
the dead bodies

549
00:34:36,370 --> 00:34:38,290
當冬天到的時候，
因為太冷了就不能把屍體埋了
when winter hit because it
was too cold to bury them.

550
00:34:38,330 --> 00:34:40,920
這地方足夠放屍體了
Enough with the dead bodies, man.

551
00:34:47,090 --> 00:34:49,340
快點
Come on.

552
00:34:57,060 --> 00:35:01,610
好的，有樓梯，我們得爬到43階梯以上
Okay, these are stairs.
We have to go up 43 more.

553
00:35:01,650 --> 00:35:04,150
斯科特，慢點
Scott, easy.

554
00:35:12,280 --> 00:35:14,330
那是什麼？
Yo, what's that?

555
00:35:14,370 --> 00:35:18,500
燈上安著感應器，德爾！
The lights are on a motion
sensor. Du'h, Dell, du'h!

556
00:35:18,540 --> 00:35:21,170
這可一點也不好玩
That ain't funny.

557
00:35:34,550 --> 00:35:37,220
等等，等等，停一下，停一下！
Wait, wait, stop, stop!

558
00:35:37,270 --> 00:35:41,600
就是她...她就是艾洛斯
That's her... that's Eloise.

559
00:35:47,190 --> 00:35:48,900
所以，我們現在究竟在哪裡？
So, where the hell are we?

560
00:35:48,940 --> 00:35:51,990
好的，我們現在在這裡...
Okay, we're here now...

561
00:35:53,950 --> 00:35:56,450
你還記得嗎？
Do you remember?

562
00:35:56,490 --> 00:36:01,210
媽媽...媽媽以前有時候帶你來工作
Mom... Mom used to take you
to work sometimes,

563
00:36:01,250 --> 00:36:03,170
你還記得嗎？
do you remember?

564
00:36:03,210 --> 00:36:04,880
不是吧
Not really.

565
00:36:04,920 --> 00:36:06,800
不!
你還記得媽媽以前有時候帶你來工作嗎？
No, no, do you remember mom used
to take you to work sometimes?

566
00:36:06,840 --> 00:36:08,630
不記得了
No.

567
00:36:16,190 --> 00:36:18,690
分院區就在旁邊 大樓的五樓
Annex is on the 5th floor
of the next building.

568
00:36:18,730 --> 00:36:20,780
你穿過這些樓梯
You go through these stairs.

569
00:36:20,820 --> 00:36:22,240
它不在這個建築裏嗎？
It's not in this building?

570
00:36:22,280 --> 00:36:24,820
不在，這就是他們稱它為分院區的原因
No, that's why they call it the Annex!

571
00:36:24,860 --> 00:36:27,450
它有一條絕密的入口
It has very restricted access.

572
00:36:29,410 --> 00:36:31,330
手電！手電！
Flashlights! Flashlights!

573
00:36:36,460 --> 00:36:37,580
噓！
Shh!

574
00:36:41,920 --> 00:36:45,380
等等，我覺得我聽到一些聲音
Hold on, I think I hear something.

575
00:36:45,430 --> 00:36:47,640
好了，我要撤了
All right, I'm pulling around.

576
00:37:02,940 --> 00:37:06,070
吃了飯再回來檢查吧，我快餓死了
We can check back
after dinner, I'm starving.

577
00:37:06,110 --> 00:37:08,120
收到
Copy that.

578
00:37:15,250 --> 00:37:16,710
兄弟，你到底有什麼毛病？
Yo, man, what the fuck
is wrong with you?

579
00:37:16,750 --> 00:37:19,250
- 噓！
- 那真的很嚇人
- Shh!
- That was scary.

580
00:37:19,290 --> 00:37:21,340
好了，他們走了
在他們還沒回來之前，我們快走
Okay, they're gone. Hey, let's
go before they come back.

581
00:37:21,380 --> 00:37:22,920
快點，快點，快點！我們走吧
Come on, come on, come on! Let's go.

582
00:37:24,460 --> 00:37:27,550
它有一條非常絕密的入口
It has very restricted access.

583
00:37:27,590 --> 00:37:30,510
為什麼這麼絕密?
在分院區還有別的東西嗎？
Why is it restricted?
What else is in the Annex?

584
00:37:30,550 --> 00:37:33,520
育嬰室，你問的別的東西，就是育嬰室了
The nursery, you asked what else
was in the Annex, the nursery.

585
00:37:43,400 --> 00:37:46,280
- 這一點也不好玩？
- 對
- Isn't this fun?
- No.

586
00:37:59,080 --> 00:38:01,210
這就是分院區
This is the Annex.

587
00:38:02,540 --> 00:38:04,630
我從來沒有走這麼遠
I've never come this far.

588
00:38:13,560 --> 00:38:15,810
格萊斯醫生
Dr. Greiss.

589
00:38:16,930 --> 00:38:19,600
媽媽
Mom.

590
00:38:19,650 --> 00:38:21,610
Maybe Mom's picture will be here.
或許媽媽的照片會在這裡

591
00:38:21,650 --> 00:38:24,020
皮婭，或許媽媽的照片也在這裡！
Pia, maybe Mom's picture's here!

592
00:38:26,400 --> 00:38:28,400
皮婭，媽媽的照片在哪裡？
Where's mom's picture, Pia?

593
00:38:28,450 --> 00:38:29,910
I don't know, bud.
我不知道，老兄

594
00:38:29,950 --> 00:38:32,030
皮婭，媽媽在哪裡？
Pia, where's mom?

595
00:38:32,870 --> 00:38:34,030
媽媽？
Mom?

596
00:38:36,240 --> 00:38:37,540
媽媽？
Mommy?

597
00:38:40,040 --> 00:38:41,170
媽媽？
Mom?

598
00:38:41,210 --> 00:38:42,880
誰知道我們要從哪裡走？
Anybody know where we're going?

599
00:38:42,920 --> 00:38:45,250
我們要從哪裡走？
Where are we going?

600
00:38:45,300 --> 00:38:47,210
這上面應該有一條走廊
There should be a hallway up here.

601
00:38:47,260 --> 00:38:49,010
對，這邊，這邊！
Yes, this way, this way!

602
00:39:00,060 --> 00:39:03,150
這些是病人的骨灰
These are people's ashes.

603
00:39:04,520 --> 00:39:07,860
- 家人就把他們留在了這裡？
- 嗯
- Families just left them here?
- Yeah.

604
00:39:07,900 --> 00:39:09,610
- 斯科特，不要亂碰！
-喔噢，喔噢！
- Scotty, don't touch!
- Whoa, whoa!

605
00:39:09,650 --> 00:39:11,070
- 啊哈-啊哈
-不，拜託
- Unh-unh.
- No, come on.

606
00:39:11,110 --> 00:39:12,410
不要，兄弟
Nah, man.

607
00:39:12,450 --> 00:39:13,990
為什麼？
Why?

608
00:39:14,030 --> 00:39:15,780
- 拜託
- 不要亂碰
- Come on.
- Don't touch.

609
00:39:15,830 --> 00:39:17,580
- 我們走吧
-快點，我們走吧
- Let's go.
- Come one, let's go.

610
00:39:17,620 --> 00:39:18,870
販賣機
Vending machine.

611
00:39:18,910 --> 00:39:21,250
沒事
It's okay.

612
00:39:27,090 --> 00:39:29,800
- 斯科特！
-嗯，皮婭！
- Scott!
- Yes, Pia!

613
00:39:39,060 --> 00:39:40,640
現在感覺好噁心
Now that's just gross.

614
00:39:40,680 --> 00:39:42,230
- 什麼東西噁心？
- 看看那個，你看到了嗎？
- What's gross?
- Look at that, you see that?

615
00:40:06,670 --> 00:40:09,210
-我們該怎麼走，兄弟？
- 我們在哪裡？
- Where we going, buddy?
- Where we at?

616
00:40:09,250 --> 00:40:10,760
應該稍微...
Should be a little...

617
00:40:10,800 --> 00:40:14,720
往上走，拐角處有個地方
A little up here around the
corner somewhere.

618
00:40:14,760 --> 00:40:18,560
就是它，我見過它，這上面就是病歷室
This is it, I knew it, this is
the records room right up here!

619
00:40:18,600 --> 00:40:21,390
好了，小心，繼續我們的大冒險
All right, watch out, on our
grand adventure.

620
00:40:21,430 --> 00:40:24,900
這些死鳥是怎麼回事？ 該死!
What's up with these dead birds?
Aw, shit.

621
00:40:26,310 --> 00:40:27,650
去你媽的
Fuck that.

622
00:40:27,690 --> 00:40:29,110
這些都是死鳥！
These are dead birds!

623
00:40:34,570 --> 00:40:36,360
嘿，等等！
Hey, wait up!

624
00:40:40,910 --> 00:40:44,210
該死，到底有多少個房間？
Shit, how many rooms are there?

625
00:40:44,250 --> 00:40:46,460
看這個
Yo, look at this.

626
00:40:52,630 --> 00:40:55,260
Agh!

627
00:40:58,600 --> 00:41:01,010
斯科特，沒事了，快點
Scotty, it's okay. Come on.

628
00:41:01,060 --> 00:41:03,600
- 該死
-快點
- Aw, shit.
- Come on.

629
00:41:03,640 --> 00:41:06,940
哦，天吶
Oh, my God.

630
00:41:09,310 --> 00:41:12,530
所以他們只是說說，該死的清潔工
So they just said, fuck cleaning up.

631
00:41:12,570 --> 00:41:14,490
天吶
Holy shit.

632
00:41:14,530 --> 00:41:16,150
對嗎？
Right?

633
00:41:16,200 --> 00:41:18,530
斯科特，跟緊點
Scotty, stay close.

634
00:41:18,570 --> 00:41:20,780
吉米·霍法
Jimmy Hoffa.

635
00:41:20,830 --> 00:41:23,120
誰打死了圖帕克
Who shot Tupac.

636
00:41:23,160 --> 00:41:26,080
我前女友的電話本上也找不到
My ex-girlfriend's phonebook,
can't find that shit.

637
00:41:26,120 --> 00:41:28,040
拜託，兄弟，我們究竟該怎麼找
Come on, man, how the hell
are we supposed to find

638
00:41:28,080 --> 00:41:30,750
一個地方的證明，比如個地方，兄弟們
a certificate in a place like this, man?

639
00:41:30,790 --> 00:41:32,460
6到8個月，去你的
Six to eight months, my ass.

640
00:41:32,500 --> 00:41:34,670
我要進另一個病歷室看看
Yo, I'm gonna go into
another record room.

641
00:41:34,710 --> 00:41:36,170
你好，鴿子！
Hi, pigeon!

642
00:41:36,220 --> 00:41:38,550
- 別亂碰，哥哥
- 好吧
- Don't touch, buddy.
- Okay.

643
00:41:40,300 --> 00:41:42,350
再說一遍你姑姑的名字？
What's your aunt's name again?

644
00:41:42,390 --> 00:41:45,980
吉娜維芙...吉娜維芙·馬丁
Genevieve... Genevieve Martin.

645
00:41:58,530 --> 00:42:01,030
哥哥？
Buddy?

646
00:42:01,070 --> 00:42:03,290
明白我的意思了嗎？
See what I meant?

647
00:42:03,330 --> 00:42:07,040
知道我說的了吧，忙不過來了吧？
我去找他
See what I'm talking about,
hands full? I'm gonna find him.

648
00:42:07,080 --> 00:42:08,790
斯科特？
Scotty?

649
00:42:11,000 --> 00:42:14,210
斯科特，現在別玩了
Scott, don't play right now.

650
00:42:17,380 --> 00:42:19,890
斯科特，拜託
Scotty, come on.

651
00:42:34,020 --> 00:42:37,690
斯科特？斯科特？
Scott? Scotty?

652
00:43:01,510 --> 00:43:05,260
斯科特，你能聽到我嗎？求你出來吧
Scott, can you hear me?
Please come in.

653
00:43:31,330 --> 00:43:33,710
儲藏室
Supply closet.

654
00:43:33,750 --> 00:43:34,830
明白了，賤人
Gotcha, bitch.

655
00:43:37,000 --> 00:43:41,130
我找到了2號病歷室
Yo, I found record room two.

656
00:43:48,100 --> 00:43:51,100
懷特醫生，電話
Dr. White, telephone.

657
00:43:51,140 --> 00:43:52,940
給我趴下！
Get down!

658
00:43:52,980 --> 00:43:54,270
停一停！
Stop!

659
00:44:14,000 --> 00:44:17,130
一眼望去全是屎
Whole lot of shit to go through.

660
00:44:17,170 --> 00:44:19,920
嘿，德爾，你知道幾點了嗎？
Hey, Dell, you got the time?

661
00:44:19,960 --> 00:44:21,840
嘿，去你媽的！
Hey, yo, fuck you!

662
00:45:05,260 --> 00:45:07,640
斯科特！
Scotty!

663
00:46:03,900 --> 00:46:06,030
沒事了
It's okay.

664
00:46:09,860 --> 00:46:12,950
皮婭，找到斯科特了嗎？
Pia, any luck with Scott?

665
00:46:12,990 --> 00:46:14,700
沒有，我還在找
No, I'm still looking.

666
00:46:14,740 --> 00:46:18,120
嗯，我這邊可能真的需要些幫助
Yeah, well, really could use
some help up here.

667
00:46:18,160 --> 00:46:20,080
嗯，我...我現在馬上過去
Yeah, I'm... I'm coming now.

668
00:47:20,060 --> 00:47:22,100
Agh!

669
00:47:31,950 --> 00:47:37,240
沒事了...你沒事了
It's okay... you're okay.

670
00:48:15,620 --> 00:48:18,280
斯科特？
Scotty?

671
00:48:58,870 --> 00:49:01,450
他們沒意識到的是，我們需要
What they fail to realize is,
is that we need

672
00:49:01,490 --> 00:49:02,700
面對我們的恐懼
to confront our fears.

673
00:49:02,750 --> 00:49:04,620
戰勝它們，而不是任由它們發展
Conquer them, not coddle them.

674
00:49:36,700 --> 00:49:38,410
- 開始吧
- 不，不要！
- Go ahead.
- No, no!

675
00:50:03,850 --> 00:50:05,310
這就是我
That's me.

676
00:50:10,730 --> 00:50:12,110
這就是我
That's me.

677
00:50:30,670 --> 00:50:34,210
Agh!

678
00:50:37,760 --> 00:50:39,630
到底怎麼回事...
What the hell...

679
00:50:39,680 --> 00:50:44,390
發生了什麼？你們是誰？發生了什麼？
What's happening? Who are you?
What's happening?

680
00:50:45,720 --> 00:50:47,270
有人嗎？
Hello?

681
00:50:51,560 --> 00:50:56,070
天吶，格萊斯簡直就是個施虐狂
Jesus, Greiss is one
sadistic motherfucker.

682
00:50:56,110 --> 00:50:57,740
找到了嗎？
Any luck?

683
00:51:00,110 --> 00:51:04,740
沒有，找到了格萊斯的，你找到斯科特了嗎？
Not really. Found the M's.
Find Scott?

684
00:51:04,780 --> 00:51:08,290
沒有，我找不到他，我開始有點擔心了
No, I can't find him.
I'm starting to worry.

685
00:51:08,330 --> 00:51:11,870
他可能正玩得開心呢，對嗎？
He's probably having a ball. Right?

686
00:51:11,920 --> 00:51:13,750
嗯
Yeah.

687
00:51:13,790 --> 00:51:17,210
聽著，我找到了格萊特的，
所以...我覺得我快找到我姑姑的了
Look, I just found the M's,
so... I'm really close.

688
00:51:17,260 --> 00:51:19,420
應該不會花太長時間
Shouldn't be too long.

689
00:51:19,470 --> 00:51:21,090
我可以幫你
I can help you.

690
00:51:26,680 --> 00:51:28,600
凱瑟琳...
Catherine...

691
00:51:31,940 --> 00:51:34,690
喔噢，喔噢，喔噢，我找到了，
我找到了，好極了！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, I got it,
I got it! Yes!

692
00:51:34,730 --> 00:51:35,650
什麼？
What?

693
00:51:35,690 --> 00:51:38,990
吉娜維芙·馬丁！好極了！
Genevieve Martin! Yes!

694
00:51:39,030 --> 00:51:42,070
德爾，斯科特，我們找到了
Dell, Scotty, we found it.

695
00:51:42,110 --> 00:51:44,570
太棒了！
Fantastic!

696
00:52:09,350 --> 00:52:10,810
在這裡裡去世的
Died here.

697
00:52:12,810 --> 00:52:14,980
等等
Hold on.

698
00:52:16,270 --> 00:52:17,980
所以她在5月5號死的
So she died May 5th.

699
00:52:18,020 --> 00:52:20,610
嗯，那就是30年前的今天
Yeah, that was 30 years ago to the day.

700
00:52:21,780 --> 00:52:23,610
喔
Wow.

701
00:52:23,650 --> 00:52:27,450
上面沒說...沒說她怎麼死的？
Doesn't say... doesn't say how she died?

702
00:52:31,700 --> 00:52:33,250
嗯，好吧...
Yeah, well...

703
00:52:34,920 --> 00:52:39,000
召集隊員，去慶祝吧，嗯哼？
Round up the troops
and go celebrate, huh?

704
00:52:39,050 --> 00:52:42,800
嘿...沒有你和斯科特，我也不可能找到這個
Hey... I couldn't have done this
without you and Scott.

705
00:52:42,840 --> 00:52:44,300
我會找到他的
We'll find him.

706
00:52:54,440 --> 00:52:58,270
我的錶...怎麼回事？
My watch... what the hell?

707
00:52:58,310 --> 00:53:00,650
什麼鬼？
What the fuck?

708
00:53:18,420 --> 00:53:19,340
Agh!

709
00:53:24,590 --> 00:53:28,800
哦，該死，我們看看這裡有什麼？
Oh shit. What do we have here?

710
00:53:32,600 --> 00:53:34,890
古柯鹼 愛死你了
Gotta love Codeine.

711
00:53:47,360 --> 00:53:50,240
他媽真該死
Fuckin' shit, man.

712
00:54:00,290 --> 00:54:02,290
麥角酰二乙胺（一種迷幻藥）

713
00:54:23,020 --> 00:54:24,980
你們一定都飽餐一頓了吧，斯科特在哪裡？
Y'all must be stoked.
Where's Scott?

714
00:54:25,030 --> 00:54:26,650
我們找到了！
We got it!

715
00:54:26,690 --> 00:54:27,740
這裏面好熱啊
Is it hot in here?

716
00:54:27,780 --> 00:54:29,240
我們趕快離開這裡吧
Let's get the fuck out of here.

717
00:54:29,280 --> 00:54:32,580
斯科特，我們已經找到了我們要找的，
請回答
Scotty, we got what we need,
please respond.

718
00:54:32,620 --> 00:54:34,080
你們中有人聯繫過他嗎，因為他都
Will one of you guys try him
because he's just

719
00:54:34,120 --> 00:54:35,580
不聽我的
not listening to me.

720
00:54:35,620 --> 00:54:37,290
嗯，我聯繫他
Yeah, I got him.

721
00:54:37,330 --> 00:54:40,420
斯科特拿著你的破設備過來，
兄弟，我們找到它了
Yo, Scott, get your crazy
ass here, man, we found it.

722
00:54:41,330 --> 00:54:42,840
嘿...
Hey...

723
00:54:42,880 --> 00:54:44,380
你還好嗎？
You okay?

724
00:54:44,420 --> 00:54:47,130
嗯，我很好，我很好
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm good, I'm good.

725
00:54:47,170 --> 00:54:50,090
你確定嗎？你看起來有點不正常
Are you sure? You look a little crazy.

726
00:54:53,350 --> 00:54:55,060
把包放下
Put that bag down.

727
00:54:55,100 --> 00:54:57,930
你把包放下，閉嘴吧
You put the fucking bag down.
Shut the fuck up.

728
00:54:57,980 --> 00:55:03,150
老兄，嘿，看著我，沒人在那裡，
沒人在那裡，沒人在那裡
Brother, hey, look at me.
No one's there. No one's there.

729
00:55:03,190 --> 00:55:04,480
你是在告訴我你看不到他嗎？
You're telling me you don't see him?

730
00:55:04,520 --> 00:55:06,320
他一直跟我說把包放下
He keeps telling me to put the bag down.

731
00:55:06,360 --> 00:55:09,490
嘿，嘿，老兄，沒人在那裡，
看著我，這裡只有我們！
Hey, hey, brother, no one's there.
Look at me, it's just us!

732
00:55:09,530 --> 00:55:11,240
不，你看到他了，他就在你身後，
一直看著我
No, you see him, he's right
behind you, keep looking at me.

733
00:55:11,280 --> 00:55:12,150
放輕鬆
Relax.

734
00:55:12,150 --> 00:55:13,540
老兄，你一直那樣看著我，老兄
Dude, you keep looking
at me like that, dude.

735
00:55:13,580 --> 00:55:16,460
德爾，我們一直都在看到奇怪的東西，
但那不是真的
Dell, we've all been seeing
crazy things, it's not real.

736
00:55:16,500 --> 00:55:18,170
我們拿到了死亡證明，
我們可以拿到那筆錢了
We got the certificate,
we got the money.

737
00:55:18,210 --> 00:55:19,840
快點振作起來，我們拿到證明了
Snap out of it, we got the certificate.

738
00:55:19,880 --> 00:55:21,420
別他媽那樣看著我！
Stop fucking looking at me!

739
00:55:21,470 --> 00:55:23,130
- 喔噢，搞什麼，兄弟！
-德爾，夠了！
- Whoa, what the fuck, man!
- Dell, stop it!

740
00:55:23,180 --> 00:55:24,840
- 嘿，把槍放下！
-雅各布，做點什麼！
- Hey, put the gun down!
- Jacob, do something!

741
00:55:24,890 --> 00:55:28,510
德爾？看著我，看著我，
你的手怎麼回事？兄弟
Dell? Look at me, look at me.
What happened to your hand, man?

742
00:55:28,560 --> 00:55:30,270
手怎麼樣了？
What about it?

743
00:55:30,310 --> 00:55:32,980
對，對，對，看著我，沒事了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, look at me, it's okay.

744
00:55:33,020 --> 00:55:35,610
對，對，我是雅各布，就是我
Yeah, yeah, it's Jacob, it's just me.

745
00:55:35,650 --> 00:55:37,610
- 我的手為什麼在流血？
- 放輕鬆，沒事了
- Why's my hand bleeding.
- Just relax, it's okay.

746
00:55:37,650 --> 00:55:39,320
你弄的嗎？
You did this?

747
00:55:39,360 --> 00:55:42,030
我什麼都沒做，這裡只有我們，
看著我，相信我
I did not do anything. It's just us.
Look at me, trust me.

748
00:55:42,070 --> 00:55:43,910
看著我，就是我，就是雅各布
It's just... look at me, it's
just me, it's Jacob.

749
00:55:43,950 --> 00:55:44,700
- 好吧
- 好嗎？
- Okay.
- All right?

750
00:55:44,700 --> 00:55:46,490
雅各布，小心他在你身後...
Jacob, watch out he's right...

751
00:55:49,790 --> 00:55:52,000
德爾！雅各布，做點什麼！
Dell! Jacob, do something!

752
00:55:52,040 --> 00:55:54,710
德爾！德爾！
Dell! Dell!

753
00:55:56,250 --> 00:55:58,380
- 德爾！
- 嘿，德爾！
- Dell!
- Hey, Dell!

754
00:55:58,420 --> 00:55:59,710
等等，我們現在在哪裡？
Wait, where are we?

755
00:55:59,750 --> 00:56:02,590
離我遠點
Get away from me!

756
00:56:02,630 --> 00:56:06,430
不，這是我的眼鏡，我需要它，
我需要它，不，不是我的十字架！
No, those are my glasses, I need those.
No, not my cross!

757
00:56:29,120 --> 00:56:31,160
哦，不，我的眼鏡！
Oh, no, my glasses!

758
00:56:31,200 --> 00:56:32,950
先生們，準備進行經眶白質切斷手術
Gentlemen, prepare for a transorbital.

759
00:56:33,000 --> 00:56:36,000
不，我不想接受手術，
放開我！離我遠點！
No, I don't want a transorbital.
Get off me! Get away from me!

760
00:56:40,170 --> 00:56:42,420
護士，神經細胞
Nurse, neutroplast.

761
00:56:42,460 --> 00:56:45,300
離我遠點！不！
Get away from me! No!

762
00:56:45,340 --> 00:56:46,880
這一定弄錯了！
This is a mistake!

763
00:56:46,930 --> 00:56:48,680
沒弄錯，請綁住他
No mistake. Strap him down, please.

764
00:56:53,390 --> 00:56:55,060
- 德爾！
- 斯科特？
- Dell!
- Scott?

765
00:56:55,100 --> 00:56:56,690
斯科特？
Scott?

766
00:57:15,250 --> 00:57:16,910
醫生，要麻醉嗎？
Anesthesia, Doctor?

767
00:57:16,960 --> 00:57:18,790
不必了
Not necessary.

768
00:57:18,830 --> 00:57:20,790
如果你不記得傷痛的話，
你以後就再也感受不到它了
If you don't remember pain,
then you never really felt it.

769
00:57:24,880 --> 00:57:28,470
冷靜一下，幾分鐘之後，
你將會成為一個全新的人
Just calm down. In a few
minutes, you'll be a new man,

770
00:57:28,510 --> 00:57:30,090
你不會記得任何一件事
and you won't remember a thing.

771
00:57:45,990 --> 00:57:48,320
瓊斯醫生，讓眼瞼張開
Dr. Jones, hold that eyelid open.

772
00:58:01,250 --> 00:58:03,040
錘子
Hammer.

773
00:58:10,050 --> 00:58:11,890
斯科特！
Scotty!

774
00:58:26,030 --> 00:58:27,440
斯科特！
Scotty!

775
00:58:27,490 --> 00:58:28,820
斯科特？
Scott?

776
00:58:32,910 --> 00:58:34,330
該死
Shit.

777
00:58:34,370 --> 00:58:37,790
不，不，不！斯科特！
No, no, no! Scotty!

778
00:58:37,830 --> 00:58:40,410
- 走，快走
-你前面帶路
- Go, go.
- You lead the way out.

779
00:59:17,030 --> 00:59:18,660
Agh! Agh!

780
00:59:35,970 --> 00:59:38,010
開開門！
Open the door!

781
00:59:41,680 --> 00:59:44,020
Agh! Agh!

782
01:00:05,080 --> 01:00:07,170
開開門！
Agh! Open the door!

783
01:01:07,730 --> 01:01:09,480
往下走
Go down.

784
01:01:12,530 --> 01:01:14,150
斯科特！
Scotty!

785
01:01:20,530 --> 01:01:22,490
好的，他應該在下面
Okay, he should be down here.

786
01:01:22,540 --> 01:01:24,330
你剛剛說你看到了什麼？
What did you say you were seeing?

787
01:01:24,370 --> 01:01:27,000
一個小女孩，
她想給我看一個盒子還是什麼的
A little girl. She was trying
to show me a box or something.

788
01:01:27,040 --> 01:01:30,880
進了育嬰室，然後她就消失了
Inside the nursery...
Then she just vanished.

789
01:01:30,920 --> 01:01:33,210
你認為我瘋了吧
You think I'm nuts.

790
01:01:33,250 --> 01:01:35,710
不...嗯...，或許吧
No... yeah... well, maybe.

791
01:01:35,760 --> 01:01:37,970
那個洞應該在這裡
The hole should be here.

792
01:01:38,010 --> 01:01:41,550
我想說...它可能在下面的樓層裏，
可能更深
I mean... it went down some
floors, it was pretty deep.

793
01:01:41,600 --> 01:01:44,470
或許我該回去，你聽到音樂了嗎？
Maybe I got turned around.
Are you hearing music?

794
01:01:44,520 --> 01:01:45,720
嗯
Yeah.

795
01:01:52,360 --> 01:01:54,690
斯科特？
Scotty?

796
01:02:04,660 --> 01:02:06,870
你聽到那個了，對吧？
You're hearing that, right?

797
01:02:33,819 --> 01:02:37,865
♪ Looks like it's all
just falling on down ♪

798
01:02:37,907 --> 01:02:41,952
♪ Oh but it's got soul ♪

799
01:02:41,994 --> 01:02:44,955
♪ I'm in a hole ♪

800
01:02:44,997 --> 01:02:51,670
♪ Maybe we're all just getting old ♪

801
01:02:51,712 --> 01:02:57,218
♪ There's no place here that I belong ♪

802
01:02:57,259 --> 01:03:02,765
♪ I thought I'd be lucky
Man it's all wrong ♪

803
01:03:02,806 --> 01:03:07,144
♪ So I motored back to Newtown ♪

804
01:03:07,186 --> 01:03:09,230
♪ Well it feels right ♪

805
01:03:09,271 --> 01:03:14,985
♪ I motored back to Newtown
on a Saturday night ♪

806
01:03:15,027 --> 01:03:22,826
♪ Oh I motor back to Motown
back to where I belong ♪

807
01:04:39,040 --> 01:04:41,540
嘿，你覺得你自己究竟在做什麼？
Hey, what the hell are
you think you doing?

808
01:05:13,110 --> 01:05:16,410
斯科特？斯科特，我一直在找你，哥哥
Scott? Scotty, we've been
looking for you, buddy.

809
01:05:16,450 --> 01:05:18,200
嘿，斯科特
Hey, Scott.

810
01:05:18,240 --> 01:05:20,500
嘿，斯科特，快回來！
Hey, Scott, come back!

811
01:05:25,960 --> 01:05:27,250
嘿！
Hey!

812
01:05:28,880 --> 01:05:30,920
斯科特！
Scott!

813
01:05:30,970 --> 01:05:32,590
斯科特！站住！
Scotty, hold up!

814
01:05:37,390 --> 01:05:39,220
嘿！
Hey!

815
01:06:11,460 --> 01:06:17,470
斯科特，不！斯科特，
不！斯科特，究竟為什麼！
Scotty, no! Scotty, no!
Scotty, why!

816
01:06:17,510 --> 01:06:19,680
親愛的，不要！
Baby, no!

817
01:06:19,720 --> 01:06:24,350
不，斯科特！我的天吶，不要！
No, Scotty! Why? My God, no!

818
01:06:24,390 --> 01:06:26,770
你做了什麼？
What'd you do?

819
01:06:32,990 --> 01:06:34,700
What the fuck did you do?
你到底做了什麼？

820
01:06:34,740 --> 01:06:41,620
媽的回答我！
Fucking answer me!

821
01:06:41,660 --> 01:06:43,160
放開我！
Get the fuck off me!

822
01:06:43,200 --> 01:06:46,120
如你所見，死傷是難免的
As you can see, medicine
is not an exact science.

823
01:06:47,880 --> 01:06:50,040
但是現在是時候為你治療了
But now it's time for your treatment.

824
01:06:55,720 --> 01:06:57,390
快點，我們走！
Come on, let's go!

825
01:07:09,070 --> 01:07:10,990
- 快走，快走！
- 我們快走！
- Go, go!
- Let's go!

826
01:07:20,070 --> 01:07:20,660
嘿！
Hey!

827
01:07:21,410 --> 01:07:22,270
雅各布！
Jacob!

828
01:07:22,310 --> 01:07:23,850
快走！
Go!

829
01:07:24,910 --> 01:07:27,460
嘿，嘿，求你停車！
Hey, hey, stop please!

830
01:07:31,330 --> 01:07:32,790
嘿，嘿！
Hey, hey!

831
01:07:32,790 --> 01:07:34,790
我們需要幫助！求求你！求求你！
We need help! Please, please!

832
01:07:34,790 --> 01:07:37,590
裏面有人在襲擊我的朋友，
求你，我們需要幫助！
Somebody just attack my friend inside.
Please, we need help!

833
01:07:37,590 --> 01:07:38,590
等等，等等
Hold on, hold on.

834
01:07:38,600 --> 01:07:41,600
Please, we need help,
somebody will get hurt, hurry.
求你，我們需要幫助，
有人會受傷的，快點

835
01:07:41,600 --> 01:07:44,100
請你待在這裡！我馬上會回來
待在這裡!
Please stay here!
I'll be right back, stay here.

836
01:07:56,800 --> 01:07:58,800
嘿，謝天謝地，嘿
Hey, thank God. Hey.

837
01:08:01,600 --> 01:08:03,600
- 等等，等等，等等，
- 不，一定是弄錯了
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- No, this is some mistake.

838
01:08:03,600 --> 01:08:04,700
另外那個警官在哪裡？
Where are the other officer?

839
01:08:04,700 --> 01:08:07,700
- 沒有其他警官
- 不！
- No other officer.
- No!

840
01:08:09,700 --> 01:08:10,700
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?

841
01:08:10,700 --> 01:08:13,200
一定有別的警官進了那個門
There's other officer,
go through that door.

842
01:08:21,600 --> 01:08:26,100
不！不，不，不，一定是弄錯了，
聽我說，求求你！
No! No, no, no. This is a mistake.
Listen to me, please!

843
01:08:29,100 --> 01:08:31,100
雨剛剛停了
The rain just stop.

844
01:08:31,910 --> 01:08:34,910
The building is a cloak.
Everything's changed.
這棟樓是個幌子，一切都被改變了

845
01:08:34,910 --> 01:08:36,910
就在你出來的時候
When were you came outside.

846
01:08:37,910 --> 01:08:41,510
等等，等等，等等，我現在知道了，
是讓這一切都變回到過去嗎？
Wait, wait, wait, I get it now.
Making it all change back to the past?

847
01:08:41,910 --> 01:08:44,910
- 是你說的意思嗎？
- 坐在那裡，閉上你的嘴
- Is that what you says?
- Just sit there and shut up!

848
01:08:54,540 --> 01:08:56,670
請安靜下來，坐下來
Quiet down please, take your seats.

849
01:08:58,460 --> 01:09:01,130
安靜下來
Quiet down.

850
01:09:01,170 --> 01:09:03,970
今天我們有兩個有趣的病例研究
We have two interesting
case studies today.

851
01:09:04,010 --> 01:09:09,890
這位病人患得是急性幽閉恐懼症
This patient suffers from an
acute form of claustrophobia.

852
01:09:09,930 --> 01:09:12,180
他最嚴重且最害怕的恐懼就是
The most severe and frightening
of which is specifically...

853
01:09:12,230 --> 01:09:14,140
醒來之後，發現...
the fear of waking up and discovering...

854
01:09:14,190 --> 01:09:15,480
自己被活埋了
that you're buried alive.

855
01:09:15,520 --> 01:09:17,560
所以，當他的麻醉藥失效後
So, when his anesthesia wears off,

856
01:09:17,610 --> 01:09:19,520
他會發現自己在停屍間的櫃子裏
he'll find himself in a morgue drawer.

857
01:09:19,570 --> 01:09:23,240
這迫使他直面自己的終極恐懼
Forcing him to face his ultimate fear.

858
01:09:23,280 --> 01:09:26,160
或許你們想知道為什麼堵住他的嘴
Perhaps you're wondering
why he's gagged.

859
01:09:26,200 --> 01:09:27,660
當他的醒的時候
Well, when he comes to,

860
01:09:27,700 --> 01:09:29,330
我們可不想讓他吵醒死者
we wouldn't want him to wake the dead.

861
01:09:32,290 --> 01:09:34,460
約翰，請把他帶走
John, take him away, please.

862
01:09:37,080 --> 01:09:40,460
現在又一個很有意思的病例
Now, this is a most interesting case.

863
01:09:42,050 --> 01:09:45,930
這種病有好幾個名字，恐尖症就是其中一個
There are several names for it.
Aichmophobia is one.

864
01:09:45,970 --> 01:09:47,340
還有人知道嗎？
Anyone?

865
01:09:49,100 --> 01:09:50,560
Tryp... Trypanophobia.
暈針症

866
01:09:50,600 --> 01:09:54,560
好極了，最致命的恐懼就是打針
Excellent. A deathly fear of injections.

867
01:09:54,600 --> 01:09:56,810
這種恐懼非常強大，與其讓病人病著
A fear so strong the patient
would rather suffer...

868
01:09:56,850 --> 01:10:00,440
還不如讓她接受治療
the illness than to allow its cure.

869
01:10:00,480 --> 01:10:04,740
這種恐懼症困擾了我們這些醫生好多年
This phobia has plagued us
doctors for many years.

870
01:10:09,700 --> 01:10:11,280
你們注意到這個病人也被堵住了嘴
You'll notice that
the patient is gagged.

871
01:10:11,280 --> 01:10:13,160
要記住最重要的事情就是
What is most important to remember is,

872
01:10:13,200 --> 01:10:15,830
我們絕不能失去決心
is we must not lose our resolve.

873
01:10:15,870 --> 01:10:18,670
無論我們多麼同情這些病人，
我們必須記住
No matter how we feel for the
patient, we have to remember

874
01:10:18,710 --> 01:10:20,880
我們是在幫他們，而不是傷害他們
that we're helping them,
not hurting them.

875
01:10:20,920 --> 01:10:23,380
弗萊徹護士會接替我
Nurse Fletcher will take over?

876
01:10:23,420 --> 01:10:26,260
因為我要進行一場特別的生產手術
As I have
a very special birth to perform.

877
01:11:02,170 --> 01:11:03,960
救命！
Help!

878
01:11:19,980 --> 01:11:22,400
救命！救命！
Help! Help!

879
01:11:50,590 --> 01:11:51,930
護士！
Nurse!

880
01:11:53,260 --> 01:11:54,640
我去抓她！
I got her!

881
01:11:57,310 --> 01:11:58,720
阻止她！
Stop her!

882
01:13:19,600 --> 01:13:21,310
雅克布？
Jacob?

883
01:13:23,310 --> 01:13:24,690
雅克布？
Jacob?

884
01:13:24,730 --> 01:13:26,520
救命啊！救命啊！
Help! Help!

885
01:13:26,560 --> 01:13:27,730
雅克布！
Jacob!

886
01:13:29,020 --> 01:13:33,070
- 雅克布！
-救命啊！救命啊！
- Jacob!
- Help! Help! Help!

887
01:13:33,110 --> 01:13:34,610
雅克布？
Jacob?

888
01:13:34,650 --> 01:13:36,410
救命啊！
Help!

889
01:13:39,330 --> 01:13:41,410
你沒事了
You're okay.

890
01:13:49,590 --> 01:13:51,170
快點
Come on.

891
01:13:53,800 --> 01:13:55,680
謝謝你，長官
Thank you, Officer.

892
01:14:02,470 --> 01:14:05,310
蓋上這個，想辦法混進去，雅各布
Cover up and just try
to blend in, Jacob.

893
01:14:34,920 --> 01:14:36,470
東邊的走廊...
East corridor...

894
01:14:47,100 --> 01:14:50,400
會帶他們去哪裏呢？看看那個名字
Where would they take them?
Look at the name.

895
01:14:56,990 --> 01:15:01,160
哦，天吶，她...
Oh, my God. She was...

896
01:15:01,200 --> 01:15:03,280
她懷孕了
She was pregnant.

897
01:15:03,330 --> 01:15:05,750
On your birthday.
就在你出生那天

898
01:15:08,290 --> 01:15:13,460
不，不，這不可能，這不可能
No, no, it can't be. It can't be.

899
01:15:21,050 --> 01:15:23,930
哦，天吶
Oh, my God.

900
01:15:23,970 --> 01:15:28,730
喔噢，喔噢，雅各布，你不能那樣，
這裏到處都是警衛
Whoa, whoa, Jacob, you can't.
There's security everywhere.

901
01:15:39,450 --> 01:15:41,360
是個男孩
It's a boy.

902
01:15:41,410 --> 01:15:43,620
恭喜你，醫生
Congrats, Doc.

903
01:15:43,660 --> 01:15:45,410
哦，該死
Oh shit.

904
01:15:52,170 --> 01:15:54,090
不要
Don't.

905
01:15:54,130 --> 01:15:56,250
- 我必須得
-不，雅各布
- I have to.
- No, Jacob.

906
01:16:34,830 --> 01:16:37,210
你好
Hi.

907
01:16:37,250 --> 01:16:39,460
我是雅各布
It's Jacob.

908
01:16:45,890 --> 01:16:50,470
就是我...我就是雅各布
It's me... it's Jacob.

909
01:17:04,360 --> 01:17:07,450
給你，讓我們吃了這鎮痛藥
Here, let's take this for the pain.

910
01:17:22,260 --> 01:17:23,800
我們來這邊
Here we go.

911
01:17:35,810 --> 01:17:38,270
他好漂亮
He's so beautiful.

912
01:17:38,310 --> 01:17:40,190
想好名字了嗎？
Thought of a name?

913
01:17:40,230 --> 01:17:41,650
雅各布
Jacob.

914
01:17:41,690 --> 01:17:44,320
雅各布
Jacob?

915
01:17:44,360 --> 01:17:46,950
真好聽的名字
That's a beautiful name.

916
01:17:48,740 --> 01:17:50,660
抱歉，我聽不到你說什麼
Sorry, I can't hear you.

917
01:18:00,960 --> 01:18:04,550
別擔心，吉娜，
這個孩子是不會在這種糟糕的地方
Don't worry, Gen, this is one
child that won't grow up

918
01:18:04,590 --> 01:18:07,890
長大的，我不在乎他的爸爸是誰
in this God-forsaken place,
I don't care who his father is.

919
01:18:07,930 --> 01:18:10,470
我會馬上給你的哥哥打電話
I'll call your brother right now.

920
01:19:08,240 --> 01:19:10,950
- 他們去哪裡了？
-那邊
- Where'd they go?
- There.

921
01:19:49,780 --> 01:19:52,610
什麼...她究竟在做什麼？
What... What the hell is she doing?

922
01:20:16,220 --> 01:20:18,600
皮婭，過來，甜心
Pia, come here, sweetheart.

923
01:20:23,770 --> 01:20:26,150
那是我的洋娃娃
That was my doll.

924
01:20:26,190 --> 01:20:29,690
皮婭，看這個小嬰兒
Pia, Look... look at this baby.

925
01:20:29,740 --> 01:20:32,570
我給他蓋上，好嗎？
I'm gonna cover him up
a little bit, okay?

926
01:20:39,790 --> 01:20:41,870
那是我媽媽
That's my mother.

927
01:20:44,380 --> 01:20:46,880
謝謝你，甜心
Thank you, sweetheart.

928
01:20:57,510 --> 01:21:00,720
現在它就是你的，你好好照顧他
This is gonna be yours now.
You take good care of it.

929
01:21:00,770 --> 01:21:03,390
有位先生就在外面的汽車旁等著，好了
There's a gentleman waiting
outside by a car, okay.

930
01:21:03,440 --> 01:21:05,190
我想讓你把這盒子給他
And I want you to give this box to him.

931
01:21:05,230 --> 01:21:07,060
他會好好照顧他的
He's gonna take really good care of him,

932
01:21:07,110 --> 01:21:08,820
確保讓他安全到家，好嗎？
make sure he gets home safely, okay?

933
01:21:08,860 --> 01:21:12,610
所以，現在走吧，皮婭，
不要因為任何人停下來，好嗎？
So, now go, Pia, and don't
stop for anybody. Okay?

934
01:21:22,960 --> 01:21:24,040
皮婭？
Pia?

935
01:21:27,790 --> 01:21:29,290
繼續...走吧
Go on... go.

936
01:21:31,880 --> 01:21:33,170
我的兒子在哪裏？
Where's my son?

937
01:21:35,340 --> 01:21:37,890
我的孩子在哪裡？
Where's my son?

938
01:21:48,690 --> 01:21:50,860
我的孩子在哪裡？！
Where's my son?!

939
01:21:52,860 --> 01:21:55,400
找到那孩子
Find that kid.

940
01:21:55,450 --> 01:21:58,030
緊急封鎖，封鎖所有出口
Immediate lockdown, seal all exits.

941
01:22:00,910 --> 01:22:03,200
好了，我們走吧
All right, let's go.

942
01:22:17,380 --> 01:22:19,050
你想知道我為什麼會有幽閉恐懼症嗎
You wonder why I'm claustrophobic.

943
01:22:19,090 --> 01:22:20,680
我出生的第一天就在那東西裏待著
I spent my first
full fucking day in that thing.

944
01:22:20,720 --> 01:22:22,060
你要做什麼？
What are you gonna do?

945
01:22:22,100 --> 01:22:24,430
在1980年的這天發生了一場火災
There was a fire on this day in 1980.

946
01:22:24,480 --> 01:22:27,730
現在...現在這裏會有一場大火
Now... now there's gonna
be a bigger one.

947
01:22:27,770 --> 01:22:31,480
除非我判斷有誤...我的舅舅，
不，是我的爸爸
Unless I missed my guess,
my uncle... no, my father

948
01:22:31,520 --> 01:22:34,030
會在這裡停車，然後偷偷用你拿的那個盒子
is going to be pulling up
and you smuggle me

949
01:22:34,070 --> 01:22:37,780
把我帶走
out in that box you've been carrying.

950
01:22:37,820 --> 01:22:39,740
好了
Okay.

951
01:22:39,780 --> 01:22:41,780
給你，拿著這個，然後退後
Here, take this and stand back.

952
01:22:44,870 --> 01:22:46,910
走，走，快走，退後！
Go, go, go, stay back!

953
01:22:48,290 --> 01:22:52,000
這邊，快走！火災報警器啟動了
Here, go! Hit the fire alarm.

954
01:22:53,300 --> 01:22:55,130
快點！
Come on!

955
01:22:57,260 --> 01:23:01,800
清理醫院！清理醫院！這邊！
Clear the hospital!
Clear the hospital! This way!

956
01:23:01,850 --> 01:23:05,470
現在我們要清理樓層！
Let's clear the floors now!

957
01:23:05,520 --> 01:23:07,560
你們得出來，請大家從裏面出來
You need to exit,
everybody exit the building.

958
01:23:21,820 --> 01:23:23,780
等等，雅各布，看
Wait, Jacob, look.

959
01:23:33,750 --> 01:23:36,170
不，不！雅各布！不，雅各布！
No, no! Jacob! No, Jacob!

960
01:23:36,210 --> 01:23:39,720
- 不，不！你得走了！
- 雅各布！不，放開我！
- No! No! You gotta go!
- Jacob! No, let me go!

961
01:23:39,760 --> 01:23:41,840
有人抓了他！得有人幫他，求求你！
Somebody get him!
Somebody has to help him, please!

962
01:23:41,890 --> 01:23:43,470
為什麼你們不聽我說的！
Why won't you listen to me!

963
01:23:43,510 --> 01:23:45,430
有人願意聽我說嗎？
Will somebody listen to me please.

964
01:23:45,470 --> 01:23:47,220
- 他抓了我的朋友
-女士，聽著，跟我來
- He grabbed my friend.
- Lady, listen, come with me!

965
01:23:47,270 --> 01:23:49,770
這地方已經關門了！拜託
This place has been closed down!
Come on.

966
01:23:49,810 --> 01:23:51,270
- 裏面有個醫生！
- 聽我說！根本沒有醫生！
- There's a doctor in there!
- Listen to me! No, no doctor!

967
01:23:51,310 --> 01:23:54,110
等等，不，求求你，
有一個醫生，不，聽著！
Wait, no please, there's
a doctor. No, listen!

968
01:23:54,150 --> 01:23:57,190
他殺了我的哥和我媽，求你聽我說！
He killed my brother and my
mother. Please listen to me!

969
01:23:57,230 --> 01:24:00,030
這裏面已經30年沒醫生了
No doctors have been
in there for 30 years.

970
01:24:00,070 --> 01:24:01,110
毯子
Blanket.

971
01:24:01,150 --> 01:24:04,030
他們想殺了他！
They tried to kill him!

972
01:24:54,670 --> 01:24:56,380
皮婭？
Pia?

973
01:25:01,380 --> 01:25:03,260
好的
Okay.

974
01:25:06,050 --> 01:25:07,720
好的
Okay.

975
01:25:09,680 --> 01:25:12,480
我覺得你或許想要這個
Well, I thought you might
like to have these.

976
01:25:29,490 --> 01:25:31,620
雅各布·馬丁到底發生了什麼？
What really happened to Jacob Martin?

977
01:25:49,510 --> 01:25:50,680
到地方了嗎？
Get anywhere?

978
01:25:59,980 --> 01:26:01,820
他很喜歡那個地方
He is obsessed with that place

979
01:26:01,860 --> 01:26:04,110
如果他在那裏和我們走散了
或者發生什麼事的話...
and if he wanders off
or something happens...

980
01:26:04,150 --> 01:26:06,450
快去快回，我會看好他的，我保證
Quick in, quick out.
I'll watch him, I promise.

981
01:26:06,490 --> 01:26:08,950
斯科特
Yo, Scott,

982
01:26:08,990 --> 01:26:12,580
拿上你的破裝備到這裡，
兄弟，我們找到它了
get your crazy ass here, man,
we found it.

983
01:26:12,620 --> 01:26:14,620
你還記得嗎？媽媽以前有時候
Do you remember? Mom used to take you

984
01:26:14,660 --> 01:26:18,540
帶你去工作，你還記得嗎？你還記得嗎？
to work sometimes. Do you remember?
Do you remember?

985
01:26:24,260 --> 01:26:27,930
皮婭...名字挺好聽的
Pia... that's a pretty name.

986
01:26:33,970 --> 01:26:36,140
皮婭，你好好照顧它
Pia, you take good care of it,

987
01:26:36,180 --> 01:26:38,850
確保讓他安全到家，好嗎？
make sure it gets home safely, okay?

988
01:26:50,430 --> 01:26:54,150
哦，天吶...哦，天吶！
Oh, God... oh, God! Agh!

989
01:26:54,810 --> 01:26:56,770
哦，該死！
Oh, fuck!

990
01:27:01,530 --> 01:27:03,700
哦，該死！救命！
Oh, fuck! Help!

991
01:27:08,830 --> 01:27:11,120
歡迎回家，兒子
Welcome home, son.

992
01:27:43,862 --> 01:27:51,639
Missing 10% lines and added manually
by me " H@w-to-kiLL " @subscene.com

993
01:27:52,450 --> 01:28:04,170
這部影片以紀念艾洛斯精神病院以前的病人，
他們的家人以及艾洛斯的醫護人員。

994
01:28:07,760 --> 01:28:19,440
電影製片人希望得到維恩契約，首席執行官
羅伯特·A·菲恩諾以及它的電影創新分部的合作

