1
00:00:19,954 --> 00:00:25,187
- 別 停手 - 你個該死的傻冒
- No. Stop. - You silly fucking twit.

2
00:00:25,187 --> 00:00:29,515
你特么的就是一個腦殘的騷貨 你心知肚明吧
You are one stupid fucking bitch, you know that.

3
00:00:29,515 --> 00:00:33,008
- 閉上你的鳥嘴 - 別
- Shut the fuck up. - No.

4
00:00:36,872 --> 00:00:38,727
你在這啊
There you are.

5
00:00:39,868 --> 00:00:40,708
別 別
No! No.

6
00:00:44,140 --> 00:00:46,691
你個小屁精
You little shit.

7
00:00:46,691 --> 00:00:47,441
別 
No!

8
00:01:40,685 --> 00:01:42,113
安娜塔西雅 斯蒂爾
Anastasia Steele?

9
00:01:46,224 --> 00:01:48,203
謝謝
Thanks.

10
00:02:45,374 --> 00:02:47,350
好 知道了
Yeah, got it.

11
00:02:47,350 --> 00:02:50,923
- 早上好 海德先生 - 安娜 叫我杰克就好
- Good morning, Mr Hyde. - Anna, please, just Jack.

12
00:02:50,923 --> 00:02:53,608
茶 沒記錯吧 淡淡的紅茶
Tea right? Weak, black.

13
00:02:54,420 --> 00:02:58,696
其實應該是我去幫你買熱飲 不過謝謝了 杰克
I'm supposed to get this for you but Thank you! Jack.

14
00:03:13,677 --> 00:03:20,120
嗨 這里太棒了 到處都是珊瑚 海龜 和美酒 還有
Hi! This is amazing. It's all coral and turtles and booze and..

15
00:03:20,120 --> 00:03:23,083
你應該一起來 你為什么不來呢
You should be here. Why aren't you here?

16
00:03:23,083 --> 00:03:24,514
告訴我那個人渣哥們
And tell that douchebag

17
00:03:24,515 --> 00:03:27,191
我要好好浪一天
brother of mine to take a day off for once.

18
00:03:27,191 --> 00:03:29,921
- 好了 再見安娜 - 再見啦
- Alright, Bye Anna. - Bye..!

19
00:04:12,912 --> 00:04:16,520
- 立馬就要嗎 - 不 他們可以等一下
- This for me? Nah, they can wait.

20
00:04:16,520 --> 00:04:19,791
哦 光彩照人啊 今晚是有約嗎
Okay. Look nice. Going out tonight?

21
00:04:19,791 --> 00:04:24,672
今晚我朋友搞了個攝影展
A friend of mine has a photography exhibition opening tonight.

22
00:04:24,672 --> 00:04:27,772
- 那 我可以走了嗎 - 沒問題
- So, can I go? - Good.

23
00:04:27,772 --> 00:04:30,401
你是怎么搞定那些底稿的
How did you make out with those manuscripts?

24
00:04:30,402 --> 00:04:31,955
噢 其實真的挺好的
Oh, really great actually.

25
00:04:31,955 --> 00:04:35,490
像這個 嗯 音狐
...This one, um.. Voice Fox.

26
00:04:35,490 --> 00:04:37,589
引人入勝 我愛不釋手
...I coudn't put it down.

27
00:04:37,589 --> 00:04:42,477
它文筆犀利 主旨明確 而且我覺得它真的很有內涵
It's so sharp and relevant and I think it's really got something.

28
00:04:42,477 --> 00:04:44,905
- 真是這樣嗎 - 對
- You think? - Yeah.

29
00:04:44,905 --> 00:04:47,460
- 好 我會看看的  - 太好了
- Alright, I'll check it out. - Great.

30
00:04:47,460 --> 00:04:50,444
- 玩的開心 安娜 - 謝謝 - 今天辛苦啦
- Have fun tonight Anna...thank You. - Thanks for today.

31
00:04:52,358 --> 00:04:55,378
- 再見 漢娜  -再見
- Goodnight Hanna. - Bye.

32
00:05:12,126 --> 00:05:13,289
謝謝
Thanks.

33
00:05:29,341 --> 00:05:31,009
額滴神啊
Oh my God.

34
00:05:32,144 --> 00:05:34,517
老天爺啊
Jesus Christ.

35
00:05:42,153 --> 00:05:45,621
安娜 你來了
Anna! You made it.

36
00:05:46,146 --> 00:05:51,338
何塞  這里怎么到處都是我的照片
Jose. It's like, so much of my face in here.

37
00:05:51,338 --> 00:05:54,668
如果我先和你打招呼 你肯定會覺得很不好意思
If I had asked, You'd been like I'm too shy.

38
00:05:54,668 --> 00:05:58,052
- 對啊 - 但你的照片
- Yeah. - But you...

39
00:05:59,182 --> 00:06:02,380
- 是我最得意的作品 - 這實在是 額
- Is my best stuff. - That's... um...

40
00:06:02,380 --> 00:06:07,304
- 你喜歡它們嗎 - 這些照片太
- Do you like them? - They are super...

41
00:06:07,830 --> 00:06:09,461
太大了
Large.

42
00:06:10,559 --> 00:06:15,003
有位男士把肖像照都買下來了
All portraits were sold to one man.

43
00:06:16,202 --> 00:06:18,380
你在開玩笑吧
You're kidding.

44
00:06:20,157 --> 00:06:23,786
顯然 有人很喜歡它們
Well, somebody likes them.

45
00:06:24,111 --> 00:06:27,234
他們把第六區的作品全買下了
They just bought all six.

46
00:06:27,234 --> 00:06:30,105
- 第六區全部作品 - 今天的晚餐我請客 沒問題吧
- All six? - Dinner's on me tonight, Okay?

47
00:06:31,380 --> 00:06:32,930
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.

48
00:07:04,000 --> 00:07:05,387
安娜塔西雅
Anastasia.

49
00:07:10,481 --> 00:07:13,588
是你 是不是 就是你把這些照片都買下的吧
It was you. Wasn't it? You just went and buy all of this?

50
00:07:14,607 --> 00:07:17,777
我不喜歡其他人對你評頭論足
I don't like strangers talking at you.

51
00:07:18,770 --> 00:07:21,797
你為什么會在這
Why are you here?

52
00:07:22,265 --> 00:07:24,117
為了等你
For you.

53
00:07:25,162 --> 00:07:30,829
嗨 我們找個地方好好聊聊好嗎
Hey. Can we talk somewhere... Private?

54
00:07:30,829 --> 00:07:31,489
不行
No.

55
00:07:32,319 --> 00:07:34,966
好吧 我不是很擅長做這種事 而且我也
Okay I'm not very good at this. I've never had..

56
00:07:35,391 --> 00:07:37,705
我也不想再做一次
Never wanted to try again.

57
00:07:40,241 --> 00:07:43,190
- 克里斯蒂安 我覺得這不是個好提議 - 我們聊聊吧
- Christian. I know, it's not a good idea. - Let's talk.

58
00:07:43,190 --> 00:07:45,790
行嗎 只是聊聊
Okay? Just talk please.

59
00:07:46,843 --> 00:07:48,874
和我一起吃晚餐
Have dinner with me.

60
00:07:54,719 --> 00:07:56,868
好 行 我可以和你吃飯
Okay, fine. I'll have dinner with you.

61
00:07:58,620 --> 00:08:04,110
只是因為我很餓 但是我們只是聊聊 僅此而已 沒有其他
Because I'm hungry, but we are only talking. And that is it.

62
00:08:06,308 --> 00:08:10,180
- 你們還要再考慮一下嗎 - 不用 兩塊牛排 一份中薯
- Would you like some more time? - No,Two steaks, medium fries.

63
00:08:10,180 --> 00:08:11,278
一份蔬菜沙拉
Green vegetables.

64
00:08:11,608 --> 00:08:14,019
還有我的沙拉要超大份的
Actually I'm gonna have a King more Salad.

65
00:08:15,678 --> 00:08:17,317
行
Fine..

66
00:08:17,543 --> 00:08:20,072
最后來兩杯紅酒
And two glasses of Browseable Liquares.
	~
67
00:08:20,072 --> 00:08:21,807
先生 我們的紅酒是成瓶賣的
We only sell that by the bottle sir.

67
00:08:21,807 --> 00:08:24,103
- 那就一瓶 - 好的 先生
- A bottle then. - Yes Sir.

68
00:08:25,388 --> 00:08:27,118
謝謝
Thanks.

69
00:08:27,828 --> 00:08:29,357
所以
So...

70
00:08:29,357 --> 00:08:31,073
我們聊聊吧
Let's talk.

71
00:08:36,248 --> 00:08:38,670
我想要你回來
I want you back.

72
00:08:39,525 --> 00:08:42,148
我想要重新協商一下我們的協議
I like to re-negotiate terms.

73
00:08:43,380 --> 00:08:45,968
但我不知道怎么協商
But I don't see how.

74
00:08:47,370 --> 00:08:50,607
因為你會說這就是你做事的方式
Of things you would said That's the way you are.

75
00:08:50,607 --> 00:08:54,181
但是上次發生的事 絕對不會再發生
But what happened last time. Is not gonna happen again.

76
00:08:54,181 --> 00:08:55,828
你怎么能這么說
How can you say that?

77
00:08:58,000 --> 00:09:00,570
我知道是我讓你來
I know that I asked you to,

78
00:09:00,570 --> 00:09:03,356
來突破我的承受極限 但是
...show me how far I can go but..

79
00:09:06,380 --> 00:09:09,598
你還沒有擺脫你所遭受的痛苦
You aren't getting off on the pain you inflicted.

80
00:09:12,869 --> 00:09:14,993
痛苦依舊在你心里滋生繁衍
That's still in you.

81
00:09:14,993 --> 00:09:17,067
我正在努力擺脫它
I'm working on it.

82
00:09:17,067 --> 00:09:20,179
擺脫什么
Working on what?

83
00:09:22,376 --> 00:09:24,993
如果你不能對我敞開心扉 我是沒有辦法回去的
I can't do this if you won't talk to me.

84
00:09:26,593 --> 00:09:29,356
- 你想了解什么 - 你的一切 
- What do you wanna know? - Everything.

85
00:09:30,958 --> 00:09:32,084
行
Fine.

86
00:09:47,413 --> 00:09:49,063
嘿 我們自己來
Yo, we'll manage.

87
00:09:59,306 --> 00:10:01,376
我四歲的時候 我的生母死了
My birth mother died when I was four.

88
00:10:01,891 --> 00:10:04,626
她是個癮君子。
She was an addict, crack.

89
00:10:05,425 --> 00:10:07,313
其他的你就可以自己想象了
You could fill in the blanks.

90
00:10:08,154 --> 00:10:10,547
- 為什么你之前不告訴我 - 我說了
- Why didn't you tell me that? - I did..

91
00:10:10,547 --> 00:10:13,925
但是你當時在睡覺
But you were asleep at that time.

92
00:10:15,242 --> 00:10:19,202
好吧 行 額
Okay. Well, umm..

93
00:10:19,202 --> 00:10:20,617
一般來說
Generally...

94
00:10:21,468 --> 00:10:26,510
交流的關鍵是交流雙方都意識清醒
A key part of communication is that both parties be conscious.

95
00:10:29,364 --> 00:10:33,079
我很抱歉你媽媽發生那種事
I'm really sorry about your mother.

96
00:10:34,232 --> 00:10:36,905
都過去了
It's in the past.

97
00:10:36,905 --> 00:10:41,221
現在 我帶你來這是為了討論別的
Now, I brought you here to negotiate.

98
00:10:41,834 --> 00:10:43,833
你要簽訂新協議嗎
You are open to new terms?

99
00:10:46,361 --> 00:10:48,348
沒有規定
No rules.

100
00:10:49,217 --> 00:10:50,698
沒有懲罰
No punishments.

101
00:10:54,689 --> 00:11:00,143
沒有規定 沒有懲罰 還有不能再有事瞞著我
No rules. No punishments. And no more secrets.

102
00:11:01,238 --> 00:11:02,994
沒問題
I can do that..

103
00:11:02,994 --> 00:11:06,234
你想要一個  你叫它什么
You want a... What do you call it?

104
00:11:06,706 --> 00:11:08,848
傳教士式的關系么
A vanilla relationship?

105
00:11:09,262 --> 00:11:11,519
我是說我們只做你能接受的事
I mean we only do what you are comfortable with.

106
00:11:13,259 --> 00:11:15,257
但是你需要那些啊
But you need all these things.

107
00:11:17,039 --> 00:11:19,142
我更需要你
I need you more.

108
00:11:26,363 --> 00:11:30,213
- 斯蒂爾女士 - 謝謝你泰勒
- Ms Steele. - Thanks Taylor.

109
00:11:34,896 --> 00:11:38,699
只是送你而已 我沒別的要求
No strings attached.

110
00:12:02,759 --> 00:12:06,413
有點小饑渴 但知道克制 我喜歡
This is spiky. I like it.

111
00:12:10,543 --> 00:12:16,756
- 我明天給你打電話 - 好的 晚安
- I'll call you tomorrow. - Okay, good night.

112
00:12:58,209 --> 00:13:00,042
安娜
Anna!

113
00:13:00,042 --> 00:13:02,395
- 我聽說了很多關于你的事哦 - 噢
- I've been hearing a lot of good things about you. - Oh.

114
00:13:02,395 --> 00:13:03,693
我早就告訴你了 莉茲
Told you Liz..

115
00:13:03,693 --> 00:13:06,556
- 她確實要閱讀 - 嗨 杰克
- This one actually reads. - Hey Jack.

116
00:13:06,556 --> 00:13:09,744
人事部的大佬到這來干嘛啊 我們有什么麻煩了嗎
What's the head of HR doing lurking around? Are we in trouble?

117
00:13:09,744 --> 00:13:12,667
那倒沒有 我來這只是為了鼓勵一下她
Not at all, I'm just here to encourage.

118
00:13:12,959 --> 00:13:14,387
真的么 我想
Really? Well, I think a

119
00:13:14,388 --> 00:13:17,244
在勞里那兒喝幾杯倒是能解決這個問題
round of drinks at Lauries would do the trick.

120
00:13:17,647 --> 00:13:20,557
不好意思 我還有會要開 不然我肯定去
Sorry meetings, otherwise...

121
00:13:20,557 --> 00:13:24,364
- 誰是勞里 - 哦 是轉角處的一家酒吧
- Who's Laurie? - Oh it's a bar around the corner.

122
00:13:24,364 --> 00:13:26,544
周五去那是我們的慣例
Friday is a bit of a ritual.

123
00:13:27,150 --> 00:13:31,732
- 你應該來 - 確實 還是要社交一下啊
- You should come. - Absolutely, go network.

124
00:13:31,732 --> 00:13:35,309
不 我想去的 但是我今晚已經有安排了
No, I would.. I have plans tonight.

125
00:13:35,579 --> 00:13:39,336
有別的安排也可以去喝一杯嘛 很快的啊
So have your plan come along. Just for a quick one.

126
00:13:39,783 --> 00:13:41,777
你好 對
Hello? Yeah..

127
00:13:45,437 --> 00:13:47,309
玩得開心哦
Have fun.

128
00:13:55,925 --> 00:14:00,583
- 安娜塔西雅 - 不好意思 我們之前認識么
- Anastasia. - I'm sorry, have we met before?

129
00:14:01,166 --> 00:14:02,715
沒事 
It's okay.

130
00:14:03,268 --> 00:14:05,210
我就一無名小卒
I am nobody.

131
00:14:05,210 --> 00:14:09,938
嘿 勞里在這邊 走吧 我請客
Hey, Lauries is this way. Come on, I'm buying.

132
00:14:15,317 --> 00:14:18,285
- 好啦 來了 - 謝啦
- Alright...Here we go. - Thanks.

133
00:14:18,285 --> 00:14:19,770
大家人都去哪啦
Where is everyone?

134
00:14:19,770 --> 00:14:21,744
你知道的 現在還早嘛
You know..Still early.

135
00:14:21,744 --> 00:14:25,672
你對音狐的見解很有趣嘛
Your comments on Voice Fox were interesting.

136
00:14:25,672 --> 00:14:28,363
我一般不是很喜歡政治驚悚片
I'm not usually into political thrillers.

137
00:14:28,363 --> 00:14:29,945
哦 我覺得那本書
Yeah, well, I think they are

138
00:14:29,946 --> 00:14:32,714
很像但丁的地獄 但是
parallels with Dante's inferno were amazing but..

139
00:14:32,714 --> 00:14:35,996
你說服我了 我會去看看
Yeah, you convince me. I'm reading.

140
00:14:35,996 --> 00:14:38,404
哦 這不錯哦
Oh. That's great.

141
00:14:38,404 --> 00:14:39,843
嘿
Hey.

142
00:14:39,843 --> 00:14:43,996
嗨 克里斯蒂安 這是杰克 海德
Hi, Christian this is Jack Hyde.

143
00:14:43,996 --> 00:14:49,135
- 我是她的男朋友 - 我是她的老板
- I am her boyfriend. - I am the boss.

144
00:14:49,135 --> 00:14:52,766
- 你想喝點什么 克里斯 - 謝謝了 杰克
- What will you have, Chris? - Thanks, Jack.

145
00:14:53,123 --> 00:14:54,459
下次吧
Another time.

146
00:14:57,497 --> 00:14:58,445
謝謝
Thanks.

147
00:15:03,117 --> 00:15:04,059
有機會再約
Another time.

148
00:15:05,558 --> 00:15:08,181
我沒想到你居然那么跟他說話
I can't believe you just talked to him like that.

149
00:15:08,181 --> 00:15:11,202
- 他可是在覬覦我的東西 - 誰是你的
- He wants what is mine. - What's yours?

150
00:15:11,202 --> 00:15:13,331
有點過分了
It's a little presumptuous.

151
00:15:14,319 --> 00:15:16,938
他就是我上司 克里斯蒂安 你冷靜一點
He is my boss, Christian, You gotta calm down.

152
00:15:18,235 --> 00:15:20,771
冷靜不是我的專長
Calm isn't really my forte.

153
00:15:22,401 --> 00:15:23,901
我知道什么能讓你冷靜冷靜
I know something that could help.

154
00:15:29,919 --> 00:15:31,713
你知道這不是我想要的
You know this is not what in mind.

155
00:15:33,327 --> 00:15:36,124
你上次購物是什么時候
When is the last time you went shopping?

156
00:15:36,124 --> 00:15:37,692
一個星期前在休斯頓
Houston. A week ago.

157
00:15:38,583 --> 00:15:41,128
- 你買了什么 - 一家航空公司
- What did you buy? - An Airline.

158
00:15:45,507 --> 00:15:46,603
接著
Here.

159
00:15:49,744 --> 00:15:51,213
你喜歡的新口味
Your new favorite flavor.

160
00:16:00,623 --> 00:16:02,147
內個
Excuse me.

161
00:16:14,654 --> 00:16:16,174
你需要幫忙嗎
Do you need a hand with that?

162
00:16:17,759 --> 00:16:19,364
我可以搞定
I'll manage.

163
00:16:24,837 --> 00:16:26,634
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're doing.

164
00:16:26,635 --> 00:16:29,297
怎么了嘛 我正想著要做什么呢
What? I'm being a culinary mastermind.

165
00:16:29,297 --> 00:16:37,408
- 你只需要跟我提需求就好了 - 我覺得我們得慢慢來
- You only have to ask. - I think we should take it slow.

166
00:16:37,793 --> 00:16:41,540
- 好 - 嗯 好
- Okay. - Ok... Okay.

167
00:16:44,713 --> 00:16:47,039
跟我說說出版社的事吧
Tell me about SIP.

168
00:16:47,266 --> 00:16:51,494
- 最近怎么樣 - 挺好的
- How is it going? - It's good.

169
00:16:52,275 --> 00:16:55,738
杰克好像真的對我的觀點感興趣
Jack seems genuinely interested in my opinion.

170
00:16:56,214 --> 00:16:57,439
有什么硬性要求嗎
What's moral like?

171
00:16:57,829 --> 00:17:00,054
要求的話 你說得就像我們每天早上
Moral? You mean like we all sitting in a circle

172
00:17:00,054 --> 00:17:02,260
圍坐在一起唱公司司歌那樣
and singing the company song in the morning.

173
00:17:02,804 --> 00:17:05,761
只是為了讓大家都開心
That's just for well managed to people happy.

174
00:17:06,406 --> 00:17:08,236
- 噢 不是吧 - 怎么了
- Oh my God. - What?

175
00:17:09,531 --> 00:17:11,217
你收購了出版社嗎
You are buying SIP?

176
00:17:12,174 --> 00:17:14,270
不 你不能這樣 那是我的工作
No, you can't do that. That's my job.

177
00:17:14,631 --> 00:17:16,783
你不能干涉我的工作
You can't start interfering in my career.

178
00:17:16,783 --> 00:17:18,709
不是你想的那樣
It's not about that.

179
00:17:18,709 --> 00:17:22,384
我想要進駐出版業 他們是最好的選擇
I've wanted to move into publishing. They're the best fit.

180
00:17:23,576 --> 00:17:25,579
但這樣你就是我上司了
But you're gonna be my boss.

181
00:17:25,579 --> 00:17:28,154
嚴格來講 我會是你上司上司的上司
Technically, I'll be your bosses bosses' boss.

182
00:17:28,670 --> 00:17:31,661
然后我就要跟我上司上司的上司睡了
And I'm gonna be sleeping with my bosses bosses' boss.

183
00:17:31,661 --> 00:17:33,525
沒錯 你現在正跟他吵架呢
Alright now, you're arguing with him.

184
00:17:33,525 --> 00:17:35,136
是啊 因為他就是個蠢貨
Yeah, because he's being an ass.

185
00:17:35,432 --> 00:17:36,776
蠢貨 你確定嗎
An ass. Really?

186
00:17:37,127 --> 00:17:38,870
蠢貨
Ass.

187
00:17:49,386 --> 00:17:51,226
你這樣是越界了
You know that's off limits.

188
00:17:54,523 --> 00:17:56,441
我需要一份行為指南
I'm gonna need a road map.

189
00:18:18,505 --> 00:18:20,637
我以為你想慢慢來
I thought you wanted to take it slow.

190
00:18:24,446 --> 00:18:26,502
你想要什么 安娜塔西雅
What do you want Anastasia?

191
00:18:29,451 --> 00:18:31,494
你得說出來
Well to communicate you have to tell me.

192
00:18:35,328 --> 00:18:37,522
我要你
I want you.

193
00:18:53,744 --> 00:18:55,064
我穿得太拘束了
I'm too dressed.

194
00:19:07,510 --> 00:19:08,755
不要停
Keep going.

195
00:19:34,366 --> 00:19:35,691
親我
Kiss me.

196
00:20:10,455 --> 00:20:14,231
你想要什么 安娜塔西雅
What do you want Anastasia?

197
00:20:15,866 --> 00:20:18,290
我要你的全部
I want all of you.

198
00:20:55,879 --> 00:20:58,202
對性這方面
For sex.

199
00:21:04,075 --> 00:21:08,486
我看過奧斯汀和勃朗特
I was reading Austin and Bronte.

200
00:21:08,486 --> 00:21:10,913
沒人能達到那樣的標準
Nobody ever measure up to that.

201
00:21:12,834 --> 00:21:15,886
我想我在等那個特別的人
I guess I was waiting for something exceptional.

202
00:21:18,522 --> 00:21:20,702
直到我遇見了你
And then I met you.

203
00:21:24,164 --> 00:21:26,350
那奧斯汀小姐
Will Miss Austin.

204
00:21:27,523 --> 00:21:29,484
贊成這樣嗎
Approve of this?

205
00:21:31,962 --> 00:21:33,371
我也是很浪漫主義的
I was being romantic.

206
00:21:33,371 --> 00:21:36,609
而你就那么走進我的生活 用你的浪蕩小丁丁勾引我
And then you just go and distract me with your kinky fuckery.

207
00:21:36,992 --> 00:21:39,342
- 浪蕩小丁丁 - 嗯哼
- Kinky Fuckery. - Ah uhh!

208
00:21:39,342 --> 00:21:42,034
雖然不知道什么意思 但聽起來還不錯
I don't know what that is. But I like the sound of it.

209
00:22:20,389 --> 00:22:23,194
你睡得很安穩 我就沒有叫醒你
You look so peaceful I didn't wanna wake you.

210
00:22:25,385 --> 00:22:26,755
沒什么可吃的早飯
It's not much for breakfast.

211
00:22:27,117 --> 00:22:29,072
除非你想吃冷餐
Unless you want cold stir-fry.

212
00:22:34,838 --> 00:22:38,054
給你 這是你給我的支票 你應該拿回去
Here. The check you gave me for one day You should have it back.

213
00:22:38,054 --> 00:22:39,262
收下吧
Keep it.

214
00:22:39,262 --> 00:22:41,480
收下 這是2萬4美元
Keep it? It's 24 thousand dollars.

215
00:22:41,708 --> 00:22:43,158
安娜
Anna...

216
00:22:44,096 --> 00:22:46,004
我十五分鐘就能賺那么多
I make that kind of money every fifteen minutes...

217
00:22:46,004 --> 00:22:47,048
所以 收下吧
So keep it.

218
00:23:10,355 --> 00:23:12,522
安德里亞 早上好
Andrea, good morning.

219
00:23:13,431 --> 00:23:15,274
能麻煩你轉2萬4美金
Could you please transfer $24,000

220
00:23:15,275 --> 00:23:17,508
到安娜塔西雅 斯蒂爾女士的賬戶上嗎
into the account of Ms Anastasia Steele?

221
00:23:17,508 --> 00:23:18,762
不行 你這是干什么
No. What are you doing?

222
00:23:19,581 --> 00:23:21,621
好的 謝謝
That's fine, Thank you.

223
00:23:23,626 --> 00:23:26,134
你怎么會有我賬戶信息
Why do you have my bank account details?

224
00:23:26,944 --> 00:23:28,560
這附近有什么好吃的早飯嗎
What's good for breakfast around here?

225
00:23:28,560 --> 00:23:31,183
克里斯蒂安 你怎么知道我銀行賬戶的
Christian, how do you have my bank information?

226
00:23:36,337 --> 00:23:37,352
謝謝
Thank you.

227
00:23:40,007 --> 00:23:42,096
我付賬比你快哦
Gotta be quicker than that Grey.

228
00:23:45,937 --> 00:23:48,350
今晚我父母要舉辦一個慈善晚會
My parents are hosting a charity ball tonight.

229
00:23:49,016 --> 00:23:51,037
我答應了要參加
I've promised I will make an appearance.

230
00:23:51,038 --> 00:23:52,301
你想跟我一起來嗎
Want you to come with me.

231
00:23:55,015 --> 00:23:59,728
我從沒參加過舞會 沒有合適的衣服
I've never been to a ball. I don't have a dress for that.

232
00:23:59,728 --> 00:24:02,379
而且 我也不會弄頭發
Also, what am I gonna do with my hair?

233
00:24:02,379 --> 00:24:04,043
我認識一個人很專業的
I know someone.

234
00:24:04,043 --> 00:24:06,845
你也不用擔心穿什么
And you don't need to worry about the dress.

235
00:24:06,845 --> 00:24:08,895
都會幫你弄好的
It's all gonna be taken care of.

236
00:24:10,076 --> 00:24:11,624
怎么了
What is it?

237
00:24:13,160 --> 00:24:14,843
剛剛那兒站了個女孩
There was just a girl over

238
00:24:14,844 --> 00:24:17,823
昨天在我公司外面也見到了
there and she was outside my office yesterday.

239
00:24:17,823 --> 00:24:19,401
她還知道我的名字
And she knew my name...

240
00:24:19,401 --> 00:24:23,281
手腕上纏著繃帶 感覺很奇怪
and she had a bandage on her wrist, it was really strange.

241
00:24:25,540 --> 00:24:27,742
我們走吧
We should go.

242
00:24:41,518 --> 00:24:44,765
嘿 最近怎么樣 不錯嗎 那挺好的
Hey, how you doing? Good okay!

243
00:24:57,556 --> 00:25:01,133
嘿 過得好嗎
Hey, how you doing?

244
00:25:28,803 --> 00:25:34,153
- 安娜 - 她就是那個羅賓遜夫人嗎
- Anna! - Is that Mrs. Robinson?

245
00:25:35,628 --> 00:25:36,682
她叫埃琳娜 林肯
Her name is Elena Lincoln.

246
00:25:36,682 --> 00:25:38,957
我不在乎她叫什么 克里斯蒂安
I don't care what her name is Christian.

247
00:25:38,958 --> 00:25:40,550
你帶我來這做什么
Why would you take me there?

248
00:25:40,550 --> 00:25:41,687
為什么你要把我帶來
Why would you take me to

249
00:25:41,688 --> 00:25:43,679
見曾經勾引你虐待你的女人
meet the woman who seduced and abused you?

250
00:25:43,679 --> 00:25:47,256
我們早就不是那種關系了 我們只是朋友而已
Our relationship ended years ago, we're just friends.

251
00:25:47,256 --> 00:25:51,253
- 和商業伙伴 - 商業伙伴 你在逗我嗎
- And business partners. - Business partners? Are you kidding me?

252
00:25:51,917 --> 00:25:56,397
你把其他奴隸也帶到這里來嗎
Would you take your subs there?

253
00:25:57,204 --> 00:26:00,637
我的天 你是為了什么 是要獲得她的批準嗎 到底是為什么
Oh my god, for what? Her approval? What is this?

254
00:26:00,637 --> 00:26:02,877
不 不是那樣的
No. It's not like that.

255
00:26:02,877 --> 00:26:06,353
今早我看見的那個女孩就是她們的其中一員 對吧
That girl I saw this morning was one of them, wasn't she?

256
00:26:06,353 --> 00:26:07,802
這個等會兒到我那兒再談
Let's discuss this back in my place,

257
00:26:07,803 --> 00:26:09,454
我可以找人來給你弄弄頭發
I can have someone come by, do your hair.

258
00:26:09,454 --> 00:26:11,110
克里斯蒂安 我不關心什么頭發
Christian, I don't care about my hair.

259
00:26:11,111 --> 00:26:12,462
告訴我 到底發生什么了
Explain to me, what's going on?

260
00:26:12,462 --> 00:26:15,208
到我那兒去后我會告訴你的 來吧
I'll explain when we are there. Come on.

261
00:26:16,087 --> 00:26:18,261
好吧 你可以選擇走路或者讓我抱你走
Ok, you either walk or I can carry you.

262
00:26:18,261 --> 00:26:20,587
- 你不會這么做的 - 不 這是你的選擇
- You wouldn't do that. - No it's your choice.

263
00:26:22,927 --> 00:26:25,165
算了 好吧 我自己走
Okay, fine fine.. I'll walk.

264
00:26:29,830 --> 00:26:32,721
她叫利拉 威廉姆斯
Her name is Leila Williams.

265
00:26:32,721 --> 00:26:35,351
兩年前她曾給我當過一段時間的奴隸
She's my sub for a while about 2 years ago.

266
00:26:35,351 --> 00:26:38,047
她怎么了
What happened to her?

267
00:26:38,047 --> 00:26:42,741
她野心太大了 我不想慣著她 所以關系就終止了
She wanted more. I didn't. So I ended it.

268
00:26:43,891 --> 00:26:46,654
她離開后結了婚 我以為她已經看開了
She left, got married, I thought she moved on.

269
00:26:46,654 --> 00:26:49,262
但隨后她的老公在車禍中去世
But then her husband died in a car crash.

270
00:26:49,262 --> 00:26:51,957
她徹底崩潰了
She had a break down.

271
00:26:54,607 --> 00:26:57,214
那么她現在想要什么呢
And what does she want now?

272
00:26:57,728 --> 00:26:59,690
我和你之前在喬治亞的時候
When you and I were in Georgia together.

273
00:26:59,690 --> 00:27:02,098
她突然出現
She turned up here and tried to slit her wrist

274
00:27:02,098 --> 00:27:04,193
想在我的管家瓊斯太太面前割腕自殺
in front of Mrs Jones, my housekeeper.

275
00:27:04,193 --> 00:27:04,969
我的天哪
Oh my God...

276
00:27:04,969 --> 00:27:08,443
凱爾送她去了醫院 但當我到那兒時
Cale took her to the hospital, But the time I got there.

277
00:27:08,443 --> 00:27:10,153
她不見了
She taken off.

278
00:27:10,153 --> 00:27:12,535
我的人一直嘗試找她
My people have been trying to find her.

279
00:27:13,462 --> 00:27:16,250
你的人
Your people?

280
00:27:16,479 --> 00:27:19,058
是搜集這些材料的人嗎
Is that who put this together?

281
00:27:22,747 --> 00:27:24,965
是不是也有我的調查材料
Is there one on me?

282
00:27:29,525 --> 00:27:31,654
讓我看看
Let me see it.

283
00:27:58,666 --> 00:28:01,973
目標在里士滿路上的克萊頓五金店打工
Subject works part time at Clayton Hardware, Richmond Road.

284
00:28:03,026 --> 00:28:06,963
你知道嗎 他們都沒記錄我上廁所的次數
You know, they didn't time my bathroom breaks.

285
00:28:07,398 --> 00:28:10,242
你應該把你的錢要回來
You should probably get your money back.

286
00:28:11,050 --> 00:28:14,497
我讓他們全面調查過每個奴隸
I had them drawn up and any perspective submissive.

287
00:28:15,055 --> 00:28:16,356
干得好
Nice, Jesus.

288
00:28:16,786 --> 00:28:19,065
我沒想過會變成這樣
I had no idea what this was gonna become.

289
00:28:19,065 --> 00:28:21,070
- 我不知道事態會發展得不一樣 - 不一樣
- I didn't know it would be different. - Different?

290
00:28:21,930 --> 00:28:23,970
真的嗎
Really?

291
00:28:24,674 --> 00:28:27,132
這就是你之前帶我去羅賓遜太太那兒的原因嗎
Is that why you brought me to Mrs. Robinson?

292
00:28:27,132 --> 00:28:30,594
你曾經把其他所有女人帶到那兒 僅僅是因為我與眾不同嗎
Where you brought all the other women because I'm so different?

293
00:28:31,956 --> 00:28:34,049
我承認那樣做是錯誤的
That was wrong, I admit.

294
00:28:34,050 --> 00:28:37,190
全都錯了 所有的事情都是錯的
It's all wrong, all of this is wrong.

295
00:28:39,325 --> 00:28:43,192
你把錢存進我的賬戶里 但我并不想要你的錢
You put money into my account. That I don't want it.

296
00:28:43,403 --> 00:28:46,250
你甚至還買下我工作的公司
You bought the company I work for.

297
00:28:47,070 --> 00:28:50,774
這不叫做戀愛關系 克里斯蒂安 這叫做占有關系
This isn't a relationship Christian, It's ownership.

298
00:28:52,608 --> 00:28:55,494
我想試著了解你
I'm trying to understand you.

299
00:28:55,753 --> 00:29:00,458
我只是想離你更近一些
I'm just wanting to get close to you.

300
00:29:02,072 --> 00:29:03,714
你總是做一些奇怪的事
But it's really difficult to do

301
00:29:03,715 --> 00:29:06,363
讓人很難去理解你
that when you keep doing bizarre things like this.

302
00:29:06,363 --> 00:29:07,662
我不知道該怎么接近你
And it's really difficult

303
00:29:07,663 --> 00:29:09,898
你甚至都不讓我觸碰你
to do that when you won't let me touch you.

304
00:29:18,892 --> 00:29:21,796
到我房間來
Come to my bedroom.

305
00:29:22,135 --> 00:29:25,320
你瘋了嗎 性愛解決不了這個問題
Sex is not gonna fix this right now. Are you insane?

306
00:29:25,320 --> 00:29:25,975
安娜
Anna.

307
00:29:26,522 --> 00:29:28,081
求你了
Please.

308
00:29:31,989 --> 00:29:33,903
你想要個行為指南嗎
You wanted a road map?

309
00:29:48,749 --> 00:29:50,256
從這開始
Start here.

310
00:30:25,101 --> 00:30:27,194
這是我能承受的范圍
Those are my boundaries.

311
00:30:31,616 --> 00:30:33,707
還可以接受
I can live with that.

312
00:30:35,400 --> 00:30:38,159
那都是你的了
Then I'm all yours.

313
00:30:44,493 --> 00:30:46,689
格雷先生 你的客人已經到了
Mr Grey, your appointment has arrived.

314
00:30:47,758 --> 00:30:49,660
把帶他到安娜的房間
Send him into Anna's room.

315
00:30:51,623 --> 00:30:54,047
- 他到了 - 誰來了
- He's here. - Who is here?

316
00:31:00,057 --> 00:31:02,336
頭發挽起來 會很好看
Harold, I think yes?

317
00:31:02,336 --> 00:31:05,762
你的脖子非常美
Your neck is beautiful.

318
00:31:05,762 --> 00:31:08,109
克里斯蒂安
Christian?

319
00:31:12,716 --> 00:31:14,817
再見啦 貝拉
Ciao, Bella.

320
00:32:01,244 --> 00:32:04,222
你打算一直傻站在那嗎
You're just gonna stand there gawking?

321
00:32:04,222 --> 00:32:07,637
是啊 有可能
Yeah, I think I might.

322
00:32:26,494 --> 00:32:28,675
我在想
So I was thinking.

323
00:32:29,420 --> 00:32:33,839
如果你戴上它 今晚可能會更刺激
Tonight might be more stimulating. If you wore these.

324
00:32:37,628 --> 00:32:40,855
這個要怎么戴
How am I supposed to wear those?

325
00:32:41,334 --> 00:32:46,270
首先你要把它弄濕
Well, you have to get them wet first.

326
00:32:46,659 --> 00:32:47,619
想知道嗎
Curious?

327
00:32:52,661 --> 00:32:54,432
好吧
Okay.

328
00:32:54,864 --> 00:32:56,651
張開嘴
Open your mouth.

329
00:33:05,888 --> 00:33:07,774
很好
Good.

330
00:33:09,584 --> 00:33:12,502
現在轉過身去 彎下腰
Now turn, bend over.

331
00:33:13,072 --> 00:33:16,625
不 我是不會讓你把它放進我屁股的
No, you're not putting those in my butt.

332
00:33:16,625 --> 00:33:18,830
不是放你屁股
They don't go in your butt.

333
00:33:38,498 --> 00:33:40,228
別動
Stay still.

334
00:33:48,164 --> 00:33:50,506
站直后轉過來
Stand up straight and turn around.

335
00:33:59,609 --> 00:34:01,261
感覺怎么樣
How is it feel?

336
00:34:03,640 --> 00:34:05,095
有點奇怪
Weird.

337
00:34:06,322 --> 00:34:07,402
但挺舒服
But good.

338
00:34:09,967 --> 00:34:12,640
然后呢
What do they do?

339
00:34:13,548 --> 00:34:15,477
你會知道的
You'll find out.

340
00:34:17,555 --> 00:34:22,271
戴上這對銀飾 效果會更好
Wear the silver satin, It will go well with this.

341
00:34:25,969 --> 00:34:29,043
別緊張 只是對耳飾
Don't worry. They are for your ears.

342
00:34:51,167 --> 00:34:53,821
我有跟你提過這是個假面舞會嗎
Did I mention that it was a masked ball?

343
00:34:53,821 --> 00:34:54,315
沒有
No.

344
00:34:58,037 --> 00:35:00,840
你的新保鏢們也要戴上面具嗎
Your new bodyguards need to wear these too?

345
00:35:02,011 --> 00:35:03,224
為了安全起見
Just being safe.

346
00:35:03,224 --> 00:35:05,982
實際上不會有人察覺到他們
You won't even notice they are here.

347
00:35:07,354 --> 00:35:09,015
來吧
Come on!

348
00:35:51,427 --> 00:35:55,560
- 所有人都在看我們 - 都在看你
- Everybody is looking at us. - Not us, you.

349
00:35:55,560 --> 00:35:58,086
克里斯蒂安 我真高興你們能來
Christian, I'm so glad you made it.

350
00:35:58,086 --> 00:36:01,189
- 母親  - 叫母親太正式了吧
- Mother. - Mother is so formal honestly.

351
00:36:01,189 --> 00:36:02,936
- 嗨 - 嘿
- Hi. - Hey.

352
00:36:03,767 --> 00:36:05,275
這東西真是太漂亮了
This things are beautiful.

353
00:36:05,276 --> 00:36:08,175
既玄妙神秘 又令人煩惱
And they are mysterious, they are pain in the ass.

354
00:36:09,140 --> 00:36:13,179
- 你真是明艷照人 - 謝謝
- You look spectacular. - Thank you.

355
00:36:13,179 --> 00:36:16,615
- 你也是 這禮服真漂亮 - 謝謝你 安娜
- So do you. This dress is so beautiful. - Thank you Anna.

356
00:36:16,615 --> 00:36:19,153
真的很高興你和克里斯蒂安一起回來
I am so glad you are back with Christian.

357
00:36:19,154 --> 00:36:20,640
沒有你 他魂兒都丟了
He was lost without you.

358
00:36:20,640 --> 00:36:23,528
- 能把舞伴還給我了嗎 - 那當然了
- May I have my date back please? - By all means.

359
00:36:23,528 --> 00:36:27,354
- 不當電燈泡啦 - 這邊請
- Spoil sport. - This way..

360
00:36:38,517 --> 00:36:43,739
安娜 我天哪 你這一身 簡直美得不像話
Anna, My God. Your dress, it should be illegal.

361
00:36:43,739 --> 00:36:44,819
是啊 米婭
Yeah. Mia.

362
00:36:47,617 --> 00:36:51,760
-嗨 差點沒認出你來 -對啊 煥然一新的我
- Hey, I barely recognized you? - Yeah, the new me.

363
00:36:53,045 --> 00:36:57,116
- 嗯 造型很大膽 - 你是怎么忍得了他的呢
- Well, it is very bold. - How do you stand him?

364
00:36:57,116 --> 00:36:59,895
你可知道 他年少時就是調皮搗蛋的大魔頭
Do you know that he was an even bigger pain as a teenager?

365
00:36:59,895 --> 00:37:01,947
被四所學校開除
He got expelled from 4 different schools.

366
00:37:02,420 --> 00:37:04,292
- 都是因為打架斗毆  - 夠了啊
- For brawling. - It's enough.

367
00:37:04,292 --> 00:37:06,135
- 簡直無法無天 - 米婭
- Yeah, totally out of control. - Mia..

368
00:37:06,135 --> 00:37:08,919
- 說夠了吧 - 待會兒見
- Enough. - I'll be right back.

369
00:37:09,573 --> 00:37:11,517
- 嗨 - 安娜
- Hi - Anna?

370
00:37:11,517 --> 00:37:15,216
你等會兒就坐在這兒 挨著卡里克
You will be sitting here darling, Right next to Carrick.

371
00:37:15,216 --> 00:37:17,482
先生們 女士們
Welcome ladies and gentlemen...

372
00:37:17,482 --> 00:37:21,964
歡迎參加一年一度的舞會 眾所周知 今晚所得收益
To our Annual Ball. As you know, proceeds from this evening

373
00:37:21,964 --> 00:37:23,123
都將捐給慈善機構
will go to the charity

374
00:37:23,124 --> 00:37:25,389
這所慈善機構是由我和格雷絲于多年前共同成立的
That Grace and I founded so many years ago.

375
00:37:25,389 --> 00:37:29,753
服務于那些父母為癮君子的兒童們
Coping together, working to make life better for the children.

376
00:37:29,753 --> 00:37:32,169
- 力圖改善他們的生活 - 還好嗎
- Of parents addicted to drugs. - Everything okay?

377
00:37:32,676 --> 00:37:36,560
下面很榮幸把話筒交給我們的主持人
And now thankfully I'll be handing off my speaking duties

378
00:37:36,560 --> 00:37:40,573
紐曼 保羅先生
to our master of ceremonies Mr. Newman Paul.

379
00:37:44,308 --> 00:37:45,148
餓嗎
Hungry?

380
00:37:50,606 --> 00:37:53,182
現在你知道銀球的作用了吧
Now you know what those silver balls do.

381
00:37:53,781 --> 00:37:56,367
- 1萬5千美元 - 1萬5千美元
- 15 thousand dollars. - 15 thousand dollars..

382
00:37:56,367 --> 00:38:00,680
1萬5千美元一次 兩次 成交
Going once, going twice... Sold!

383
00:38:02,816 --> 00:38:05,191
各位先生們 女士們 開門大吉啊 
That's a great start, Ladies and Gentlemen.

384
00:38:05,192 --> 00:38:07,180
2號競拍品是 豪華小屋
Now lot number 2, a weeks vacation..

385
00:38:07,180 --> 00:38:09,480
一周體驗
At a luxury Chalet.

386
00:38:09,480 --> 00:38:13,111
位于科羅拉多州的阿斯彭 捐贈者為克里斯蒂安 格雷先生
in Aspen, Colorado, donated by Mr. Christian Grey.

387
00:38:14,849 --> 00:38:16,831
起拍價為一萬美元
Let's start the bid off at ten thousand dollars.

388
00:38:16,831 --> 00:38:18,566
- 一萬美元 - 謝謝你女士
- Ten thousand. - Thank you ma'am.

389
00:38:18,566 --> 00:38:19,929
一萬美元
Ten thousand dollars.

390
00:38:19,929 --> 00:38:22,338
我都不知道你在阿斯彭也有房子
I didn't know you had a place in Aspen.

391
00:38:22,338 --> 00:38:25,218
我房產可多了去了
I have a lot of places.

392
00:38:25,813 --> 00:38:27,967
1萬7千美元
Seventeen Thousand.

393
00:38:27,967 --> 00:38:29,662
1萬7千美元 謝謝你 先生
Seventeen thousand dollars, thank you, sir.

394
00:38:29,662 --> 00:38:30,176
1萬8
Eighteen?

395
00:38:30,176 --> 00:38:33,016
- 1萬8 - 1萬8千美元 謝謝你
- Eighteen thousand, - Eighteen thousand dollars, thank you!

396
00:38:33,016 --> 00:38:36,957
- 有人出1萬9嗎 - 1萬9 1萬9千美元
- Do I hear 19?..19? - 19! 19 Thousand dollars.

397
00:38:36,957 --> 00:38:37,958
謝謝先生 
Thank you sir. A week of...

398
00:38:37,958 --> 00:38:40,814
美國最佳滑雪勝地一周豪華體驗
Luxury in America's finest ski resort.

399
00:38:40,814 --> 00:38:45,871
- 2萬4千美元 - 新人出手 2萬4千美元
- 24 Thousand dollars. - New blood, 24 Thousand dollars.

400
00:38:45,871 --> 00:38:48,945
- 是有誰出了2萬5千嗎 - 這錢是給你的
- Do I hear 25 Thousand? - The money was for you.

401
00:38:48,945 --> 00:38:51,950
但現在我打算捐給需要這筆錢的人
And now it will go to someone who needs it.

402
00:38:51,950 --> 00:38:54,918
我真是不知道該對你感恩戴德
I don't know whether to worship at your feet...

403
00:38:55,160 --> 00:38:57,166
還是該打你屁屁
Or spank you.

404
00:38:57,680 --> 00:39:01,984
- 一次競價 兩次競價 - 我覺得還是選項二吧
- Going once.. Going twice. - I think, um...Take option two.

405
00:39:03,956 --> 00:39:06,548
銀色禮服的年輕女士 它是你的了
Sold to the young lady in silver.

406
00:39:14,898 --> 00:39:15,899
我們走吧
Let's go.

407
00:39:42,457 --> 00:39:46,178
你喜歡這個
You want this?

408
00:40:23,991 --> 00:40:27,542
如果你覺得太疼了 就讓我停手 明白嗎
If you think it's too much. You just tell me to stop. Understood?

409
00:40:27,542 --> 00:40:28,543
嗯
Yeah.

410
00:40:59,724 --> 00:41:01,445
別動
Hold still.

411
00:41:54,765 --> 00:41:57,604
這是你的房間嗎
Is this your room?

412
00:41:58,067 --> 00:41:59,668
有一陣子是
Once upon a time.

413
00:42:12,300 --> 00:42:13,913
這是誰
Who is this?

414
00:42:17,565 --> 00:42:19,012
是你母親嗎
Is that your mother?

415
00:42:26,288 --> 00:42:28,888
你知道你可以直說你不想談這個的
You know you can just say you don't wanna talk about it.

416
00:42:28,888 --> 00:42:31,670
是 我不想談這個
Yeah, I don't wanna talk about it.

417
00:42:33,199 --> 00:42:36,031
走吧 他們該找我們了
Let's go. They'll be missing us.

418
00:42:37,143 --> 00:42:39,535
啊 我一會兒下去
Uh, I just need a minute.

419
00:42:40,754 --> 00:42:43,183
- 樓下見 - 好
- I'll meet you downstairs. - Okay.

420
00:42:44,251 --> 00:42:46,603
記得戴上假面
Don't forget your mask.

421
00:43:25,230 --> 00:43:28,065
- 什么 - 沒事
- What? - Nothing.

422
00:43:51,772 --> 00:43:53,579
克里斯蒂安有女友了
Christian has a date.

423
00:43:54,170 --> 00:43:58,543
- 我很驚訝 - 什么
- I'm impressed. - I'm sorry?

424
00:43:59,131 --> 00:44:02,937
埃琳娜 我很想見你
Elena. I wanted to meet you.

425
00:44:05,275 --> 00:44:10,233
- 真抱歉 我一點也不想 - 嘿 你不該把我當敵人的
- I can't say the same, excuse me. - Hey, I'm not the enemy.

426
00:44:12,148 --> 00:44:14,942
我知道你對克里斯蒂安的所作所為
I know what you did to Christian.

427
00:44:14,942 --> 00:44:18,364
我所做的不過是讓他認識到真正的自己
All I did was to lead him to the truth of who he really is.

428
00:44:18,910 --> 00:44:22,560
沒有我 他可能會進監獄 或者死掉
Without me, he'd be in jail. Or dead.

429
00:44:22,560 --> 00:44:24,343
他會同意我說的
And he would say the same.

430
00:44:24,343 --> 00:44:28,811
你以為你是他生命里第一個被用來拯救他自己的女人嗎
Do you think you're the first woman he helped to save him?

431
00:44:29,178 --> 00:44:31,988
他的生活里需要一個性奴
He needs a submissive in life.

432
00:44:32,415 --> 00:44:35,466
不僅僅在床上干的那種
Not just in the bed room.

433
00:44:35,837 --> 00:44:40,696
不 他已經變了 那不再是他想要的了
No, he's changing that. It's not he wants anymore.

434
00:44:40,696 --> 00:44:43,140
但他骨子里需要這些 而且你可別以為我是那種
But it's what he needs. And you don't strike me

435
00:44:43,140 --> 00:44:45,475
想要做他性奴的女人 
as the type of women who wants to be owned.

436
00:44:46,282 --> 00:44:50,157
如果你真的想讓他開心 如果你想要幸福
If you really wanna make him happy, If you wanna be happy.

437
00:44:50,849 --> 00:44:54,377
- 那就放手 - 不可能
- You let him go. - There is no way.

438
00:44:54,690 --> 00:44:57,613
像你這樣的人永遠不會明白我們所擁有的一切
That someone like you could never understand what we have.

439
00:44:57,613 --> 00:45:01,509
我也曾經歷過那些 我曾經擁有的也不比你少
I've been there，nothing less.

440
00:45:01,993 --> 00:45:03,481
一點都不
Nothing.

441
00:45:03,823 --> 00:45:06,449
無論你和克里斯蒂安之間發生過什么
Whatever happens between me and Christian,

442
00:45:06,449 --> 00:45:08,543
都與我無關
is none of your goddamn business.

443
00:45:08,543 --> 00:45:11,121
所以你特么離我們遠點
So you stay the fuck away from us.

444
00:45:17,105 --> 00:45:18,443
嘿
Hey.

445
00:45:18,922 --> 00:45:21,610
- 我們是不是可以走了 - 我想走了
- We should think about going. So.. - I wanna go now.

446
00:45:31,350 --> 00:45:32,916
埃琳娜跟你說了什么
What did Elena say to you?

447
00:45:38,706 --> 00:45:41,601
一些老調重彈 無關緊要的話
Nothing I didn't already know.

448
00:45:45,071 --> 00:45:47,458
你能送我回我家嗎
Will you just take me to my house?

449
00:45:47,968 --> 00:45:50,314
今晚跟我走
Stay with me tonight.

450
00:46:01,800 --> 00:46:03,780
嘿 醒醒 我們到家了
Hey, wake up. We're home.

451
00:46:11,590 --> 00:46:13,019
先生
Sir?

452
00:46:14,473 --> 00:46:16,371
乖乖待在這兒
Stay here.

453
00:46:43,423 --> 00:46:44,796
怎么回事
What happened?

454
00:46:45,699 --> 00:46:47,879
這是我的車 我的車怎么成這樣了
That's my car. What happened to my car?

455
00:46:48,108 --> 00:46:49,672
檢查下我的屋子 如果沒事的話再通知我
Check the apartment. Tell me when it's safe.

456
00:46:49,697 --> 00:46:51,220
好的先生 馬上
Yes Sir, right away.

457
00:46:51,220 --> 00:46:53,326
史密斯 你跟著格雷先生
Smith you stick with Mr Grey

458
00:46:54,785 --> 00:46:56,162
我們要去哪
Where are we going?

459
00:46:56,882 --> 00:46:58,351
克里斯蒂安
Christian?

460
00:46:59,445 --> 00:47:00,920
你覺得這會是埃琳娜干的嗎
Do you think it was Elena?

461
00:47:01,489 --> 00:47:03,970
你真的覺得她會干出這種事
You really think she would do something like that?

462
00:47:07,357 --> 00:47:10,085
我真不明白我們為什么不能回你家
I really don't see why we just can't go back to your apartment.

463
00:47:10,085 --> 00:47:12,003
那里就像堡壘一樣安全
That place is like a fortress.

464
00:47:12,090 --> 00:47:14,182
她根本不可能進去
There is no way, she could've gotten in there.

465
00:47:14,182 --> 00:47:17,081
她也不可能進入車庫
She shouldn't be able to get into the garage either.

466
00:47:17,534 --> 00:47:19,592
我不會冒任何險
I'm not taking any chances.

467
00:47:27,359 --> 00:47:30,367
- 嘿 格雷先生 - 游艇在這邊
- Hey, Mr Grey! - The Yacht.

468
00:47:32,280 --> 00:47:34,397
那是船員 我們在這兒待一晚上
That's the crew. We'll be here to the morning.

469
00:47:41,138 --> 00:47:43,682
要不是我 你也不會遇到這些亂七八糟的事
If something would've happened to you because of me.

470
00:47:44,074 --> 00:47:46,443
不
It won't.

471
00:47:46,785 --> 00:47:48,912
我不會有事的
Nothing's gonna happen to me.

472
00:47:56,229 --> 00:47:58,365
我能把這個洗掉嗎
Can I wash this off?

473
00:48:01,739 --> 00:48:04,618
- 不要洗到別的地方去了 - 好
- Don't stray from the lines. - Okay.

474
00:48:36,256 --> 00:48:41,773
這是燙傷嗎 是誰這樣對你
Are these burns? Who did this to you?

475
00:48:43,844 --> 00:48:46,151
繼續吧 那都過去了
Go on. It's over.

476
00:48:52,024 --> 00:48:55,228
我知道這對你來說是多么艱難
I know how difficult it is for you to,

477
00:48:56,379 --> 00:48:59,696
對我敞開心扉吧
Open up to me and...

478
00:49:00,148 --> 00:49:02,970
告訴我所有的一切
tell me these things.

479
00:49:05,601 --> 00:49:08,720
你是我的全部
You gotta mean the world to me.

480
00:49:09,866 --> 00:49:12,280
如果你愛我
It means you love me.

481
00:49:13,500 --> 00:49:16,474
是的 我愛你
Yes, I do.

482
00:49:45,052 --> 00:49:48,278
所以你就是這樣學會用繩子打結的
So this is where your knot tying expertise comes from.

483
00:49:48,278 --> 00:49:51,850
早啊 睡得好嗎
Good morning. You sleep well?

484
00:49:51,850 --> 00:49:53,687
非常好
I did.

485
00:49:55,826 --> 00:49:57,802
這艘船真的很美
This boat is really beautiful.

486
00:49:58,174 --> 00:50:00,227
這是我從西雅圖帶過來的
This is from my Yard in Seattle.

487
00:50:00,676 --> 00:50:04,213
- 你自己建造的 - 我只是出了些力而已
- You build it? - I had some help.

488
00:50:04,485 --> 00:50:06,287
它叫格雷絲號
It's called the Grace.

489
00:50:08,187 --> 00:50:12,315
- 以你母親的名字命名的 - 你看起來很驚訝
- After your mom? - You seem surprised!

490
00:50:12,315 --> 00:50:15,924
為什么你對她這么好呢
Why you're always so cool towards her?

491
00:50:16,362 --> 00:50:18,403
我會一直記得格雷絲
I will ever think of Grace.

492
00:50:18,403 --> 00:50:21,276
在我的生母死后 是她給了我第二次生命
She saved my life after my birth mom died.

493
00:50:23,722 --> 00:50:25,468
你還記得你的生母嗎
Do you remember your birth mom?

494
00:50:26,187 --> 00:50:27,520
我努力去忘記
I try not to.

495
00:50:30,412 --> 00:50:33,319
她怎么了
What happened to her?

496
00:50:33,682 --> 00:50:37,755
她嗑藥過量 三天后我發現了她的尸體
She overdosed, they found her body three days later.

497
00:50:39,482 --> 00:50:42,795
- 那時候你在哪里 - 和她在一起
- Where were you? - I was with her.

498
00:50:44,535 --> 00:50:45,775
天哪
My god!

499
00:50:47,611 --> 00:50:49,859
帶走我的母親 再帶我去醫院
Took her away... Took me to hospital.

500
00:50:51,327 --> 00:50:54,428
格蕾絲也在場
Grace was there.

501
00:50:56,946 --> 00:50:59,320
謝謝你告訴我這些
Thank you for telling me.

502
00:51:04,007 --> 00:51:06,696
你看那個房子
Look at that house.

503
00:51:07,824 --> 00:51:10,156
真是美如畫
That's beautiful.

504
00:51:10,156 --> 00:51:13,128
從這個角度看起來簡直夢幻極了 真想知道誰那么幸運住在那 
The view is probably amazing. I wonder who lives there.

505
00:51:13,758 --> 00:51:17,999
那是一個海上的老寡婦 多年前她丈夫去世了
It's an old sea widow. Lost her husband years ago.

506
00:51:17,999 --> 00:51:21,201
每晚她都會坐在窗子前 等她丈夫回家
She sits at the window every night, waiting for him to come home.

507
00:51:22,948 --> 00:51:25,794
- 這是你現編的吧 - 沒錯
- Did you just make that up? - Yeah.

508
00:51:28,411 --> 00:51:30,533
想開船回家嗎
You want to take that home?

509
00:51:30,533 --> 00:51:33,826
- 我來開嗎 - 對 你來開
- Me? - Yeah, you! Come on.

510
00:51:33,826 --> 00:51:35,823
我不行的啊
You can't do that.

511
00:51:59,638 --> 00:52:00,939
對 就這樣
Right there.

512
00:52:00,939 --> 00:52:02,813
- 怎么樣 - 可以
- Okay? - Okay.

513
00:52:11,365 --> 00:52:15,289
- 別松手 - 不 我得讓你自己開 - 別松手
- Don't let go. - Ok, I have to. - Don't.

514
00:52:15,289 --> 00:52:15,812
行嗎
Okay?

515
00:52:15,812 --> 00:52:17,991
- 準備好了嗎 - 嗯 我試試
- You Ready? - Okay.

516
00:52:33,387 --> 00:52:36,150
是我在開 天吶 我做到了
I'm steering it, I'm doing it.

517
00:52:36,150 --> 00:52:38,149
我是船長
I'm the captain.

518
00:52:51,379 --> 00:52:53,609
- 嗨 - 嘿 杰克
- Hi. - Hey Jack.

519
00:52:53,609 --> 00:52:56,275
下班了之后再打私人電話 知道嗎
Personal calls on your own time okay?

520
00:53:04,933 --> 00:53:06,022
怎么了
Ya?

521
00:53:06,022 --> 00:53:08,210
你收到我的短信了嗎
Did you get my message?

522
00:53:08,210 --> 00:53:12,557
早上九點 你該和里克 克魯斯通電話的
You had a phone call this morning with Rick Crussi at 9am.

523
00:53:12,582 --> 00:53:13,411
靠 完全忘了
Shit.

524
00:53:14,141 --> 00:53:16,621
沒事 我再問問 跟他們重新訂時間
I just gonna reschedule that. I'll ask them.

525
00:53:16,621 --> 00:53:20,131
你預訂房間了嗎 紐約營的事
Did you book our rooms? For New York Camp?

526
00:53:20,406 --> 00:53:20,814
你說什么
Sorry?

527
00:53:20,814 --> 00:53:24,893
這周五的紐約書展會 寫在日程里的
The New York Book expo, this Friday. It's in the diary.

528
00:53:24,893 --> 00:53:27,365
哦 當然 我當然給你訂房間了
Yeah, I know. Yeah, I booked your room of course.

529
00:53:27,762 --> 00:53:31,673
那你呢 我的秘書應該也和我一起參加
And you? I was expecting that my assistant also attends.

530
00:53:33,688 --> 00:53:35,706
我不知道我也要參加 抱歉
I didnt know that. I'm sorry.

531
00:53:35,706 --> 00:53:38,546
別道歉了 趕緊給你訂一間房
Don't apologize, just get yourself a room.

532
00:53:39,521 --> 00:53:42,837
除非你不想去 想和你男朋友待在一起
Unless you rather stay back with your boyfriend.

533
00:53:43,295 --> 00:53:45,557
反正你也不是很在意工作
It's not like you need the work.

534
00:53:47,868 --> 00:53:50,077
我會解決的
I'll sort it out.

535
00:53:50,077 --> 00:53:52,280
嗨 里克 我是杰克 周末過得怎么樣啊
Hey Rick, it's Jack. How was your weekend?

536
00:53:54,585 --> 00:53:55,770
不會吧
No shit?

537
00:54:04,041 --> 00:54:07,858
太美了 簡直太美了 我都欲罷不能了
They're amazing amazing." But I can't put it down.

538
00:55:05,828 --> 00:55:06,548
有人嗎
Hello?

539
00:55:10,623 --> 00:55:12,023
克里斯蒂安 你在嗎
Christian?

540
00:55:14,866 --> 00:55:16,992
- 天吶 嚇我一跳 - 不好意思 斯蒂爾小姐
- Oh, Oh my God! - Excuse me Miss Steele.

541
00:55:16,992 --> 00:55:19,343
- 我不是有意嚇到你的 - 哦 沒事
- I didn't mean to startle you. - No, no...

542
00:55:19,343 --> 00:55:22,738
只是 你走路聲音太輕了
I... You were very quiet.

543
00:55:22,738 --> 00:55:24,793
我是瓊斯 格雷先生的管家
I am Mrs. Jones, Mr. Grey's housekeeper.

544
00:55:24,793 --> 00:55:25,900
來 我幫你拿吧 
May I?

545
00:55:27,524 --> 00:55:29,872
哦 謝謝你
Sure... Thank you.

546
00:55:30,700 --> 00:55:33,394
我叫安娜 想必你已經認識我了
I am Anna. But you knew that already,

547
00:55:33,395 --> 00:55:35,797
我們上周見過
because you've seen me last week.

548
00:55:36,203 --> 00:55:39,582
格雷先生在書房 剛剛通完電話
Mr Grey is in his study just finishing up a call.

549
00:55:39,582 --> 00:55:41,766
- 我去廚房忙了 有需要你就說 - 好的 謝謝你
- I'll be in the kitchen if you need me. - I'll be fine.

550
00:56:59,536 --> 00:57:01,671
有看到自己喜歡的嗎
You see anything you like?

551
00:57:05,705 --> 00:57:08,345
門沒上鎖
The door was unlocked.

552
00:57:09,718 --> 00:57:12,545
我會跟瓊斯太太交代下去
I'll have to talk to Mrs. Jones.

553
00:57:14,254 --> 00:57:15,890
她經常進來這個房間嗎
Does she come in here a lot?

554
00:57:19,480 --> 00:57:21,021
會打掃這里嗎
Dust in here?

555
00:57:22,991 --> 00:57:25,221
這是乳夾
That was a nipple clips.

556
00:57:29,190 --> 00:57:31,691
來 把你手給我
Come here, give me your hand.

557
00:57:43,000 --> 00:57:45,318
把它們取下來痛感更加強烈
It's even more intense when you take 'em off.

558
00:58:00,671 --> 00:58:01,934
這個是什么
What's this?

559
00:58:03,890 --> 00:58:07,360
好了 解說到此結束
Ok, that's enough show and tell.

560
00:58:07,360 --> 00:58:09,122
這個到底是干什么用的
What's this?

561
00:58:09,351 --> 00:58:12,788
學會跑之前要先練習走 循序漸進
Let's learn to walk before we run.

562
00:58:14,513 --> 00:58:16,845
我比較喜歡跑
I kinda like running.

563
00:58:22,728 --> 00:58:27,021
上次我們玩花樣的時候 觸發了我的另一面
Last time we did this. You saw another side of me.

564
00:58:27,661 --> 00:58:29,028
你倉皇逃離
And you left.

565
00:58:29,823 --> 00:58:33,035
上次跟現在不是一回事
Last time was different.

566
00:58:39,033 --> 00:58:41,605
好吧 我們不在這里做
All right! But not here.

567
00:58:43,203 --> 00:58:45,901
瓊斯太太
Mrs. Jones.

568
00:58:46,558 --> 00:58:48,478
我的天
Oh my God.

569
01:00:22,274 --> 01:00:23,604
你是我的
You're mine.

570
01:00:25,273 --> 01:00:27,072
如你所愿
I'm yours.

571
01:00:56,410 --> 01:00:58,185
- 你還行嗎 - 可以
- You okay? - Yeah.

572
01:01:23,719 --> 01:01:26,785
你知道我們總得談談去紐約的事
You know at some point we're gonna need to talk about New York.

573
01:01:27,149 --> 01:01:28,402
我們不是談過了嗎
We have talked about it.

574
01:01:28,632 --> 01:01:31,081
你不同意不算談過
You, forbidding is not us talking about it.

575
01:01:32,493 --> 01:01:35,994
如果你想去紐約 除非同行的不是海德
If you wanna go to New York, don't go with Hyde.

576
01:01:35,994 --> 01:01:37,151
讓我帶你去 我在紐約有住處
let me take you. I have a place there.

577
01:01:37,496 --> 01:01:41,096
是這樣不錯 但這次不是去度假
Of course you do. This isn't some sort of vacation..

578
01:01:41,096 --> 01:01:44,461
這是和老板去出差 我想得到他的賞識
It's a work-trip with my boss. Who I would like to impress.

579
01:01:45,797 --> 01:01:47,369
你知道他在最近一年半里
You know he's had 3 assistants

580
01:01:47,370 --> 01:01:49,467
有過三個助理 最后都辭職不干了
in the last 18 months. All of them quit.

581
01:01:49,467 --> 01:01:51,663
- 而且都不沒打招呼離職的 - 你覺得我沒能力做他的助理
- Without notice. - You don't think I can handle him?

582
01:01:51,940 --> 01:01:53,783
不是這回事
That's not it.

583
01:01:54,045 --> 01:01:56,149
你的語氣出賣了你
That's what it feels like.

584
01:01:57,511 --> 01:02:00,783
安娜 我完全相信你可以處理所有事
Anna, I know full well that you can handle anything.

585
01:02:01,059 --> 01:02:05,756
如果你真的想去 我也不會攔著你
And if you really wanna go, then I can't stop you.

586
01:02:06,546 --> 01:02:08,999
當然紐約我想親自帶你去
But I would like to take you there myself.

587
01:02:13,568 --> 01:02:15,053
好吧
Okay.

588
01:02:16,950 --> 01:02:19,088
- 真的嗎 - 是啊
- Okay? - Yeah.

589
01:02:20,224 --> 01:02:23,692
我是說我當然想和你一起去
I mean of course, I would rather see New York with you.

590
01:02:24,126 --> 01:02:27,850
天吶 我討厭和你有爭執
God, I hate it when we fight.

591
01:02:28,859 --> 01:02:33,685
這不算爭執 就是正常溝通而已
That wasn't a fight. That was a conversation.

592
01:02:33,932 --> 01:02:36,162
就是有人講話
That was, you know, when somebody talks,

593
01:02:36,162 --> 01:02:39,147
有人聽 然后解決問題
and the other person listens and you resolve an issue.

594
01:02:39,147 --> 01:02:42,263
- 就是這樣 - 不可思議是嗎
- That's how it works. - It's crazy. Isn't it?

595
01:02:44,724 --> 01:02:47,546
- 晚安 安娜 - 你也是 漢娜
- Good night Anna. - Good night Hanna.

596
01:03:13,799 --> 01:03:14,571
你準備下班嗎
You leaving?

597
01:03:14,571 --> 01:03:17,818
我正打算跟你說件事
I was actually just about to come talk to you.

598
01:03:17,818 --> 01:03:19,594
是去紐約的事
About New York.

599
01:03:20,231 --> 01:03:21,519
有什么問題嗎
Is there a problem?

600
01:03:22,765 --> 01:03:27,009
你給我這次機會我不勝感激 杰克
I'm so grateful for the opportunity Jack but..

601
01:03:27,009 --> 01:03:30,322
但是現在告訴我有點晚了 我無法更改既定的計劃
with such short notice, I made plans that I can't change.

602
01:03:30,869 --> 01:03:33,205
但是周末我都會手機在線
But I will have my phone on me all weekend.

603
01:03:33,206 --> 01:03:35,325
如果你需要任何幫助 都可以找我
So if you need anything, I'm available.

604
01:03:37,861 --> 01:03:38,912
安娜 坐
Anna, have a seat.

605
01:03:42,629 --> 01:03:44,156
真的 我真的太抱歉了
I'm really, I'm sorry.

606
01:03:47,350 --> 01:03:49,996
我認為在這里你前途不可限量
I think you have tremendous potential here.

607
01:03:51,267 --> 01:03:53,486
但是我不想在訓練一個不把這個職位
But I don't wanna waste my time training someone

608
01:03:53,486 --> 01:03:55,498
當回事的人身上浪費時間
who doesn't take this position seriously.

609
01:03:55,498 --> 01:03:59,437
- 我很當回事 這是我夢寐以求的工作 - 好吧 那么去紐約和圖書展
- I do! This is my dream job. - Well then, shouldn't..

610
01:03:59,437 --> 01:04:03,007
難道不是你夢想的一部分嗎
going to New York and the book expo, be part of that dream?

611
01:04:03,007 --> 01:04:06,228
那是 那是的
...It is it is...

612
01:04:06,228 --> 01:04:08,528
那只是一場誤會 絕不會再發生
It was just a misunderstanding. It won't happen again.

613
01:04:08,528 --> 01:04:11,431
因為有很多條件達標的人
Because there are plenty of qualified people.

614
01:04:11,431 --> 01:04:13,486
他們為了這份工作會不顧一切
Who would kill for this job.

615
01:04:13,486 --> 01:04:16,191
聽著 我不想自吹自擂 但是 
Look, I don't wanna brag. But I'm a..

616
01:04:16,191 --> 01:04:18,500
我真的是個很棒的老師
Pretty great teacher.

617
01:04:20,080 --> 01:04:21,643
我確信你是的
I'm sure you are.

618
01:04:21,643 --> 01:04:26,100
我只是看不到你對這份工作的主動性
I'm just not seeing the initiative on your side of it.

619
01:04:27,025 --> 01:04:29,420
我讀了很多 比你要求的多
I've read more than you ask me to.

620
01:04:30,093 --> 01:04:32,817
- 而且我是最好的 - 我是說
- And I'm on top of. - I'm talking about.

621
01:04:32,817 --> 01:04:36,048
你應該更加努力 
Going the extra mile...

622
01:04:36,816 --> 01:04:39,378
除非你想讓我
...Unless you want me to

623
01:04:39,633 --> 01:04:42,662
和克里斯蒂安 格雷競爭
Compete with Christian Grey.

624
01:04:43,135 --> 01:04:45,209
得到你的關注
For your attention.

625
01:04:45,521 --> 01:04:50,359
那晚克里斯蒂安對你那么無禮 我很抱歉
I apologize that Christian was so curt with you the other night.

626
01:04:50,359 --> 01:04:52,763
你就是為了這件事嗎
Is that what this is about?

627
01:04:53,164 --> 01:04:57,261
你男朋友出了名的
Your boyfriend has a reputation for being..

628
01:04:58,386 --> 01:05:01,432
無情 你就喜歡這個嗎
a little ruthless. Is that what you like?

629
01:05:02,359 --> 01:05:04,041
你如果對我的工作有意見
If you have problem with my work,

630
01:05:04,042 --> 01:05:05,825
那就報告給人事部
then you should take it up with HR.

631
01:05:06,273 --> 01:05:09,376
這么嚴肅干什么
Why are you being so serious?

632
01:05:09,376 --> 01:05:12,131
你以為我要干什么 讓你上我嗎
What do you think I'm gonna do? Make you fuck me?

633
01:05:12,131 --> 01:05:13,885
杰克
Jack.

634
01:05:13,885 --> 01:05:15,901
我只是在想
I just think.

635
01:05:16,859 --> 01:05:19,209
只是在想
I just think.

636
01:05:20,148 --> 01:05:23,011
如果你要上 至少也要和
If you gonna fuck your way the problem is that you should do it

637
01:05:23,011 --> 01:05:26,405
能讓你變的更聰明的人上床
with someone who can at least make you smarter.

638
01:05:28,312 --> 01:05:30,470
而不是只能讓你變富的人
Not just richer.

639
01:05:30,828 --> 01:05:31,548
對嗎
Right?

640
01:05:33,135 --> 01:05:36,474
- 不要這樣  - 不要怎樣
- Don't. - Don't what?

641
01:05:37,378 --> 01:05:41,494
這些問題都不是認真的
None of these is serious, Serious question.

642
01:05:42,502 --> 01:05:44,622
你是愿意用肉體換紙醉金迷的生活
Do you wanna be kept?

643
01:05:46,712 --> 01:05:49,120
還是想被認真對待
Or taken seriously?

644
01:05:49,827 --> 01:05:54,234
- 我想要離開了 讓我走 杰克 - 而且
- I like to leave, please Jack. - Plus.

645
01:05:55,423 --> 01:05:58,074
我可以讓你
I can make you cum.

646
01:05:58,074 --> 01:06:00,755
享受前所未有的高潮
Like nobody else has.

647
01:06:01,515 --> 01:06:03,957
他給不了你
Not him.

648
01:06:04,582 --> 01:06:08,190
- 別人都給不了 - 閉嘴變態
- Not anyone. - No.

649
01:06:17,683 --> 01:06:19,332
安娜 安娜 發生什么事了
Anna? Anna, what happened?

650
01:06:19,332 --> 01:06:22,323
杰克 杰克他 他想要
Jack. It's Jack. He's trying to..

651
01:06:22,323 --> 01:06:23,112
想要非禮我
To touch me.

652
01:06:23,112 --> 01:06:25,860
- 我要殺了這個混蛋 - 不 不 不要去好嗎
- I'll kill him. - No, no, please don't go.

653
01:06:25,860 --> 01:06:27,693
不要去 不要離開我身邊
Don't go. Don't leave me please.

654
01:06:27,693 --> 01:06:30,192
你進去 沒事的 寶貝
Go. It's okay. Hey.

655
01:06:31,158 --> 01:06:33,448
我的東西都落在那 我什么都沒帶出來
I left everything. I don't have any of my stuff.

656
01:06:33,448 --> 01:06:36,547
沒事的 沒關系我們先走吧
It's fine. Let's go come on.

657
01:06:36,547 --> 01:06:41,307
已經取消了他的護照 很好
And his pass has been canceled. Good.

658
01:06:41,307 --> 01:06:44,022
謝謝你杰里 晚安
No. Thank you Jerry. Good night.

659
01:06:48,260 --> 01:06:50,603
這件事情最輕的結果
Well, at least that's dealt with.

660
01:06:50,603 --> 01:06:52,977
就是解雇海德
Heim's out. He's been fired.

661
01:06:56,213 --> 01:06:57,800
你怎么做到的 這樣
How? That's.LO

662
01:06:58,390 --> 01:07:02,592
是你 我還以為你和SIP公司的協議還沒有完成呢
You. But I thought your deal with SIP hasn't been finished yet.

663
01:07:02,592 --> 01:07:05,794
的確還沒完成 但是我認識SIP的CEO
It's not. But I know the CEO.

664
01:07:06,293 --> 01:07:07,784
我告訴了他們事情的經過
I told 'em what happened.

665
01:07:08,693 --> 01:07:10,537
從今以后 你永遠不用再受他的氣了
You'll never have to see him again.

666
01:07:11,401 --> 01:07:13,792
在他被解雇以后我還能在那邊工作嗎
Am I still gonna have a job now he's not there?

667
01:07:14,799 --> 01:07:17,402
- 嗯 如果你不工作的話 你可以 - 克里斯蒂安
- Well, if you don't, you can... - Christian.

668
01:07:17,402 --> 01:07:19,770
你知道我有多愛工作
You know I love working.

669
01:07:20,076 --> 01:07:22,930
你不能就這樣把我鎖在你的銅雀臺里
You can't keep me locked up in your penthouse.

670
01:07:27,907 --> 01:07:29,227
如果我把房子的鑰匙交給你呢
What if I give you a key?

671
01:07:31,148 --> 01:07:34,060
我是說 假如你有了鑰匙
I mean.. what if you have a key and..

672
01:07:34,060 --> 01:07:37,003
你就可以在家里放些你自己的東西
You kept some of your stuff here.

673
01:07:37,003 --> 01:07:39,625
或者直接全部都搬過來
Keep all of your stuff here.

674
01:07:39,625 --> 01:07:42,247
然后睡在這兒 你明白我的意思嗎
And you slept, you know?

675
01:07:42,247 --> 01:07:44,190
不是睡在你自己的房子里
Not at your place.

676
01:07:46,735 --> 01:07:49,719
你是在邀請我和你同居嗎
Are you asking me to move in with you?

677
01:07:55,555 --> 01:07:58,095
- 你確定嗎 - 我確定
- Are you sure? - Yes.

678
01:08:00,077 --> 01:08:02,227
我每時每刻都想要見到你
I want you here all the time.

679
01:08:03,765 --> 01:08:05,446
想你時 你就能在我身邊
As soon as possible.

680
01:08:11,838 --> 01:08:14,469
那你之前說的跑之前要先學會走路呢
What'd happen to learning to walk before we run?

681
01:08:16,378 --> 01:08:17,731
這個只會是
Well, that's just one of the

682
01:08:17,732 --> 01:08:20,148
我們早餐時閑聊的話題
many things that we can talk about over breakfast.

683
01:08:26,179 --> 01:08:27,942
我可以再考慮一下嗎
Can I think about it?

684
01:08:28,439 --> 01:08:29,399
當然可以
Sure. Ya.

685
01:08:40,072 --> 01:08:42,240
- 莉茲 嗨 - 安娜
- Liz, hi. - Anna.

686
01:08:42,240 --> 01:08:44,720
你聽說了沒 杰克昨天晚上辭職了
Don't know if you've heard. Jack resigned last night.

687
01:08:44,720 --> 01:08:45,888
我現在忙的不行
I'm kind of a hurry.

688
01:08:45,889 --> 01:08:48,810
賽斯現在不招聘新人 我們要被瘋狂壓榨了
Seth isn't recruiting right now. So we're screwed.

689
01:08:49,190 --> 01:08:51,299
你現在需不需要我幫忙呢
So you don't need me anymore then?

690
01:08:51,299 --> 01:08:53,051
我們想要找你臨時負責一些項目
We're trying to find you something temporary.

691
01:08:53,051 --> 01:08:55,240
今天早上的會議你能代替杰克出席嗎
Could you to fill in for Jack in this morning meeting?

692
01:08:55,932 --> 01:08:58,869
- 是高級編輯的會議嗎 - 幫這一天就好
- At the senior editors' meeting? - Just for today.

693
01:08:58,869 --> 01:09:00,904
你是唯一一個熟悉杰克所有工作的人
You're the only one who knows Jack entire slate.

694
01:09:00,904 --> 01:09:01,576
是 但雖然這么說
Well yeah,

695
01:09:01,576 --> 01:09:04,655
我 我 我
but I.. I.. I..

696
01:09:06,509 --> 01:09:08,148
也對 這對你來說可能太難了
You're right. That's too much.

697
01:09:10,913 --> 01:09:12,438
不 我可以做到的
No. I can do it.

698
01:09:13,790 --> 01:09:15,416
沒關系 我能做到
It's fine. I can do it.

699
01:09:17,018 --> 01:09:18,054
很好
Great.

700
01:09:20,666 --> 01:09:22,666
結束了就給我打電話
Call me when you're done.

701
01:09:25,100 --> 01:09:28,609
我們應該少開新坑 多發售有名頭的作者的書
We need to print fewer titles. Stick with established authors.

702
01:09:28,609 --> 01:09:31,913
- 聚焦在核心讀者身上 - 擴大一下
- Focus on our core readership. - Expand it.

703
01:09:32,970 --> 01:09:33,690
不好意思
I'm sorry.

704
01:09:35,430 --> 01:09:38,531
安娜 你覺得我們應該有怎樣的出版策略
So Anna. What do you think we should be publishing?

705
01:09:40,853 --> 01:09:43,131
呃 我們需要新聲音
Um.. Newer voices.

706
01:09:43,131 --> 01:09:45,161
他們和出名作者一起發售
Along with your established authors.

707
01:09:45,537 --> 01:09:49,850
以音狐為例 他上周有八萬點擊量
Voice Fox, for example, got 80,000 hits last week.

708
01:09:49,850 --> 01:09:50,428
真的嗎
Really?

709
01:09:50,428 --> 01:09:54,886
網上瀏覽和傳統紙質印刷銷售并不一樣
Online don't automatically translate to print sales.

710
01:09:54,886 --> 01:09:57,373
呃 它們可以是一樣
Well.. but they could.

711
01:09:57,373 --> 01:10:00,436
他的在線讀者群體集中在18至24歲
His online audience is the 18 to 24 demographics.

712
01:10:00,436 --> 01:10:03,704
那些才是我們應該關注的讀者群體
And those are exactly the readers we should be chasing.

713
01:10:04,240 --> 01:10:05,860
我可以給你們看看數據
I mean I can show you the stats.

714
01:10:05,861 --> 01:10:08,240
我真的認為他值得我們一試
I Really, I think he is worth taking a risk on.

715
01:10:10,642 --> 01:10:11,932
也許我們可以先看看
Maybe we should take a look.

716
01:10:22,208 --> 01:10:23,684
好主意
Great idea.

717
01:10:25,362 --> 01:10:27,112
呃 安娜
Er.. Anna?

718
01:10:27,681 --> 01:10:30,226
羅奇先生 我很抱歉我有些失禮了
Mr Roach. I'm really sorry if I was out of line.

719
01:10:30,226 --> 01:10:32,800
不 不用這樣 你說的很有道理
No. Don't be sorry. You make lot of sense.

720
01:10:33,400 --> 01:10:36,815
現在 杰克 海德走了你現在準備怎么辦
Now. So what are you doing now that Jack Hyde is gone?

721
01:10:37,131 --> 01:10:40,130
呃 莉茲說有些臨時活可以干
Um.. Well, Liz mentioned something temporary.

722
01:10:40,130 --> 01:10:41,114
我不清楚
I don't know.

723
01:10:41,114 --> 01:10:44,220
好 要不你先臨時代替一下杰克吧
Okay. Well, why don't you fill in for Jack temporarily?

724
01:10:44,572 --> 01:10:47,358
- 行嗎 - 呃
- Good? - Um..

725
01:10:47,747 --> 01:10:51,158
很好 就這么定了
Great. Okay. That's settled.

726
01:10:52,364 --> 01:10:56,780
- 敬SIP新任小說編輯 - 代理小說編輯
- To SIP's new fiction editor. - Acting fiction editor.

727
01:11:02,483 --> 01:11:04,380
克里斯蒂安 這事你是不是幫了我
Christian, did you have something to do with this?

728
01:11:04,990 --> 01:11:08,890
沒有啊 都是你自己的努力
No. Hey, it was all you.

729
01:11:10,850 --> 01:11:14,409
- 你不相信我 - 我真的自己都不敢相信
- But you don't believe me? - I don't believe it myself.

730
01:11:18,730 --> 01:11:22,940
- 我昨晚問了你一個問題 - 搬過來和你住嗎
- I asked you a question last night. - About moving in with you?

731
01:11:28,656 --> 01:11:31,593
我只是覺得我可能
I just think that I'm probably..

732
01:11:32,636 --> 01:11:35,396
我需要從我的公寓拿些東西
I need to get somethings from my apartment.

733
01:11:38,680 --> 01:11:40,151
那都可以安排
That can be arranged.

734
01:11:41,500 --> 01:11:42,565
很好
Good.

735
01:11:44,147 --> 01:11:49,469
現在 如果可以的話 我們能回家慶祝嗎
Now, maybe we could, take this celebration home.

736
01:11:51,919 --> 01:11:54,251
結賬 謝謝
The Check please.

737
01:12:03,192 --> 01:12:06,216
把你的內褲脫掉
Take off your panties.

738
01:12:06,507 --> 01:12:08,067
現在就脫
Do it now.

739
01:12:10,250 --> 01:12:14,289
- 在這里嗎 - 對 就在這 現在
- Right in here? - Yeah, right here, now.

740
01:14:03,535 --> 01:14:04,709
別高潮了
Don't cum.

741
01:14:28,703 --> 01:14:31,970
并且詹妮需要找個人去和克魯斯簽約
And Jenny need someone to sign off on the new Crushi.

742
01:14:33,171 --> 01:14:35,639
我一直在催杰克去做
I kept asking Jack to do that.

743
01:14:35,639 --> 01:14:39,773
然而 杰克有點懶 你沒注意到嗎
Yeah well, Jack was kind of lazy. Didn't you notice?

744
01:14:39,773 --> 01:14:43,907
耶 他好像把這叫做藝術氣質
Yah. I believe he called it artistic temperament.

745
01:14:46,606 --> 01:14:49,131
謝謝你漢娜
Thank you Hanna.

746
01:14:53,090 --> 01:14:54,096
嘿
Hey.

747
01:14:54,764 --> 01:14:56,851
你能接下這工作真是太棒了
It's great that you're doing this.

748
01:14:56,851 --> 01:14:58,969
但這真是太奇怪了 我知道
But it's totally weird. I know.

749
01:14:58,969 --> 01:15:01,406
- 我知道 - 這意味著
- I know. - Meaning?

750
01:15:01,406 --> 01:15:03,867
那我是不是該叫你斯蒂爾小姐
Am I expected to call you Miss Steele?

751
01:15:03,867 --> 01:15:05,670
我還是傾向于你叫我安娜
I expect you to call me Anna.

752
01:15:06,239 --> 01:15:08,899
而且我也不用你幫我拿咖啡
And I don't expect you to fetch me coffee.

753
01:15:08,899 --> 01:15:11,589
除非你去拿自己的順帶捎上我的
Unless you're getting some for yourself.

754
01:15:11,589 --> 01:15:12,768
除此之外
And..

755
01:15:13,352 --> 01:15:18,639
其余剩下的 就隨機應變吧 可以嗎
The rest of it, we'll just make up as we go. Okay?

756
01:15:18,978 --> 01:15:20,161
好的
Okay.

757
01:15:37,287 --> 01:15:38,349
斯蒂爾小姐
Miss Steele.

758
01:15:42,317 --> 01:15:43,864
該死的
Damn it.

759
01:15:44,645 --> 01:15:47,044
你在這呆著 我就進去拿點東西然后就退房出來
Take it. I'm just gonna grab some stuff and check them out.

760
01:15:47,044 --> 01:15:48,356
我該進去幫你
I should go over help with you.

761
01:15:48,357 --> 01:15:49,908
不用了 我馬上就出來
No. It's okay. I'd just be 2 seconds.

762
01:15:49,908 --> 01:15:51,454
沒事
It's all good.

763
01:15:53,130 --> 01:15:54,222
嗨 羅絲
Hey Ross.

764
01:16:35,950 --> 01:16:37,067
利拉
Leila.

765
01:16:41,969 --> 01:16:47,869
克里斯蒂安就在樓下 你想去見他嗎
Christian is downstairs. Do you want to see him?

766
01:16:49,880 --> 01:16:52,200
我是來找你的
I came to see you.

767
01:16:55,228 --> 01:16:56,228
好吧
Okay.

768
01:16:59,895 --> 01:17:01,593
他告訴我發生過什么
He told me what happened.

769
01:17:05,621 --> 01:17:08,018
我知道你一定承受了許多痛苦
I know you're in a lot of pain.

770
01:17:09,294 --> 01:17:11,294
對此我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

771
01:17:11,781 --> 01:17:14,157
他讓你直呼他的名字
He lets you call him by his name.

772
01:17:15,566 --> 01:17:20,177
他跟我一直提起你 他很關心你
He talks about you all the time. He cares about you.

773
01:17:24,605 --> 01:17:26,263
別說謊
Don't lie.

774
01:17:29,485 --> 01:17:31,384
告訴我我哪一點比不上你
Tell me what you have that I don't.

775
01:17:32,674 --> 01:17:33,913
沒有
Nothing.

776
01:17:36,600 --> 01:17:38,056
我根本不值一提
I'm nothing.

777
01:17:40,610 --> 01:17:42,337
他會厭倦我的
He'll get tired of me.

778
01:17:42,813 --> 01:17:45,065
主人睡在你的床上
Master sleeps in your bed.

779
01:17:45,603 --> 01:17:48,055
- 你怎么知道的 - 我看見了
- How do you know that? - I saw you.

780
01:17:49,103 --> 01:17:53,241
我看見你了 我知道你愛他
I watched you. I know you love him.

781
01:17:53,241 --> 01:17:54,965
我也愛他
I do too.

782
01:17:55,980 --> 01:17:57,351
我們都愛他
We all do.

783
01:17:58,194 --> 01:18:01,146
- 有什么話不能把槍放下好好說呢 - 你根本不了解他
- Why don't you put the gun down? - You don't know him.

784
01:18:01,146 --> 01:18:04,037
到底喜歡什么 你給不了他想要的
What he likes. You don't give him what he wants.

785
01:18:04,037 --> 01:18:06,886
他不是真的愛你
He's pretending with you.

786
01:18:19,564 --> 01:18:21,029
不 克里斯蒂安
No. Christian.

787
01:18:43,126 --> 01:18:44,754
跪下
Kneel.

788
01:19:03,412 --> 01:19:04,454
安娜
Anna.

789
01:19:05,179 --> 01:19:07,017
回家里等著我
Go to Scott wait for me there.

790
01:19:11,879 --> 01:19:14,714
至少這次 服從你所聽到的
For once, just do as you're told.

791
01:19:19,106 --> 01:19:21,146
泰勒 帶她離開這
Taylor, get her outta here.

792
01:19:34,361 --> 01:19:35,376
請吧 斯蒂爾小姐
Miss Steele.

793
01:19:41,995 --> 01:19:46,468
- 斯蒂爾小姐 安娜 - 得了吧 泰勒
- Miss Steele? Anna? - Stop it, Taylor.

794
01:21:13,650 --> 01:21:17,286
我不在乎 她已經失蹤三小時了
I don't care. She's been gone for 3 hours,

795
01:21:17,287 --> 01:21:19,537
而且現在她無家可歸
she doesn't have her cell.

796
01:21:19,537 --> 01:21:20,912
身無分文
Or her purse.

797
01:21:24,358 --> 01:21:26,226
掛吧 她在這兒了
Forget it, she's here.

798
01:21:30,706 --> 01:21:32,410
你他媽去哪了
Where the fuck have you been?

799
01:21:35,722 --> 01:21:37,291
我讓你直接回來啊
I told you to come straight here.

800
01:21:37,291 --> 01:21:40,031
我都派人去大街小巷尋你了
I have had people out combing the streets looking for you.

801
01:21:40,031 --> 01:21:43,179
我很抱歉我總是不按規矩行事
I'm sorry I don't always do as I'm told.

802
01:21:43,179 --> 01:21:46,878
或許你只是需要一個對你的命令言聽計從的傀儡
Maybe you just really need someone who obeys every command.

803
01:21:47,096 --> 01:21:48,535
瞎說什么
Don't be ridiculous.

804
01:21:48,535 --> 01:21:52,592
我看見了 克里斯蒂安 我看見你和利拉在一起的樣子  
I saw you. Christian. I saw the way you were with Leila.

805
01:21:52,592 --> 01:21:56,655
她手里有槍 安娜 我必須得安撫她
She had a gun Anna. I would do anything to subdue her.

806
01:21:58,295 --> 01:21:59,696
她現在在哪兒
Where is she now?

807
01:22:00,720 --> 01:22:02,020
在這兒嗎
Is she here?

808
01:22:02,020 --> 01:22:04,428
什么 不 當然不在
What? No. Of course not.

809
01:22:04,669 --> 01:22:07,383
她正在精神病院接受治療
She's in a psych ward getting the help that she needs.

810
01:22:09,900 --> 01:22:11,118
那挺好
Lucky.

811
01:22:11,118 --> 01:22:13,928
- 我知道她嚇到你了   - 是啊 我被她嚇死了
- I know she scares you. - Yeah. She scare me.

812
01:22:16,010 --> 01:22:21,859
但是看見你和她在一起那樣兒 我更是吃驚 
But you scare me more. Seeing you like that with her.

813
01:22:21,859 --> 01:22:24,371
我不可能給得了你這些東西
I will never be able to give you that.

814
01:22:24,371 --> 01:22:28,253
充當你的欲奴 對你百依百順
Kind of submission and obedience.

815
01:22:28,253 --> 01:22:29,285
安娜
Anna.

816
01:22:29,520 --> 01:22:32,479
別來煩我 我需要靜靜
Don't crowd me. I need space.

817
01:22:32,479 --> 01:22:34,169
- 別這樣 -克里斯蒂安
- Now please don't do. - Christian.

818
01:22:34,169 --> 01:22:37,599
- 不要拋下我 - 我只是需要好好想想
- Don't give up on me. - I just need to think a little bit.

819
01:22:37,599 --> 01:22:39,903
不要離開我
Don't leave me.

820
01:22:43,200 --> 01:22:44,647
你在做什么
What are you doing?

821
01:22:46,070 --> 01:22:47,460
你起來
Get up.

822
01:22:50,530 --> 01:22:52,032
你在做什么
What are you doing?

823
01:22:52,907 --> 01:22:57,298
看著我 看著我
Look at me. Look at me.

824
01:23:04,030 --> 01:23:05,575
我好怕
I'm scared.

825
01:23:10,406 --> 01:23:12,995
我知道你說你有我就足夠了
I know you say that I'm enough.

826
01:23:15,925 --> 01:23:19,015
但有些東西對你來說已經成了家常便飯
But there are certain things that you're used to getting.

827
01:23:19,015 --> 01:23:23,259
而那些我永遠都給不了你
That I will never ever ever be able to give you.

828
01:23:25,518 --> 01:23:28,935
或許現在還好 但
And it might be fine for right now, but..

829
01:23:29,460 --> 01:23:32,300
一旦你又開始欲求不滿那又該如何
What's gonna happen when you start needing them again?

830
01:23:32,300 --> 01:23:33,026
我不會的
I won't.

831
01:23:33,230 --> 01:23:36,033
你怎么知道你不會 我要怎么相信你
How do you know that? How can I believe you,

832
01:23:36,033 --> 01:23:38,693
我甚至無法理解你為啥想玩這種主宰一切的游戲
I don't even understand your need to dominate.

833
01:23:38,693 --> 01:23:42,252
我不是主宰者 我不是
I'm not a dominant. I'm not.

834
01:23:43,113 --> 01:23:45,209
我們的行話叫施虐狂
The right term is a sadist.

835
01:23:46,291 --> 01:23:49,472
看到和你長得像的女人 我都對她們下不去手
I get off in punishing woman. Woman who look like you.

836
01:23:49,472 --> 01:23:50,822
是像你母親
Like your mother.

837
01:23:52,517 --> 01:23:53,561
是
Yes.

838
01:23:53,561 --> 01:23:56,186
我知道那簡直就是一團糟
And I know how fucked up that is.

839
01:23:56,794 --> 01:23:59,994
但如果你要離開我的話
When you left,

840
01:23:59,994 --> 01:24:04,401
我發誓我會停下來 只要這能讓你回心轉意
I swore that I would stop if that's what it took to get you back.

841
01:24:05,076 --> 01:24:06,949
但我已經受夠了
But I'm done with it.

842
01:24:07,773 --> 01:24:11,283
人世間有百媚千紅 唯有你是我情之所鐘
You mean more to me than anything else.

843
01:24:14,585 --> 01:24:18,783
我想說服自己相信你 真的 但我做不到 
I want to believe you. I do. But I can't. I..

844
01:24:18,783 --> 01:24:21,290
安娜 把手給我
Anna, give me your hand.

845
01:24:24,125 --> 01:24:25,175
這就是我 全部的我
This is me. All of me.

846
01:24:29,930 --> 01:24:32,451
- 克里斯蒂安 - 我整個人 自內而外 都是你的
- Christian. - I'm all yours.

847
01:25:35,379 --> 01:25:36,383
不
No.

848
01:25:39,856 --> 01:25:40,945
不
No.

849
01:25:42,625 --> 01:25:47,401
嘿 嘿 沒事的 我在這兒呢
Hey.. hey.. hey.. hey.. It's okay. I'm right here.

850
01:25:48,100 --> 01:25:49,690
我在這呢
I'm right here.

851
01:25:54,478 --> 01:25:56,147
嫁給我吧
Marry me.

852
01:25:57,135 --> 01:26:00,381
- 什么 - 我想讓你嫁給我
- What? - I want you to marry me.

853
01:26:03,163 --> 01:26:07,119
克里斯蒂安 你還在做夢吧
Christian. I think you're dreaming.

854
01:27:10,161 --> 01:27:13,112
- 早安 - 早
- Good morning. - Morning.

855
01:27:16,344 --> 01:27:19,375
- 昨晚睡的好嗎 - 挺好的
- Sleep okay? - I did.

856
01:27:19,375 --> 01:27:22,436
- 你呢 - 相當好
- You? - Like a luck.

857
01:27:22,436 --> 01:27:24,458
一覺睡到天亮
Out all night.

858
01:27:28,013 --> 01:27:33,458
你昨晚沒有夢到什么奇怪的事情吧
You didn't.. have any weird dreams or anything or like.

859
01:27:33,458 --> 01:27:36,634
- 夜里有沒有醒 -沒有
- Wake up at all. - No.

860
01:27:37,768 --> 01:27:39,461
什么都不記得了
Nothing I can think of.

861
01:27:41,398 --> 01:27:43,358
不過倒是記得我好像 
I mean there was a little thing about asking you to

862
01:27:43,383 --> 01:27:45,887
向你求婚了 除此之外 什么印象都沒有
marry me but aside from that, no.

863
01:27:45,887 --> 01:27:48,259
別跟我開那種玩笑
Don't mess with me like that.

864
01:27:48,599 --> 01:27:52,829
誰說我是開玩笑的了
Huh. Who says I mess with you?

865
01:27:54,466 --> 01:27:56,754
好點了嗎
That better?

866
01:28:01,074 --> 01:28:02,564
我是認真的
I meant it.

867
01:28:04,021 --> 01:28:05,674
我想娶你
I want to marry you.

868
01:28:06,822 --> 01:28:08,462
為什么
Why?

869
01:28:09,552 --> 01:28:11,030
因為我想
Because I want to spend

870
01:28:11,031 --> 01:28:13,924
與你一起慢慢變老
every second of the rest of my life with you.

871
01:28:20,768 --> 01:28:24,449
你不用馬上就答應我
I don't expect you to say yes right away.

872
01:28:24,449 --> 01:28:26,614
我知道我情況比較復雜
I know I'm complicated.

873
01:28:28,680 --> 01:28:31,307
是有一點點
Just a little bit.

874
01:28:35,403 --> 01:28:39,319
你居然有個助理 我還以為你是別人的助理
You have an assistant? I thought you were an assistant.

875
01:28:39,674 --> 01:28:42,332
好吧 這個說來話長 怎么了
Ah, it's a long story. What's going on?

876
01:28:42,332 --> 01:28:44,732
克里斯蒂安生日我送什么比較好
what do I get Christian for his birthday?

877
01:28:44,732 --> 01:28:48,444
這個男人什么都有 就是缺少幽默感
The boy already has everything except the sense of humor.

878
01:28:48,444 --> 01:28:52,967
額  他生日  他什么時候生日
Er.. his. His birthday. When is his birthday?

879
01:28:52,967 --> 01:28:55,672
周日 他沒告訴你嗎 真奇怪
Sunday. He didn't tell you? He is so weird.

880
01:28:55,673 --> 01:28:57,938
爸媽準備給他辦個派對
Mom and Dad is throwing him a party.

881
01:28:57,938 --> 01:29:01,027
他不是剛開過一次派對嗎 
Didn't he just had a party?

882
01:29:01,027 --> 01:29:05,453
那是個舞會  這次只有家人 朋友 聽聽音樂 看看煙火
That was a ball. This is just family, friends, music, fireworks..

883
01:29:05,453 --> 01:29:08,830
這沒什么的呀 送他個領帶怎么樣
No biggie. Hey, what about a tie?

884
01:29:09,634 --> 01:29:11,393
克里斯蒂安有一大堆領帶
Christian has a lot of ties.

885
01:29:11,918 --> 01:29:15,674
- 襪子 背帶 什么的 給我個建議也好啊  - 還有  噢 天吶 
- Socks, suspenders, throw me a bone here. - And, oh.. god.

886
01:29:15,674 --> 01:29:16,914
米婭 我要掛電話了
Mia, I gotta go.

887
01:29:16,914 --> 01:29:20,313
好吧 不過星期天我可要去親自找你 拜拜
Okay, okay. But Sunday I'll hunt you down myself. Bye

888
01:29:23,866 --> 01:29:25,021
完美
Perfect.

889
01:29:33,084 --> 01:29:36,258
- 這個有禮品盒嗎 - 稍等
- Do you have a gift-box? - One second.

890
01:29:39,183 --> 01:29:40,409
嘿
Hey.

891
01:29:47,363 --> 01:29:50,181
斯蒂爾女士 你好嗎
Ms Steele. How's your day?

892
01:29:50,602 --> 01:29:54,207
挺好的 格雷先生 泰勒去哪了
Looking up, Mr Grey. Where's Taylor?

893
01:29:54,207 --> 01:29:56,116
他去取我的包了
He went to get my bag.

894
01:29:56,498 --> 01:29:58,285
你的包 你要去哪
Your bag? Where you going?

895
01:29:58,573 --> 01:30:01,568
我和羅絲要去波特蘭開會
Ross and I have to go to Portland for some meetings.

896
01:30:01,568 --> 01:30:04,992
我明晚就回來
I'll be back tomorrow night.

897
01:30:06,179 --> 01:30:08,153
你準備什么時候和我說你生日的事情
When are you going to tell me about your birthday?

898
01:30:10,507 --> 01:30:13,242
你爸媽準備給你辦個派對
Your parents are throwing you a party.

899
01:30:13,243 --> 01:30:15,330
難不成到時候我們就呆在家里
Were we gonna just stay home?

900
01:30:15,726 --> 01:30:19,728
- 他們每年都要辦一次生日聚會 - 是啊 那可是生日
- They do this every year. - Well yeah. Birthday.

901
01:30:21,606 --> 01:30:25,853
一個生日而已 我覺得沒必要這么大操大辦
My arrival in the world isn't something I feel like celebrating.

902
01:30:26,660 --> 01:30:29,218
我想要為你慶生
I feel like celebrating it.

903
01:30:31,429 --> 01:30:34,317
到你生日的那天再打開它
Can't open it till the day of event.

904
01:30:34,976 --> 01:30:37,486
那么為什么要現在給我呢
Then why give it to me now?

905
01:30:38,705 --> 01:30:40,716
這叫糖果效應
Call it delayed gratification.

906
01:31:44,188 --> 01:31:47,174
克里斯蒂安 這是什么情況
Christian. What is that?

907
01:31:49,571 --> 01:31:53,040
噢 我的天啊 噢 不
Oh my god. Oh no.

908
01:31:58,564 --> 01:32:00,245
克里斯蒂安 怎么辦啊
Christian. What's going on?

909
01:32:00,245 --> 01:32:03,411
- 請求支援 請求支援 請求支援 - 怎么了
- Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! - What's happening?

910
01:32:10,376 --> 01:32:12,426
別別別
Stop it.

911
01:32:12,426 --> 01:32:16,030
抓緊 別松手
Hold tight. Hold tight.

912
01:32:29,095 --> 01:32:32,951
- 你好 - 噢我的上帝啊 你曬黑了
- Hi. - Oh my god, you're so tanned.

913
01:32:32,951 --> 01:32:33,591
容光煥發
Glowing.

914
01:32:33,591 --> 01:32:36,826
- 安娜 來杯啤酒嗎? - 好的 再好不過了
- Want a beer Anna? - Yes please please.

915
01:32:37,192 --> 01:32:39,385
- 你好 何塞 - 嗨
- Hi Jose. - Hey.

916
01:32:39,385 --> 01:32:44,070
- 近況如何 - 那么恭喜你榮升小說編輯
- How's it going? - So, congratulations fiction editor.

917
01:32:44,070 --> 01:32:47,992
- 是的 她現在可是位高權重 - 你家那位怎么樣了
- Right. She's a big deal now. - And how's your hottie?

918
01:32:48,572 --> 01:32:53,556
克里斯蒂安很好 他讓我搬去和他住
Christian is good. He asked me to move in with him.

919
01:32:54,220 --> 01:32:57,514
- 什么 - 安娜要搬去和克里斯蒂安住 
- What? - Anna is moving in with Christian.

920
01:32:57,514 --> 01:33:00,352
噢 太棒了 你知道的 我們可以共享一些小秘密
Oh that's great. You know, We could use some privacy.

921
01:33:01,900 --> 01:33:04,584
你真狡猾
You're so subtle.

922
01:33:06,190 --> 01:33:08,358
所以你看起來有點緊張但是卻很開心?
So you're serious but are you happy?

923
01:33:08,359 --> 01:33:10,166
我真為你高興
Cause that's all I care about.

924
01:33:10,166 --> 01:33:14,440
我 我的意思是這很復雜 但是我從未像現在這么開心
I.. I mean it's complicated but I have never been happier.

925
01:33:14,440 --> 01:33:17,495
- 嘿 米婭 怎么了 你聽說了何塞的攝影展了嗎?
- Hey Mia, whassup? - Did you hear about Jose's show?

926
01:33:17,495 --> 01:33:21,565
真難以置信 他自己都沒想到會廣受贊譽
It was incredible. Really he was amazing. He got rave review.

927
01:33:21,565 --> 01:33:24,109
- 說來聽聽 - 等下 等等 米婭 慢點說
- I gotta check it out. - Wait wait Mia, slow down.

928
01:33:25,504 --> 01:33:27,719
媽的 好吧 好吧 馬上
Shit. Okay. Yea, yeah Right away.

929
01:33:29,878 --> 01:33:32,889
克里斯蒂安的飛機在回波特蘭的途中失聯了
Christian's chopper went missing on the way back to Portland.

930
01:33:32,889 --> 01:33:35,177
現在他們正在成立搜救小組
They're setting up search parties right now.

931
01:33:35,871 --> 01:33:37,833
來吧 快點
Come on, let's go.

932
01:33:38,602 --> 01:33:40,480
關于這則不幸新聞的更多消息
More on this breaking story is

933
01:33:40,481 --> 01:33:43,737
由我們的記者雷切爾 泰勒播報 雷切爾
about from field our reporter Rachel Taylor. Rachel.

934
01:33:43,737 --> 01:33:45,400
謝謝約翰 現在正在為大家播報的是
Thank you John. I'm speaking to you live

935
01:33:45,400 --> 01:33:47,390
一架飛往西雅圖的私人飛機失事事件
from the private helicopter terminal at Seattle.

936
01:33:47,390 --> 01:33:50,746
他們會找到他的 他會沒事的 他可是克里斯蒂安
They'll find him. He'll be okay. It's Christian.

937
01:33:50,746 --> 01:33:52,192
今天下午晚些時候
Late this afternoon,

938
01:33:52,192 --> 01:33:55,419
一架空客H130的直升機
the helicopter was an Airbus helicopter H130.

939
01:33:55,419 --> 01:33:57,971
我們還能做什么
Is there anything we can do?

940
01:33:57,971 --> 01:34:01,880
盡管克里斯蒂安只有27歲但他持證多年 飛行經驗豐富
And Christian only 27 years old had extensive flying experience.

941
01:34:01,880 --> 01:34:02,638
好了 再見吧
Alright bye.

942
01:34:02,638 --> 01:34:04,888
他是西雅圖最年輕的億萬富翁之一，也是跨國公司
One of Seattle's youngest billionaire has grazed

943
01:34:04,888 --> 01:34:07,144
格雷企業控股有限公司的
the charismatic head of Grey enterprise holdings.

944
01:34:07,144 --> 01:34:09,787
最受矚目的鉆石王老五
a multi-national conglomerate..

945
01:34:09,787 --> 01:34:14,642
- 我的上帝啊 能來人關掉這個嗎 - 請不要關掉
- Jesus. Would someone shut them up. - No please.

946
01:34:14,642 --> 01:34:16,936
把聲音調低一點 好了 謝謝你
Just turn it down. Okay. Thank you.

947
01:34:17,951 --> 01:34:21,359
你在發抖 我給你拿件毛衣吧 沒事的
You're shivering. I'll get you a sweater. Okay.

948
01:34:26,163 --> 01:34:28,516
安娜 茶
Anna. Tea.

949
01:34:33,118 --> 01:34:36,890
他會沒事的 他一定吉人天相
He's gonna be fine. He has to be okay.

950
01:34:40,233 --> 01:34:42,516
我們在一起的時間太少了
We haven't had any time.

951
01:34:43,311 --> 01:34:45,990
我們應該有更多相處的時間
We need to have more time.

952
01:34:46,589 --> 01:34:49,473
你們以后有的是時間
You will have plenty of time.

953
01:34:51,252 --> 01:34:54,280
我們還是高興你跟我們在一起共渡難關
We're still glad that you're here with us.

954
01:34:54,281 --> 01:34:56,011
也慶幸你出現在克里斯蒂安的生命中
And in Christian's life.

955
01:34:57,480 --> 01:35:00,218
你讓他發生了很大的改變
You've made such a difference to him.

956
01:35:02,177 --> 01:35:04,739
他從未讓任何人如此
He never let anyone get..

957
01:35:05,204 --> 01:35:08,434
的靠近 直至你的出現
close. Until you came along.

958
01:35:10,690 --> 01:35:13,399
格蕾絲 他很愛你
Grace. He adores you.

959
01:35:13,399 --> 01:35:17,480
我知道 不過孩子長大總會疏遠父母 這
I know. But children grown out of their parents and thats..

960
01:35:17,480 --> 01:35:21,061
這沒關系 只要他們開心
that's fine. As long as they're happy.

961
01:35:21,831 --> 01:35:27,918
他和你在一起很開心
And he.. is happy.. with you.

962
01:35:28,327 --> 01:35:31,207
這正是我盼望的
And that's all I ever wanted.

963
01:35:31,207 --> 01:35:32,284
聲音開大點
Turn it up.

964
01:35:32,284 --> 01:35:35,188
克里斯蒂安 格雷和他的同事羅絲 貝利
That Christian Grey and his colleague Ross Bailey

965
01:35:35,188 --> 01:35:36,998
已獲救 兩人安全無恙
have been found safe and well

966
01:35:36,999 --> 01:35:39,996
此時此刻 他們在回西雅圖的途中
and at this moment on their way back to Seattle.

967
01:35:42,049 --> 01:35:43,566
你們在這干什么
What the hell y'all doing here?

968
01:35:43,566 --> 01:35:46,190
克里斯蒂安 天啊 克里斯蒂安 你是怎么回來的
Christian. Oh my god. Christian..How did you get here?

969
01:35:49,188 --> 01:35:53,557
發生了什么事 天啊 你為什么不打電話
What happened, Oh my god. Why didn't you call?

970
01:35:53,557 --> 01:35:57,077
我出了點事 手機弄丟了
I had an accident. I lost my phone.

971
01:35:57,077 --> 01:36:00,154
我很好 羅絲也很好
I'm fine. Ros is fine.

972
01:36:00,542 --> 01:36:02,122
他回來了 剛剛走了進來
He's here, he just walked in.

973
01:36:02,123 --> 01:36:04,357
他看上去糟透了 但沒有受傷
He looks like shit but he is in one piece

974
01:36:06,420 --> 01:36:08,535
大家放松點 我很好 好嗎
Guys, relax. I'm fine. Okay.

975
01:36:10,896 --> 01:36:12,663
讓我向我的女孩打個招呼
Let me say hi to my girl.

976
01:36:12,663 --> 01:36:15,166
過來 老媽
Come on mom.

977
01:36:18,727 --> 01:36:20,760
想我嗎
Miss me?

978
01:36:35,817 --> 01:36:38,368
- 我以為  - 嘿 嘿
- I thought...  - Hey..Hey..

979
01:36:38,368 --> 01:36:39,208
對不起
Sorry..

980
01:36:40,875 --> 01:36:44,709
我很害怕 非常害怕
I was so scared... So scared.

981
01:36:48,507 --> 01:36:50,988
我以為永遠失去你了
I thought I lost you forever.

982
01:36:51,224 --> 01:36:55,030
不會的 我在這
Not a chance. I'm here.

983
01:37:05,837 --> 01:37:07,995
- 回去小心點 - 讓我再待會
- Careful.. - No.

984
01:37:08,726 --> 01:37:11,604
- 媽  - 好吧
- Mom. - Okay..

985
01:37:13,164 --> 01:37:15,446
我們明天見 晚安
We'll see you tomorrow. Good night.

986
01:37:22,070 --> 01:37:25,890
- 午夜都過了 - 我還不困
- It's after midnight. - I'm not tired.

987
01:37:26,238 --> 01:37:29,837
不 今天是你的生日
No, it's your birthday.

988
01:37:32,040 --> 01:37:34,096
是啊
Yeah.

989
01:37:34,672 --> 01:37:39,103
- 生日快樂  - 謝謝
- Happy birthday.  - Thank you.

990
01:37:42,345 --> 01:37:45,123
我送你的禮物還帶著嗎
Do you still have the gift I gave you?

991
01:37:59,226 --> 01:38:01,035
你知道你不需要這樣的
You know you don't have to.

992
01:38:02,081 --> 01:38:03,831
我想要的只有你
All I want is you.

993
01:38:04,167 --> 01:38:06,578
- 你打開看看 - 好的
- Just open it.  - Okay.

994
01:38:13,397 --> 01:38:17,066
- 一個鑰匙串 - 翻過來看看
- A key chain.  - Turn it over.

995
01:38:26,270 --> 01:38:28,882
這是說 你愿意 對吧
This is meant, Yes Yes?

996
01:38:29,274 --> 01:38:30,413
是的
Yes.

997
01:38:30,621 --> 01:38:32,345
是的 是的 我愿意
Yes Yes Yes.

998
01:38:41,284 --> 01:38:44,238
所以這一段時間我一直把答案裝在口袋里
So this whole time I had the answer in my pocket?

999
01:38:45,904 --> 01:38:50,325
安娜塔西雅 斯蒂爾
我該拿你怎么辦
Anastasia Steele. What am I gonna do with you?

1000
01:39:22,473 --> 01:39:27,418
帶我去紅房子 帶我去那兒
Take me...to the Red house. Take me.. take me to the red house.

1001
01:39:28,334 --> 01:39:30,203
- 你確定嗎 - 是的
- Are you sure? - Yes.

1002
01:42:18,143 --> 01:42:19,228
你好
Hi.

1003
01:42:21,448 --> 01:42:23,731
- 格雷先生 需要香檳嗎 - 謝謝
- Champagne, Mr. Grey? - Thanks.

1004
01:42:23,731 --> 01:42:27,011
我能祝您生日快樂嗎
And can I just say happy birthday?

1005
01:42:27,631 --> 01:42:29,710
當然了 謝謝你
Sure, thank you.

1006
01:42:32,808 --> 01:42:34,975
- 克里斯蒂安 - 媽媽
- Christian. - Mom..

1007
01:42:34,975 --> 01:42:37,195
- 生日快樂 - 謝謝
- Happy Birthday. - Thank you.

1008
01:42:37,699 --> 01:42:40,733
安娜 真高興能再見到你
And Anna, so good to see you again.

1009
01:42:40,993 --> 01:42:44,389
- 你昨晚見過我倆了 - 是
- You saw us last night. - Yes.

1010
01:42:44,697 --> 01:42:48,732
那是因為我從不把事情的發生看作理所當然
And because of that I'm never taking anything for granted.

1011
01:42:48,732 --> 01:42:50,238
從不
Ever again.

1012
01:42:50,486 --> 01:42:54,022
我聽說你發生了墜機事故 你沒事吧
Hey, I heard about the crash. Are you okay?

1013
01:42:54,022 --> 01:42:55,654
我沒事 埃琳娜 謝謝關心
I'm fine, Elena, thank you.

1014
01:42:56,302 --> 01:43:00,714
安娜 請容許我向你介紹我的好朋友 埃琳娜 林肯
Anna, let me introduce to you my good friend Elena Lincoln.

1015
01:43:01,025 --> 01:43:03,748
- 我們在化裝舞會上見過 - 是的
- We met at the masquerade. - Yes..

1016
01:43:04,183 --> 01:43:06,158
很高興再次見到你
Nice to see you again.

1017
01:43:07,606 --> 01:43:09,833
- 失陪 - 去吧
- Excuse us. - Surely.

1018
01:43:09,833 --> 01:43:12,522
她很優秀
She's fantastic.

1019
01:43:19,944 --> 01:43:22,997
各位女士 先生們 米婭
Ladies and gentlemen, Mia..

1020
01:43:24,446 --> 01:43:27,333
感謝你們今晚的蒞臨
I wanna thank you all for coming here this evening.

1021
01:43:27,333 --> 01:43:30,361
我本想舉辦的是家庭小聚會 真是多虧了米婭
I was expecting small family gathering, Thanks Mia..

1022
01:43:30,361 --> 01:43:32,372
但我很高興你們的到來
But I'm happy that you're all here.

1023
01:43:32,373 --> 01:43:34,613
因為我有事宣布
Because I have an announcement to make.

1024
01:43:35,150 --> 01:43:39,918
如你們所知 我和羅絲昨天死里逃生
As most of you know. Yesterday Ros and I had a narrow escape.

1025
01:43:40,882 --> 01:43:44,841
這事提醒了我們 何為真正重要的東西
And something like that, Reminds us of what really matters.

1026
01:43:44,841 --> 01:43:48,570
以及把握當下的重要性
And how important it is to seize the day.

1027
01:43:48,570 --> 01:43:52,113
安娜 請你上來一會
Anna, come up here a second, please.

1028
01:44:01,375 --> 01:44:02,711
不久前
So a while ago I was

1029
01:44:02,712 --> 01:44:05,719
我傾情于這位年輕而優秀的女士
looking up to meet this amazing young woman..

1030
01:44:05,744 --> 01:44:07,381
安娜塔西雅 斯蒂爾
Anastasia Steele.

1031
01:44:07,406 --> 01:44:09,817
我很快就意識到 她是我的真命天女
Very quickly I realized that she was the one,

1032
01:44:09,842 --> 01:44:11,888
想攜手一生的人
I wanted to share my life with.

1033
01:44:12,092 --> 01:44:15,050
我向她求婚
So I asked her to marry me.

1034
01:44:15,050 --> 01:44:16,810
她答應了
And she said yes.

1035
01:44:19,260 --> 01:44:21,052
太棒了
So good.

1036
01:44:33,234 --> 01:44:36,182
- 歡迎加入我們的大家庭 - 謝謝
- Welcome to the family. - Thank you.

1037
01:44:36,182 --> 01:44:39,660
我不用再面對我的客戶了 我重獲新生了
I wouldn't meet my client anymore. I would just rehydrate.

1038
01:44:39,660 --> 01:44:42,082
- 天哪 別哭 - 恭喜
- Oh My God, don't do that. - Congratulations.

1039
01:44:42,082 --> 01:44:45,974
- 媽媽 - 我愛你
- Hi, mom. - I love you.

1040
01:44:47,687 --> 01:44:50,203
干得漂亮 哥哥
Well done, big brother.

1041
01:44:50,412 --> 01:44:52,853
戒指呢 給我看看戒指
Ring! Show me the ring.

1042
01:44:53,155 --> 01:44:54,900
我們會一起去挑戒指
We're gonna choose it together.

1043
01:44:54,900 --> 01:44:55,901
沒有大鉆戒嗎
No rock?

1044
01:44:55,926 --> 01:45:00,134
克里斯蒂安 格雷 太棒了 我有嫂子了
...Christian Grey. Oh my god! I have a sister.

1045
01:45:12,664 --> 01:45:15,601
你自由了幾個星期后 居然要結婚了
Leave you alone for a couple of weeks and this is what happens?

1046
01:45:15,601 --> 01:45:18,235
我知道 很抱歉沒早告訴你
I know, I'm sorry I didn't tell you.

1047
01:45:18,235 --> 01:45:20,193
傻瓜 過來
Oh please. Come here.

1048
01:45:22,152 --> 01:45:23,988
所以你對西雅圖鉆石王老五
So how does it feel to

1049
01:45:24,018 --> 01:45:26,606
感覺如何
Seattle most eligible bachelor?

1050
01:45:26,606 --> 01:45:30,297
- 雖然這有點嚇人 不過 - 只有你才能做到
- It's a little scary but... - If anyone can make it work, it's you.

1051
01:45:30,830 --> 01:45:33,108
嘿 嫂嫂
Hey, sis-in-law.

1052
01:45:33,108 --> 01:45:37,080
恭喜了 克里斯蒂安可是個很走運的家伙
Congratulations. Christian's a very lucky guy.

1053
01:45:37,080 --> 01:45:40,393
不管怎樣你已經被他攬入懷中了
...You however are certified

1054
01:45:41,178 --> 01:45:42,343
不好意思打斷一下
Sorry to interrupt, Mia

1055
01:45:42,344 --> 01:45:44,573
米婭想嘗一杯你調的雞尾酒
wants to taste one of your killer cocktails.

1056
01:45:44,573 --> 01:45:45,786
哦 馬上就來
Oh, coming right up.

1057
01:45:47,868 --> 01:45:50,355
看到你讓我們的閑談升溫真好
Nice to see you heat it on our little talk.

1058
01:45:56,414 --> 01:45:58,903
你是怎么覺得我會一直聽你說下去
What makes you think that I would ever listen to you?

1059
01:45:58,903 --> 01:46:00,464
你并不在乎克里斯蒂安
You don't care about Christian.

1060
01:46:00,464 --> 01:46:03,833
他會明白的 我保證
he will see to that. I'll make sure of it.

1061
01:46:03,833 --> 01:46:08,674
他會看透你的 你沒戲 埃琳娜
He'll see right through you. It's over for you... Elena.

1062
01:46:08,674 --> 01:46:11,944
你對他來說只是一個用錢養著的小玩物
You're just a mousy little thing after his money.

1063
01:46:11,944 --> 01:46:14,822
他不是個適合結婚的對象
He's not capable of marriage.

1064
01:46:21,050 --> 01:46:22,734
謝謝你 克里斯蒂安
Thank you, Christian.

1065
01:46:22,734 --> 01:46:24,099
你怎么會在這里 埃琳娜
Why're you even here Elena?

1066
01:46:25,903 --> 01:46:29,022
她不適合你 你并不了解什么適合我
She's not right for you. You don't know what's right for me.

1067
01:46:29,145 --> 01:46:31,298
你教我怎么操 埃琳娜
You tell me how to fuck Elena.

1068
01:46:31,565 --> 01:46:33,526
但安娜教會我如何去愛
Anna tell me how to love.

1069
01:46:33,526 --> 01:46:35,535
她不過是下一個排到隊的
She's just the next one in line.

1070
01:46:35,535 --> 01:46:38,191
滾出去
Get out of my house.

1071
01:46:42,410 --> 01:46:45,777
別騷擾我的孩子 馬上從我家滾出去
Leave my children alone and get the hell out of my house.

1072
01:46:58,672 --> 01:47:00,046
安娜 寶貝
...Anna, darling.

1073
01:47:02,777 --> 01:47:05,195
你能讓我們單獨呆一會兒嗎
Would you give us a moment alone please?

1074
01:47:34,594 --> 01:47:36,430
剛才的事 我很抱歉
I'm sorry about that.

1075
01:47:39,947 --> 01:47:41,852
你媽媽還好嗎
Is your Mom okay?

1076
01:47:42,345 --> 01:47:44,289
當然
Sure is..

1077
01:47:44,929 --> 01:47:48,940
埃琳娜已經走了 
Elena's gone. Like gone gone?

1078
01:47:48,965 --> 01:47:52,312
都結束了 生意 所有事
I'm done. The business, everything..

1079
01:47:52,312 --> 01:47:55,651
具體事項我明天會讓我的人處理
I'll have my people sort out the details tomorrow.

1080
01:47:57,228 --> 01:48:01,580
我明白她對你來說很重要 我很抱歉
I know she was important to you. I'm sorry.

1081
01:48:04,057 --> 01:48:05,898
- 你是 - 不 不
- Are you? - No... No.

1082
01:48:09,637 --> 01:48:11,634
你拿的什么
What's that you got there?

1083
01:48:25,543 --> 01:48:28,415
跟我來 我有東西要給你看
Come with me. There is something I need to show you.

1084
01:48:32,173 --> 01:48:34,958
上次我們來過這里 我被你扛在肩上
Last time we came down here. I was over your shoulder.

1085
01:48:35,698 --> 01:48:37,015
噢 是啊
Oh yeah.

1086
01:48:53,818 --> 01:48:55,557
你先請
After you.

1087
01:49:07,329 --> 01:49:09,395
我的天吶
Oh my God!

1088
01:49:09,395 --> 01:49:13,478
- 你想要一束鮮花嗎 - 我的天吶
- You want a bunch of flowers? - Oh my God!

1089
01:49:13,478 --> 01:49:15,965
沒事的 別擔心
It's ok. It's ok.

1090
01:49:21,879 --> 01:49:23,299
克里斯蒂安
...Christian.

1091
01:49:25,999 --> 01:49:28,275
這里太夢幻了
This is amazing.

1092
01:49:34,934 --> 01:49:35,894
做我的女人
Be mine.

1093
01:49:37,845 --> 01:49:40,307
和我共度余生
Share my life with me.

1094
01:49:41,120 --> 01:49:42,120
好
Yes.

1095
01:49:43,077 --> 01:49:44,993
嫁給我
Marry me.

1096
01:49:47,584 --> 01:49:49,146
哦 寶貝
Oh baby.

1097
01:49:49,741 --> 01:49:51,465
好吧
Alright.

1098
01:50:06,343 --> 01:50:08,260
那是你做的嗎
Did you do that?

1099
01:50:23,484 --> 01:50:25,958
這太漂亮了 噢
It's so pretty. Oh!

1100
01:51:15,575 --> 01:51:17,134
我鄭重承諾
I solemnly vow

1101
01:51:18,363 --> 01:51:20,262
我會真心愛你
to love you faithfully

1102
01:51:21,200 --> 01:51:24,395
只要我們都活著 我就一定會護你周全
and to keep you safe for as long as we both shall live.

