1
00:01:29,520 --> 00:01:32,770
愛的拐點

2
00:03:02,340 --> 00:03:03,140
貝卡
Becca?

3
00:03:04,260 --> 00:03:05,030
貝卡
Becca?

4
00:03:06,280 --> 00:03:09,300
你好 佩吉
Oh...hey Peg.

5
00:03:09,820 --> 00:03:11,060
看上去真不錯
It looks so nice back here.

6
00:03:11,440 --> 00:03:13,940
我就是想把花園稍微整理一下
Well, I'm just, you know, trying to get things back into shape.

7
00:03:14,150 --> 00:03:16,730
不知道你和豪威今晚有沒有空
Listen, I don't know if you and Howie are free tonigh.

8
00:03:16,740 --> 00:03:18,310
我們約了幾個人一起過來吃晚餐
Having a few people over for dinner.

9
00:03:18,320 --> 00:03:20,450
真謝謝你一番好意 佩吉
Oh, that's very sweet of you.

10
00:03:20,450 --> 00:03:21,530
我知道時間很倉促
I know it's really short notice.

11
00:03:21,540 --> 00:03:23,150
但我們已經有安排了
Actually, we have plans.

12
00:03:23,990 --> 00:03:29,120
下次吧 好久沒跟皮特說過話了
Oh. Oh, well. But, uh, another time though. I haven't talked to Pete in ages.

13
00:03:29,130 --> 00:03:30,450
倒沒什么新鮮事
Well you haven't missed much. He's

14
00:03:30,460 --> 00:03:33,430
他還是那副熊樣 老樣子
still the same s.O.B. He always was.

15
00:03:33,430 --> 00:03:36,470
天啊 不好意思
Oh God. I'm so sorry.

16
00:03:37,750 --> 00:03:38,590
沒事
It's okay.

17
00:03:38,590 --> 00:03:39,500
-太對不起了 -不用 不用
I am so sorry.

18
00:03:39,500 --> 00:03:40,780
真的 沒什么
No, it's fine.

19
00:03:40,780 --> 00:03:41,960
看我笨手笨腳的
These stupid feet.

20
00:03:43,120 --> 00:03:45,360
祝你們晚餐愉快 佩吉
Well, have a great dinner, Peg.

21
00:03:46,440 --> 00:03:47,710
我們下次再一起吃飯
We'll do it next time.

22
00:03:47,720 --> 00:03:49,430
好 一定
Absolutely.

23
00:03:51,330 --> 00:03:52,530
幫我跟豪威問個好
Say hi to Howie for me.

24
00:03:52,540 --> 00:03:54,530
我會的
I sure will.

25
00:03:55,140 --> 00:03:56,600
再見
Goodbye.

26
00:03:57,040 --> 00:03:58,290
再見
Bye bye.

27
00:04:20,140 --> 00:04:21,890
聞上去很香啊
Mmmm. Smells good in there.

28
00:04:21,900 --> 00:04:24,390
如果佩吉問你 就說我們今晚出去了
If Peg asks, we went out tonight.

29
00:04:27,310 --> 00:04:28,710
去哪了
Where'll we go?

30
00:04:29,440 --> 00:04:31,220
去看斯托帕德的戲了
We saw the Stoppard play.

31
00:04:31,470 --> 00:04:32,270
是嗎
Really?

32
00:04:32,550 --> 00:04:33,870
看得開心嗎
Did we enjoy it?

33
00:04:34,190 --> 00:04:34,980
非常開心
Very much.

34
00:04:37,150 --> 00:04:39,530
她又邀我們去吃飯了
She asked us to dinner again.

35
00:04:41,090 --> 00:04:42,800
她是好意
She's just being nice.

36
00:04:43,530 --> 00:04:45,750
那你去那邊吃好了
You're more than welcome to go over there.

37
00:04:53,370 --> 00:04:54,880
拋下你的意式燴飯嗎
And abandon your risotto?

38
00:04:55,100 --> 00:04:57,480
小心點 豪威 鍋很燙
Careful, Howie. The pan's hot.

39
00:05:06,940 --> 00:05:07,460
嘿
Hey...

40
00:05:07,850 --> 00:05:09,140
我去沖個澡
Hey... I'm gonna hop in the shower.

41
00:05:09,830 --> 00:05:13,070
晚餐大概二十分鐘好
Uh- Huh. About twenty minutes.

42
00:05:33,910 --> 00:05:35,590
喂
Hello?

43
00:05:39,390 --> 00:05:41,070
現在都幾點了
What time is it?

44
00:05:43,910 --> 00:05:45,400
怎么了
What's going on?

45
00:06:00,270 --> 00:06:02,230
沒什么要說的嗎
You have nothing to say?

46
00:06:03,990 --> 00:06:04,520
謝謝
Thank you?

47
00:06:06,220 --> 00:06:07,420
你酗酒斗毆
You were in a bar- Fight

48
00:06:07,730 --> 00:06:08,680
那不是酗酒斗毆
It wasn't a bar- Fight

49
00:06:09,410 --> 00:06:12,300
你在酒吧和人打架
You were in a bar. Fighting.

50
00:06:13,040 --> 00:06:15,810
那不是打架 有個喝醉的女生沖著我吼
It wasn't a fight. Some drunk girlwas screaming in my face,

51
00:06:15,810 --> 00:06:17,300
我就打了她 僅此而已
so I hit her and that was the end of it.

52
00:06:17,310 --> 00:06:18,880
那個女生是誰
Well who was she?

53
00:06:18,890 --> 00:06:20,620
不認識
I don't know.

54
00:06:20,910 --> 00:06:23,090
別人不會無緣無故沖你吼
People don't scream at you for no reason.

55
00:06:23,100 --> 00:06:25,580
當然會 你該多出來玩玩
Sure they do, you should get out more.

56
00:06:26,300 --> 00:06:28,880
天哪 伊姿 這真像杰瑞·斯普林格
God Izzy, it's so...jerry springer.

57
00:06:28,890 --> 00:06:32,290
你什么意思 我很垃圾是嗎
What's that supposed to mean? You think I'm trashy?

58
00:06:32,540 --> 00:06:35,180
你不能老這樣 你不再是小孩子了
You can't keep doing this. You're not a kid anymore.

59
00:06:35,490 --> 00:06:37,010
我不知道這還有截止日期的
I didn't know there was a cutoff date.

60
00:06:37,290 --> 00:06:39,710
的確有 瞎胡鬧的日子總要有個頭
Well there is. For acting like ajackass, there's a cutoff date...

61
00:06:40,610 --> 00:06:42,460
別讓我老為你擔心了
I wanna stop worrying about you.

62
00:06:43,650 --> 00:06:46,150
不用擔心我 被打趴下的是她
Hey, don't worry about me. She was the one on the floor.

63
00:06:49,250 --> 00:06:50,970
我今晚能去你那睡嗎
Can I stay with you tonight?

64
00:07:22,100 --> 00:07:26,240
準備好 一 二 三 好高啊
Ready? One, two, three. That was high!

65
00:07:30,400 --> 00:07:31,670
丹尼 回頭看我
Danny, look at me when you come back.

66
00:07:31,830 --> 00:07:32,690
他在慢慢習慣
He's getting used to it.

67
00:07:32,690 --> 00:07:34,020
-想吃蛋糕嗎 -想
- Do you want any cake. - Yeah!

68
00:07:34,020 --> 00:07:35,820
我們今天有蛋糕嗎
Oh, do we have cake today?

69
00:07:35,820 --> 00:07:37,370
-有 -有嗎
- Yeah. - Yeah, we do.

70
00:07:39,080 --> 00:07:41,870
我的天啊 你真想吃嗎
Oh, my gosh. And you really want some?

71
00:08:07,710 --> 00:08:08,940
這不是打女玉嬌龍嗎
Well, if it isn't Ma Barker.

72
00:08:09,330 --> 00:08:11,090
我要知道那是誰就搞笑了
I'm sure that would be very funny if I knew who that was.

73
00:08:11,370 --> 00:08:12,670
我去和瑞克打壁球了
Rick and I are gonna play squash.

74
00:08:13,160 --> 00:08:14,390
-有事打我電話 -好的
I have my cell if you need me.

75
00:08:14,670 --> 00:08:17,770
壁球 你還打壁球啊 豪威
Squash. You go play squash, Howie.

76
00:08:18,120 --> 00:08:19,360
你都不知道壁球是什么吧
You don't even know what squash is.

77
00:08:19,370 --> 00:08:21,840
我才不關心什么是壁球
I don't care what squash is

78
00:08:22,830 --> 00:08:23,890
喂
Hello?

79
00:08:27,110 --> 00:08:28,860
是的 是的
Yeah! Yeah.

80
00:08:31,090 --> 00:08:32,230
我以為她會殺了我
I thought she was gonna kill me!

81
00:08:32,240 --> 00:08:35,340
我知道 奧吉一定告訴她了
Yeah, I know. I think Auggie must have told her.

82
00:08:35,780 --> 00:08:37,990
我得掛了 再見
Hey, I gotta go.

83
00:08:39,850 --> 00:08:43,370
謝謝 貝卡
Mmm. Thank you Becca.

84
00:08:44,300 --> 00:08:46,240
現在我知道這東西是什么了
I know what this stuff is now.

85
00:08:46,700 --> 00:08:48,250
我喜歡它上面烤得脆脆的
Oo, I like the way it cracks.

86
00:08:48,760 --> 00:08:50,020
喜歡吧
Of course you do.

87
00:08:51,060 --> 00:08:52,780
你其實認識那個女人
So you did know that woman.

88
00:08:53,210 --> 00:08:55,320
天啊 你怎么偷聽我講電話
Oh my God! Why are you listening to my phone conversations?

89
00:08:55,950 --> 00:08:58,480
你是不是和那女生的男朋友上床了
Are you sleeping with that girl's boyfriend.

90
00:08:58,840 --> 00:09:00,150
他們倆已經結束了
It's been over between them. They're just

91
00:09:00,160 --> 00:09:01,910
他們還住在一起只是因為租的房子
living together because of the rent.

92
00:09:01,920 --> 00:09:03,510
那她為什么找你麻煩
Then why did she accost you?

93
00:09:03,790 --> 00:09:04,850
她就是個瘋子
Because she's a lunatic!

94
00:09:09,080 --> 00:09:10,520
而且奧吉一定告訴她我懷孕了
And Auggie told her I was pregnant

95
00:09:14,570 --> 00:09:15,370
你不會吧
You are not.

96
00:09:15,840 --> 00:09:19,390
你一定會喜歡他的 他特棒 是搞音樂的
You're gonna love him. He's a really great guy. He's a musician!

97
00:09:20,330 --> 00:09:21,320
那很好啊
That's terrific.

98
00:09:21,350 --> 00:09:24,160
他有工作 是個音樂人
He works, Becca. He gets work as a musician.

99
00:09:25,860 --> 00:09:26,840
你們認識多久了
How long have you known?

100
00:09:27,470 --> 00:09:28,320
幾個星期吧
A few weeks.

101
00:09:29,160 --> 00:09:29,900
你告訴媽了嗎
Did you tell Mom?

102
00:09:31,120 --> 00:09:33,530
不會吧 你先告訴媽了
Oh, come on. You told Mom before me?

103
00:09:33,540 --> 00:09:34,860
我沒辦法
I had to.

104
00:09:35,030 --> 00:09:36,000
為什么不告訴我
Why didn't you tell me?

105
00:09:36,010 --> 00:09:37,760
為什么要告訴你
Why do you think?

106
00:09:43,940 --> 00:09:45,270
對不起 貝卡 我知道它來的不是時候
- I'm sorry, Becca. I know the timing

107
00:09:45,270 --> 00:09:46,570
那你能怎么辦呢
really sucks. - Hey, what can ya do?

108
00:09:47,440 --> 00:09:49,770
很高興你最后還是告訴了我
I'm just glad you finally told me.

109
00:10:14,120 --> 00:10:17,790
翻修廚房的事黛比快把我弄瘋了
Debbie's been driving me crazy with these kitchen renovations.

110
00:10:17,800 --> 00:10:20,700
跟你說 光是討論廚房臺面板...
The counter-top negotiations alone...

111
00:10:20,980 --> 00:10:22,080
告訴過你不要娶一個事業狂
I told you not to marry an agent.

112
00:10:24,420 --> 00:10:26,340
她還沒打電話來 知道嗎
She still hasn't called, you know.

113
00:10:28,410 --> 00:10:28,970
是的 我知道
No, I know.

114
00:10:31,380 --> 00:10:33,370
我不想招人煩 只是...
I don't mean to be a pest about it, but...

115
00:10:34,520 --> 00:10:36,280
我知道貝卡接到她電話會很高興的
I just know Becca would love to hear from her.

116
00:10:36,290 --> 00:10:42,250
我明白 我會告訴她的 豪威 她還是有點...
I know. I tell her, Howie. I do. But she's still...

117
00:10:44,760 --> 00:10:46,800
可能被嚇壞了了吧 我猜
I don't know freaked out, I guess.

118
00:10:47,660 --> 00:10:49,080
已經八個月了
It's been eight months.

119
00:10:49,430 --> 00:10:51,300
我知道 我會跟她說說
I know. I'll talk to her.

120
00:10:52,040 --> 00:10:52,700
謝了
Thank you.

121
00:10:53,320 --> 00:10:55,960
孩子們怎么樣
Hey, how are the kids?

122
00:10:56,620 --> 00:11:02,240
挺好的 艾米麗在學芭蕾 羅比在樂樂棒球隊
They're good. Emily's doing ballet. Robby is in tee-ball.

123
00:11:02,710 --> 00:11:05,560
不錯嘛 樂樂棒球
Wow. Tee-ball.

124
00:11:10,250 --> 00:11:14,120
你們倆想過再要一個嗎
Have you guys talked at all about having another?

125
00:11:16,580 --> 00:11:18,980
沒
No.

126
00:11:21,970 --> 00:11:22,950
還有點太早
It's a little soon.

127
00:11:25,910 --> 00:11:27,010
試一試沒啥不好
Just be open-minded.

128
00:11:27,460 --> 00:11:28,900
我這不都來了嗎
I'm here, aren't I?

129
00:11:39,060 --> 00:11:39,790
你們怎么樣
How's it going?

130
00:11:39,800 --> 00:11:41,680
還可以
Good.

131
00:11:41,680 --> 00:11:42,490
還過得下去吧
Yeah, good. Hanging in there.

132
00:11:42,940 --> 00:11:44,740
-確定嗎 -是的
- You sure. - Yeah.

133
00:11:44,820 --> 00:11:47,330
-嗨 凱文 -嗨 你好
- Hey, Kevin. - Hi. Hi.

134
00:11:47,410 --> 00:11:49,620
我們只是...
Yeah, we... We just...

135
00:11:51,750 --> 00:11:54,710
我們得知貝卡的妹妹懷孕了 所以...
We found out that Becca's sister is pregnant, so...

136
00:11:55,510 --> 00:11:56,880
-豪威 -怎么了
- Howie. - What?

137
00:11:56,960 --> 00:12:00,670
那很不容易 我記得我表妹懷孕的時候
That can be hard, I remember when my cousin got pregnant.

138
00:12:00,760 --> 00:12:03,590
其實也沒什么大不了的
Yeah, it's not really a big deal.

139
00:12:04,800 --> 00:12:05,700
好吧
Okay.

140
00:12:06,800 --> 00:12:08,080
如果你們想聊聊這事
Okay. If you wanna talk about it though,

141
00:12:08,090 --> 00:12:09,910
傾訴小組就在那邊 不用了
you know the group's right here.

142
00:12:10,160 --> 00:12:13,640
"大家好 新來的衰人"
Yeah, I don't think so. "Hey everybody, fresh meat."

143
00:12:14,530 --> 00:12:15,340
貝卡 好一點
Becca, be nice.

144
00:12:15,350 --> 00:12:16,920
她有讓你想起莉迪亞嗎
Doesn't she remind of you of Lydia?

145
00:12:17,590 --> 00:12:20,120
幾年前組里有個女人
There was this woman in the group a couple years ago.

146
00:12:20,400 --> 00:12:22,550
四年 是四年前
It was four. Four years ago.

147
00:12:23,010 --> 00:12:25,100
具體幾年不是重點
Well it doesn't really matter whenshe was here,

148
00:12:25,110 --> 00:12:28,590
重點是她讓我想起了莉迪亞
my point is that she reminds me of Lydia.

149
00:12:29,410 --> 00:12:32,110
她最開始對這種互助小組并不感冒
She reallywasn't into the support group model at first.

150
00:12:32,850 --> 00:12:34,050
你們在組里有多久了
How long have you been in group?

151
00:12:35,030 --> 00:12:36,230
到六月有八年了
It'll be eight years in june.

152
00:12:40,100 --> 00:12:44,250
我沒...我沒想到有這么久
Oh, I didn't... I didn't realize it was that long.

153
00:12:45,080 --> 00:12:46,210
我們是老油條了
Yeah, we're the veterans. You know for us,

154
00:12:46,220 --> 00:12:50,220
對我們來說 這是和大家保持聯絡的好方法
It's a good way to touch base.

155
00:12:50,220 --> 00:12:52,650
每個人情況不同
Everyone's on a different schedule...

156
00:12:53,660 --> 00:12:54,120
當然 是啊
Of course. Of course.

157
00:12:59,240 --> 00:13:04,040
有時候 她會在夢里來看我
She, uh, she visits me sometimes.In dreams.

158
00:13:04,040 --> 00:13:12,540
她讓我放心 她和上帝在一起 我們也曾有過快樂的日子
And she tells me it's okay. And she's with God. And we have good days,

159
00:13:15,000 --> 00:13:19,880
如果你想想以前有過那么多歡樂的日子 就會感到好過一些
then you think that if you have enough good days it might actually get better.

160
00:13:20,380 --> 00:13:22,460
確實感覺好了一些
You know, it does get better and then...

161
00:13:23,170 --> 00:13:27,180
-但是 上星期是她的周年忌日 -到上星期二滿一周年
- It was her anniversary last week and... - A year last Tuesday.

162
00:13:30,050 --> 00:13:33,370
結果一切又從頭開始了
And it just starts all over again.

163
00:13:33,370 --> 00:13:36,590
我們只能相互安慰
We just have to remind each other

164
00:13:38,990 --> 00:13:43,540
這都是上帝的安排
that it was just part of God's plan. And

165
00:13:43,550 --> 00:13:49,500
原因我們無從知曉 只有上帝才知道
we can't know why. Only God can know why.

166
00:13:51,520 --> 00:13:56,050
上帝要帶走她 他那里缺一個天使
God had to take her. He needed another angel.

167
00:13:56,920 --> 00:13:58,210
他需要加一個天使
He needed another angel.

168
00:13:58,220 --> 00:13:59,840
為什么他不造一個
Why didn't he just make one?

169
00:14:00,750 --> 00:14:03,120
再多造一個天使 我的意思是
Another angel. I mean, he's God after all.

170
00:14:03,130 --> 00:14:08,120
他可是上帝啊 為什么他不再造一個天使呢
Why didn't he just make another angel?

171
00:14:16,100 --> 00:14:16,820
像這樣
Just...

172
00:14:20,600 --> 00:14:22,560
立馬就可以變出一個
Just putting it out there...

173
00:14:27,230 --> 00:14:28,420
我想走了
I'll like to go.

174
00:14:30,980 --> 00:14:32,630
我覺得我們該走了
I think we're gonna go.

175
00:14:33,870 --> 00:14:34,540
可以嗎
Is that alright?

176
00:14:42,080 --> 00:14:43,220
失陪了
Excuse us.

177
00:14:45,400 --> 00:14:49,610
他們在屬于他們的時間里發言 你得尊重人家
They're talking, it's their time, and you have to respect that.

178
00:14:49,610 --> 00:14:49,850
好了
Come on.

179
00:14:50,270 --> 00:14:52,360
你坐在那幾個星期不說一句話
I mean, you sit there for weeks and you don't say a word.

180
00:14:52,370 --> 00:14:55,560
抱歉 我受不了那些神神鬼鬼的 你知道的
I'm sorry. I can't stand the God-freaks. You know that.

181
00:14:55,840 --> 00:14:57,740
但不是所有人都這樣 凱文和嘉比就沒有
But they're not all like that. Kevin and Gabby aren't.

182
00:14:57,950 --> 00:15:00,050
不 凱文和嘉比已經是訴苦專業戶了
No. Kevin and Gabby are professional wallowers.

183
00:15:00,060 --> 00:15:02,800
拜托 八年了 豪威 八年啊
I mean come on? Eight years, Howie.

184
00:15:03,260 --> 00:15:06,500
如果你想最后變成那個樣子...
Eight. If that's what you want to become, then...

185
00:15:06,510 --> 00:15:08,110
如果你想先暫停一下 不是暫停 我再也不去了
Look, if you wanna take a break-

186
00:15:08,390 --> 00:15:09,060
不 我以后不會再去了
No, not a break, I'm done.

187
00:15:10,080 --> 00:15:11,660
我知道伊姿的事讓你心煩意亂
I know the Izzy stuff got under your skin.

188
00:15:11,670 --> 00:15:13,790
別這樣 求你了
Please don't do that. One semester of psychology

189
00:15:13,800 --> 00:15:18,900
十五年前學了一學期的心理學 你就能給人做心理分析了
fifteen years ago and suddenly you can analyze.

190
00:15:18,900 --> 00:15:19,770
什么啊 貝卡
Well jesus, Becca.

191
00:15:19,770 --> 00:15:21,750
我不喜歡傾訴小組
I just don't like the group. I gave

192
00:15:21,760 --> 00:15:23,460
我試過了 不適合我
it a try, and it's not for me.

193
00:15:23,460 --> 00:15:26,520
行 不適合你
Okay. It's not for you.

194
00:15:27,880 --> 00:15:29,040
多謝
Thank you.

195
00:15:32,060 --> 00:15:34,980
不在這吃的話你不介意吧
Do you mind if we not eat here?

196
00:15:34,980 --> 00:15:37,640
這里沒什么我很想吃的菜
Nothing's really jumping out at me.

197
00:17:03,180 --> 00:17:09,210
太子 別叫 過來吃東西 快來 好好待著
Taz! Stop! Come here and eat! Come on!

198
00:17:09,830 --> 00:17:11,620
不好意思 它其實不咬人
Sorry. He's not really dangerous.

199
00:17:11,690 --> 00:17:12,490
快吃
Hey, eat.

200
00:17:12,490 --> 00:17:13,400
只是有點呆
Just kinda dumb.

201
00:17:13,680 --> 00:17:15,560
我知道 它是我的狗
No, I know. He's my dog.

202
00:17:16,050 --> 00:17:19,480
哦 你是貝卡吧
Oh, you're Becca! Of course! I

203
00:17:19,970 --> 00:17:22,510
我該想到是你的 我是奧吉
should have recognized you, of course. I'm Auggie.

204
00:17:23,400 --> 00:17:26,510
-你好 奧吉 -你好
- Oh. Hi, Auggie. - Hi.

205
00:17:26,510 --> 00:17:29,340
天啊 為什么不告訴我你要過來
Oh my God, why didn't you tell me you were

206
00:17:29,340 --> 00:17:32,300
不然我就收拾收拾屋子了
coming over? I would've picked up the house.

207
00:17:32,690 --> 00:17:34,440
那是奧吉
That's Auggie.

208
00:17:34,600 --> 00:17:36,490
是的 我們見過面了 伊姿在嗎
Yeah, we met. Is Izzy here?

209
00:17:36,490 --> 00:17:37,880
在 她在這兒呢
Oh yeah, she's here.

210
00:17:37,880 --> 00:17:38,950
她被餐廳炒魷魚了
She got fired from the Applebee's.

211
00:17:41,160 --> 00:17:44,480
我本打算把這些都捐給愛心機構的
I was planning to bring it all down to

212
00:17:44,480 --> 00:17:47,110
但還好沒有
goodwill, but now I'm glad I didn't.

213
00:17:47,110 --> 00:17:50,600
看看這些小襯衫 小毛衣
Look at all these shirts, and the sweaters.

214
00:17:50,600 --> 00:17:52,940
貝卡 寶寶是不是得先穿很久的嬰兒裝
I don't know, bec. They're in babyclothes for so long

215
00:17:52,940 --> 00:17:55,430
之后才穿得了這些吧
Before he could even fit into that stuff.

216
00:17:55,430 --> 00:17:57,220
孩子長得飛快 你會知道的
It comes up very quickly. You'll see.

217
00:17:57,220 --> 00:17:58,920
到時你會很高興我留著這些
You're gonna be happy I saved them.

218
00:18:00,220 --> 00:18:01,140
他也住在這里嗎
Is he living here?

219
00:18:01,150 --> 00:18:03,820
他走投無路 被女朋友踢出來了
He has to. His girlfriend kicked him out.

220
00:18:03,820 --> 00:18:05,100
是前女友
Ex-girlfriend.

221
00:18:05,100 --> 00:18:06,370
她明白我的意思
She knew what I meant.

222
00:18:06,370 --> 00:18:07,250
看這件
Did you see this one?

223
00:18:08,060 --> 00:18:11,890
真可愛 可萬一是女孩怎么辦
Cute. Look at thay but what if it's a girl?

224
00:18:12,600 --> 00:18:14,590
不知道 那就給別人吧
I don't know, then I'll give them to

225
00:18:14,600 --> 00:18:16,600
你會感謝我的
someone else. You're gonna thank me.

226
00:18:16,600 --> 00:18:18,590
這些衣服可夠穿好幾年的
A couple years worth of clothes here.

227
00:18:18,600 --> 00:18:20,270
想想可以省多少錢
Think of the money you'll save.

228
00:18:20,270 --> 00:18:21,570
這不是錢的問題
It's not about the money.

229
00:18:21,570 --> 00:18:25,760
這就是錢的問題 你該朝這方面想了
Well it should be. You need to start thinking about that.

230
00:18:25,760 --> 00:18:28,650
尤其如果孩子的爸爸是個音樂家的話
Especially if the Dad's a musician.

231
00:18:28,650 --> 00:18:31,290
告訴你 養孩子花費很大的
It costs a lot to raise a child.

232
00:18:31,300 --> 00:18:34,510
那會很奇怪 貝卡
It'd be weird, Becca. If it's a boy. To see

233
00:18:34,520 --> 00:18:37,360
如果是個男孩 看他穿丹尼的衣服跑來跑去
him running around in Danny's clothes.

234
00:18:38,400 --> 00:18:39,850
我會覺得很怪
I would feel weird about it.

235
00:18:45,910 --> 00:18:52,370
是的 抱歉 那確實會挺怪
Yeah, I'm sorry. Of course it'd be weird.

236
00:18:52,370 --> 00:18:53,910
謝謝你的好意
It was a nice offer.

237
00:18:53,970 --> 00:18:56,850
他圣誕啊生日什么的會收到很多衣服
You're gonna get a lot of clothes anyway christmas,

238
00:18:56,850 --> 00:18:59,450
你也用不著為這個擔心
birthdays. You won't have to worry about that.

239
00:18:59,450 --> 00:19:00,310
可能是個女孩
It's probably a girl anyway. I'm a

240
00:19:00,320 --> 00:19:02,310
我預測這些很準的
little psychic about these things.

241
00:19:02,320 --> 00:19:06,750
記得我說過希拉會生個女兒嗎 還有凱倫
Remember I said Sheila was having a girl? And Karen?

242
00:19:07,800 --> 00:19:09,340
我覺得她肚子里會是個女兒
I think there's a girl in there.

243
00:19:09,340 --> 00:19:12,260
我希望是 我想要個女兒
I hope there is. I mean I want a girl

244
00:19:12,260 --> 00:19:15,540
只要孩子生下來健康就好 可我還是希望要個女兒
I want as it's healthy obviously, but I hope it's a girl.

245
00:19:15,920 --> 00:19:16,780
我也是
Me too.

246
00:19:18,450 --> 00:19:20,980
你想吃點咖啡蛋糕嗎寶貝 我準備了咖啡蛋糕
You want some coffee cake, honey? I got some coffee cake in here.

247
00:19:20,980 --> 00:19:22,020
我要走了
I'm gonna take off. I promised Howie

248
00:19:22,030 --> 00:19:24,920
我答應豪威會準備晚飯的
that I'd pick up some dinner.

249
00:19:25,720 --> 00:19:26,920
看不去挺不錯
Mmm looks good though.

250
00:19:32,390 --> 00:19:34,430
來 吃點蛋糕
Here. Eat some cake.

251
00:19:52,640 --> 00:19:57,250
愛心捐助

252
00:21:05,050 --> 00:21:07,210
校車

253
00:21:41,640 --> 00:21:43,270
瑞克打壁球什么時候贏過我
When did Rick ever beat me in squash?

254
00:21:43,930 --> 00:21:45,870
他有說起過黛比嗎
Did he mention Debbie at all?

255
00:21:47,660 --> 00:21:50,470
你可以直接打電話給她 就不用我們傳話了
You can call her, you know. Get the reports directly.

256
00:21:50,480 --> 00:21:52,670
我不想打給她 她應該打給我
I don't wanna call her. She should call me.

257
00:21:55,960 --> 00:21:56,620
如果羅比或艾米麗發生什么事
I would have been there for her if God forbid

258
00:21:56,630 --> 00:21:59,220
我一定會去陪她
anything had ever happened to Robby or Em.

259
00:22:04,010 --> 00:22:05,560
我不會像她一樣消失
I wouldn't have vanished the way she did.

260
00:22:09,920 --> 00:22:10,450
我不會
I wouldn't.

261
00:22:12,560 --> 00:22:13,050
豪威
Howie?

262
00:22:15,970 --> 00:22:16,780
你懂我意思嗎
You know what I mean?

263
00:22:28,040 --> 00:22:28,460
嗯
Yeah.

264
00:22:49,950 --> 00:22:50,440
豪威
Howie.

265
00:22:56,200 --> 00:23:03,670
轉過去 來吧 親愛的 你需要放松
Turn around. Come on, you need to relax.

266
00:23:17,910 --> 00:23:19,700
你肩膀很僵硬
You're shoulders are all knotted up.

267
00:23:20,330 --> 00:23:22,970
是的
Yeah, well...

268
00:23:24,900 --> 00:23:30,100
忘了黛比 忘了那些煩心事
Forget about Debbie, and whatever else is bothering you.

269
00:23:34,000 --> 00:23:37,660
我知道你在干嘛 調暗燈光
Ohhh, I see what this is. Dimmingthe lights

270
00:23:38,580 --> 00:23:44,260
你想勾引我 想把我灌醉
You're trying to seduce me. Plyingme with liquor

271
00:23:44,270 --> 00:23:46,940
這招在大學時挺管用
It worked in college. That's enough.

272
00:23:53,560 --> 00:23:56,120
行了
That's enough.

273
00:23:58,710 --> 00:23:59,520
你去哪
Where are you going?

274
00:23:59,870 --> 00:24:04,220
我今天有點煩躁 對不起 今天一天感覺都很怪
I'm feeling kinda antsy tonight. I'm sorry. It was a weird day...

275
00:24:06,550 --> 00:24:07,560
對
Right.

276
00:24:08,170 --> 00:24:09,150
怎么 又想發牢騷嗎
What, now you're gonna pout?

277
00:24:10,260 --> 00:24:11,520
都八個月了
Well it's been eight months.

278
00:24:11,530 --> 00:24:12,940
是誰一直念念不忘的
But who's keeping track?

279
00:24:12,950 --> 00:24:14,780
是我 是我念念不忘
I am. I'm keeping track.

280
00:24:15,840 --> 00:24:19,500
我還沒準備好 豪威 我只是...
I'm just not ready yet, Howie.

281
00:24:19,500 --> 00:24:24,140
讓你覺得不正常我很抱歉
I'm sorry if you think that's abnormal

282
00:24:24,140 --> 00:24:25,960
我沒有 我一點沒覺得不正常
I don't. I don't think that's normal at all but...

283
00:24:25,960 --> 00:24:27,070
那還有什么問題
Then what's the problem?

284
00:24:27,080 --> 00:24:28,790
我們起碼得朝那個方向前進
We need to at least head in that direction,

285
00:24:28,800 --> 00:24:30,500
開始可能會有些怪 但...
which might feel strange at first, but...

286
00:24:30,510 --> 00:24:32,010
但你想做愛
But you wanna have sex

287
00:24:32,290 --> 00:24:32,920
別這樣說
Well don't say it like that.

288
00:24:32,930 --> 00:24:35,050
你剛才就是想引誘我上床
You're trying to rope me into having sex!

289
00:24:35,280 --> 00:24:37,180
我沒有 我沒想引誘你上床
I am not. I wasn't roping you into sex-

290
00:24:37,390 --> 00:24:38,370
放艾爾·格林的歌還不是引誘嗎
Al Green isn't roping?

291
00:24:38,370 --> 00:24:38,950
不是
No.

292
00:24:38,950 --> 00:24:39,800
那是什么
Al Green?

293
00:24:39,800 --> 00:24:41,740
我只是覺得好聽 僅此而已
I thought it was nice. That's all.

294
00:24:41,740 --> 00:24:43,790
我只是想讓氣氛好些
I was trying to make things nice.

295
00:24:43,900 --> 00:24:47,640
不行的 你無能為力 抱歉
Well you can't.You just can't, I'm sorry.

296
00:24:47,640 --> 00:24:51,510
氣氛不會好了
Things aren't "nice" anymore.

297
00:24:58,340 --> 00:25:00,050
你扶他一會兒
And, will you hold him for a second?

298
00:25:00,050 --> 00:25:01,040
扶住了 就那樣
Just hold him, just hold him like that.

299
00:25:01,040 --> 00:25:01,710
爸爸 停下
Dad, quit it!

300
00:25:01,710 --> 00:25:02,410
停下來
Quit it.

301
00:25:02,410 --> 00:25:04,330
把他拉起來 好了
Yeah, pull him past you. All right, now.

302
00:25:04,330 --> 00:25:06,480
太子想站到輪胎上
Cause Taz wants to go on the tire

303
00:25:08,090 --> 00:25:11,370
準備好了嗎 我要放手了 準備好了嗎
Okay, you ready? I'm gonna let you go. Ready?

304
00:25:11,380 --> 00:25:12,200
好了
Yes.

305
00:25:12,200 --> 00:25:17,140
走咯 抬起腳
Here goes. There! Whoa! Keep your feet up.

306
00:25:17,140 --> 00:25:19,170
丹尼 回頭看看我
Danny, look at me on the way back.

307
00:25:19,170 --> 00:25:20,640
腳抬起來 丹尼
Keep your feet up, Danny.

308
00:25:43,420 --> 00:25:45,510
嗨
Hey.

309
00:25:48,450 --> 00:25:52,300
如果你不去傾訴小組 就去見見別人吧
If you're not gonna go to group, I think you should see someone.

310
00:25:55,370 --> 00:25:56,560
好
Aha!

311
00:26:03,930 --> 00:26:05,270
今天有什么安排嗎
Any plans for the day?

312
00:26:06,260 --> 00:26:07,110
健身 就這點安排
You're looking at 'em.

313
00:26:10,590 --> 00:26:11,240
晚上見
Well, I'll see you tonight.

314
00:26:11,240 --> 00:26:12,310
好的
Yup.

315
00:27:03,500 --> 00:27:05,200
蘇富比拍賣行

316
00:27:21,130 --> 00:27:24,260
我想找活動部的斯科特·貝德
Hi, I'm here to see Scott Bader in the events department.

317
00:27:25,980 --> 00:27:27,880
我這里沒有貝德這個名字
I don't have a Bader listed.

318
00:27:28,790 --> 00:27:30,340
那可真是奇怪
Oh. Well that's weird.

319
00:27:33,510 --> 00:27:34,880
凱特·費恩 這個人有吧
Kate Finn. What about Kate?

320
00:27:36,220 --> 00:27:37,800
有個羅伯特·費恩 在藝術品部
I have a Robert Finn in dec. arts?

321
00:27:40,300 --> 00:27:41,940
如果您預約了 我可以打個電話
If you have an appointment, I can

322
00:27:41,940 --> 00:27:44,060
請問您的名字是
just call up there. Who are you?

323
00:27:45,680 --> 00:27:48,280
我沒有和誰預約
Um...I'm just...I didn't have an appointment actually.

324
00:27:49,440 --> 00:27:51,340
我只是個老員工 曾經在這里工作
I'm just an old friend. I used to work here.

325
00:27:51,620 --> 00:27:52,400
貝卡
Becca?

326
00:27:56,160 --> 00:27:58,100
-蓋瑞 -你怎么來了
-Gary? -Heeey. What are you doing here?

327
00:27:58,370 --> 00:28:01,180
我到市區來辦點事
Um...I had some errands in the city,

328
00:28:01,180 --> 00:28:03,600
就想順便來看看老朋友
and thought I'd pop in and say hello.

329
00:28:03,610 --> 00:28:05,480
但看起來熟人們都走了
But apparently nobody works here anymore.

330
00:28:05,490 --> 00:28:08,350
是啊 斯科特三月份跳到佳士得了
Oh yeah, Scott went over to Christie's

331
00:28:08,360 --> 00:28:10,220
那個叛徒
back in March. The traitor.

332
00:28:11,210 --> 00:28:13,170
還能見到你仍在這兒端茶送水也挺高興
Well nice to see you're still doing the coffee runs at least.

333
00:28:13,180 --> 00:28:16,660
不不 我一般不干這活了 我頂了斯科特的缺
Oh, no, I don't usually-- Um, I'm in Scott's old job.

334
00:28:20,140 --> 00:28:21,660
你家里人怎么樣
Hey, how's the family?

335
00:28:22,570 --> 00:28:26,850
蓋瑞 我知道這兒很忙
You know what, Gary? I know how busy it gets up there,

336
00:28:26,860 --> 00:28:28,880
你還是忙你的事兒去吧
So I'm gonna let you get back to it.

337
00:28:29,040 --> 00:28:30,210
是的 這一點沒變
Yeah, that hasn't changed.

338
00:28:30,680 --> 00:28:32,270
很高興見到你
It was great to see you though

339
00:28:32,270 --> 00:28:33,340
我也是
Yeah, you too.

340
00:29:24,960 --> 00:29:26,800
這可是有罰金的
Well there are fines you know.

341
00:29:27,210 --> 00:29:27,830
我知道
No, I know

342
00:29:27,840 --> 00:29:31,350
這書超了很長時間 我們發過幾次通知
The book's quite overdue. We've sent out several notices.

343
00:29:31,820 --> 00:29:32,590
所以我就來了
Yeah, that's why I'm here.

344
00:29:33,220 --> 00:29:33,860
七塊
Seven dollars.

345
00:29:38,740 --> 00:29:40,030
謝謝
Thank you.

346
00:29:47,220 --> 00:29:49,850
《平行宇宙》

347
00:29:55,060 --> 00:29:55,870
需要幫忙嗎
Can I help you?

348
00:29:57,810 --> 00:30:01,150
是的 我能借這本書嗎
Uh, yes, actually. Would it be possible for me to check this out?

349
00:30:02,570 --> 00:30:03,960
當然可以
Certainly.

350
00:30:12,080 --> 00:30:14,030
"我要變成小溪里的鱒魚
"I will become a fish in a trout stream

351
00:30:14,030 --> 00:30:16,020
并將離開你" 看他在...
and I will swim away from you? Look he's

352
00:30:16,270 --> 00:30:18,360
他在水里呢
He's in the water.

353
00:30:18,370 --> 00:30:20,450
是的
Yes, he is, "If you become a fish in

354
00:30:20,460 --> 00:30:25,050
"如果你變成小溪里的鱒魚" 他媽媽說
the trout stream, said his mother

355
00:30:25,050 --> 00:30:27,530
"我就變成漁夫 為你捕魚"
I will become a fisherman and I will fish for you."

356
00:30:27,540 --> 00:30:28,800
對不起
Oh! Sorry.

357
00:30:32,990 --> 00:30:34,990
-嗨 -嗨
-Hey. -Hey.

358
00:30:35,510 --> 00:30:39,000
我搞到了今晚揚基隊比賽的票 感興趣嗎
I just scored yankee tickets offa rowan. Tonight. You interested?

359
00:30:40,180 --> 00:30:42,280
我去不了 得去傾訴小組
I can't. I have group.

360
00:30:42,480 --> 00:30:46,060
今晚不去不行嗎 哪有棒球重要
You can't skip one night? They'rebehind home plate.

361
00:30:48,630 --> 00:30:49,160
下次吧
Another time.

362
00:30:50,600 --> 00:30:52,780
如果有下次的話
If there is one.

363
00:30:56,760 --> 00:30:57,700
今晚怎么落單了
Going stag tonight?

364
00:30:58,160 --> 00:30:59,810
是啊
Uh, yeah.

365
00:31:00,100 --> 00:31:04,880
貝卡暫時不來參加小組活動了
Becca's gonna...take a little break. from the group.

366
00:31:07,380 --> 00:31:08,190
我去拿杯咖啡
I'm gonna get a coffee.

367
00:31:13,010 --> 00:31:13,390
坐下來吧
Wanna sit?

368
00:31:14,270 --> 00:31:14,760
好的
Yeah.

369
00:31:21,760 --> 00:31:22,010
你好
Hello?

370
00:31:22,160 --> 00:31:24,120
媽媽 是我
Hey Mom, it's me.

371
00:31:24,400 --> 00:31:25,140
怎么了
What's wrong?

372
00:31:25,190 --> 00:31:27,950
沒什么 我想為伊姿做個生日蛋糕
Nothing. I was just...thinking about making

373
00:31:27,960 --> 00:31:30,410
你覺得怎么樣
Izzy's birthday cake. Would that be alright?

374
00:31:30,910 --> 00:31:32,360
親愛的 你不必做這些
Oh honey, you don't need to do all that.

375
00:31:32,370 --> 00:31:34,890
我給她買個凱菲的蛋糕就行了
I was just gonna grab her one of those

376
00:31:34,890 --> 00:31:35,960
她喜歡那味道
carvel things. She likes those.

377
00:31:35,970 --> 00:31:40,020
沒關系的 我就是想找點事情做
I don't mind. It'll give me something to do.

378
00:31:40,030 --> 00:31:42,060
那好吧
Okay then.

379
00:31:42,470 --> 00:31:44,100
今晚不去傾訴小組嗎
No group tonight?

380
00:31:45,000 --> 00:31:48,100
豪威去了 他們老是在說上帝什么的
Howie's there. It's too much God talk for me, so...

381
00:31:52,600 --> 00:31:53,020
怎么了
What.

382
00:31:53,800 --> 00:31:57,700
沒什么 一些人覺得那樣會獲得安慰
Nothing. It's just...some people find that comforting.

383
00:31:57,880 --> 00:31:59,680
是 但我聽得很煩
Yeah, well, it pisses me off.

384
00:32:00,100 --> 00:32:02,170
你知道嗎 貝卡 你哥哥死的時候
You know, Becca, when your brother died,

385
00:32:02,170 --> 00:32:03,830
我發現教堂對我很有幫助
I found the church very helpful.

386
00:32:04,070 --> 00:32:10,260
我知道 但那是你 不是我 丹尼也不是阿瑟
I know you did, but that's you, not me. And Danny isn't Arthur.

387
00:32:10,430 --> 00:32:12,260
那時我每周日都帶你去教堂
You know, I brought you to church every Sunday.

388
00:32:12,340 --> 00:32:15,010
咱們別再說這些了好嗎 媽媽
Let's not start this again, okay Mom?

389
00:32:15,550 --> 00:32:19,270
我打電話只是想說一下蛋糕的事
I'm just... I'm just calling about the cake.

390
00:32:19,880 --> 00:32:22,350
你不一定每件事都正確 如果真的有上帝呢
You're not right about everything, you know.

391
00:32:22,350 --> 00:32:23,640
如果的確有上帝呢
What if there is a God?

392
00:32:24,030 --> 00:32:26,350
那他就是個殘酷的蠢貨
Then I'll say he's a sadistic prick.

393
00:32:26,600 --> 00:32:27,830
好吧 貝卡 別說了
Alright, Becca. That's enough.

394
00:32:28,140 --> 00:32:29,800
"你信奉我 我卻視你為糞土"
"worship me and I'll treat you like shit."

395
00:32:32,390 --> 00:32:34,950
難怪你會喜歡上帝 他跟我爸一個樣
No wonder you like him, he sounds just like Dad.

396
00:32:40,530 --> 00:32:41,660
對不起
I'm sorry.

397
00:32:45,970 --> 00:32:47,340
你要做蛋糕嗎
You're gonna do the cake then?

398
00:32:48,470 --> 00:32:49,000
是的
Yeah.

399
00:32:52,000 --> 00:32:53,700
好的 那明天見
Right, I'll see you tomorrow.

400
00:32:57,790 --> 00:33:00,490
誰會在保齡球館開生日聚會呢
Who has a birthday party at a bowling alley anyway?

401
00:33:00,500 --> 00:33:02,430
伊姿覺得她還是十四歲呢
Izzy thinks she's still fourteen.

402
00:33:02,960 --> 00:33:04,860
如果你不想參加 我們可以不去
If you're not up to this we don't have to go..

403
00:33:05,800 --> 00:33:08,010
只是個聚會而已 沒事
No, it's just a party. I'll be fine.

404
00:33:13,900 --> 00:33:16,670
我希望你能把那東西拿走
I really wish you'll take that out of here, Howie.

405
00:33:18,990 --> 00:33:19,820
你很少坐這車 有什么關系嗎
You're hardly in this car, what's the difference?

406
00:33:19,830 --> 00:33:21,900
這很奇怪 感覺很怪
It feels weird.

407
00:33:26,060 --> 00:33:27,320
如果我們再要一個怎樣
What if we give it another try?

408
00:33:28,840 --> 00:33:30,230
-什么 -再要個孩子
- Another baby. - What?

409
00:33:32,020 --> 00:33:33,270
我們不是很年輕了
Well we're not getting any younger.

410
00:33:33,270 --> 00:33:34,990
那天晚上你想做愛就是這意思嗎
Is that what the sex thing was about the other night?

411
00:33:35,280 --> 00:33:36,080
不是
No-

412
00:33:36,440 --> 00:33:37,150
你想讓我懷孕對嗎
You trying to get me pregnant?

413
00:33:37,160 --> 00:33:40,600
貝卡 不 當然不是
Becca, no, of course not. I know it's scary, but maybe it might..

414
00:33:40,610 --> 00:33:45,890
我知道這有些唐突 但也許那會讓我們的生活重歸正軌
Help us get us back on track.

415
00:33:46,380 --> 00:33:46,950
重歸正軌?
On track?

416
00:33:47,550 --> 00:33:48,500
怎么 不能說說這個嗎
What, we can't talk about it?

417
00:33:51,690 --> 00:33:52,710
我覺得我們應該賣掉那房子
I think we should sell the house.

418
00:33:53,310 --> 00:33:54,940
我一直在考慮這事 既然現在說到這個話題...
I've been thinking about it, and since we're on the topic...

419
00:33:55,030 --> 00:33:56,990
什么 我們什么時候說到這個話題了
What? What you mean? How are we on the topic?

420
00:33:57,070 --> 00:33:59,070
我跟一位房產經紀人談過 她說我們可以盡快讓人...
I talked to a realtor, and she thinks we can pull together...

421
00:33:59,160 --> 00:34:02,280
-跟房產經紀談過 你什么意思 -...來看房...
- What do you mean, talked to a realtor? -...an open house pretty quickly, and then...

422
00:34:02,370 --> 00:34:04,700
你去見房產經紀怎么不告訴我
Why would you talk to a realtor without telling me?

423
00:34:05,110 --> 00:34:06,260
我現在告訴你了
I'm telling you now.

424
00:34:07,460 --> 00:34:10,160
你想要重歸正軌 我覺得搬家會有幫助的
You want to get us back on track, I think it'd help if we moved.

425
00:34:10,520 --> 00:34:11,180
我們喜歡那棟房子
We love that house.

426
00:34:11,610 --> 00:34:12,620
他無處不在 豪威
He's everywhere, Howie. The puzzles,

427
00:34:12,630 --> 00:34:14,330
我能在門框上看到他的手印
the fingerprints on the door jambs.

428
00:34:14,340 --> 00:34:16,380
我喜歡看到他的手印
I like seeing his fingerprints.

429
00:34:16,390 --> 00:34:19,450
那是因為你不必整天坐在那兒盯著看
That's because you don't have to sit and stare at them all day.

430
00:34:19,660 --> 00:34:20,820
你可以去工作 你可以逃避
You get to go to work. You get to escape!

431
00:34:20,830 --> 00:34:22,080
我不想搬家
I don't want to move!

432
00:34:22,330 --> 00:34:23,170
我也不想要第二個孩子
And I don't want another baby!

433
00:34:23,450 --> 00:34:24,370
上帝
Jesus!

434
00:34:30,960 --> 00:34:31,840
干什么
What are you doing?

435
00:34:31,840 --> 00:34:35,820
你說我干什么 我看下蛋糕 還好
What do you think I'm doing? I'm checking the cake. It's fine.

436
00:34:40,570 --> 00:34:43,160
開玩笑吧 肯尼迪家族嗎
Are you kidding? The kennedys? With the

437
00:34:43,160 --> 00:34:45,420
又是暗殺 又是腦白質切除手術
assassinations...the lobotomy...?!

438
00:34:46,750 --> 00:34:51,310
但那不是什么詛咒 只是倒霉吧
Yeah, but that's not a curse though. That's just bad luck.

439
00:34:51,320 --> 00:34:52,680
那飛機墜毀呢
The plane crashes?

440
00:34:53,300 --> 00:34:56,190
太有錢了 這就是他們的詛咒
Too much money, that's their curse. If

441
00:34:56,190 --> 00:34:59,170
如果肯尼迪家族的人像正常人一樣生活
those kennedys lived like normal people

442
00:34:59,620 --> 00:35:01,030
現在大部分還會活著的
Most of them would still be alive.

443
00:35:01,120 --> 00:35:02,680
真可悲
I think it's sad.

444
00:35:03,240 --> 00:35:06,670
這些人長得那么好 就這樣香消玉殞了
All those goodlooking people falling out of the sky like that.

445
00:35:06,680 --> 00:35:08,590
真是可惜了
It's a friggin? Waste.

446
00:35:08,600 --> 00:35:09,920
我不是說別帶酒嗎
Didn't I say no wine?

447
00:35:09,930 --> 00:35:11,350
她自己帶來的
She brought it herself

448
00:35:11,840 --> 00:35:15,040
這多好啊 坐在一起談論政治
Isn't this nice? Sitting aroundtalking politics?

449
00:35:15,040 --> 00:35:17,430
我從來沒這樣過 很好的轉變
I never do this. It's a nice change.

450
00:35:18,240 --> 00:35:18,980
開始禮物環節吧
Let's do gifts.

451
00:35:19,440 --> 00:35:20,880
-好呀 -好的
Yes! Pass em!

452
00:35:21,440 --> 00:35:24,500
來了 很沉
Okay. It's heavy.

453
00:35:24,750 --> 00:35:28,520
太漂亮了 真舍不得打開
It's so pretty. I hate to rip it open.

454
00:35:32,240 --> 00:35:33,720
浴室套裝
It's a bathroom set.

455
00:35:35,440 --> 00:35:37,160
這份禮物很實用
It's more of a practical gift.

456
00:35:37,620 --> 00:35:39,040
你送這個是不是想告訴我
Is this your way of telling me you don't

457
00:35:39,050 --> 00:35:41,630
你不喜歡我的"活寶三人組"浴簾
like my three stooges shower curtain?

458
00:35:43,810 --> 00:35:44,550
我不知道該給你買什么
I didn't know what to get you.

459
00:35:44,760 --> 00:35:46,200
說真的 這真棒
Seriously, this is great.

460
00:35:46,570 --> 00:35:47,600
快說謝謝
Say thank you.

461
00:35:47,600 --> 00:35:49,810
謝謝你 貝卡 謝謝你 豪威
Thank you, Becca. Thank you, Howie.

462
00:35:49,810 --> 00:35:51,990
別謝我 貝卡選的
Don't thank me, Becca picked it out

463
00:35:52,680 --> 00:35:53,760
該我了
Okay, now me.

464
00:35:55,000 --> 00:35:56,300
謝謝
Thank you.

465
00:35:57,180 --> 00:35:58,830
我知道這有點兒早 但是...
I know it's a little early but-

466
00:35:59,530 --> 00:36:05,790
上帝啊 真可愛 想的真周到 謝謝你 媽媽
Oh, my God! So sweet. Thank you, Mommy.

467
00:36:08,590 --> 00:36:11,450
我原以為生日禮物不要送嬰兒用品呢
I thought we weren't doing baby stuff. For the birthday.

468
00:36:11,460 --> 00:36:14,790
我以為那些是寶寶出生前的派對上才送的
I thought we'd wait for the shower.

469
00:36:15,180 --> 00:36:18,240
不 親愛的 這不是嬰兒用品 這是孕婦用品
No honey, it's not baby stuff, it's Mommy stuff.

470
00:36:18,520 --> 00:36:20,310
這很棒 貝卡 我需要浴室用品
This is perfect, bec. I needed a bathroom set.

471
00:36:20,640 --> 00:36:22,190
可你更需要嬰兒用品
Yeah, but you need baby stuff more.

472
00:36:22,940 --> 00:36:24,380
我們可以收回
We can take it back.

473
00:36:24,390 --> 00:36:25,700
沒錯 應該這樣
That's right, we should. I'll get you a basket of

474
00:36:25,710 --> 00:36:29,270
我要送你一籃妙思樂的乳液 能防止妊娠紋
mustela lotions. They prevent stretch marks...

475
00:36:29,270 --> 00:36:31,430
貝卡 松手 你可以下次送我乳液
Becca, let go. You can get me the lotions another time.

476
00:36:31,440 --> 00:36:34,680
你可以下次送我乳液
You can get me the lotions another time.

477
00:36:38,520 --> 00:36:39,440
我不是要...
I didn't...

478
00:36:40,180 --> 00:36:40,560
謝謝 謝謝你 貝卡
Thank you.

479
00:36:43,580 --> 00:36:44,670
謝謝
Thank you.

480
00:36:46,790 --> 00:36:47,840
還有這個
Here.

481
00:36:55,730 --> 00:36:59,420
我想起來要說亞里士多德·奧納西斯什么事了
Oh, I just remembered what I was gonna say about Aristotle Onassis!

482
00:36:59,790 --> 00:37:03,590
是關于他在飛機失事中死去的兒子
It was about the son who died in the plane crash!

483
00:37:04,090 --> 00:37:04,860
-可以走了嗎 -可以
- You ready to go. - Yeah.

484
00:37:04,930 --> 00:37:06,550
我跑題去扯肯尼迪了
You should have stopped him from going off

485
00:37:06,640 --> 00:37:10,680
你們應該阻止我
on all that Kennedy stuff,

486
00:37:08,470 --> 00:37:10,830
因為我要說的是奧納西斯
because my point was about onassis and how he put up a reward

487
00:37:10,840 --> 00:37:15,720
他許下重賞 賞給能證明
to anyone who could prove that someone

488
00:37:15,720 --> 00:37:17,580
他兒子的飛機遭人破壞的人
had sabotaged his son's plane.

489
00:37:18,110 --> 00:37:20,250
他非要把這事歸咎給誰
He was so desperate to blame somebody.

490
00:37:20,810 --> 00:37:21,830
你看過這個嗎
Did you read this?

491
00:37:24,680 --> 00:37:27,360
他不甘心無緣無故就失去兒子
He needed a reason for losing his son.

492
00:37:27,670 --> 00:37:29,010
媽 你為什么要講這個故事
Mom, why are you telling this story?

493
00:37:30,140 --> 00:37:31,070
隨便說說而已 我不能說話嗎
I'm just talking. I can't talk?

494
00:37:31,530 --> 00:37:32,920
你從來不是隨便說說
You never just talk.

495
00:37:32,930 --> 00:37:34,470
謝謝你們參加我的生日聚會
Thank you guys for coming to my party.

496
00:37:34,480 --> 00:37:35,880
貝卡 你做的蛋糕真好吃
Becca the cake was so good.

497
00:37:35,890 --> 00:37:38,730
你忘了你哥死后我是怎么熬過來的嗎
You forget what I went through when your brother died.

498
00:37:38,910 --> 00:37:41,270
你覺得我什么都不知道 其實不是 貝卡
You think I don't know anything, but I do Becca!

499
00:37:41,580 --> 00:37:42,460
比如指責嗎
Like who to blame?

500
00:37:42,630 --> 00:37:44,660
拜托 這是我的生日聚會
You guys, this is my birthday party.

501
00:37:44,670 --> 00:37:46,290
我們走吧 這不是針對你
Let it go. That's not on you.

502
00:37:46,720 --> 00:37:49,740
我不是在說指責 我是在說安慰
I'm not talking about blame, I'm talking about comfort.

503
00:37:49,750 --> 00:37:51,250
安慰 很好
Ohhh, comfort. Well then.

504
00:37:51,250 --> 00:37:52,450
你從哪里獲得安慰
Where are you getting it?

505
00:37:52,450 --> 00:37:53,520
安慰嗎 我不需要
Comfort? I'm not.

506
00:37:53,520 --> 00:37:54,160
我覺得你需要
Well I think you should.

507
00:37:54,170 --> 00:37:57,130
好吧 我這就去買 看能不能在易趣網上淘到
Okay. I'll get right on that then. See what I can dig up on ebay.

508
00:37:57,140 --> 00:37:59,920
我只是想幫你 貝卡
I'm just trying to help you, Becca. I wish someone

509
00:37:59,930 --> 00:38:03,020
阿瑟死的時候我真希望能有人安慰我一下
had given me a little advice when Arthur died.

510
00:38:03,030 --> 00:38:04,060
知道我怎么想的嗎
You know what I wish? I wish you would stop comparing

511
00:38:04,070 --> 00:38:08,890
我希望你別老拿丹尼和阿瑟比較 丹尼是個四歲的孩子 追狗跑到了馬路上
Danny to Arthur! Danny was a four-year-old

512
00:38:08,890 --> 00:38:13,880
阿瑟是個三十歲的癮君子 吸毒過量而死
Boy who chased his dog into the street! Arthur was a thirty-year-old heroin addict who OD'd!

513
00:38:14,470 --> 00:38:17,480
說實話 我很不愿意你將他們混為一談
frankly I resent how you keep lumping them together!

514
00:38:17,900 --> 00:38:19,420
可他仍是我的兒子
He was still my son.

515
00:38:30,900 --> 00:38:34,040
我們要走了 伊姿 希望你喜歡那套浴室用品
We're gonna go. Izzy, I hope you enjoy the bathroom set.

516
00:38:34,050 --> 00:38:35,560
會的
I'm gonna.

517
00:38:46,920 --> 00:38:49,430
阿瑟死的時候 我也跟她一樣沮喪
When Arthur died, I was just as upset as she was,

518
00:38:49,440 --> 00:38:51,490
但從未遷怒于其他人
but I never took it out on other people.

519
00:38:53,880 --> 00:38:54,870
那貝雷女士呢
What about Mrs. Bailey?

520
00:38:56,930 --> 00:38:59,560
提她干什么
Nobody's talking about Mrs. Bailey!

521
00:39:28,880 --> 00:39:30,390
你給那個修房頂的家伙打電話了嗎
Hey, did you call that guy about the roof?

522
00:39:30,850 --> 00:39:32,180
我找不到他的號碼
I couldn't find the number.

523
00:39:34,120 --> 00:39:37,350
我手機里有 在壁爐架上
It's in my phone. It's on the mantle.

524
00:39:40,730 --> 00:39:41,570
他叫什么名字
What's his name?

525
00:39:44,270 --> 00:39:45,810
不是用他名字存的
It's not under his name.

526
00:39:47,690 --> 00:39:49,380
那我怎么給他打電話呢
Then how am I supposed to call him if I--?

527
00:39:49,970 --> 00:39:51,400
查找一下"屋頂男"
It's under roof guy.

528
00:39:51,410 --> 00:39:53,310
屋頂男
Roof guy.

529
00:39:54,460 --> 00:39:56,510
我應該是用這名字存的
Well what was I supposed to put itunder.

530
00:39:58,450 --> 00:40:00,250
這電話我不會用
I don't know how to use this thing.

531
00:40:03,190 --> 00:40:04,190
沒反應
It doesn't--

532
00:40:05,620 --> 00:40:07,410
向下翻
Okay, now scroll down.

533
00:40:07,780 --> 00:40:08,580
還是不行
Now what?

534
00:40:08,580 --> 00:40:09,170
用手指向下滑
Scroll down with your finger.

535
00:40:09,170 --> 00:40:10,190
你來吧
You do it.

536
00:40:15,180 --> 00:40:16,110
屋頂男
Roof guy.

537
00:40:16,660 --> 00:40:17,640
謝謝
Thank you.

538
00:40:36,030 --> 00:40:37,410
你在等我嗎
Are you waiting for me?

539
00:40:38,380 --> 00:40:45,090
是的 對不起 我以為你會坐校車
Oh. Um, hi. Yeah, I...I'm sorry, I thought you took the bus.

540
00:40:46,650 --> 00:40:47,170
沒錯
I do.

541
00:40:47,810 --> 00:40:48,510
今天不坐嗎
Right. But not today?

542
00:40:49,880 --> 00:40:51,390
沒坐 我今天翹課了
Not today, no. Today I skipped school.

543
00:40:52,440 --> 00:40:55,180
你不應該逃課啊 年輕人
...you shouldn't be playing hooky, young man.

544
00:41:00,060 --> 00:41:01,460
你為什么等我
Why are you waiting for me?

545
00:41:05,330 --> 00:41:06,280
我想和你談談
I thought we could talk.

546
00:41:08,570 --> 00:41:09,200
談什么
About what?

547
00:41:14,690 --> 00:41:15,640
這樣可以嗎
Is this okay?

548
00:41:17,250 --> 00:41:18,200
挺好
Yeah. It's fine.

549
00:41:20,140 --> 00:41:21,020
不會很奇怪嗎
It's not too weird?

550
00:41:21,720 --> 00:41:25,100
不會 我是說
Um, no. I mean...

551
00:41:27,560 --> 00:41:32,130
我明白 對我來說也很奇怪
No, I know. It's weird for me too.

552
00:41:35,500 --> 00:41:37,230
你不喜歡學校嗎
Don't you like school?

553
00:41:38,110 --> 00:41:39,030
很喜歡
I like it alright.

554
00:41:39,980 --> 00:41:43,000
我只是以為你不想去上學 所以...
Okay. I just thought, you seem to not be going so

555
00:41:43,230 --> 00:41:49,080
-我已經被大學錄取了 -所以... 所以就無所謂了
- I've been accepted to college already, so... - Oh. So it's not a big deal then.

556
00:41:49,080 --> 00:41:52,880
不 如果被我媽發現 就有所謂了
No, it is a big deal, but...only if my mother finds out.

557
00:41:54,660 --> 00:41:56,660
她說如果我再逃課 就會沒收我的手機
She said she'll confiscate my phone if I did it again.

558
00:41:58,080 --> 00:42:00,360
不過我也不怎么用手機
Not that I use the phone anyway.

559
00:42:00,960 --> 00:42:01,940
你被哪所學校錄取了
Where are you headed?

560
00:42:02,220 --> 00:42:03,000
康涅狄格學院
Connecticut College.

561
00:42:03,240 --> 00:42:06,770
那是所好學校 而且離這不遠
That's a good school. And not too far.

562
00:42:06,770 --> 00:42:11,480
上大學的地方離家不遠 你父母一定很高興
I bet you parent pleased to you that you're gonna be close by.

563
00:42:11,800 --> 00:42:14,470
我家里就我媽 是的 她為此很高興
It's just my Mom, but yeah, she's pretty happy about it.

564
00:42:15,160 --> 00:42:17,200
她總說要去上那里的研究生
She keeps saying she's gonna apply to the grad program

565
00:42:17,210 --> 00:42:19,570
這樣就能看住我了
So she can keep an eye on me while I'm up there.

566
00:42:19,870 --> 00:42:21,600
不過這只是她的玩笑話
She's just joking though.

567
00:42:23,470 --> 00:42:25,210
因為現在我是家中唯一的孩子
She's not really looking forward to it,

568
00:42:25,210 --> 00:42:26,250
她其實不太希望我走
since I'm the only one at home now,

569
00:42:26,680 --> 00:42:29,740
但我告訴她我會盡量在周末回來
But I told her I'd come back on the weekends if I could.

570
00:42:31,840 --> 00:42:33,370
那很好
That'll be nice.

571
00:42:40,840 --> 00:42:45,880
對不起
So, I'm sorry.

572
00:42:48,550 --> 00:42:52,810
我了解 你沒必要...
Oh, I know, you don't have to...

573
00:42:52,820 --> 00:42:54,190
我知道這沒用 但是...
I know that doesn't help, but...

574
00:42:54,200 --> 00:42:55,710
不 有用 真的有用
No it does. It really does.

575
00:42:55,720 --> 00:42:59,080
-我應該主動聯系你們的 -沒事
- I know I should have tried to get in touch... - No, it's fine.

576
00:43:01,230 --> 00:43:04,560
我真希望我那天開車走了別的路
I just really wish I had driven down a different block that day.

577
00:43:07,260 --> 00:43:07,960
我知道
I know.

578
00:43:15,280 --> 00:43:16,520
那個 我差不多該走了
You know what? I should maybe go.

579
00:43:18,020 --> 00:43:19,150
好的
It's alright.

580
00:43:19,160 --> 00:43:23,190
我媽等下該不知道我跑哪去了
My Mom's gonna start to wonder where I'm at.

581
00:43:23,200 --> 00:43:25,450
沒關系的 你不用這樣
That's okay. You really don't have to.

582
00:43:29,420 --> 00:43:31,170
哪天我們再聊聊好嗎
Could we do this again sometime?

583
00:43:35,120 --> 00:43:36,230
好啊
Sure.

584
00:43:37,490 --> 00:43:38,670
好的
Okay.

585
00:44:17,590 --> 00:44:18,510
我的天啊
Jesus Christ!

586
00:44:19,320 --> 00:44:20,230
-嘿 嘉比 -我知道
- Hey, Gabby！- I can't... I know. God,

587
00:44:20,620 --> 00:44:22,660
居然被你看到我抽大麻了
I can't believe you just saw me do that.

588
00:44:23,290 --> 00:44:26,760
上帝 我不是想偷看你 我以為出什么事了
I didn't mean to sneak up on you. I thought something was wrong.

589
00:44:26,770 --> 00:44:30,500
但是聞起來 顯然一切都好
But obviously everything...smells fine.

590
00:44:30,810 --> 00:44:32,080
你還能聞出來
You can smell it huh?

591
00:44:32,730 --> 00:44:33,930
天啊
God.

592
00:44:36,450 --> 00:44:40,840
-這下大家都會知道了 -不會 -我發誓我平時從不沾這個
God, everyone in there is gonna know. I swear I never do this.

593
00:44:41,620 --> 00:44:42,430
凱文呢
Where's Kevin?

594
00:44:43,270 --> 00:44:45,710
他今晚不來了
He's not coming to group. And I blame your wife by the way.

595
00:44:45,720 --> 00:44:50,280
順便 我得埋怨一下你太太 我認為她的想法在凱文腦子里扎了根
I think she put the idea in his head.

596
00:44:50,590 --> 00:44:53,120
他好像本來就沒多喜歡這個傾訴小組
Well, he didn't seem to really like group all that much.

597
00:44:53,750 --> 00:44:57,840
他讓我很郁悶 看看我這樣子
He's gotten me all upset. I mean, look at me.

598
00:44:59,630 --> 00:45:03,190
在停車場里抽大麻
I am smoking pot in a parking lot.

599
00:45:03,190 --> 00:45:05,240
跟高中生差不多 太可笑了
It's like I'm in highschool. I'm ridiculous.

600
00:45:06,140 --> 00:45:07,190
那東西還有沒有
Do you have any more?

601
00:45:10,430 --> 00:45:14,740
有 進來吧 伙計
Yeah! Come on in, partner!

602
00:45:16,380 --> 00:45:19,130
今天要討論的是憤怒吧
Well if today is rage day,

603
00:45:22,180 --> 00:45:26,590
你們大多知道 關于憤怒我還是有話講的
Most of you know that I am a little more comfortable with rage.

604
00:45:26,600 --> 00:45:32,760
說到憤怒 我每天都跟它打交道
Talking about rage. I deal with rage every single day.

605
00:45:33,470 --> 00:45:38,240
每天上班我都聽那些家伙不停地說
And I listen to these guys at work, and they go on and on about

606
00:45:40,910 --> 00:45:42,630
鋪他們家車道什么的
Paving their driveways

607
00:45:43,120 --> 00:45:47,870
都是些沒用的廢話 他們根本不懂
or whatever, just the most stupid nonsense. They don't know.

608
00:45:50,120 --> 00:45:53,080
他們的生活還沒有支離破碎
They haven't had their lives ripped apart yet.

609
00:45:53,890 --> 00:45:57,870
-他們沒有親身經歷過 -一點沒錯 同時我很擔心...
- They're not in the club. - Exactly. Meanwhile, I'm like,

610
00:45:58,760 --> 00:46:03,630
喂 兩位 我女兒因為白血病夭折了
"Hey, guys, my daughter died of leukemia."

611
00:46:05,860 --> 00:46:08,630
不好意思 我去喝點水
I'm sorry, I need some water.

612
00:46:16,390 --> 00:46:20,170
我媽告訴我別跟壞孩子玩 你就是這種
You're one of those bad kids my mother warned me about.

613
00:46:20,690 --> 00:46:23,150
是啊 我把你帶壞了
Yes, I am corrupting you.

614
00:46:23,860 --> 00:46:25,370
別擔心 我不會告訴貝卡的
Don't worry, I won't tell Becca.

615
00:46:25,830 --> 00:46:27,920
感激不盡
I'll appreciate that.

616
00:46:29,080 --> 00:46:30,870
-晚安 -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.

617
00:46:41,520 --> 00:46:43,220
貝卡
Becca.

618
00:46:44,090 --> 00:46:44,790
貝卡
Becca.

619
00:46:45,290 --> 00:46:46,250
你干了什么
Becca What'd you do here?

620
00:46:46,250 --> 00:46:47,140
怎么了
What?

621
00:46:47,590 --> 00:46:50,300
該死 你拿我手機做什么了
Goddamn it, what did you do to my phone?

622
00:46:50,580 --> 00:46:52,970
天啊 豪威 我還以為出了什么事
Jesus, Howie. I thought something had happened.

623
00:46:52,980 --> 00:46:55,750
早上你用我手機的時候 你干什么了
This morning. When you used it. What did you do to my phone?

624
00:46:56,070 --> 00:46:59,310
-沒干什么 就是找了那個修房頂的電話 -天啊
- Nothing. I just got the number for the roof guy. - For God's sake.

625
00:46:59,590 --> 00:47:00,570
怎么了 你讓我打電話的
What, you told me to call him. You deleted Danny's video.

626
00:47:00,820 --> 00:47:03,270
你把丹尼的視頻刪了
You deleted Danny's video.

627
00:47:04,340 --> 00:47:08,580
不 我沒有 我當時...你也看見了 我就是查了個號碼
No, no I didn't. No. I just...you were right there. I just got the number.

628
00:47:08,800 --> 00:47:10,660
對 你還不停地按屏幕
Yeah, and you kept pressing the screen.

629
00:47:11,020 --> 00:47:13,480
因為我不知道你的電話怎么用
Because I couldn't figure out how to use your phone.

630
00:47:13,720 --> 00:47:16,260
我看過了 已經不見了 豪威 他的視頻我們有上百段呢
I checked already. It's gone. We have a hundred videos of him, Howie.

631
00:47:16,470 --> 00:47:17,520
不是這個問題 貝卡
That's not the point, Becca.

632
00:47:17,770 --> 00:47:19,700
那你早該把它轉到電腦上啊
Then you should've put it on your computer.

633
00:47:19,910 --> 00:47:20,900
對 是我的錯
Right, it's my fault.

634
00:47:22,020 --> 00:47:22,900
我不是這個意思
I didn't say that.

635
00:47:23,380 --> 00:47:24,700
都說了沒有了
I said it's gone!

636
00:47:24,980 --> 00:47:26,880
天啊 豪威 我又不是故意的
Jesus, Howie! I didn't do it on purpose!

637
00:47:27,120 --> 00:47:27,720
真的嗎
Are you sure?

638
00:47:28,810 --> 00:47:29,550
你這是什么意思
What does that mean?

639
00:47:29,830 --> 00:47:31,840
你覺得我故意刪了那段視頻嗎
You think I deliberately deleted his video?

640
00:47:32,080 --> 00:47:32,720
我不知道
I don't know.

641
00:47:33,980 --> 00:47:34,880
你不知道
You don't know?

642
00:47:34,890 --> 00:47:37,170
你就是在試圖擺脫他的身影
It's like you're trying to get rid of him.

643
00:47:37,170 --> 00:47:38,660
抱歉 但給我的感覺就是這樣
I'm sorry, but that's how it feels.

644
00:47:38,910 --> 00:47:40,070
每天都弄一點新變化
Every day, it's something new.

645
00:47:40,350 --> 00:47:41,090
是嗎
Really?

646
00:47:41,400 --> 00:47:42,820
對 你好像就是想去掉
Yeah. It's like you're trying to get

647
00:47:42,830 --> 00:47:44,290
所有他存在過的證據
rid of any evidence he was ever here.

648
00:47:45,800 --> 00:47:47,310
你把他的畫也從冰箱上取了下來
You took his paintings off the fridge.

649
00:47:47,590 --> 00:47:50,090
那是為了保存 都放到樓下箱子里了
Yes, to save them. They are in a box downstairs.

650
00:47:50,370 --> 00:47:51,140
好 那他的衣服呢
Okay, His clothes?

651
00:47:51,390 --> 00:47:54,680
我們又用不上那些了 你還想賣了房子
We don't need all that stuff. Your wanting to sell the house.

652
00:47:54,690 --> 00:47:56,490
還把太子送到你媽那里
Your sending Taz to your mother's.

653
00:47:56,700 --> 00:47:58,780
事情太多了 豪威 那條狗太礙事了
There was a lot going on, Howie. The dog got under foot.

654
00:47:58,990 --> 00:48:01,910
-是啊 它還能勾起你的回憶 -對 它勾起我的回憶了
- Right. And he was a reminder. - Yes, he was a reminder, and I wanted

655
00:48:01,910 --> 00:48:02,970
-我想減少一點回憶 -是你不想要那條狗
-one less reminder around here. -And since you never wanted the dog.

656
00:48:02,970 --> 00:48:05,160
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for Godssake!

657
00:48:05,160 --> 00:48:07,940
如果我沒買那條狗 丹尼應該還活著
Well if I hadn't bought the dog Danny whould still alive.

658
00:48:07,940 --> 00:48:09,860
如果我沒跑回屋里接電話
And if I hadn't run in to get the

659
00:48:09,860 --> 00:48:11,540
或者我把院門插好的話
phone or if I had latched the gate.

660
00:48:11,550 --> 00:48:13,150
是我沒插好院門
I left the gate unlatched!

661
00:48:13,360 --> 00:48:15,710
行了 我不想再這么吵了 豪威
Well I didn't check it! I'm not playing this

662
00:48:15,710 --> 00:48:18,190
這不是誰的錯 我不想再...
game again Howie. It was no one's fault.

663
00:48:18,240 --> 00:48:22,210
也不是狗的錯 狗去追松鼠 孩子去追狗
Not even the dog's. Dogs chasesquirrels, boys chase dogs.

664
00:48:22,210 --> 00:48:23,000
我知道
I know that.

665
00:48:23,000 --> 00:48:24,900
他喜歡那條狗 你卻送人了
He loved that dog! And you got rid of it!

666
00:48:24,900 --> 00:48:26,760
就像我刪掉視頻一樣是吧
Just like I got rid of the video.

667
00:48:26,760 --> 00:48:29,680
這不是視頻的事 貝卡 不是視頻的事
It's not just the video! I'm not talking about the video, Becca!

668
00:48:29,690 --> 00:48:32,160
不只是視頻 還有太子 那些畫
It's about Taz, and the paintings,

669
00:48:32,170 --> 00:48:33,570
那些衣服 所有這一切
and the clothes, and it's everything!

670
00:48:33,580 --> 00:48:39,370
家里連一張他的照片都沒掛 連門上的指紋都沒了 該死的
There's no pictures of him around! There's no fingerprints! There's nothing! God damn it!

671
00:48:39,970 --> 00:48:42,500
別再抹去他的痕跡了 你快住手吧
You have to stop erasing him! You have to stop it!

672
00:48:42,640 --> 00:48:46,820
你以為我不是每天分分秒秒都看得到他嗎
Do you really think I don't see him every second of every day?

673
00:48:49,320 --> 00:48:52,840
我不是故意刪視頻的 豪威 相信我
The video was an accident, Howie, and believe me,

674
00:48:52,930 --> 00:48:55,300
這件事我會自責一輩子的
I will beat myself up about it forever, I'm sure,

675
00:48:55,390 --> 00:48:57,050
就像所有其它我本可以避免的事一樣
just like everything else I could have prevented.

676
00:48:57,940 --> 00:48:58,920
我不是想讓你這樣 貝卡
That's not what I want, Becca.

677
00:48:59,130 --> 00:49:03,380
不是嗎 我感覺你就是想 好像你覺得我對你的愧疚還不夠
No? Because it feels like it is. It feels like maybe I don't feel badly enough for you.

678
00:49:03,390 --> 00:49:06,840
覺得我沒心沒肺 你還要我怎樣
Maybe I am not feelling enough what do you want from me?

679
00:49:11,780 --> 00:49:13,560
必須要改變一下了
I m just got to change.

680
00:49:14,470 --> 00:49:20,660
因為...我沒法再這樣下去了
Because I can't do this...like this.

681
00:49:20,660 --> 00:49:26,300
這太難了 太難了
It's too hard. It's too hard.

682
00:49:29,010 --> 00:49:33,160
我想把狗要回來 你媽把它養的太胖了
And I want that dog back. Your mother's making him fat.

683
00:49:36,140 --> 00:49:42,550
我很想那條狗 很抱歉 但是我很想它 想把它要回來
I miss the dog. I'm sorry, but I miss him. I want him back.

684
00:50:12,870 --> 00:50:14,090
你自己做的嗎
You really made these?

685
00:50:14,260 --> 00:50:15,430
對啊
I did.

686
00:50:17,120 --> 00:50:22,360
很好吃的 還是熱的
They're good. Still warm.

687
00:50:23,210 --> 00:50:24,220
很高興你喜歡吃
I'm glad you like them.

688
00:50:32,280 --> 00:50:35,340
我最近在讀那本書 那本平行宇宙的書
So I've been reading that book. The Parallel Universe book?

689
00:50:37,060 --> 00:50:39,770
是嗎 你喜歡嗎
Yeah? Did you like it?

690
00:50:40,450 --> 00:50:45,120
是啊 挺有意思的 在想要不要去買一本
Yeah, it's interesting. I don't know if I buy it.

691
00:50:45,990 --> 00:50:48,790
那些交替現實什么的
The whole alternate reality thing.

692
00:50:49,390 --> 00:50:50,290
我也不太明白
I don't know.

693
00:50:51,190 --> 00:50:52,390
但還是很有趣
But it's interesting.

694
00:50:53,990 --> 00:50:56,290
你看它是為了做學校的什么項目嗎
Did you have to do it for a school?

695
00:50:57,190 --> 00:50:58,090
不是 個人研究
No. It's research.

696
00:50:59,060 --> 00:51:02,430
個人研究
Oh. Research.

697
00:51:11,190 --> 00:51:12,190
是本漫畫
It's a comic book.

698
00:51:15,390 --> 00:51:16,390
不錯嘛
Impressive.

699
00:51:17,040 --> 00:51:19,090
-都是你自己畫的嗎 -對啊
- You did all this. - Yeah.

700
00:51:20,000 --> 00:51:21,720
真不錯
Wow. It's amazing

701
00:51:23,690 --> 00:51:24,890
講什么的
What's it about?

702
00:51:25,490 --> 00:51:27,490
講一個科學家和他兒子
A scientist, I guess. And his son.

703
00:51:29,290 --> 00:51:31,550
父親發現了一個縱橫交錯的地洞網絡
The father discovers this network of holes

704
00:51:31,550 --> 00:51:33,490
是通往其它星系和...
that leads to other galaxies and, um

705
00:51:34,590 --> 00:51:35,790
平行宇宙
Parallel Universes.

706
00:51:36,190 --> 00:51:37,590
對
Yeah.

707
00:51:38,790 --> 00:51:41,290
但是那個科學家死了 所以他兒子就得
Yeah, but the scientist dies. So the son has to go

708
00:51:42,590 --> 00:51:45,990
走進這個兔子洞去找他父親
into this rabbit hole to try and find him.

709
00:51:46,590 --> 00:51:49,090
但并非同一個人 因為他已經死了
But it's not him, because he's dead,

710
00:51:49,120 --> 00:51:51,790
所以算是他的另一個版本吧
So it's like another version of him.

711
00:51:59,990 --> 00:52:02,290
-我知道聽起來有點傻 -不傻
- I know it's kinda stupid, but... - No.

712
00:52:02,690 --> 00:52:03,490
不傻嗎 好吧
No? Okay.

713
00:52:04,990 --> 00:52:07,290
一點也不傻 我很想看看
Not at all. I would love to read it.

714
00:52:10,490 --> 00:52:11,290
可是...
Yeah it's um...

715
00:52:12,290 --> 00:52:14,190
不是那個意思 我還沒畫完
It's not done yet.

716
00:52:14,290 --> 00:52:17,890
畫完了我就給你看
But when it is done, I will let you read it.

717
00:52:18,290 --> 00:52:19,190
-好啊 -好
- Okay. - Okay.

718
00:52:26,890 --> 00:52:28,590
我不想讓你覺得不舒服
I don't want you to feel uncomfortable.

719
00:52:29,790 --> 00:52:33,860
-我... -我可能開的太快了
- I... - I might've been going too fast....

720
00:52:35,090 --> 00:52:36,090
那天
That day.

721
00:52:38,810 --> 00:52:41,790
我也不確定 但是有可能 我一直想跟你說這個
So...that's something I've been wanting to tell you.

722
00:52:45,990 --> 00:52:48,590
那里限速30英里 我可能開到了31
It's a thirty zone. And I might've been going thirty-one.

723
00:52:49,290 --> 00:52:50,290
或者32英里
Or thirty-two.

724
00:52:52,290 --> 00:52:54,580
一般我都會低頭看儀表盤
I would usually look down, to check,and if I was

725
00:52:54,580 --> 00:52:56,690
要是有點超速 我肯定會減速的
a little over, then I'd slow down obviously.

726
00:52:56,890 --> 00:52:58,490
但我沒...
But...

727
00:52:58,690 --> 00:53:00,090
走到你們那里時我可能沒看速度
I don't remember checking on your block,

728
00:53:01,490 --> 00:53:05,290
所以有可能我開的太快了
So it's possible I was going too fast.

729
00:53:06,390 --> 00:53:07,390
而且
And...

730
00:53:12,290 --> 00:53:13,990
那條狗突然竄出來
The dog ran out really fast.

731
00:53:15,290 --> 00:53:16,490
我就急打方向了
So I swerved.

732
00:53:17,790 --> 00:53:18,790
我當時不知道
I didn't know.

733
00:53:19,890 --> 00:53:20,890
我當時真不知道
I didn't know.

734
00:53:25,790 --> 00:53:26,790
我想你可能知道
I thought you should know.

735
00:53:29,190 --> 00:53:30,890
我當時可能有點超速
I might've been going a little over the limit.

736
00:53:33,790 --> 00:53:34,790
雖然我也不太確定
I can't be positive.

737
00:53:38,290 --> 00:53:41,390
-沒事的 -好吧
- It's okay. - Okay.

738
00:53:43,490 --> 00:53:44,490
好
Well.

739
00:53:45,390 --> 00:53:46,590
我知道了 沒事的
I know, okay?

740
00:53:49,390 --> 00:53:50,690
謝謝
Thank you.

741
00:54:22,590 --> 00:54:23,790
我不想進去了
I don't wanna go in there.

742
00:54:31,390 --> 00:54:32,490
漂亮 漂亮
Yes, yes!

743
00:54:41,690 --> 00:54:43,290
不好意思 我...
Sorry. I was...

744
00:54:43,690 --> 00:54:44,490
好好玩
Take care.

745
00:54:52,250 --> 00:54:54,680
拜托
Come on.

746
00:54:56,190 --> 00:54:57,690
哦 加油
Oh, come on!

747
00:54:57,790 --> 00:54:58,990
不好意思 你扔的太水了
I'm sorry, you suck...

748
00:54:59,090 --> 00:55:03,790
你的大麻弄得我有些飄 不然我能扔準點
I'll be doing better but your pot messed up my depth perception.

749
00:55:07,390 --> 00:55:08,190
-還不錯 -還行
- All right. - Yeah.

750
00:55:08,790 --> 00:55:11,490
看我也來個好的 絕不會讓你失望
I'm gonna support that one. I'm totally gonna support that one.

751
00:55:11,520 --> 00:55:12,390
多謝
Thanks.

752
00:55:14,790 --> 00:55:16,390
對了 我得跟你說句實話
Hey you know what. I have a confession to make.

753
00:55:17,190 --> 00:55:20,890
記得我說凱文離開傾訴小組了嗎
Remember when I said Kevin left group?

754
00:55:21,290 --> 00:55:22,190
記得啊
Yes.

755
00:55:23,990 --> 00:55:25,290
我其實是想說
What I meant to say..

756
00:55:27,990 --> 00:55:29,190
他離開我了
Is that he left me. He left me.

757
00:55:32,790 --> 00:55:33,690
他離開我了
He left myself.

758
00:55:38,390 --> 00:55:39,290
真的
Yeah...

759
00:55:41,990 --> 00:55:43,190
我回到家他就不見了
I came home and was gone.

760
00:55:45,490 --> 00:55:46,650
沒留個便條什么的
Wow. No note or...

761
00:55:46,690 --> 00:55:48,390
不 留了張便條
Oh there was a note.

762
00:55:48,790 --> 00:55:53,490
與其說是便條 不如說是宣言
Well, not a note so much as a manifesto.

763
00:55:55,490 --> 00:55:58,190
寫了我們相互毀滅的種種不是
On all the ways that we were destroying each other.

764
00:56:01,690 --> 00:56:02,690
天啊 不好意思
Jesus. I'm sorry.

765
00:56:03,790 --> 00:56:05,590
其實往往就這么回事 對嗎
Well...this is generally how it goes, right?

766
00:56:08,290 --> 00:56:09,590
它會改變你
It changes you.

767
00:56:11,090 --> 00:56:12,490
真的會讓一個人改變
It literally changes people.

768
00:56:14,790 --> 00:56:18,090
知道嗎 有時我覺得這是天意
You know, part of me thinks it was inevitable.

769
00:56:23,290 --> 00:56:24,490
我愛我妻子
I love my wife.

770
00:56:27,990 --> 00:56:28,990
當然了
Of course you do.

771
00:56:30,890 --> 00:56:32,190
我非常愛她
I love her very much.

772
00:56:35,390 --> 00:56:36,290
明白
Okay.

773
00:56:54,790 --> 00:56:56,990
我覺得你說得對 也許我們應該...
So I think you're right. We should maybe...

774
00:56:59,690 --> 00:57:01,790
考慮把這房子賣掉
Look into selling the house.

775
00:57:03,490 --> 00:57:04,490
也許這樣最好
It's probably for the best.

776
00:57:06,390 --> 00:57:07,590
好啊
Okay.

777
00:57:31,090 --> 00:57:32,090
別這樣
Don't do that.

778
00:57:32,290 --> 00:57:34,290
長痛不如短痛 不然永遠都邁不過去了
Quick and clean, like a band-aid. Or we'll never get through this.

779
00:57:34,390 --> 00:57:35,190
給你
Here.

780
00:57:40,390 --> 00:57:43,190
孩子 歡迎來到蘋果樂園
Hey, kid. Welcome to light up apple.

781
00:57:43,790 --> 00:57:45,090
我不知道怎么關上它
I don't know how to turn it off.

782
00:57:45,890 --> 00:57:47,890
沒孩子的人才會送這樣的禮物
Only people without children give gifts like this.

783
00:57:47,920 --> 00:57:49,790
來吧 來吧 再見了
Come on! Goodbye.

784
00:57:50,290 --> 00:57:51,150
再見了
Goodbye.

785
00:57:51,190 --> 00:57:52,690
歡迎再次光臨
I hope you'll visiting us soon.

786
00:57:56,590 --> 00:57:58,990
-黛比有聯系過你嗎 -還沒有
- Have you heard from Debbie yet. - No.

787
00:57:59,690 --> 00:58:00,990
這可不好
That's too bad.

788
00:58:01,690 --> 00:58:03,290
不過反過來情況可能會更糟
But it can be worse the other way,

789
00:58:03,790 --> 00:58:05,290
我記得阿瑟死的時候...
You know. I remember when Arthur died...

790
00:58:07,090 --> 00:58:08,120
沒關系 說吧
You can say his name.

791
00:58:08,130 --> 00:58:10,530
-沒關系嗎 -沒事
- Can I. - Yes.

792
00:58:10,790 --> 00:58:13,290
我搞不清你的規矩 我可不想再挨訓
Do not know your rules. I don't wanna get scolded again.

793
00:58:13,690 --> 00:58:16,390
你說阿瑟沒問題 別拿他們做比較就行
You can talk about Arthur. I justdon't like the comparisons.

794
00:58:20,790 --> 00:58:21,690
好的
Okay.

795
00:58:22,690 --> 00:58:23,890
更糟是什么情況呢
So how is it worse?

796
00:58:25,290 --> 00:58:28,290
-還記得莫琳·貝雷嗎 -記得啊
- You remember Maureen Bailey. - Yes.

797
00:58:29,390 --> 00:58:30,290
嗯
Well...

798
00:58:30,690 --> 00:58:33,090
你哥哥去世之后她就一直纏著我
I couldn't get rid of her after your brother passed away.

799
00:58:33,120 --> 00:58:35,390
-她老是待在咱們家里 -嗯 我有印象
- She was always at the house. - Yeah, I remember that.

800
00:58:35,790 --> 00:58:38,790
我連自己待一會的時間都沒有
Yeah well, I never had a moment to myself.

801
00:58:39,990 --> 00:58:42,390
后來有天下午喝咖啡的時候我說
So finally in the middle of coffee one afternoon, I said,

802
00:58:42,490 --> 00:58:44,790
莫琳 你怎么老是在這兒
"Maureen, why are you always here?"

803
00:58:45,090 --> 00:58:45,990
她怎么說的
What'd she say?

804
00:58:46,090 --> 00:58:49,690
她說 我想陪著你啊 娜塔 幫你分擔憂傷
She said, "i wanna be there, Nat, I wanna share in your grief."

805
00:58:50,090 --> 00:58:51,990
我就說 沒什么效果啊
And so I said "well it's not working.

806
00:58:52,690 --> 00:58:55,190
你丫每天把大屁股塞到我椅子里一坐一天
You plant your fat ass in that chair every frickin' day"

807
00:58:55,290 --> 00:58:56,890
-你不會那么說的吧 -我是那么說的
- You did not say that. - I did!.

808
00:58:56,990 --> 00:58:58,650
-媽 -我確實說了
- Mom. - I said that.

809
00:58:58,690 --> 00:59:01,390
-你說大屁股了? -我說 你天天喝我的咖啡
- You said "fat ass". - "you suck up all my coffee.

810
00:59:01,790 --> 00:59:03,530
我也沒見你離開時帶走什么憂傷
And I don't see you leaving with any of this

811
00:59:03,540 --> 00:59:05,180
你不是說和我分擔憂傷嗎
grief you're allegedly sharing with me.

812
00:59:05,190 --> 00:59:08,960
你真正從這里帶走的是我那些肉桂小面包
In fact the only thing you do take outta here are my cinnamon buns."

813
00:59:08,990 --> 00:59:10,890
當然從那以后我再也沒見過她
So I never saw her again obviously.

814
00:59:11,480 --> 00:59:14,280
天啊 簡直不敢相信
Oh my God, I can not believe it.

815
00:59:15,490 --> 00:59:16,590
我現在倒是有點內疚
I feel guilty now.

816
00:59:16,990 --> 00:59:18,790
-你才沒有呢 -有點
- You do not. - I do.

817
00:59:19,990 --> 00:59:21,090
好吧 確實沒有
You're right, I don't.

818
00:59:21,790 --> 00:59:23,090
我一點也不想她
I don't miss her at all.

819
00:59:42,090 --> 00:59:44,290
好了 搬過來了
Okay, we will be alright.

820
00:59:44,890 --> 00:59:46,190
太子安頓好了
That takes care of Taz.

821
00:59:48,790 --> 00:59:51,140
蘋果派的老把戲
Ah, the ol' apple pie trick, eh?

822
00:59:51,390 --> 00:59:52,290
什么
What?

823
00:59:52,390 --> 00:59:53,390
為來看房的人準備的吧
For the open house.

824
00:59:54,090 --> 00:59:57,290
新鮮出爐的東西讓你更有家的感覺
Warm baked goods makes it feel homier.

825
00:59:58,790 --> 01:00:00,990
只不過是做個派
No, just making a pie.

826
01:00:02,590 --> 01:00:04,090
我以為你是為看房的人準備的
I thought you were doing it for the open house.

827
01:00:05,890 --> 01:00:06,790
那么
So...

828
01:00:07,290 --> 01:00:10,390
-你不陪他們看房子是吧 -肯定不
- Now you're not gonna stay. - Oh, no. No.

829
01:00:11,390 --> 01:00:12,290
你也不該在家待著
You shouldn't either

830
01:00:14,290 --> 01:00:15,590
-真的 -沒事的
- You shouldn't. - Come on...

831
01:00:16,590 --> 01:00:17,990
我又不會礙誰的事
I'm not gonna bother anyone.

832
01:00:18,490 --> 01:00:20,690
垃圾桶在后院 歡迎看房的牌子在前面
So we have the garbage cans in the back, the sign out front.

833
01:00:20,790 --> 01:00:22,090
我還修剪了一下草坪
I mowed the lawn.

834
01:00:22,590 --> 01:00:24,190
登記表就放在這
I thought we'll set the sign-in sheet here.

835
01:00:24,790 --> 01:00:25,990
然后他們可以先到客廳看看
And they could move into the living room.

836
01:00:26,490 --> 01:00:27,490
很不錯
That's fine.

837
01:00:27,890 --> 01:00:29,890
我妻子要回避一下 我來陪他們
My wife's gonna go hide out, but I'll stick around.

838
01:00:29,920 --> 01:00:30,790
你看沒什么問題吧
If that's okay with you.

839
01:00:32,290 --> 01:00:33,890
當然 你怎么做都行
Sure. However you want to do it.

840
01:00:35,190 --> 01:00:36,490
-那太好了 -我要走了
- Okay. Perfect. - All right...

841
01:00:37,290 --> 01:00:38,890
-再見 親愛的 -再見
- Bye, baby. - Bye.

842
01:00:40,990 --> 01:00:42,090
就這些了吧
I think that's everything.

843
01:01:09,790 --> 01:01:11,490
-我知道  -窗戶朝向西南
- I know... - Southwestern exposures.

844
01:01:11,520 --> 01:01:12,590
陽光充足
Sun all day..

845
01:01:14,590 --> 01:01:15,920
去樓上看看吧
Why don't we take a look upstairs?

846
01:01:15,920 --> 01:01:17,290
好主意 我帶你們去
That's a great idea. I'll show you.

847
01:01:17,590 --> 01:01:18,490
-好的 -跟我來
- Okay. - Follow me.

848
01:01:18,520 --> 01:01:19,390
走了 寶貝
Come on, baby.

849
01:01:19,990 --> 01:01:23,480
我們的二樓在這一帶是最大的
It is the largest part in the neighborhood.

850
01:01:23,480 --> 01:01:26,300
先從主臥看起吧
We can start in the master bedroom if you want to see.

851
01:01:26,590 --> 01:01:27,590
等等 這間是什么
Wait. What's in here?

852
01:01:31,090 --> 01:01:32,190
噢
Oh.

853
01:01:32,590 --> 01:01:34,190
這是 這是...
This is... this is...

854
01:01:35,490 --> 01:01:37,290
這個房間給小家伙住一定不錯
This could be a good room for the little guy, obviously.

855
01:01:37,790 --> 01:01:39,090
怎么樣 伙計 你喜歡這個房間嗎
How about that, buddy? You like this room?

856
01:01:39,890 --> 01:01:42,790
-小心點 -那個不是你的
- Oo, careful with that. - That's not yours, honey.

857
01:01:43,290 --> 01:01:45,190
-謝謝 -你兒子多大
- Thanks. How old's your son?

858
01:01:47,790 --> 01:01:49,490
這是你兒子的房間 我猜
This is your son's room, I assume?

859
01:01:49,950 --> 01:01:52,910
嗯 曾經是
Uh, yeah. I mean...it was,

860
01:01:52,920 --> 01:01:53,890
曾經是他的房間
it was his room.

861
01:01:53,990 --> 01:01:55,240
不過他死了
But...he died.

862
01:01:55,270 --> 01:01:56,490
他死于
He died...

863
01:01:56,990 --> 01:01:58,690
是車禍 就在這房子前面
Yeah, a car. Right out front.

864
01:02:00,490 --> 01:02:01,390
天哪
Oh my god.

865
01:02:01,910 --> 01:02:05,590
天哪 -真對不起 -謝謝
- I'm so sorry.. - Thank you.

866
01:02:06,990 --> 01:02:09,590
你一定很難過吧
This must be so difficult for you.

867
01:02:10,920 --> 01:02:13,540
這很... 這很奇怪
It is... It's pretty weird.

868
01:02:15,590 --> 01:02:16,890
很奇怪 因為我仍然...
It is strange that yet...

869
01:02:17,590 --> 01:02:19,150
我有時候會忘記他已經不在了
I still forget he's not here sometimes.

870
01:02:19,190 --> 01:02:20,830
似乎他只是藏在床下
Maybe he's just hiding under the bed and he's

871
01:02:20,830 --> 01:02:22,290
隨時會蹦出來 像以前那樣
gonna pop out. That's what he used to do.

872
01:02:23,690 --> 01:02:24,690
只是...
But...

873
01:02:27,390 --> 01:02:28,390
我覺得他還在這兒
I still feel him here.

874
01:02:35,290 --> 01:02:36,790
-你們想去看看主臥嗎 -好的
- Would you like to see the master bedroom. - Yes.

875
01:02:37,090 --> 01:02:37,890
好的
Yes.

876
01:02:39,190 --> 01:02:40,190
好
Yes.

877
01:02:40,690 --> 01:02:41,690
好 我馬上來
Yeah, I'll be there.

878
01:02:43,890 --> 01:02:45,390
-誰啊 -貝卡
- Who was that. - Becca.

879
01:02:45,650 --> 01:02:47,300
她想出去逛逛
She wants to hang out.

880
01:02:50,490 --> 01:02:51,890
這主意不錯
This was a good idea.

881
01:02:52,690 --> 01:02:53,790
不錯吧
I know. I feel like a big ole balloon

882
01:02:55,090 --> 01:02:56,890
你的肚子這么早就能看出來了
You're starting to show so early.

883
01:02:56,990 --> 01:02:59,290
我知道 我覺得自己像個大氣球
Yes, I know. I feel like a balloon.

884
01:02:59,690 --> 01:03:01,990
我發誓 孩子一出生我就馬上去健身房
I swear, once this kid is born I'm going right to the gym.

885
01:03:02,690 --> 01:03:04,290
媽媽就看著孩子
While Mom watches the baby

886
01:03:05,980 --> 01:03:08,770
什么意思 媽媽就看著孩子
What does that mean, "While Mom watches the baby"?

887
01:03:09,190 --> 01:03:11,290
你在健身房的時候 媽媽可以幫你照看孩子
While you're at the gym, Mom can watch the baby.

888
01:03:11,790 --> 01:03:12,790
她喜歡看孩子
She loves that.

889
01:03:12,890 --> 01:03:16,000
不 奧吉可以看孩子 他晚上工作 白天會在家
No, Auggie can watch the baby. He works nights, so he'll be home.

890
01:03:16,190 --> 01:03:17,890
好吧 那就奧吉吧
Okay. Auggie, then.

891
01:03:17,990 --> 01:03:19,550
我討厭你給我的這種感覺
I resent the feeling I get from you

892
01:03:19,550 --> 01:03:20,890
好像我不配生孩子
that I don't deserve the baby.

893
01:03:21,790 --> 01:03:24,350
好像我不夠成熟聰明 沒法照顧好他
I'm not mature enough or smart inough to take care of him.

894
01:03:24,390 --> 01:03:27,090
如果媽媽都能做 那能有多難
I mean, my God, if Mom could do it, how hard could it be?

895
01:03:36,990 --> 01:03:38,790
-怎么樣 -挺好
- This alright. - Yeah, it's fine.

896
01:03:39,130 --> 01:03:42,610
我就買一點東西 然后咱們就吃午飯
I've just got to pick up a few things and then we can do lunch.

897
01:03:42,790 --> 01:03:44,090
好的
Okay. Well.

898
01:03:44,120 --> 01:03:45,390
我想要草莓的
I want strawberry.

899
01:03:46,190 --> 01:03:49,250
媽咪 求你了 能買點水果卷嗎
Mommy,please can I have some fruit Roll-Ups?

900
01:03:49,290 --> 01:03:52,690
-不行 薩米 你知道的 -求你了
- No, Sammy, you know the answer. - Please?

901
01:03:52,790 --> 01:03:55,690
-能買一點嗎 求你了 -薩米 不行
- Can I have some, please. - Sammy, no.

902
01:03:55,790 --> 01:03:58,990
-我想要水果卷 -不可能
- I want the fruit Roll-Ups. - Not happening.

903
01:03:59,290 --> 01:04:01,390
-求你了 我會很乖的 -別鬧了
- Please, I'll be good. - Stop it...

904
01:04:01,490 --> 01:04:02,550
-求你了 -不行
- Please. - No.

905
01:04:02,590 --> 01:04:04,040
-我保證 -不行 我不會買的
- I promise. - No. You're not gonna get them.

906
01:04:04,090 --> 01:04:05,550
知道嗎 這只要三塊錢
You know what? It's only three bucks,

907
01:04:05,550 --> 01:04:07,190
你干嘛不給他買了得了
why don't you just get him the Roll-Ups?

908
01:04:09,090 --> 01:04:10,990
這本來就沒你什么事
Not that it's any of your business,

909
01:04:11,790 --> 01:04:13,790
我們在家不允許他吃糖
but we don't allow candy in our house.

910
01:04:13,890 --> 01:04:16,190
-我兒子知道 -就是點水果
- And my son knows that. - Come on, it's just fruit.

911
01:04:16,220 --> 01:04:17,490
干嘛不哄他高興點呢
Why don't you give him a treat?

912
01:04:17,890 --> 01:04:19,390
你當媽了嗎
Are you a Mom?

913
01:04:20,490 --> 01:04:21,790
我看也不像
Yeah, I didn't think so.

914
01:04:21,820 --> 01:04:22,690
不好意思
Excuse me....

915
01:04:25,990 --> 01:04:28,790
上車去 貝卡 我說上車去
Go to the car, Becca. I said go to the car.

916
01:04:29,390 --> 01:04:30,390
別怕
It's okay.

917
01:04:31,690 --> 01:04:35,290
她八個月前剛失去了兒子 她...
She just lost her son eight months ago and she's...

918
01:04:35,320 --> 01:04:36,310
我不不管
I don't care.

919
01:04:37,690 --> 01:04:38,690
好了沒事了
Everything is okay.

920
01:04:48,390 --> 01:04:49,290
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.

921
01:04:49,990 --> 01:04:50,790
嘿
Hey.

922
01:04:51,490 --> 01:04:52,390
玩得開心嗎
Fun day out?

923
01:04:55,390 --> 01:04:56,490
這邊怎么樣
How'd it go here?

924
01:04:56,890 --> 01:04:58,490
不是很好 不是很好
Not so good.

925
01:04:59,890 --> 01:05:03,490
我們得把那個房間清理干凈
We need to clean out that room.

926
01:05:06,390 --> 01:05:07,250
好
Okay.

927
01:05:07,290 --> 01:05:08,790
把那間房改成客房之類的
Maybe make it into a guest room or something.

928
01:05:10,590 --> 01:05:11,790
還沒想好
Don't get any ideas.

929
01:05:17,290 --> 01:05:18,390
天哪
Jesus...

930
01:05:20,390 --> 01:05:21,590
你好
Hello!

931
01:05:23,590 --> 01:05:24,890
門開著 所以...
The door was wide open so...

932
01:05:27,990 --> 01:05:29,390
我敲門了 可是...
And I knocked, but...

933
01:05:29,420 --> 01:05:30,290
太子 別叫了
Taz! Shut up!

934
01:05:31,490 --> 01:05:34,350
我看見外面的歡迎看房告示了 所以我以為可以...
I saw the sign outside.. so I thought it'll be okay to-

935
01:05:34,890 --> 01:05:36,590
-你是要買房子嗎 -豪威
- You looking to buy a house. - Howie...

936
01:05:36,790 --> 01:05:37,890
不
No.

937
01:05:39,790 --> 01:05:42,750
不 我只是來給你這個的
No,I just came to give you this.

938
01:05:42,790 --> 01:05:45,090
我說等完成了就給你看的 所以...
I said I'd let you read it when it was done, so...

939
01:05:48,260 --> 01:05:51,240
這怎么回事
What...what is this?

940
01:05:52,390 --> 01:05:53,490
謝謝
Thank you.

941
01:05:55,590 --> 01:05:58,990
我們在圖書館碰見了
We...bumped into each other, in the library.

942
01:06:00,790 --> 01:06:02,890
然后...
And I... and I...

943
01:06:03,390 --> 01:06:04,790
我們決定見見面
And we decided to meet.

944
01:06:07,390 --> 01:06:08,590
你們決定見見面
You decided to meet?

945
01:06:09,590 --> 01:06:10,450
是的
Yes.

946
01:06:10,490 --> 01:06:11,690
見過幾次
A couple times.

947
01:06:12,490 --> 01:06:14,590
-是么 -對不起 我不知道
- Well... - I'm sorry. I didn't realize...

948
01:06:14,620 --> 01:06:16,190
這是...
It is...

949
01:06:16,390 --> 01:06:17,390
你們在這見面嗎
Did you meet here?

950
01:06:17,990 --> 01:06:19,490
沒有 我們在公園
No, we met in the park.

951
01:06:23,090 --> 01:06:24,090
你們在公園見面
You met in the park.

952
01:06:26,590 --> 01:06:27,490
是的
Yes.

953
01:06:28,290 --> 01:06:29,690
這么說我老婆
So my wife...

954
01:06:31,390 --> 01:06:33,790
同意在公共場所見你 而你
Agrees to meet you in a public place, and you..

955
01:06:35,890 --> 01:06:37,790
你怎么 你道歉了?
And you... apologize?

956
01:06:39,290 --> 01:06:40,590
-我想是吧 -你想是吧
- I guess. - You guess.

957
01:06:41,090 --> 01:06:41,990
好吧
Well...

958
01:06:42,990 --> 01:06:45,290
好吧 你道歉了 然后...
Okay, you apologize, and then what?

959
01:06:45,590 --> 01:06:46,740
好了 豪威 夠了
Alright, Howie, that's enough.

960
01:06:46,770 --> 01:06:47,890
-然后呢 -夠了
- And then what. - It is enough.

961
01:06:47,990 --> 01:06:50,090
-看著我 -豪威 夠了
- Look at me. - Howie, that's enough.

962
01:06:50,190 --> 01:06:52,190
-那是什么 -一本漫畫書
- What is that. - It's a comic book.

963
01:06:52,890 --> 01:06:53,890
是一本漫畫書?
It is a comic book?

964
01:06:54,590 --> 01:06:55,390
漫畫書?
A comic book?

965
01:06:55,690 --> 01:06:56,990
她讓你送到這來了嗎
Did she tell you to bring it here?

966
01:06:57,490 --> 01:06:58,990
-沒 她沒有 -她沒有
- No, she didn't. - No, she didn't.

967
01:06:59,390 --> 01:07:00,990
因為這是我們的家
Because this is our house.

968
01:07:01,590 --> 01:07:03,210
就因為門外有個告示
And just because there's a sign out

969
01:07:03,210 --> 01:07:04,790
不代表你就能闖進來
front doesn't mean you can pop in.

970
01:07:05,090 --> 01:07:06,640
豪威 好了
Howie, all right.

971
01:07:06,670 --> 01:07:08,190
-好了 -你不能就這么...不 沒好
- All right. -And you just don't... No, it's not all right!

972
01:07:08,690 --> 01:07:10,690
你不能隨便就這么走到別人家里來
You don't just walk into someone's home like that.

973
01:07:11,290 --> 01:07:13,090
你他媽至少應該給點尊重
You should show a little fucking respect.

974
01:07:14,290 --> 01:07:15,290
好了我走
All right I go.

975
01:07:17,190 --> 01:07:18,590
你是個混蛋
You're an asshole.

976
01:07:19,090 --> 01:07:19,950
等等
Wait!

977
01:07:19,990 --> 01:07:21,890
等等 杰森 等一下 對不起
Jason, wait a minute. I m sorry.

978
01:07:22,890 --> 01:07:23,790
我是個混蛋
I am an asshole!

979
01:07:37,590 --> 01:07:39,790
太子 不行
Taz, stop it.

980
01:07:51,490 --> 01:07:52,490
太子
Taz!

981
01:07:53,090 --> 01:07:54,490
太子
Taz.

982
01:07:54,990 --> 01:07:55,790
太子 不行
Taz, stop it.

983
01:07:59,840 --> 01:08:01,690
伙計
Oh, buddy..

984
01:08:36,990 --> 01:08:38,090
你怎么沒告訴過我
Why didn't you tell me?

985
01:08:41,890 --> 01:08:43,540
你回到家一身大麻味
For the same reason you don't tell

986
01:08:43,540 --> 01:08:45,290
也沒告訴我為什么
me why you come home reeking of pot.

987
01:09:26,390 --> 01:09:27,590
這事過去了嗎
Does it ever go away?

988
01:09:31,790 --> 01:09:32,790
不
No.

989
01:09:34,990 --> 01:09:36,950
我覺得沒有 對我來說從未過去
I don't think it does. Not for me it hasn't.

990
01:09:36,950 --> 01:09:38,390
已經十一年了
And that's goin'on eleven years.

991
01:09:42,590 --> 01:09:43,490
不過會有變化
It changes though.

992
01:09:46,890 --> 01:09:48,090
怎么變
How?

993
01:09:50,290 --> 01:09:51,590
我不知道
I don't know.

994
01:09:54,490 --> 01:09:55,790
或許是它的重量吧
I don't know. The weight of it, I guess.

995
01:09:57,890 --> 01:09:59,790
從某一刻起變得可以承受了
At some point it becomes bearable.

996
01:10:00,990 --> 01:10:04,090
變得讓你能從它的重壓下爬出來
It turns into something you can crawl out from under,

997
01:10:04,690 --> 01:10:06,890
能像一塊磚一樣放在口袋里帶著走
and carry around like a brick in your pocket.

998
01:10:09,090 --> 01:10:11,090
有時你甚至會暫時忘記
And you even forget it

999
01:10:11,590 --> 01:10:14,800
但總有什么事情能讓你重新想起
for while. But then you reach in for whatever reason and I...

1000
01:10:16,390 --> 01:10:20,990
就像這樣 "啊對 那件事"
"Oh right."

1001
01:10:22,990 --> 01:10:24,090
這很難受
Which can be awful.

1002
01:10:25,790 --> 01:10:26,890
但不會一直這樣
But not all the time.

1003
01:10:28,590 --> 01:10:29,890
有點像...
Sometimes it's kinda.

1004
01:10:32,290 --> 01:10:34,320
你不會喜歡它
Not that you like it exactly, but it's

1005
01:10:34,320 --> 01:10:36,090
但那就是你兒子的替代品
what you have instead of your son.

1006
01:10:37,390 --> 01:10:40,690
所以這種感覺就跟隨著你
So you carry it around.

1007
01:10:46,890 --> 01:10:50,040
揮之不去
And it doesn't go away.

1008
01:10:52,790 --> 01:10:53,690
其實...
Which is..

1009
01:10:55,990 --> 01:10:56,990
其實怎樣
Which is what?

1010
01:11:02,190 --> 01:11:05,290
其實挺好
Fine...actually.

1011
01:11:33,300 --> 01:11:36,120
兔子洞

1012
01:12:16,490 --> 01:12:18,390
-喂 -你好
- Hello. - Hi.

1013
01:12:20,190 --> 01:12:22,690
你好 我是豪威
Hey, it's Howie.

1014
01:12:25,290 --> 01:12:26,790
豪威·考伯特 傾訴小組的
Howie corbett. from group?

1015
01:12:29,790 --> 01:12:30,790
你好 豪威
Hi, Howie.

1016
01:12:38,490 --> 01:12:39,290
給 伙計
Here we go buddy

1017
01:12:42,690 --> 01:12:43,990
-嗨 -嗨
- Hey. - Hi.

1018
01:12:45,090 --> 01:12:46,460
你要去傾訴小組嗎
You're going to group.

1019
01:12:46,460 --> 01:12:47,890
-是啊 -你不想去對吧
- Yeah. -You didn't want to come, did you?

1020
01:12:48,090 --> 01:12:49,090
不想
No.

1021
01:13:42,690 --> 01:13:44,590
你好 我是杰森 有事請留言
I'm Jason. Please leave a message.

1022
01:14:20,290 --> 01:14:21,490
這里還好找吧
Did you find the house okay?

1023
01:14:26,290 --> 01:14:27,590
豪威
Howie?

1024
01:16:20,190 --> 01:16:21,390
對不起
Sorry.

1025
01:16:45,490 --> 01:16:46,590
貝卡
Becca?

1026
01:16:51,990 --> 01:16:53,190
貝卡
Becca?

1027
01:16:56,790 --> 01:16:57,690
貝卡
Becca!

1028
01:17:02,190 --> 01:17:02,990
貝卡
Becca!

1029
01:18:20,190 --> 01:18:21,190
天哪
God.

1030
01:18:23,590 --> 01:18:24,490
對不起
Sorry.

1031
01:18:26,690 --> 01:18:27,990
幾點了
What time is it?

1032
01:18:28,690 --> 01:18:29,590
差不多六點
Almost six.

1033
01:18:31,190 --> 01:18:32,590
你剛回家嗎
And you're just getting home?

1034
01:18:49,290 --> 01:18:50,490
婚禮怎么樣
So how was it?

1035
01:18:51,490 --> 01:18:52,490
挺好的
It was okay.

1036
01:18:54,290 --> 01:18:56,390
-你看上去很精神 -謝謝
- Well you look nice. - Thank you.

1037
01:18:58,590 --> 01:18:59,790
她是你女朋友嗎
Was that your girlfriend?

1038
01:19:01,590 --> 01:19:02,890
不 只是朋友而已
Just a friend.

1039
01:19:04,190 --> 01:19:05,590
她很漂亮
She's pretty.

1040
01:19:06,090 --> 01:19:06,990
是啊
Yes.

1041
01:19:07,690 --> 01:19:08,590
她很漂亮
She's pretty.

1042
01:19:10,690 --> 01:19:13,590
我很喜歡這個
Well, I liked this so much.

1043
01:19:15,690 --> 01:19:19,190
-很美 -謝謝
- It's wonderful. - Thanks. Thanks.

1044
01:19:19,220 --> 01:19:23,270
它讓我想起俄爾浦斯和歐律狄斯
It reminded me of Orpheus and Eurydice.

1045
01:19:24,290 --> 01:19:25,890
-你知道這個神話故事嗎 -不知道
- Do you know that myth. - No.

1046
01:19:27,690 --> 01:19:30,790
歐律狄斯死了 俄爾浦斯非常想她
Eurydice dies, and Orpheus misses her so much

1047
01:19:30,890 --> 01:19:34,010
就到冥府去救她
that he travels to hades to retrieve her,

1048
01:19:34,010 --> 01:19:37,110
但最后也沒能成功
but in the end it doesn't work out.

1049
01:19:38,590 --> 01:19:39,590
我應該看看這故事
I should read it.

1050
01:19:41,990 --> 01:19:44,690
這個科學家是你爸爸嗎
So, is the scientist your Dad?

1051
01:19:45,490 --> 01:19:47,290
那個男孩尋找的科學家
The scientist the boy is looking for...

1052
01:19:47,990 --> 01:19:48,890
不是
No.

1053
01:19:49,190 --> 01:19:50,490
是根據他創作的嗎
Is it based on him?

1054
01:19:51,390 --> 01:19:52,790
不是 我爸過去是英語老師
No. My Dad was an english teacher.

1055
01:19:53,990 --> 01:19:55,590
哦 我就是有點好奇
Oh. Okay. I was curious about that.

1056
01:19:56,390 --> 01:19:57,490
只是個故事而已
It's just a story.

1057
01:19:58,390 --> 01:20:00,790
-我知道 我只是 -沉浸其中了?
- No, I know. I was just... - Reading into it?

1058
01:20:06,490 --> 01:20:07,690
你覺得是真的嗎
Do you think they're real?

1059
01:20:08,490 --> 01:20:09,490
平行宇宙?
Parallel Universes?

1060
01:20:13,390 --> 01:20:15,090
我覺得這是基本的科學知識
I think it's basic science.

1061
01:20:17,090 --> 01:20:20,590
如果空間是無限的 那任何事都有可能
You know,if space is infinite, then everything is possible.

1062
01:20:22,090 --> 01:20:25,490
所以在某個地方 我可能在 做烤餅?
So somewhere out there, I'm what? I'm making pancakes?

1063
01:20:27,690 --> 01:20:29,290
-或者在水上公園 -當然 有可能
- Or at a water park. - Sure. Yes.

1064
01:20:29,390 --> 01:20:31,690
-是嗎 -都有可能 有各種可能
- Yes. - Yes. Both, wherever.

1065
01:20:33,090 --> 01:20:35,190
我想這符合概率律
I think... you know,laws of probability.

1066
01:20:36,190 --> 01:20:40,890
外面有無數個你 和無數個我
There are tons of you's out there, and tons of me's floating around.

1067
01:20:41,240 --> 01:20:42,950
是啊
Yes...

1068
01:20:42,990 --> 01:20:45,290
所以這里的只是我們的悲傷版
So this is just the sad version of us.

1069
01:20:46,690 --> 01:20:47,590
我猜是的
Yes, I guess.

1070
01:20:48,090 --> 01:20:49,390
但是還有其它版本的我們
But there are other versions.

1071
01:20:49,790 --> 01:20:53,290
在其他版本中 我們過得順心如意
Where everything goes our way.

1072
01:20:53,690 --> 01:20:55,190
如果你相信科學的話
Assuming you believe in science.

1073
01:20:58,590 --> 01:20:59,690
我喜歡這個想法
I like that thought.

1074
01:21:00,690 --> 01:21:01,690
很好
It's nice.

1075
01:21:05,690 --> 01:21:07,690
在某一個地方 我正過得開心
Somewhere out there I'm having a good time.

1076
01:22:17,190 --> 01:22:18,390
我以為你走了
I thought maybe you had left.

1077
01:22:22,190 --> 01:22:23,290
不 我沒走
No. I didn't leave.

1078
01:22:30,790 --> 01:22:32,160
我想我們可以邀請
So I was thinking we should invite

1079
01:22:32,170 --> 01:22:33,590
瑞克和黛比過來野餐
Rick and Debbie over for a cookout.

1080
01:22:39,690 --> 01:22:43,890
她不會打電話來了 她覺得我恨她
She's never gonna call. She thinks I hate her. So...

1081
01:22:44,690 --> 01:22:45,690
就給她個臺階下吧
Just let her off the hook

1082
01:22:50,090 --> 01:22:51,090
野餐?
Cookout?

1083
01:22:52,190 --> 01:22:53,290
能見見孩子們也挺好
It'll be good to see the kids.

1084
01:22:54,690 --> 01:22:57,290
我們應該給艾米麗買點東西 她過生日了
We should get something for Emily though. It's her birthday.

1085
01:22:58,190 --> 01:22:59,590
她上周就滿四歲了
She turned four last week.

1086
01:22:59,690 --> 01:23:02,890
對 好的
Right. Okay.

1087
01:23:08,290 --> 01:23:09,390
他們會提到丹尼
Danny's is coming up.

1088
01:23:11,290 --> 01:23:12,590
我知道
I know.

1089
01:23:14,290 --> 01:23:15,190
會不太好過的
That's gonna be a tough one.

1090
01:23:16,790 --> 01:23:17,790
是啊
Yes.

1091
01:23:21,590 --> 01:23:24,790
那孩子 杰森
So the kid... Jason.

1092
01:23:27,490 --> 01:23:28,790
你告訴他我們不怪他了嗎
Did you tell him we didn't blame him?

1093
01:23:30,090 --> 01:23:32,090
-我們沒怪他嗎 -我知道 但是...
- We don't blame him. - I know, but...

1094
01:23:33,990 --> 01:23:34,990
你讓他知道了嗎
Let him know that?

1095
01:23:35,590 --> 01:23:36,690
應該是吧
I guess so.

1096
01:23:38,290 --> 01:23:39,190
那就好
That's good.

1097
01:23:40,790 --> 01:23:42,790
-如果愿意你可以和他聊聊 -我不想
- You can talk with him if you want. - I do not want to.

1098
01:23:42,890 --> 01:23:43,690
好吧
Okay.

1099
01:23:50,490 --> 01:23:51,590
太安靜了
It's so quiet.

1100
01:23:53,790 --> 01:23:55,790
因為我給太子喂了點安眠藥
That's because I slipped Taz a couple ambien.

1101
01:23:57,090 --> 01:23:57,990
你可真逗
You're funny.

1102
01:23:58,490 --> 01:23:59,690
你以為我在開玩笑
You think I'm joking.

1103
01:24:07,390 --> 01:24:08,790
我們怎么辦呢
So what are we gonna do?

1104
01:24:13,690 --> 01:24:14,690
什么怎么辦
About what?

1105
01:24:16,190 --> 01:24:17,390
我不知道
I don't know.

1106
01:24:18,490 --> 01:24:19,390
我不知道
I don't know.

1107
01:24:19,990 --> 01:24:21,190
去買東西吧
Pick something.

1108
01:24:25,390 --> 01:24:26,290
好
Well...

1109
01:24:30,390 --> 01:24:31,990
我們可以去玩具城
We could go to village toys.

1110
01:24:33,790 --> 01:24:35,090
給艾米麗買套"糖果世界"
Pick up candy land for Emily.

1111
01:24:36,590 --> 01:24:37,790
她可能會喜歡
Probably something she'd like.

1112
01:24:41,490 --> 01:24:42,790
糖果 好啊
Candy, yes...

1113
01:24:48,390 --> 01:24:49,190
然后呢
Then what?

1114
01:24:51,490 --> 01:24:52,490
然后把它包上
Then we wrap it.

1115
01:24:59,090 --> 01:25:04,510
然后... 我們準備野餐
And then we have the cookout...

1116
01:25:07,860 --> 01:25:11,200
然后他們會過來
And they'll come over..

1117
01:25:15,890 --> 01:25:17,230
然后其他人也會到場
And we'll have a couple other people so...

1118
01:25:17,240 --> 01:25:20,930
所以大家不會太尷尬
It's not too awkward for anyone.

1119
01:25:22,790 --> 01:25:23,790
然后
Then...

1120
01:25:24,190 --> 01:25:25,590
為了讓他們覺得舒服
And to make them feel comfortable.

1121
01:25:26,890 --> 01:25:28,610
我們會問一些問題
We'll ask a bunch of questions about

1122
01:25:28,620 --> 01:25:32,310
問他們的孩子怎么樣了
what the kids have been up to.

1123
01:25:33,690 --> 01:25:35,190
我們會假裝很感興趣
And we'll pretend that we're really interested.

1124
01:25:37,190 --> 01:25:38,190
然后
Then...

1125
01:25:40,590 --> 01:25:44,290
我們會等某個人提起丹尼
And then we'll wait for someone to bring up Danny

1126
01:25:46,090 --> 01:25:47,190
這時孩子們在一旁玩耍
while the kids are playing.

1127
01:25:48,990 --> 01:25:50,690
然后可能會就此聊上幾句
And maybe that'll go on for a little while.

1128
01:25:54,190 --> 01:25:55,190
再之后
And after that...

1129
01:25:57,390 --> 01:25:58,390
他們就都回去了
They'll go home.

1130
01:26:02,690 --> 01:26:03,490
然后呢
And then what?

1131
01:26:08,690 --> 01:26:09,790
我不知道
I don't know.

1132
01:26:15,290 --> 01:26:16,390
總會有什么的
Something though.

