1
00:00:11,000 --> 00:00:17,000
翻譯：Mad Max 1980
歡迎轉發  並請保留譯者名

2
00:00:18,000 --> 00:00:22,800
未來的世界，由於人口過度膨脹，導致資源極度缺乏。

3
00:00:23,000 --> 00:00:28,800
為了解決這個危機，聯合國決議，
要求全世界每個國家，每年必須減少5%的人口。

4
00:00:28,800 --> 00:00:34,000
在美國，採取的方式是，所有學生每年必須參加一項聯合考試。
分數最低的學生將被處死。

5
00:00:35,000 --> 00:00:39,800
這項考試的官方名稱為 10-241。
但大多數時候被俗稱為...

6
00:00:40,000 --> 00:00:44,500
THE THINNING
削減計劃

7
00:00:46,500 --> 00:00:49,500
德州‧奧斯丁市
削減計劃考試前18小時

8
00:00:49,581 --> 00:00:51,425
Ok，記得我們討論過的嗎？
Okay, remember what we talked about?

9
00:00:51,550 --> 00:00:53,686
用方程式導出函數值。
Use the product rule
to find the derivative.

10
00:00:53,811 --> 00:00:55,929
我不會。
I can't do this.

11
00:00:56,955 --> 00:00:59,157
嘿，柯林，別吵。
Hey, Corinne, not now.

12
00:01:00,000 --> 00:01:02,419
你會的，賽門。
Yeah, you can, Simon.

13
00:01:02,544 --> 00:01:04,287
我看過你的筆記。
I've seen your scratch work.

14
00:01:04,412 --> 00:01:05,647
不要慌。
Just take your time.

15
00:01:05,772 --> 00:01:07,516
專心在數學式上。
Focus on the equation.

16
00:01:09,652 --> 00:01:10,954
Ok，我沒辦法在明天前學會。
Okay, I can't learn this by tomorrow.

17
00:01:11,079 --> 00:01:12,679
我完蛋了。
I'm totally fried.

18
00:01:14,991 --> 00:01:17,427
妳就不能把那個東西給我嗎？
Can't you just give 'em to me?

19
00:01:17,552 --> 00:01:18,261
賽門。
Simon.

20
00:01:18,386 --> 00:01:19,986
求求妳。
Please.

21
00:01:34,610 --> 00:01:35,920
多謝。
Thanks.

22
00:01:36,045 --> 00:01:38,481
你不能跟任何人說這事。
You can't tell anyone about this.

23
00:01:38,606 --> 00:01:41,851
考試一結束，立刻把它銷毀。
As soon as the test
is over, destroy it.

24
00:01:44,320 --> 00:01:47,165
你走運，這是我最後一個了。
You're lucky, that was my last one.

25
00:01:47,290 --> 00:01:47,991
妳不需要它嗎？
Don't you need it?

26
00:01:48,116 --> 00:01:49,716
不需要。
No.

27
00:01:50,726 --> 00:01:51,669
哈囉？
Hello?

28
00:01:51,794 --> 00:01:53,471
萊娜，我是波卡許醫生。
Laina, this is Dr. Perkash,

29
00:01:53,596 --> 00:01:56,666
妳母親要求出院。
your mother is asking to be
discharged from the hospital.

30
00:01:56,791 --> 00:01:57,808
什麼？
What?

31
00:01:57,933 --> 00:02:03,062
她決定不再依我們的建議治療了。
She's not so much asking as signing
herself out of care against our advice.

32
00:02:05,374 --> 00:02:06,609
我馬上到。
I'll be right there.

33
00:02:06,734 --> 00:02:09,387
請儘量拖住她。
Just please try to stall her.

34
00:02:09,512 --> 00:02:11,448
Ok，該走了。
Okay, guys, time to go.

35
00:02:21,424 --> 00:02:23,326
嗨，你們來了。
Hi, there they are.

36
00:02:25,328 --> 00:02:27,271
這個太漂亮了。
This is perfect.

37
00:02:27,396 --> 00:02:29,540
幫媽媽拿到車上去好嗎？
Can you take that to the car for mommy?

38
00:02:29,665 --> 00:02:31,401
媽，妳在幹什麼？
Mom, what are you doing?

39
00:02:31,526 --> 00:02:33,270
我在辦出院。
I am checking out.

40
00:02:35,071 --> 00:02:39,584
知道嗎，甜心，我把你的畫筆落在我的房間了。
You know what, sweetheart, I
left your markers in my room.

41
00:02:39,709 --> 00:02:42,312
願意幫媽咪去房間裡拿畫筆嗎？
Wanna go to mommy's room
and go get your markers?

42
00:02:42,437 --> 00:02:44,655
媽咪要回家了嗎？
Is mommy coming home?

43
00:02:44,780 --> 00:02:46,380
對。
Yes, I am.

44
00:02:49,485 --> 00:02:53,056
媽，妳必須留在這裡，在家裡他們沒法治療妳。
Mom, you need to be here,
they can't treat you at home.

45
00:02:53,181 --> 00:02:54,781
我知道。
I know.

46
00:02:56,959 --> 00:02:59,963
萊娜，我能跟妳說句話嗎？
Laina, can I have a word?

47
00:03:01,364 --> 00:03:04,334
這，我知道這不夠，我可以弄到更多。
Here, I know it's not all
of it, but I can get more.

48
00:03:04,459 --> 00:03:07,612
額，不，我不是要說這個。
Oh, um, no, we're past that.

49
00:03:07,737 --> 00:03:11,015
她的白血球數量不太好。
Her white blood cell count
is not doing her any favors.

50
00:03:11,140 --> 00:03:16,020
這種侵略性的耗竭，讓我們沒有太多的選擇。
And this kind of aggressive depletion
doesn't give us a lot of options.

51
00:03:16,145 --> 00:03:17,880
所以她不能回家，是嗎？
But she can't come home, right?

52
00:03:18,005 --> 00:03:19,924
她在家裡不會好的。
She's not gonna get any better there.

53
00:03:20,049 --> 00:03:24,954
我想目前能做的，是儘量讓她舒適。
I think the best thing any one can do
now is to just keep her comfortable.

54
00:03:26,389 --> 00:03:27,989
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.

55
00:03:32,862 --> 00:03:34,931
你能幫我提行李箱嗎？
Can you help me carry my suitcase?

56
00:03:35,056 --> 00:03:36,656
好啊。
Uh huh.

57
00:03:37,500 --> 00:03:42,500
州長官邸
削減計劃考試前12小時

58
00:03:44,440 --> 00:03:47,018
嘿，我要去廚房，要吃什麼嗎？
Hey, I'm gonna make a run to
the kitchen, want anything?

59
00:03:47,143 --> 00:03:48,411
不用，我不餓，布萊克，多謝你問我。
No, I'm good Blake, thanks for asking.

60
00:03:48,536 --> 00:03:49,020
你去吧。
You go ahead.

61
00:03:49,145 --> 00:03:50,113
好的，謝了。
All right, thanks man.

62
00:03:50,238 --> 00:03:51,838
沒事。
All right.

63
00:04:05,428 --> 00:04:07,028
嚇死我了。
Oh my.

64
00:04:08,164 --> 00:04:10,500
我相信我這樣嚇你，至少有19次了。
I honestly think I've done
that to you like 19 times.

65
00:04:10,625 --> 00:04:13,536
好吧，這是最後一次了。
Yeah, well, that's the last time..

66
00:04:19,175 --> 00:04:21,144
我不是那個意思。
I didn't mean it like that.

67
00:04:21,269 --> 00:04:24,055
我只是，我不想談它。
I just, I don't want to talk about it.

68
00:04:24,180 --> 00:04:25,081
愛莉，不管發生什麼事，我都會...
Ellie, no matter what happens, I'll...

69
00:04:25,206 --> 00:04:29,085
我不是來討論考試的。
I didn't come here
to talk about the test.

70
00:04:31,086 --> 00:04:34,090
來，我給你看樣東西。
Come on, I wanna show you something.

71
00:04:35,591 --> 00:04:37,191
好啊。
Okay.

72
00:04:38,928 --> 00:04:41,072
噓！這是秘密。
Sh! It's a secret.

73
00:04:41,197 --> 00:04:42,797
別這樣，愛莉。
Come on, Ellie.

74
00:04:43,958 --> 00:04:45,409
哇！
Oh my god.

75
00:04:45,534 --> 00:04:47,378
愛莉，我們不該這樣做。
Ellie we shouldn't be doing this.

76
00:04:47,503 --> 00:04:48,171
別怕。
Calm down.

77
00:04:48,296 --> 00:04:49,896
生活要有點樂子。
Live a little.

78
00:04:53,709 --> 00:04:54,710
愛莉，妳帶了泳衣了嗎？
Ellie, did you bring your bathing suit?

79
00:04:54,835 --> 00:04:56,846
沒。
No.

80
00:05:06,555 --> 00:05:08,155
來啊。
Go on.

81
00:05:26,041 --> 00:05:27,641
怎麼了？
What's wrong?

82
00:05:30,613 --> 00:05:33,057
我害怕，布萊克。
I'm scared, Blake.

83
00:05:33,182 --> 00:05:35,685
我們一起考試。
Hey, we're in this together.

84
00:05:38,220 --> 00:05:40,056
我會照顧妳的。
I'll take care of you.

85
00:05:42,825 --> 00:05:44,402
嘿，布萊克。
Hey, Blake.

86
00:05:44,527 --> 00:05:48,531
知道嗎？我想我是要點吃的。
You know, I think I do want
something from the kitchen.

87
00:05:56,238 --> 00:05:58,949
我是在比斯基家的泳池找到他的。
I found him at the Bilski's pool.

88
00:05:59,074 --> 00:06:00,674
比斯基家？
Bilskis?

89
00:06:07,883 --> 00:06:09,552
你要葩嗒餅嗎？
You want a Pop-Tart?

90
00:06:11,754 --> 00:06:13,354
不，謝了。
No thanks.

91
00:06:20,029 --> 00:06:21,631
有些人喜歡烤來吃。
Some people like to toast these.

92
00:06:21,756 --> 00:06:25,268
可我從來沒那耐性，知道嗎？
But I never have the
patience, you know.

93
00:06:25,393 --> 00:06:26,993
我喜歡吃這。
Love 'em.

94
00:06:32,641 --> 00:06:35,453
今天晚上過得有趣嗎？
Did you have fun tonight?

95
00:06:35,578 --> 00:06:38,114
明天你有什麼計劃嗎？
You got anything going on tomorrow?

96
00:06:38,239 --> 00:06:40,991
喔，等等，我的天，你明天要考試。
Oh wait, my god, you have a test.

97
00:06:41,116 --> 00:06:42,285
明天是考試日。
It's test day tomorrow.

98
00:06:42,410 --> 00:06:43,761
我全給忘了。
I completely forgot myself,

99
00:06:43,886 --> 00:06:46,022
這種事很容易忘記，是嗎？
it's so easy to forget
something like that, isn't it?

100
00:06:46,147 --> 00:06:47,198
我懂了。
I get it.

101
00:06:47,323 --> 00:06:48,923
嘿，抱歉。
Hey, sorry.

102
00:06:50,259 --> 00:06:54,664
聽著，偶而找點樂子沒什麼不對。
Look, there's nothing wrong with having
a little fun every once in a while,

103
00:06:54,789 --> 00:06:57,708
可是你得選對時間。
but you gotta pick your moments.

104
00:06:57,833 --> 00:07:02,338
生命轉捩點考試的前一晚，可不是好時候。
The night before a life altering
test it's not the moment.

105
00:07:02,463 --> 00:07:03,948
知道了。
Got it.

106
00:07:04,073 --> 00:07:05,182
教訓得對。
Solid lecture.

107
00:07:05,307 --> 00:07:06,083
馬上說完了。
Almost done.

108
00:07:06,208 --> 00:07:10,680
嗯，我知道你並不在乎我對這女孩的看法。
Now, I know that you don't really
care what I think about this girl.

109
00:07:10,805 --> 00:07:11,789
愛莉。
Ellie.

110
00:07:11,914 --> 00:07:14,551
愛莉，她讓你分心。
Ellie, but she's a distraction.

111
00:07:16,085 --> 00:07:20,130
你會有明天，明年。
Now you have tomorrow, and next year.

112
00:07:20,255 --> 00:07:24,827
而在那之後，你還有整個人生能讓你分心。
And after that you have the whole
rest of your life to be distracted.

113
00:07:24,952 --> 00:07:26,552
別搞砸了。
Don't eff it up.

114
00:07:27,963 --> 00:07:29,131
你確定不想吃塊葩嗒餅嗎？
You sure you don't want a Pop-Tart?

115
00:07:29,256 --> 00:07:30,856
晚安，爸。
Good night, Dad.

116
00:07:32,701 --> 00:07:34,301
嘿... 過來。
Hey...come here.

117
00:07:50,000 --> 00:07:53,000
削減計劃考試前3小時。

118
00:08:35,464 --> 00:08:37,064
不，不，不。
No, no, no.

119
00:08:39,334 --> 00:08:40,934
不！
No!

120
00:08:45,441 --> 00:08:47,644
繼續走。
Move along.

121
00:08:52,114 --> 00:08:53,714
操！
Shit!

122
00:09:19,241 --> 00:09:21,652
嘿，拉娜，是嗎？
Hey, Lana, right?

123
00:09:21,777 --> 00:09:23,220
是，萊娜。
Yeah, Laina.

124
00:09:23,345 --> 00:09:24,146
- 萊娜。    - 沒事。
- Laina.
- It's cool.

125
00:09:24,271 --> 00:09:25,322
抱歉，額。
Sorry, um.

126
00:09:25,447 --> 00:09:27,817
這是個尷尬的問題。
This is kind of an awkward question.

127
00:09:27,942 --> 00:09:32,021
我希望能買一個妳的學習指導裝置？
I was hoping that I could
buy one of your study guides?

128
00:09:33,322 --> 00:09:34,999
不行。
I can't.

129
00:09:35,124 --> 00:09:37,835
為什麼不行？
What do you mean I can't.

130
00:09:37,960 --> 00:09:40,963
我剛把最後一個給人了。
I just gave the last one away.

131
00:09:41,088 --> 00:09:42,688
操。
Shit.

132
00:09:44,867 --> 00:09:46,769
嘿，萊娜，等等。
Hey Laina, wait up.

133
00:09:47,903 --> 00:09:51,148
妳和布萊克‧瑞寧在一起？
So, you and Blake Renning, huh?

134
00:09:51,273 --> 00:09:52,816
不。
No, not really.

135
00:09:52,941 --> 00:09:54,176
他連我的名字都不知道。
He didn't even know my name.

136
00:09:54,301 --> 00:09:56,020
他不知道妳的名字？
He didn't know your name?

137
00:09:56,145 --> 00:09:57,480
但我們從一年級開始，就和他一起上課。
But we've been in school
with him since first grade

138
00:09:57,605 --> 00:10:00,182
然後學生們就一年一年地減少。
and there's less and
less kids each year.

139
00:10:00,307 --> 00:10:01,992
我知道，真悲哀。
I know, it's pretty tragic.

140
00:10:02,117 --> 00:10:05,521
老天，跟你最好的朋友談戀愛，也是個悲劇。
Geez, well, it's almost as tragic as
being in love with your best friend

141
00:10:05,646 --> 00:10:07,790
愛上那個連她名字都不知道的人。
who's in love with the guy that
doesn't even know her name.

142
00:10:07,915 --> 00:10:10,234
那只是我從電影上看到的故事。
But that's just something
I saw in a movie once.

143
00:10:10,359 --> 00:10:11,160
今天別說這些，凱倫。
Not today, Kellan.

144
00:10:11,285 --> 00:10:14,230
對，妳是對的，明天比較適當。
Yeah, you're right, tomorrow's
actually better for me anyway.

145
00:10:15,798 --> 00:10:18,801
不准有任何電腦裝置。
No laptops, computer devices.

146
00:10:18,926 --> 00:10:20,911
嘿，這什麼？
Hey, what the.

147
00:10:22,930 --> 00:10:23,814
不准跑。
Get back here.

148
00:10:23,939 --> 00:10:25,775
所有單位去南大門。
All units converse at the south gate.

149
00:10:25,900 --> 00:10:26,909
有個人逃跑了。
We got a runner.

150
00:10:27,034 --> 00:10:28,634
抓住那小子。
Get that kid.

151
00:10:30,212 --> 00:10:31,547
正朝你的方向去了。
Heading your way, now.

152
00:10:31,672 --> 00:10:36,786
哇，我從沒看過一個小鬼能逃過警衛。
Whoa, I've never seen a kid
make it past the guards before.

153
00:10:36,911 --> 00:10:38,062
凱倫。
Kellan.

154
00:10:38,187 --> 00:10:40,022
你又在入侵你爸的帳戶了嗎？
Are you hacking into
your dad's account again?

155
00:10:40,147 --> 00:10:41,747
額，對。
Uh, yeah.

156
00:10:46,562 --> 00:10:48,164
放倒他。
Bring him down.

157
00:10:48,289 --> 00:10:49,465
你被包圍了。
You're surrounded.

158
00:10:49,590 --> 00:10:50,874
上。
Move in.

159
00:10:50,999 --> 00:10:52,976
上，抓住他。
Come up now, on him.

160
00:10:53,101 --> 00:10:54,211
上，兄弟們。
Move in, boys.

161
00:10:54,336 --> 00:10:56,872
你是要把偷拍的保安事件視頻，傳送給新聞？
So you're going to send the stolen
security footage to the news?

162
00:10:56,997 --> 00:10:58,307
妳聽過溫蒂‧班克斯嗎？
You ever heard of Wendy Banks?

163
00:10:58,432 --> 00:10:59,383
沒。
No.

164
00:10:59,508 --> 00:11:01,143
她在奧斯丁市是非常出名的。
Well, she's a very prominent
news reporter in Austin

165
00:11:01,268 --> 00:11:04,421
而我有她直接的，私人專有 e-mail 信箱。
and I have her direct, personal,
general inquiries email address,

166
00:11:04,546 --> 00:11:08,092
我一直在把最熱門的訊息傳給她。
so I'm sending her hot
tips all the time.

167
00:11:08,217 --> 00:11:09,727
她有回應嗎？
Does she ever reply?

168
00:11:09,852 --> 00:11:11,020
喔，我想這問題我被問太多次了。
Whoa, I think I have
more than enough questions

169
00:11:11,145 --> 00:11:14,223
今天不想再回答了，感謝妳，非常的。
to answer today, thank you, very much.

170
00:11:32,174 --> 00:11:35,452
妳會沒事的，Ok？
You're gonna be okay, okay?

171
00:11:35,577 --> 00:11:37,413
妳做得到，是嗎？
You can do this, yeah?

172
00:12:00,302 --> 00:12:01,971
封鎖程序開始。
Commence lock down sequence.

173
00:12:02,096 --> 00:12:03,840
遵命。
Yes sir.

174
00:12:11,313 --> 00:12:15,017
警告，封鎖現在開始進行。
Warning, lock down is now in progress.

175
00:12:15,142 --> 00:12:17,220
30秒後完成。
30 seconds 'til lock down.

176
00:12:18,353 --> 00:12:20,923
考試在15分鐘後開始。
Testing to begin in 15 minutes.

177
00:12:29,965 --> 00:12:31,634
大家早安。
Good morning, everyone.

178
00:12:31,759 --> 00:12:34,403
我希望你們昨晚都睡得充足。
I hope you all had a good night sleep.

179
00:12:34,528 --> 00:12:36,339
我只要你們知道
I just want you to know

180
00:12:37,506 --> 00:12:40,910
你們這一年都表現傑出，不要管今天會發生什麼。
that you've all had a great year,
and despite what happens today,

181
00:12:41,035 --> 00:12:44,113
我為你們每一位感到驕傲。
I am proud of each
and every one of you.

182
00:12:45,647 --> 00:12:51,195
試題都不容易，但裡面沒有鬼計陷阱。
These questions are tough, but
they are not aimed to trick you.

183
00:12:51,320 --> 00:12:53,522
專心，慢慢來。
So, focus, take your time.

184
00:12:55,557 --> 00:12:58,995
而事情看起來不論多困難，
And no matter how hard something looks,

185
00:13:00,028 --> 00:13:01,998
機會總是在的。
there's always a chance.

186
00:13:03,165 --> 00:13:05,000
你們有2小時可以做答。
You'll have two hours
to complete the test.

187
00:13:05,125 --> 00:13:06,376
不准交談。
No talking.

188
00:13:06,501 --> 00:13:08,570
目光集中在你的平板電腦上。
Keep your eyes on your own tablet.

189
00:13:08,695 --> 00:13:13,976
這次是個精準的考試，能測出你的天資才能。
This time is an accurate test that
will determine your aptitude.

190
00:13:14,101 --> 00:13:17,046
你們知道，這是每個年級的期末考。
As you know, all grades are final.

191
00:13:17,171 --> 00:13:19,949
拿起你們的平板，開始考試。
Pick up your tablets and begin.

192
00:14:14,770 --> 00:14:17,606
考試時間還剩一分鐘。
You have one minute remaining.

193
00:14:29,718 --> 00:14:33,055
時間到，放下平板電腦，考試結束。
Time's up, tablets down, test is over.

194
00:15:02,250 --> 00:15:04,653
好，這是考試的結果。
Okay, here are the results.

195
00:15:14,296 --> 00:15:15,896
Donald Green.

196
00:15:19,201 --> 00:15:21,712
跟我來。
Come with me.

197
00:15:21,837 --> 00:15:23,437
Kellie Jeffries.

198
00:15:25,107 --> 00:15:27,250
這裡。
This way.

199
00:15:27,375 --> 00:15:28,975
Marcus Langley.

200
00:15:30,579 --> 00:15:32,022
別碰我。
Don't touch me.

201
00:15:32,147 --> 00:15:33,182
- 走。    - 別碰我。
- Come on.
- Don't touch me.

202
00:15:33,307 --> 00:15:34,850
- 別動手。    - 碰我。
- Hands out.
- Touch me.

203
00:15:34,975 --> 00:15:36,285
Lane Vic.

204
00:15:36,410 --> 00:15:38,729
不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不！
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!

205
00:15:38,854 --> 00:15:40,722
他在逃跑，他在逃跑。
He's on the move, he's on the move.

206
00:15:40,847 --> 00:15:42,825
嘿，抓住他，回來。
Hey, get him, back row.

207
00:15:42,950 --> 00:15:45,127
擋住門口。
Give him the door.

208
00:15:54,169 --> 00:15:55,769
Carrie Billich.

209
00:15:58,874 --> 00:16:00,776
來，是時候該走了。
Come on, it's time to go.

210
00:16:00,901 --> 00:16:03,312
求求你，不要，求求你。
Please stop, please.

211
00:16:05,847 --> 00:16:07,447
最後。
And finally.

212
00:16:09,885 --> 00:16:11,485
Peter Strand.

213
00:16:16,658 --> 00:16:18,258
Ellie Harper.

214
00:16:21,329 --> 00:16:22,929
不，不！
No, no!

215
00:16:27,402 --> 00:16:31,173
恭喜，你們都通過考試了。
Congratulations, you've all passed.

216
00:16:33,475 --> 00:16:36,353
你們現在可以去接待室了。
You can go to the rec room now.

217
00:16:36,478 --> 00:16:37,880
州長，布萊克打電話來。
Governor, Blake's on the phone.

218
00:16:38,005 --> 00:16:39,589
很好。
Oh, good.

219
00:16:39,714 --> 00:16:42,451
布萊克，我剛得到了好消息，恭喜你。
Blake, I just heard the
good news, congratulations.

220
00:16:42,576 --> 00:16:46,622
爸，他們抓走了愛莉，她要被"削減"了。
Dad, they took Ellie, she's
going to the thinning.

221
00:16:46,747 --> 00:16:48,347
天吶。
Oh god.

222
00:16:49,391 --> 00:16:50,567
我很難過。
I'm sorry son.

223
00:16:50,692 --> 00:16:51,827
我們必須做些什麼，爸。
We have to do something, Dad.

224
00:16:51,952 --> 00:16:54,071
打通電話，你可以說那只是個錯誤。
Just make a phone call, you
can say it was a mistake.

225
00:16:54,196 --> 00:16:55,364
你知道我不能那麼做。
You know I can't do that.

226
00:16:55,489 --> 00:16:56,506
爸。
Dad.

227
00:16:56,631 --> 00:16:57,900
孩子，我們都必須遵守法律。
Son, we all have to obey the law.

228
00:16:58,025 --> 00:17:00,277
不論是如何地痛苦。
No matter how painful it is.

229
00:17:00,402 --> 00:17:04,448
我不能失去她，爸，我愛她。
I can't lose her, Dad, I love her.

230
00:17:04,573 --> 00:17:06,608
對不起，孩子，我無能為力。
I'm sorry, son, my hands are tied.

231
00:17:10,579 --> 00:17:12,714
排好隊。
Stay in the line.

232
00:17:12,839 --> 00:17:14,591
繼續前進。
Keep going.

233
00:17:17,219 --> 00:17:18,819
你，來這裡。
You, this way.

234
00:17:31,733 --> 00:17:32,734
你幹什麼？
What are you doing?

235
00:17:32,859 --> 00:17:34,111
回到隊伍裡。
Get back in line.

236
00:17:34,236 --> 00:17:35,879
放下它。
Put that down.

237
00:17:39,574 --> 00:17:41,718
跑，愛莉！
Run, Ellie!

238
00:17:41,843 --> 00:17:43,443
快跑！
Go, now!

239
00:17:46,381 --> 00:17:47,583
她跑向大廳了。
She went down the hall.

240
00:17:47,708 --> 00:17:51,220
幫我，幫我，不，不，不，拜託，不！
Help, help, no, no, no, please, no!

241
00:17:51,345 --> 00:17:52,945
不！
No!

242
00:17:55,290 --> 00:17:56,325
沒什麼好看的。
There's nothing to see.

243
00:17:56,450 --> 00:17:57,167
不！
No!

244
00:17:57,292 --> 00:17:58,961
快，快點，走這裡。
Come on, hurry up, this way.

245
00:17:59,086 --> 00:18:00,686
不，不，不！
No, no, no!

246
00:18:02,497 --> 00:18:03,907
放她走！
Let her go!

247
00:18:04,032 --> 00:18:05,809
放她走！
Let her go!

248
00:18:05,934 --> 00:18:07,469
不要，放她走！
No, let her go!

249
00:18:07,594 --> 00:18:09,212
布萊克！
Blake!

250
00:18:09,337 --> 00:18:11,207
愛莉！愛莉！愛莉！
Ellie! Ellie! Ellie!

251
00:18:16,000 --> 00:18:20,000
一年後

252
00:18:22,500 --> 00:18:26,000
削減計劃考試前24小時

253
00:18:29,524 --> 00:18:31,860
嘿，偉德，加油。
Hey Wade, come on in, boy.

254
00:19:10,365 --> 00:19:12,275
格來斯先生？
Mr. Glass?

255
00:19:12,400 --> 00:19:14,303
有時間嗎？
Do you have a minute?

256
00:19:30,418 --> 00:19:32,921
柯妮，看好妳弟弟。
Corinne, watch your brother.

257
00:19:37,592 --> 00:19:39,502
嗨。
Hi.

258
00:19:39,627 --> 00:19:41,063
我知道妳要我別再弄了。
I know you told me to stop,

259
00:19:41,188 --> 00:19:44,366
但我花了太多功夫在這盤裡，所以拜託了。
but I made way too much of
this casserole, so please.

260
00:19:44,491 --> 00:19:45,701
喬依，關掉它。
Joey, turn it off.

261
00:19:45,826 --> 00:19:47,336
柯妮要讀書。
Corinne has to study.

262
00:19:47,461 --> 00:19:50,313
對不起，太謝謝妳了。
I'm sorry, thank you so much.

263
00:19:50,438 --> 00:19:52,374
這樣，明天妳有人能照顧喬依嗎？
Listen, do you have someone
to watch Joey tomorrow?

264
00:19:52,499 --> 00:19:54,351
因為我認識一個很棒的白天時段的褓姆。
Because I know of a great day care.

265
00:19:54,476 --> 00:19:56,586
康瑟家說他們能照顧他，謝謝妳。
The Consores said they'd
watch him, thank you.

266
00:19:56,711 --> 00:19:58,080
我知道那是柯妮的第一次考試。
I know it's Corinne's first test.

267
00:19:58,205 --> 00:20:00,382
我們會沒事的。
We're going to be fine.

268
00:20:02,050 --> 00:20:04,953
妳知道，只要妳需要我，我隨時都在。
You know I'm here if you need me.

269
00:20:06,087 --> 00:20:08,424
明天見，Ok？
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?

270
00:20:43,057 --> 00:20:45,127
那麼，到明天前？
So, as far as tomorrow?

271
00:20:46,461 --> 00:20:48,931
什麼事都不必擔心。
I wouldn't worry about a thing.

272
00:21:21,129 --> 00:21:26,535
如果你在看這段視頻，那麼我已經死了。
If you're watching this video,
then I am no longer alive.

273
00:21:26,600 --> 00:21:29,800
削減計劃考試前3小時

274
00:21:31,239 --> 00:21:32,808
五角形有幾個邊？
How many sides does a pentagon have?

275
00:21:32,933 --> 00:21:34,017
五個。
Five.

276
00:21:34,142 --> 00:21:35,076
是什麼讓人生病的？
What causes disease?

277
00:21:35,201 --> 00:21:37,053
細菌。
Bacteria.

278
00:21:37,178 --> 00:21:38,113
字母總共有幾個？
How many letters are in the alphabet?

279
00:21:38,238 --> 00:21:39,838
26.

280
00:21:42,150 --> 00:21:44,052
誰愛妳？
Who loves you?

281
00:21:44,177 --> 00:21:47,697
妳啊。
You do.

282
00:21:47,822 --> 00:21:49,658
妳會做得非常好。
You're going to do great.

283
00:21:49,783 --> 00:21:51,126
我好愛妳。
I love you so much.

284
00:21:51,251 --> 00:21:53,161
我也愛妳。
I love you, too.

285
00:21:58,633 --> 00:22:00,877
嘿，準備好要走了嗎？
Hey, you ready to go?

286
00:22:01,002 --> 00:22:02,602
嗯。
Uh huh.

287
00:22:06,274 --> 00:22:07,417
麻煩姓名？
Name, please?

288
00:22:07,542 --> 00:22:08,844
柯妮‧麥可斯。
Corinne Michaels.

289
00:22:08,969 --> 00:22:11,421
Ok，多謝。
Okay, thanks.

290
00:22:11,546 --> 00:22:13,146
好運，柯妮。
Good luck, Corinne.

291
00:22:15,250 --> 00:22:17,552
麻煩姓名？
Name, please?

292
00:22:23,258 --> 00:22:25,435
您下午一點要和記者會面。
You have a sit down with
Greet the Press at 1pm

293
00:22:25,560 --> 00:22:26,595
直接在宣佈結果之後。
directly after the announcement.

294
00:22:26,720 --> 00:22:27,637
很好，那麼演講呢？
Great, what about the speech?

295
00:22:27,762 --> 00:22:29,231
今天早上拿到了修訂版，修得非常好。
We got the revisions this
morning, they're good.

296
00:22:29,356 --> 00:22:30,232
喬吉娜簽名了嗎？
Did Georgina sign off?

297
00:22:30,357 --> 00:22:31,641
是的。
Yes, sir.

298
00:22:31,766 --> 00:22:35,037
您的車會在上午11點為您準備好。
Your car will be ready for you at 11.

299
00:22:39,807 --> 00:22:42,051
嘿，敲敲門。
Hey, knock knock.

300
00:22:42,176 --> 00:22:43,820
你有什麼事？我要來不及了。
What do you want, I'm running late.

301
00:22:43,945 --> 00:22:45,714
不是我做的每件事都有所深意。
Not everything I do
has a grand intention.

302
00:22:45,839 --> 00:22:47,816
我只是想打個招呼。
I just wanted to say hey.

303
00:22:49,551 --> 00:22:51,151
嘿。
Hey.

304
00:22:53,688 --> 00:22:55,965
布萊克。
Blake.

305
00:22:56,090 --> 00:22:58,527
我也希望當時我能做些什麼。
I wish there was something
I could have done.

306
00:22:58,652 --> 00:23:00,929
但我們都不能凌駕法律。
But none of us are above the law.

307
00:23:01,054 --> 00:23:03,265
我不能，你不能，愛莉也不能。
Not me, not you, not Ellie.

308
00:23:03,390 --> 00:23:05,675
這是個好台詞。
That's a good line.

309
00:23:05,800 --> 00:23:09,071
你應該用在你今天的演說裡，
You should use it in your speech today.

310
00:23:10,905 --> 00:23:14,510
還有什麼是你想試試的？
Is there anything else
you want to try out?

311
00:23:34,095 --> 00:23:34,996
嘿。
Hey.

312
00:23:35,121 --> 00:23:37,207
嘿。
Hey.

313
00:23:37,332 --> 00:23:40,510
真不敢相信這是最後一次了。
I can't believe this is the last one.

314
00:23:40,635 --> 00:23:42,337
我不知道我現在為什麼要告訴妳，但我已經汗如雨下了。
I don't know why I'm telling you this
right now but I'm sweating so much

315
00:23:42,462 --> 00:23:44,514
連我的背包都濕了。
that my backpack is just wet.

316
00:23:44,639 --> 00:23:46,082
真噁心。
That's gross.

317
00:23:46,207 --> 00:23:47,342
我知道妳對這事不會緊張。
I know you don't stress
out about this stuff

318
00:23:47,467 --> 00:23:52,222
因為妳是個天才或啥的，可是，妳一定也會有點鬆了口氣的感覺。
because you're a genius or whatever,
but, you gotta be a little bit relieved.

319
00:23:52,347 --> 00:23:54,224
我是說，想想看，這是最後一次
I mean, think about it,
this is the last time

320
00:23:54,349 --> 00:23:55,917
你要為了"年級"擔憂了。
you have to worry about grades forever.

321
00:23:56,042 --> 00:23:57,642
不完全正確。
Not exactly.

322
00:23:58,753 --> 00:24:01,197
你知道，你不必和我混在一起，沒關係的。
You know you don't have to
hang out with me, it's okay.

323
00:24:01,322 --> 00:24:02,958
喔，真的？妳真好。
Oh, really, sweet.

324
00:24:06,194 --> 00:24:08,037
我騙到妳了嗎？
Did I get you?

325
00:24:08,162 --> 00:24:09,831
沒有，你每天都這樣搞。
No, you do this everyday.

326
00:24:09,956 --> 00:24:13,076
喔，我每天都這樣搞嗎？
Oh, well, do I do this everyday?

327
00:24:13,201 --> 00:24:15,278
'Ello，我看起來像英國人嗎？
'Ello, do I look British?

328
00:24:15,403 --> 00:24:17,003
我看起來像個英國人嗎？
Do I look like a British person?

329
00:24:18,406 --> 00:24:20,617
讓開，婊子們。
Out of the way, bitches.

330
00:24:20,742 --> 00:24:24,580
偉德‧弗瑞門，全明星四分衛，在此！
Wade Freeman, all star
quarterback, represent!

331
00:24:27,015 --> 00:24:29,092
那傢伙怎麼會還留在這？
How the hell is that guy still here?

332
00:24:29,217 --> 00:24:30,159
他也許很聰明。
Maybe he's smart.

333
00:24:30,284 --> 00:24:31,319
這是你的電話嗎？
Is this your phone?

334
00:24:31,444 --> 00:24:32,153
給你。
Here you go.

335
00:24:32,278 --> 00:24:34,531
喔，夥計，給你，我很抱歉。
Oh, dude, oh here you go, I'm sorry.

336
00:24:34,656 --> 00:24:35,991
嗚，老兄，你肯定會被"削減"的。
Aw man, you're definitely
getting thinned.

337
00:24:36,116 --> 00:24:37,800
去找吧，婊子。
Go fetch, bitch.

338
00:24:37,925 --> 00:24:39,525
他一個人關在衣櫥裡就最聰明了。
Closeted smart.

339
00:24:45,800 --> 00:24:48,370
- 開始封鎖程序。    - 遵命。
- Commence lock down sequence,
- Yes sir.

340
00:24:50,705 --> 00:24:54,275
警告，封鎖程序現在開始。
Warning, lock down is now in progress.

341
00:24:54,400 --> 00:24:57,287
封鎖30秒後完成。
30 seconds until lock down.

342
00:24:57,412 --> 00:25:00,182
考試在15分鐘後開始。
Testing to begin in 15 minutes.

343
00:25:02,717 --> 00:25:05,887
警告，封鎖程序現在開始。
Warning, lock down is now in progress.

344
00:25:10,425 --> 00:25:12,702
抱歉，瑞丁州長。
Excuse me, Governor Redding.

345
00:25:14,788 --> 00:25:16,865
閣下，我想你該看看這個。
Sir, I think you're gonna
want to take a look at this.

346
00:25:16,990 --> 00:25:18,590
是你的兒子。
It's your son.

347
00:25:31,145 --> 00:25:32,347
全班早安。
Good morning, class.

348
00:25:32,472 --> 00:25:34,724
早安，柯爾小姐。
Good morning, Miss Cole.

349
00:25:34,849 --> 00:25:37,385
現在，在我們開始前，我要給你們看一段很特別的影片。
Now, before we begin, I'm going to
show you a really special video

350
00:25:37,510 --> 00:25:40,756
在你們開始考試前，Ok？
before you take your first test, okay?

351
00:25:45,893 --> 00:25:49,431
這是地球，我們的家。
This is planet Earth, our home.

352
00:25:49,556 --> 00:25:51,366
看她多快樂？
See how happy she is?

353
00:25:53,301 --> 00:25:55,904
可是，她並不是一直這麼快樂。
Well, she wasn't always so happy.

354
00:25:56,029 --> 00:26:00,909
知道嗎？不久之前，地球覺得很不舒服。
You see, not so long ago, the
Earth wasn't feeling so well.

355
00:26:02,343 --> 00:26:04,446
首先，她太熱了。
First, she got too hot.

356
00:26:07,048 --> 00:26:08,450
接著，海平面開始升高，
Then, the oceans started to rise,

357
00:26:08,575 --> 00:26:12,362
讓地球上的朋友們，能居住的土地更少了，
leaving less room on the
land for Earth's friends,

358
00:26:12,487 --> 00:26:15,798
土地少了，人卻越來越多，
and with less land and
more and more people,

359
00:26:15,923 --> 00:26:18,460
沒有足夠的空間供給每一個人。
there was just not enough
room for everybody.

360
00:26:18,585 --> 00:26:21,671
幸好，全世界的男孩與女孩們，
Luckily, boys and girls
from all over the world

361
00:26:21,796 --> 00:26:25,100
聚集起來，並且想出了一個很酷的法子
got together and came up
with some very cool ways

362
00:26:25,225 --> 00:26:29,304
每一年消滅5%的人口。
to eliminate five percent of
their population annually.

363
00:26:36,110 --> 00:26:37,946
你還好嗎，柯爾小姐？
You okay, Miss Cole?

364
00:26:39,514 --> 00:26:41,283
一切都沒事吧？
Everything all right?

365
00:26:42,550 --> 00:26:46,521
因為如果妳做不了，我們可以找別人來。
Because if you are not up for it, we
can have someone else come down here.

366
00:26:46,646 --> 00:26:48,765
不用，我可以。
No, I'm fine.

367
00:26:48,890 --> 00:26:50,492
只是需要幾分鐘。
Just need a minute.

368
00:27:02,336 --> 00:27:05,507
有些地方，向他們的老年人說再見。
Some places say goodbye to their oldest.

369
00:27:05,632 --> 00:27:09,118
有些地方，爸爸和媽媽只准生一個小孩。
Others only let mommies
and daddies have one baby.

370
00:27:09,243 --> 00:27:14,691
在美國，如果只讓最聰明的男女孩生活在這裡？
In America, what if only the smartest
boys and girls got to live here?

371
00:27:14,816 --> 00:27:17,727
這樣，空間就足夠了。
That way, there's enough to go around.

372
00:27:17,852 --> 00:27:21,130
然後，美國就可以再度成為最偉大的國家。
And America could be
the best country again.

373
00:27:21,255 --> 00:27:22,365
這不是很棒嗎？
Isn't that neat?

374
00:27:22,490 --> 00:27:25,435
現在，從1到12年級(高三)的孩子
Now, all kids from 1st
grade til 12th grade

375
00:27:25,560 --> 00:27:29,765
都要接受 10-241 的考試，來幫助地球健康起來。
get to take the 10-241 test to
help planet Earth feel great.

376
00:27:36,838 --> 00:27:40,483
好，現在，到時間該你們拿起你們的平板電腦了，Ok？
'Kay, now, it's time for everyone
to pick up your tablets, okay?

377
00:27:40,608 --> 00:27:45,380
你會有一個很刺激的測驗，就像我們之前練習過的。
You have a very exciting test
today, just like we practiced.

378
00:27:45,505 --> 00:27:52,829
這些問題很難，但如果你不慌不忙，專心一致，
These questions are hard, but
if you take your time, and focus,

379
00:27:52,954 --> 00:27:55,857
記住，機會永遠都在。
remember there's always a chance.

380
00:27:57,892 --> 00:28:00,829
好，拿起你的平板電腦，開始做答。
Okay, pick up your tablets and begin.

381
00:28:02,363 --> 00:28:03,963
祝好運。
Good luck.

382
00:28:06,033 --> 00:28:11,047
如果你在看這段視頻，那麼我已經死了。
If you're watching this video,
then I am no longer alive.

383
00:28:11,172 --> 00:28:13,474
今天，我會故意答錯題目
Today, I will be filling
in enough incorrect answers

384
00:28:13,599 --> 00:28:16,486
讓我的 10-241 考試徹底失敗。
to definitely fail my 10-241 examine.

385
00:28:16,611 --> 00:28:19,489
我爸願意挺這個制度。
My dad wants to stand by this system.

386
00:28:19,614 --> 00:28:23,952
他就得挺處死他兒子的制度。
He's gonna have to stand by a system
that put his own son to death.

387
00:28:29,090 --> 00:28:30,266
我要他立即回家。
I want him home now.

388
00:28:30,391 --> 00:28:32,227
- 閣下，我們不能...    - 我要他回家，立刻！
- Sir, we can't...
- I want my son home now!

389
00:28:32,352 --> 00:28:34,596
考試已經開始了，學校已經被全面封鎖。
Testing's already begun, the
school's on complete lock down.

390
00:28:34,721 --> 00:28:36,497
混帳！混帳！
God damnit, god damnit!

391
00:28:45,640 --> 00:28:48,109
長官，他們為您準備好了。
Sir, they're ready for you.

392
00:28:51,612 --> 00:28:53,212
去走走。
Take a walk.

393
00:29:20,675 --> 00:29:22,444
這是梅森‧康
This is Mason King.

394
00:29:48,169 --> 00:29:49,070
什麼事，納森？
Yes, Nathan.

395
00:29:49,195 --> 00:29:50,705
這題我不會。
I don't know this one.

396
00:29:50,830 --> 00:29:52,430
妳能教我嗎？
Can you help me?

397
00:29:59,680 --> 00:30:02,058
抱歉，我不能。
Sorry, I can't.

398
00:30:02,183 --> 00:30:04,585
就盡你的能力，Ok？
Just do your best, okay?

399
00:30:04,710 --> 00:30:06,596
Okay.

400
00:30:25,740 --> 00:30:29,067
時間到，放下平板，考試結束。
Time's up, tablets down, test is over.

401
00:30:46,761 --> 00:30:50,665
如果我唸到你的名字，請站起來跟著引導人走。
If I call your name, I want you
to stand up and follow the leader.

402
00:30:50,790 --> 00:30:54,703
完成考試後，我們會放音樂。
We're gonna play a song
while we grade the test.

403
00:31:15,515 --> 00:31:17,166
Nicole Chung.

404
00:31:19,819 --> 00:31:21,419
不，不！
No, no!

405
00:31:24,690 --> 00:31:26,501
放開我。
Get off me.

406
00:31:48,389 --> 00:31:49,989
Mark Salazar.

407
00:31:51,392 --> 00:31:53,628
跟我來。
Come with me.

408
00:31:57,190 --> 00:31:59,275
Sarah Foster.

409
00:31:59,400 --> 00:32:01,644
不，不，不！
No, no, no!

410
00:32:01,769 --> 00:32:04,172
不，不，求你別，不要，不！
No, no, please no, don't, no!

411
00:32:07,408 --> 00:32:11,079
恭喜，剩下來的，你們通過考試了。
Congratulations, the
rest of you passed.

412
00:32:12,847 --> 00:32:14,447
最後的。
And lastly.

413
00:32:21,655 --> 00:32:23,255
Laina Michaels.

414
00:32:27,128 --> 00:32:28,728
什麼？
What?

415
00:32:30,865 --> 00:32:34,225
來吧，該走了。
Come on, it's time to go.

416
00:32:37,338 --> 00:32:38,938
下課。
Class dismissed.

417
00:32:42,877 --> 00:32:44,153
他安全了嗎？
Is he safe?

418
00:32:44,278 --> 00:32:45,346
轉移完成了。
The transfer is complete.

419
00:32:45,471 --> 00:32:47,456
一切都在掌控下，州長。
Everything is in order, governor.

420
00:32:47,581 --> 00:32:49,692
梅森，我非常欣賞你的能力。
Mason, I appreciate your discretion.

421
00:32:49,817 --> 00:32:52,461
一如往常，我需要你的指示讓它成為正式的官方命令。
As always, I need the word
from you to make it official.

422
00:32:52,586 --> 00:32:53,654
我們允許開始消減行動了嗎？
Are we approved to
commence the thinning.

423
00:32:53,779 --> 00:32:54,489
允許。
You are approved.

424
00:32:54,614 --> 00:32:56,458
是的，長官。
Yes, sir.

425
00:32:57,825 --> 00:32:59,425
好了。
Good.

426
00:33:01,195 --> 00:33:02,763
好，那麼您準備好了嗎？
Good, are you ready?

427
00:33:02,888 --> 00:33:04,665
推銷夢想的時間到了。
Time to sell the dream.

428
00:33:28,389 --> 00:33:33,669
警官，等等，我是坎卓拉‧博爾奇，我是萊娜的老師。
Officer, wait, I'm Kendra
Birch, I'm Laina's teacher.

429
00:33:33,794 --> 00:33:35,838
萊娜是我最好的學生。
Laina's the best student I've ever had.

430
00:33:35,963 --> 00:33:39,400
我認為她不及格是非常不可能的事。
I'm finding it very difficult to
believe that she failed the exam.

431
00:33:39,525 --> 00:33:42,370
也許她的平板電腦出了問題？
Maybe there was a
problem with her tablet?

432
00:33:42,495 --> 00:33:44,547
求求你，做些什麼！
Do something, please?

433
00:33:44,672 --> 00:33:47,116
改正錯誤。
Make it right.

434
00:33:48,876 --> 00:33:50,786
陳，西棟這兒有位老師。
Chang, there's a
teacher in the west corridor

435
00:33:50,911 --> 00:33:52,680
她認為有個學生的成績有錯誤。
who thinks there's a mistake
with a student's test.

436
00:33:52,805 --> 00:33:54,857
請協助。
Please advise.

437
00:33:54,982 --> 00:33:56,217
學生的名字叫什麼？
What's the name of the student?

438
00:33:56,342 --> 00:33:57,827
麥可司，萊娜‧麥可司。
Michaels, Laina Michaels.

439
00:33:57,952 --> 00:33:59,654
看看麥可司。
Look up, Michaels.

440
00:33:59,779 --> 00:34:01,379
名字是萊娜。
First name, Laina.

441
00:34:02,556 --> 00:34:06,194
沒有錯誤，繼續進行，別再停止隊伍了。
There's no mistake, proceed, and
don't hold up the line again.

442
00:34:06,319 --> 00:34:07,919
不，我不能。
No, I can't.

443
00:34:09,997 --> 00:34:12,541
機會永遠會有。
There's always a chance.

444
00:34:12,666 --> 00:34:14,736
離開這裡。
Get the hell out of here.

445
00:34:17,671 --> 00:34:20,441
我們走，前進。
Let's go, move out.

446
00:34:38,025 --> 00:34:41,370
嘿，恭喜啊，你做到了！
Hey, congratulations, you made it!

447
00:34:41,495 --> 00:34:43,205
法蘭克‧哈樓恩，EG 電子公司。
Frank Halloran, EG Electric.

448
00:34:43,330 --> 00:34:45,399
你不是瑞丁州長的公子嗎？
Aren't you Governor Redding's son?

449
00:34:45,524 --> 00:34:48,937
我很樂於和你談談你的未來。
I'd like to talk to
you about your future.

450
00:34:51,605 --> 00:34:53,205
嘿，克萊爾！
Hey, Clare!

451
00:34:59,913 --> 00:35:01,513
快啊。
Come on.

452
00:35:05,019 --> 00:35:05,895
好孩子。
Thata boy.

453
00:35:06,020 --> 00:35:07,620
好樣的，凱倫
Thata boy, Kellan.

454
00:35:41,088 --> 00:35:43,724
當我祖父開創環球伺服時，
When my grandfather
started at Server Global,

455
00:35:43,849 --> 00:35:46,202
他只和他信得過的人共事。
he only worked with
people he could trust.

456
00:35:46,327 --> 00:35:50,364
而我可以告訴你們，今天，最能讓他信任的人就是我的好友
And I can tell you, today, that he
would trust no one more than my friend

457
00:35:50,489 --> 00:35:56,070
偉大德州的領導人，迪恩‧瑞丁州長！
and the leader of the great state
of Texas, Governor Dean Redding!

458
00:35:56,195 --> 00:35:57,338
謝謝妳，喬吉娜
Thank you, Georgina.

459
00:35:57,463 --> 00:35:59,063
謝謝妳。
Thank you.

460
00:36:00,908 --> 00:36:02,577
謝謝，謝謝。
Thank you, thank you.

461
00:36:03,744 --> 00:36:05,546
德州多麼光輝的一天！
What a great day in Texas!

462
00:36:09,950 --> 00:36:14,263
做為這偉大的州的州長六年來，
Being governor of this great
state for the past six years,

463
00:36:14,388 --> 00:36:17,491
我們完成了一些不可思議的成就。
we've accomplished some
pretty incredible things.

464
00:36:17,616 --> 00:36:19,001
我們平衡了預算。
We balanced the budget.

465
00:36:19,126 --> 00:36:21,095
我們甚至多出了些結餘。
We even had a little bit
of change left to spare.

466
00:36:23,764 --> 00:36:31,605
我們打擊降低了26%的犯罪率，而最了不起的，
We cracked down on crime by 26%, and
above all, we are number one in education

467
00:36:31,730 --> 00:36:34,342
我們是全美國教育的第一名。
in the entire United States of America.

468
00:36:43,117 --> 00:36:46,020
跟著隊伍走。
Move down the line.

469
00:36:49,656 --> 00:36:51,392
跟著隊伍走。
Move down the line.

470
00:36:54,661 --> 00:36:56,939
我們的世界很擁擠。
Our world is crowded.

471
00:36:57,064 --> 00:36:59,408
我們必須面對事實。
We had to look facts square in the eye.

472
00:36:59,533 --> 00:37:01,610
- 你一定很驕傲。    - 做一些困難的決定。
- You must be really proud.
- And make some hard decisions.

473
00:37:01,735 --> 00:37:06,107
我們必須共同決定，我們希望活在什麼樣的世界裡。
We had to collectively decide, what
kind of world do we want to live in?

474
00:37:07,741 --> 00:37:10,812
25年前，美國有了麻煩。
25 years ago, America was in trouble.

475
00:37:27,194 --> 00:37:30,732
準備清除污染。
Prepare for decontamination.

476
00:37:32,065 --> 00:37:33,735
脫掉所有的衣服。
Remove all clothing.

477
00:37:53,921 --> 00:37:57,433
有些人說，削減計劃是野蠻的行為。
There are those that say
the thinning is barbaric.

478
00:37:57,558 --> 00:38:01,696
那麼我要問，領導革新是野蠻嗎？
Well, I ask you, is it barbaric
to be leading in innovation?

479
00:38:09,036 --> 00:38:13,641
成為196個國家中，
Is it barbaric to be the number one
most informed and educated population

480
00:38:13,766 --> 00:38:16,366
最有活力，教育程度最高的人口，是野蠻嗎？
in 196 countries?

481
00:38:18,512 --> 00:38:20,214
成為第一的強者是野蠻嗎？
Is it barbaric to be the best?

482
00:38:23,217 --> 00:38:29,098
如果你不工作，如果你不支持我們的偉大社會，
If you don't work, if you don't
support our great society,

483
00:38:29,223 --> 00:38:31,959
那你就是生活在制度之外。
then you are living off the system.

484
00:38:32,084 --> 00:38:33,684
那就是寄生蟲。
That is a parasite.

485
00:38:35,062 --> 00:38:37,531
而你們知道我們是怎麼對付寄生蟲的嗎？
And do you know what
we do with parasites?

486
00:38:37,656 --> 00:38:39,567
我們把牠們清除掉。
We wash them out.

487
00:38:45,906 --> 00:38:47,842
今天一個中等的學生
Today's average student

488
00:38:49,009 --> 00:38:51,086
是昨天的資優生。
is yesterday's valedictorian.

489
00:38:51,211 --> 00:38:52,213
把這告訴佛蒙特州。
Tell that to Vermont.

490
00:38:52,338 --> 00:38:53,938
把這告訴奧勒岡州。
Tell that to Oregon.

491
00:38:56,617 --> 00:38:59,428
我們把競爭引入教室。
We introduced competition
in the classroom

492
00:38:59,553 --> 00:39:02,089
而結果如何，他們自己已經說明白了。
and the results speak for themselves.

493
00:39:06,293 --> 00:39:07,728
把這些穿上。
Put these on now.

494
00:39:07,853 --> 00:39:12,941
我們偉大的國家，還有許多挑戰橫亙眼前。
Our great country has many
challenges still ahead.

495
00:39:13,066 --> 00:39:14,666
經由你們的幫助，
And with your help,

496
00:39:16,003 --> 00:39:18,606
我們可以用德州做得好的經驗
we can take the good
things we've done in Texas

497
00:39:18,731 --> 00:39:22,243
領導美國的其他州，進入更美好的明天
and lead the rest of America
into an even greater tomorrow.

498
00:39:29,850 --> 00:39:32,487
長官，請幫幫我。
Sir, please, help me.

499
00:39:33,887 --> 00:39:35,656
你知道，你不該在這通道的。
You know, you shouldn't be in the hallway.

500
00:40:48,362 --> 00:40:52,264
這一小時，這一分鐘，
This hour, this minute,

501
00:40:53,300 --> 00:40:55,677
這個時刻。
this moment.

502
00:41:09,783 --> 00:41:12,019
我檢視了我自己
I have looked inside myself

503
00:41:13,420 --> 00:41:17,625
以及在各位面前的偉大德州。
and in front of the people
of the great state of Texas.

504
00:41:28,001 --> 00:41:30,279
不，不！
No, no!

505
00:41:30,404 --> 00:41:32,973
我在這裡宣佈我要競選
I came here to declare my candidacy

506
00:41:33,098 --> 00:41:36,410
美國總統。
for president of the
United States of America.

507
00:42:06,373 --> 00:42:08,784
留在你的椅子上。
Stay in your seat.

508
00:42:08,909 --> 00:42:09,943
嘿，回到椅子上。
Hey, back to the chair.

509
00:42:10,068 --> 00:42:11,587
留在座位上。
Remain seated.

510
00:42:11,712 --> 00:42:12,980
坐下。
Sit down!

511
00:42:13,105 --> 00:42:14,715
不！
No!

512
00:42:14,840 --> 00:42:16,959
坐下！
Get down!

513
00:42:17,084 --> 00:42:18,352
喂，你，坐下！
Hey you, sit down!

514
00:42:18,477 --> 00:42:20,262
馬上！
Now!

515
00:42:20,387 --> 00:42:21,989
把他控制下來！
Get them in control!

516
00:42:39,506 --> 00:42:41,475
系統當機，開始遏止模式。
System is down,
commence containment mode.

517
00:42:41,600 --> 00:42:43,811
叫維克多‧伍茲立刻去控制室。
Send Victor Woods directly
to the control room.

518
00:42:43,936 --> 00:42:46,046
我們需要系統的完整補丁。
We need a full patch of
the electrical system.

519
00:42:46,171 --> 00:42:48,890
收到。
Copy that.

520
00:43:03,530 --> 00:43:06,141
維克多‧伍茲，到控制室報到。
Victor Woods,report to the control room.

521
00:43:06,266 --> 00:43:08,335
所有人退後，退後。
Everybody stand back, stand back.

522
00:43:08,460 --> 00:43:10,345
額，維克多‧伍茲，謝了。
Uh, Victor Woods, thanks.

523
00:43:10,470 --> 00:43:11,972
我們遇到了輕微的停電。
We've had a minor power outage.

524
00:43:12,097 --> 00:43:14,742
直到更進一步的通知，任何人禁止離開房間。
Nobody leave this room until further notice.

525
00:43:22,783 --> 00:43:24,092
他們為什麼離開座椅？
What are they doing out of the chairs?

526
00:43:24,217 --> 00:43:26,487
有些禁錮裝置在停電時失效。
Some of the restraints shorted
during the power outage.

527
00:43:26,612 --> 00:43:28,455
但我們已經控制住情況。
But we got it under control.

528
00:43:28,580 --> 00:43:30,365
你數過人頭了嗎？
Have you done a head count?

529
00:43:30,490 --> 00:43:31,992
長官，門是鎖著的。
Sir, the door's locked.

530
00:43:32,117 --> 00:43:34,795
他們不可能逃走。
There's no way they could have.

531
00:43:34,920 --> 00:43:37,439
我不是在和你討論。
This isn't a discussion.

532
00:43:37,564 --> 00:43:39,066
電力何時恢復？
When's the power back?

533
00:43:39,191 --> 00:43:40,868
大約再30分鐘。
Power's about 30 away.

534
00:43:40,993 --> 00:43:44,713
攝像鏡需要不同的補丁。
The cameras are gonna need a separate patch.

535
00:43:44,838 --> 00:43:46,438
把它搞定。
Just get it done.

536
00:43:55,115 --> 00:43:57,025
嘿！
Hey!

537
00:43:57,150 --> 00:43:59,461
你在這做什麼？
What are you doing down here?

538
00:43:59,586 --> 00:44:00,962
你可來了。
It's about time.

539
00:44:01,087 --> 00:44:02,456
我10分鐘前就呼叫你們了。
I called for you 10 minutes ago.

540
00:44:02,581 --> 00:44:03,457
什麼？
What?

541
00:44:03,582 --> 00:44:04,366
我是博爾奇小姐。
I'm Miss Birch.

542
00:44:04,491 --> 00:44:05,334
我教的是高中一年到三年的班。
I teach 10th to 12th grade.

543
00:44:05,459 --> 00:44:06,393
等等，妳為什麼穿著...
Wait, why are you wearing...

544
00:44:06,518 --> 00:44:08,428
我剛看到一個學生下樓梯去了。
I just saw a student go down that stairwell.

545
00:44:34,588 --> 00:44:35,489
有幾個？
What's the count?

546
00:44:35,614 --> 00:44:38,767
少了一個。
There's one unaccounted for.

547
00:44:38,892 --> 00:44:40,402
你少了個學生。
You lost a student.

548
00:44:40,527 --> 00:44:41,995
我不知道她怎麼出去的。
I don't know how she got out.

549
00:44:42,120 --> 00:44:43,405
她？
She?

550
00:44:43,530 --> 00:44:47,175
她名字叫萊娜‧麥可司。
Her name is Laina Michaels.

551
00:44:47,300 --> 00:44:48,900
她在哪裡？
And where is she?

552
00:44:52,939 --> 00:44:54,516
布萊克？
Blake?

553
00:44:54,641 --> 00:44:56,017
羅倫？
Lauren?

554
00:44:56,142 --> 00:44:58,253
你沒通過考試？
You failed the test?

555
00:44:58,378 --> 00:45:00,422
我是萊娜，不是。
It's Laina, and no.

556
00:45:00,547 --> 00:45:03,058
我是不可能不及格的。
There's no way I failed that test.

557
00:45:03,183 --> 00:45:04,585
你在這做什麼？
What are you doing here?

558
00:45:04,710 --> 00:45:06,261
你沒通過嗎？
Didn't you pass?

559
00:45:06,386 --> 00:45:07,888
我故意不及格。
I failed the test on purpose.

560
00:45:08,013 --> 00:45:09,531
什麼？
You did what?

561
00:45:09,656 --> 00:45:13,327
我給我爸出了個大難題，他居然解決了。
I put my dad between a rock and a
hard place and he moved the rock.

562
00:45:14,394 --> 00:45:16,330
有些事情不對勁。
Something's not right.

563
00:45:16,455 --> 00:45:19,533
來，我想我知道該去哪裡。
Come on, I think I know where to go.

564
00:45:28,375 --> 00:45:32,847
四層出現漏洞，四層出現漏洞。
Level four breach, level four breach.

565
00:45:34,581 --> 00:45:36,525
四層出現漏洞。
Level four breach.

566
00:45:36,650 --> 00:45:40,128
- 來。    - 四層出現漏洞。
- Come on.
- Level four breach.

567
00:45:40,253 --> 00:45:41,922
四層出現漏洞。
Level four breach.

568
00:45:42,956 --> 00:45:43,991
嘿，嘿，別。
Hey, hey, come on.

569
00:45:44,116 --> 00:45:45,100
退後。
Stay back.

570
00:45:45,225 --> 00:45:46,301
嘿，到底是他媽的怎麼回事？
Hey, what the hell's going on?

571
00:45:46,426 --> 00:45:47,527
所有人留在原地。
Everybody stay where you are.

572
00:45:47,652 --> 00:45:50,438
很快就解決了。
This will all be over soon.

573
00:45:50,563 --> 00:45:53,475
長官，過中午了。
Sir, it's past noon.

574
00:45:53,600 --> 00:45:56,303
我們仍然在封鎖狀態，直到狀況解決。
We're still in lock
down until this is done.

575
00:45:56,428 --> 00:45:58,113
任何人不得進出。
No one comes in or out.

576
00:45:58,238 --> 00:46:01,141
父母們已經在問，什麼時候能見到他們的孩子。
Parents are already asking
when they'll see their children.

577
00:46:01,266 --> 00:46:03,852
失蹤學生的狀況如何？
What's the status on the missing student?

578
00:46:03,977 --> 00:46:05,345
四層正常。
All clear on level four.

579
00:46:05,470 --> 00:46:10,258
立刻把所有教師帶到 A 室。
I want every teacher brought
to holding room A immediately.

580
00:46:10,383 --> 00:46:12,286
是的，長官。
Yes, sir.

581
00:46:21,194 --> 00:46:23,438
Okay.

582
00:46:23,563 --> 00:46:25,566
妳想往哪裡走？
Where do you want to go?

583
00:46:26,967 --> 00:46:29,578
我們要去他們存放考試結果的地方。
We need to find where they keep the tests.

584
00:46:29,703 --> 00:46:30,671
妳打算做什麼？
What are you gonna do?

585
00:46:30,796 --> 00:46:33,040
偷明年的考試答案？
Steal the answers for next year?

586
00:46:33,165 --> 00:46:34,449
你說什麼？
Excuse me?

587
00:46:34,574 --> 00:46:36,977
妳知道，妳的那個小生意。
You know, for your little side business.

588
00:46:37,102 --> 00:46:41,181
妳賣答案給學生們賺錢。
Where you sell the answers
to desperate kids for money.

589
00:46:43,750 --> 00:46:45,452
你不知道你在說什麼。
You don't know what you're talking about.

590
00:46:45,577 --> 00:46:47,229
不，我知道。
No, I do.

591
00:46:47,354 --> 00:46:50,691
無辜的孩子被打到底層而死了。
Innocent kids are killed
to meet a bottom line.

592
00:46:50,816 --> 00:46:54,161
而妳卻因為這樣而賺到錢。
And you found a way to profit off them.

593
00:46:55,996 --> 00:47:00,734
告訴我，萊娜，妳是把錢花去哪裡了？
Tell me, Laina, what did you
spend the money on first?

594
00:47:00,859 --> 00:47:02,911
買了輛車？
Was it a car?

595
00:47:03,036 --> 00:47:04,705
或許是高級服裝？
A nice dress, maybe?

596
00:47:07,007 --> 00:47:08,607
我媽。
My mom.

597
00:47:10,744 --> 00:47:14,748
我們需要找到方法去付醫療費。
We had to figure out a way
to pay for the treatments.

598
00:47:14,873 --> 00:47:20,220
我們賣了所有能賣的東西，但仍然不夠。
We sold everything we could,
but, it still wasn't enough.

599
00:47:21,654 --> 00:47:24,599
我並不為我做的事覺得光榮。
I'm not proud of what I did.

600
00:47:24,724 --> 00:47:27,628
我只是不知道還能怎麼做。
I just didn't know what else to do.

601
00:47:29,329 --> 00:47:32,066
最終，都無所謂了。
In the end it didn't even matter.

602
00:47:34,801 --> 00:47:39,673
很好笑，在學校裡他們每天都在教我們如何解決問題。
You know, it's funny, every day in school
they teach us how to solve problems.

603
00:47:39,798 --> 00:47:43,711
可是沒有一個答案可以用在現實人生。
But none of those answers are on the real world.

604
00:47:45,345 --> 00:47:47,014
我真是個混蛋。
I'm such a dick.

605
00:47:48,048 --> 00:47:49,357
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.

606
00:47:49,482 --> 00:47:50,492
沒事。
It's okay.

607
00:47:50,617 --> 00:47:53,988
多謝你承認是個混蛋。
Thank you for admitting you're a dick.

608
00:47:55,588 --> 00:47:57,699
我也很抱歉。
I'm sorry, too.

609
00:47:57,824 --> 00:48:03,597
我一直喜歡你，但我想我只是在嫉妒愛莉。
I just always liked you and I guess
I was kind of jealous of Ellie.

610
00:48:03,722 --> 00:48:05,473
妳喜歡我？
You like me?

611
00:48:05,598 --> 00:48:07,267
嗯，像是，過去式了。
Liked, past tense.

612
00:48:10,603 --> 00:48:12,373
那麼，現在你能幫我嗎？
Now, can you help me?

613
00:48:13,807 --> 00:48:16,217
額，可以，我可以找到控制室。
Um, yeah, I can get us to the control room

614
00:48:16,342 --> 00:48:18,512
可是沒有電力，我們能做的也很有限。
but with the power out
there's not much we can do.

615
00:48:18,637 --> 00:48:20,237
沒錯。
Right.

616
00:48:23,817 --> 00:48:26,020
- 不好意思。    - 抱歉。
- Excuse me.
- Sorry.

617
00:48:30,824 --> 00:48:33,393
我們可以順著網路電纜走，可以帶我們到伺服器室。
We can follow the network cables,
which will lead to the server room

618
00:48:33,518 --> 00:48:35,036
那裡控制伺服器的電力。
which runs on reserve power.

619
00:48:35,161 --> 00:48:36,396
對，可是不是每部電腦都需要
Yeah, but don't all computers require

620
00:48:36,521 --> 00:48:39,299
- 管理員的密碼...    - 管理員卡？
- administrator access...
- Access card?

621
00:48:39,424 --> 00:48:41,024
來吧。
Come on.

622
00:48:44,370 --> 00:48:45,480
是，我們正在做。
Yeah, we're doing it.

623
00:48:45,605 --> 00:48:47,808
我很好，我很高興終於能把這事放到行事曆裡了。
I'm great, I'm glad we could
finally get this on the calendar.

624
00:48:47,933 --> 00:48:49,117
我也是。
As am I.

625
00:48:49,242 --> 00:48:52,146
10秒，10秒。
10 seconds, 10 seconds.

626
00:48:57,884 --> 00:48:59,586
知道了，謝謝你。
Got it, thank you.

627
00:49:14,901 --> 00:49:16,670
密碼卡和身份證明。
Key cards and I.D.s

628
00:49:24,878 --> 00:49:26,421
謝謝你加入我們，州長。
Thank you for joining us, governor.

629
00:49:26,546 --> 00:49:29,149
多謝你邀請我來這，溫斯，很高興能來這裡。
Thank you for having me here,
Vince, it's a pleasure to be here.

630
00:49:29,274 --> 00:49:30,617
州長，對不起。
Governor, I apologize.

631
00:49:30,742 --> 00:49:33,061
我們要上臨時新聞。
We're getting breaking news right now.

632
00:49:33,186 --> 00:49:37,699
有個事件正發生在奧斯丁市的願景高中。
There is a story developing at Vista
Point High School, right here in Austin.

633
00:49:37,824 --> 00:49:41,328
我們得到消息，學校仍然在封鎖中。
We're getting word that the
school is still under lock down.

634
00:49:41,453 --> 00:49:43,805
而考試應該已經在幾個小時前結束了。
Now, the test should have ended hours ago.

635
00:49:43,930 --> 00:49:45,131
父母們已經越來越不安。
Parents are growing concerned

636
00:49:45,256 --> 00:49:48,810
由於學校表示，學生能離校的時間並不確定。
as the school is said to be
holding students indefinitely

637
00:49:48,935 --> 00:49:52,305
由於並未說明他們的子女安全與否。
with no word as to whether or
not their children are safe.

638
00:49:52,430 --> 00:49:57,452
那麼，州長，您對於這些擔心的選票有什麼說法？
Now, governor, what do say
to these concerned voters?

639
00:49:57,577 --> 00:50:03,139
嗯，目前我並未獲得事件的詳細情況報告。
Well, while, I don't have any
immediate details on the incident,

640
00:50:04,517 --> 00:50:08,797
但我可以說，我們有國家最好的部隊在現場
I can say that we do have the
best team in the nation on site

641
00:50:08,922 --> 00:50:13,268
任何問題和狀況，都能在最短時間內解決。
and that any problems or confusion
will be resolved shortly.

642
00:50:13,393 --> 00:50:17,564
誰能告訴我，到底學校是他媽的出了什麼事。
Somebody tell me what the hell
is going on at that school.

643
00:50:20,500 --> 00:50:21,468
比我們想像的更糟糕。
It's worse than we thought.

644
00:50:21,593 --> 00:50:22,811
給我看。
Show me.

645
00:50:22,936 --> 00:50:24,004
父母們已經等待超過兩個小時了
Parents have been waiting for over two hours

646
00:50:24,129 --> 00:50:26,773
對於他們在願景高中的孩子們
with little to no information
on what has happened

647
00:50:26,898 --> 00:50:29,184
發生的事件，只有極少的資訊透露出來。
to their children at Vista Point High.

648
00:50:29,309 --> 00:50:33,288
我們不知道孩子們究竟是通過了考試，還是沒有，或是其他狀況。
We don't know if our son passed
the test or failed or anything.

649
00:50:33,413 --> 00:50:36,858
今天對我們來說是個難熬的日子，我們需要答案。
This day is hard enough for all
of us and we deserve answers.

650
00:50:36,983 --> 00:50:38,760
這個社區經驗了煎熬的時光
This community has been through enough.

651
00:50:38,885 --> 00:50:42,497
願景高中裡的學生和他們的父母們，沒有得到任何的通知。
No parents of students at Vista
Point have been notified as of yet.

652
00:50:42,622 --> 00:50:44,925
我們會為您持續報導這一怪異事件。
We'll keep you updated
as this bizarre story.

653
00:50:45,050 --> 00:50:47,694
把康叫到緊急通訊線上。
Get King on the emergency line

654
00:50:57,370 --> 00:50:58,970
密碼卡和身份證明。
Key card and I.D.

655
00:51:04,277 --> 00:51:06,213
我是梅森‧康
This is Mason King.

656
00:51:56,429 --> 00:51:58,932
我有幾千個快氣壞了的父母們
I'm about to have a thousand
royally pissed off parents

657
00:51:59,057 --> 00:52:01,910
在高中前面的新聞廣播車，述說高中停電的消息
talking to news vans in front
of a school with no power.

658
00:52:02,035 --> 00:52:04,579
我要你向我解釋，這究竟是怎麼回事。
I need you to explain to me how
this is even remotely handled.

659
00:52:04,704 --> 00:52:05,905
電纜很快就能修復了。
The cables are nearly patched through.

660
00:52:06,030 --> 00:52:07,448
我們很快就能恢復電力。
We'll have power back shortly.

661
00:52:07,573 --> 00:52:10,910
一但電力恢復，削減計劃立即繼續，你明白嗎？
As soon as the power is on, the
thinning continues, you understand?

662
00:52:11,035 --> 00:52:12,487
全國都盯著我們在看。
The eyes of the nation are on us.

663
00:52:12,612 --> 00:52:14,047
我們沒有一丁點的犯錯空間。
We have zero room for failure.

664
00:52:14,172 --> 00:52:15,749
了解，長官。
Understood, sir.

665
00:52:15,874 --> 00:52:17,225
我們會找到她的。
We'll find her.

666
00:52:17,350 --> 00:52:18,318
我們會找到她的。
We'll find her.

667
00:52:18,443 --> 00:52:20,043
找到誰？
Find who?

668
00:52:23,589 --> 00:52:24,557
布萊克
Blake!

669
00:52:24,682 --> 00:52:26,282
布萊克！
Blake!

670
00:52:32,065 --> 00:52:33,675
布萊克，呼吸。
Blake, breathe.

671
00:52:33,800 --> 00:52:35,400
布萊克，呼吸。
Blake, breathe!

672
00:52:55,621 --> 00:52:57,999
發生了那事兒。
So that happened.

673
00:52:58,124 --> 00:52:59,724
把這穿上。
Go put these on.

674
00:53:05,631 --> 00:53:10,337
我需要請你做一位紳士，或你可以自動自發嗎？
So, am I going to have to ask you
or are you going to be a gentleman?

675
00:53:11,571 --> 00:53:13,407
我可以做一位紳士。
I'll be a gentleman.

676
00:53:28,154 --> 00:53:30,824
我需要請妳做一位淑女嗎？
Do I need to ask you to be a lady?

677
00:53:30,949 --> 00:53:32,433
抱歉。
Sorry.

678
00:53:32,558 --> 00:53:33,760
沒事。
It's all good.

679
00:53:33,885 --> 00:53:37,631
我偷瞄了妳大概三次，所以我們打平了。
I got like a three quick
peeks, so we're even.

680
00:53:39,031 --> 00:53:41,442
Ok，你現在高雅了嗎？
Okay, are you decent?

681
00:53:41,567 --> 00:53:44,738
不，但我有穿衣服。
No, but I am wearing clothes.

682
00:53:50,510 --> 00:53:54,414
那麼，我想我們該想法回到那上面去了。
So I guess we're gonna have to figure out
a way to get back up there, somehow.

683
00:53:55,548 --> 00:53:59,019
你去想辦法吧，我要進那兒去。
You do that, I'm going
to go through here.

684
00:54:02,822 --> 00:54:04,032
到底是他媽怎麼回事？
What the hell is this?

685
00:54:04,157 --> 00:54:06,126
我們通過考試了，這他媽的太鬼扯了。
We passed the test, this is bullshit.

686
00:54:06,251 --> 00:54:08,036
我要回家。
I want to go home.

687
00:54:08,161 --> 00:54:09,662
沒人告訴我們是咋回事。
No one has told us anything.

688
00:54:09,787 --> 00:54:12,040
難道我們要無期限地坐在這裡？
Are we just supposed to
sit here, indefinitely?

689
00:54:12,165 --> 00:54:14,567
事情解決前，任何人不准離開。
Nobody leaves this room
until we get the all clear.

690
00:54:14,692 --> 00:54:16,169
別指揮我要做什麼。
Don't tell me what to do.

691
00:54:16,294 --> 00:54:18,405
你知道我父母是誰嗎？
Do you have any idea
who my parents are?

692
00:54:18,530 --> 00:54:19,314
我要離開。
I'm leaving.

693
00:54:19,439 --> 00:54:21,039
退後！
Stay back!

694
00:55:00,947 --> 00:55:02,547
操。
Shit.

695
00:55:32,245 --> 00:55:33,713
我們沒辦法下去。
We can't go down there.

696
00:55:33,838 --> 00:55:36,182
他們人太多了。
There's too many of them.

697
00:55:36,307 --> 00:55:38,159
我們需要那個卡。
We need that card.

698
00:55:38,284 --> 00:55:40,220
沒那玩意兒，我們到不了電腦那裡。
I don't think we can get
to the computer without it.

699
00:55:40,345 --> 00:55:44,124
Ok，那麼，應該還有其他辦法。
Okay, well, there's
got to be another way.

700
00:55:46,692 --> 00:55:48,528
妳要去哪兒？
Where are you going?

701
00:56:02,575 --> 00:56:04,277
就是這裡了。
This is the one.

702
00:56:04,402 --> 00:56:05,645
好。
All right.

703
00:56:05,770 --> 00:56:07,370
準備好了？
You ready?

704
00:56:59,065 --> 00:57:00,665
完美。
Perfect.

705
00:57:14,213 --> 00:57:15,957
布萊克，快。
Blake, hurry.

706
00:57:17,041 --> 00:57:18,641
走，走，走。
Go, go, go.

707
00:59:17,870 --> 00:59:19,246
布萊克？
Blake?

708
00:59:19,371 --> 00:59:20,473
妳搞定那個。
You take care of that.

709
00:59:20,598 --> 00:59:22,709
我去削減處。
I'm going to the thinning.

710
00:59:34,453 --> 00:59:36,964
Ok，主要的新聞台一小時內會到達。
Okay, the major networks
should be here within the hour.

711
00:59:37,089 --> 00:59:38,357
我還是不了解您將要說什麼。
I still don't understand what you'll say.

712
00:59:38,482 --> 00:59:39,634
記者就像嗜血的鯊魚，泰德。
The press are like sharks, Ted.

713
00:59:39,759 --> 00:59:41,060
他們一聞到血，就會蜂擁而至。
They smell blood,they'll come swimming.

714
00:59:41,185 --> 00:59:45,264
我們必須給他們些鮮肉嚐。
We just need to give them some fresh meat.

715
00:59:48,501 --> 00:59:50,803
我們發現他被打得很慘。
We found him beat up pretty bad.

716
00:59:50,928 --> 00:59:53,272
你被個女孩痛扁。
You got beat up by a girl.

717
00:59:53,397 --> 00:59:55,475
不，長官，額，是的，長官。
No, sir, well, yes sir.

718
00:59:55,600 --> 00:59:57,200
他們有兩個人。
It was two of them.

719
00:59:59,912 --> 01:00:02,223
兩個女孩？
Two girls?

720
01:00:02,348 --> 01:00:03,891
不，一個是男的。
No, it was a male student.

721
01:00:04,016 --> 01:00:05,184
他們偷襲我。
They got the jump on me.

722
01:00:05,309 --> 01:00:07,854
另一個說她是老師。
The other said she was a teacher.

723
01:00:09,155 --> 01:00:11,825
那老師叫什麼名字？
What was the teacher's name?

724
01:00:22,134 --> 01:00:23,870
這太荒謬了。
This is ridiculous.

725
01:00:25,471 --> 01:00:27,741
對啊，整件事都是。
Yes, this whole thing is.

726
01:00:29,241 --> 01:00:34,221
你，我不知道，但事情結束後，我要去喝酒。
I don't know about you, but I
could use a drink after this.

727
01:00:34,346 --> 01:00:35,946
我也是。
Me too.

728
01:00:37,449 --> 01:00:40,286
妳要跟我一起喝嗎？
You want to join me for one later?

729
01:00:41,420 --> 01:00:42,830
好啊。
Sure.

730
01:00:42,955 --> 01:00:44,432
好。
Good.

731
01:00:44,557 --> 01:00:46,493
我得警告你。
I have to warn you,

732
01:00:47,593 --> 01:00:50,263
我的酒品可不太好。
I get a little handsy when I drink.

733
01:00:52,331 --> 01:00:54,434
我可以接受。
I can deal with handsy.

734
01:00:56,602 --> 01:00:58,905
那麼，放學後見？
So I'll see you after school?

735
01:00:59,030 --> 01:01:00,540
到時見。
I'll see you then.

736
01:01:00,665 --> 01:01:02,265
行。
'Kay.

737
01:01:43,000 --> 01:01:46,000
請滑動管理員卡

738
01:01:50,000 --> 01:01:53,000
登入者
梅森‧康
密碼

739
01:01:54,894 --> 01:01:56,494
操。
Shit.

740
01:02:02,401 --> 01:02:04,545
凱倫。
Kellan.

741
01:02:09,000 --> 01:02:14,500
你必須幫幫我..... 我要一段梅森‧康登入的視頻，盡快，拜託，我全指望你了。

742
01:02:14,500 --> 01:02:16,000
訊息送出
凱倫離線狀態

743
01:02:16,282 --> 01:02:17,882
快啊。
Come on.

744
01:02:22,221 --> 01:02:23,890
博爾奇小姐，是嗎？
Miss Birch, right?

745
01:02:25,024 --> 01:02:27,260
讓我們繼續之前的事吧。
Let's continue where we left off.

746
01:02:27,385 --> 01:02:28,985
密碼卡和身份證。
Key card and I.D.

747
01:02:39,672 --> 01:02:41,272
很好。
Very well.

748
01:02:46,312 --> 01:02:47,912
密碼卡和身份證。
Key card and I.D.

749
01:02:53,218 --> 01:02:55,529
我一定是弄丟了。
I must have dropped it.

750
01:02:55,654 --> 01:02:57,590
不對，我想不是。
No, I don't think so.

751
01:02:58,657 --> 01:03:00,192
抱歉，這肯定是個錯誤。
Excuse me, this is a mistake.

752
01:03:00,317 --> 01:03:01,917
所有人離開。
Everybody out.

753
01:03:08,067 --> 01:03:10,336
兩秒前它還在。
I had it two seconds ago.

754
01:03:11,971 --> 01:03:13,506
她在哪？
Where is she?

755
01:03:13,631 --> 01:03:15,231
誰？
Who?

756
01:03:18,978 --> 01:03:20,578
我不知道你在說誰。
I don't know who you're talking about.

757
01:03:23,841 --> 01:03:25,059
斷了。
I'm broke.

758
01:03:25,184 --> 01:03:26,784
這是最後一次我禮貌地問你。
This is the last time
that I'll ask nicely.

759
01:03:27,845 --> 01:03:29,445
萊娜在哪？
Where's Laina?

760
01:03:50,000 --> 01:03:52,500
你必須幫幫我..... 我要一段梅森‧康登入的視頻，盡快，拜託，我全指望你了。

761
01:03:55,014 --> 01:03:56,614
老天，是萊娜。
Oh my god, Laina.

762
01:04:15,500 --> 01:04:17,614
我希望妳知道妳在做什麼。

763
01:04:44,000 --> 01:04:46,000
搜尋學生: 柯琳‧麥可司

764
01:04:46,000 --> 01:04:52,500
搜尋學生: 柯琳‧麥可司
成績: 86% 通過

765
01:04:52,500 --> 01:05:02,000
搜尋學生: 萊娜‧麥可司

766
01:05:02,000 --> 01:05:03,000
搜尋學生: 柯琳‧麥可司
成績: 98% 不及格

767
01:05:03,000 --> 01:05:07,000
偉德‧弗瑞門
成績: 42% 通過

768
01:05:07,000 --> 01:05:10,000
布萊克‧瑞丁
成績: 15% 通過

769
01:05:14,000 --> 01:05:19,000
愛莉‧哈波
成績: 88% 不及格

770
01:05:27,806 --> 01:05:31,544
我們現有的資料是，今天上午大約11點45分
All the information we have as of now
is this morning, approximately 11:45am,

771
01:05:31,669 --> 01:05:36,780
願景高中的學生，萊娜‧麥可司考試未通過
Laina Michaels, a student at Vista
Point High, failed an exam.

772
01:05:37,783 --> 01:05:40,352
然後她攻擊了數名安全警衛，
She then proceeded to
attack several DPC officers,

773
01:05:40,477 --> 01:05:44,298
兩名受傷，另兩名不幸死亡。
injuring two and tragically
killing two others.

774
01:05:44,423 --> 01:05:46,092
從那時開始，學生們被移往，
Since then, the
students have been moved

775
01:05:46,217 --> 01:05:50,296
一個安全的處所，由老師們保護著
to a safe place and are being protected
under the watchful eye of our teachers

776
01:05:50,421 --> 01:05:53,340
直到逮捕到麥可司小姐。
until Miss Michaels can be apprehended.

777
01:05:53,465 --> 01:05:55,101
柯琳，需要送妳回家嗎？
Corinne, do you need a ride home?

778
01:05:55,226 --> 01:05:59,238
我以一個父親的身份對你們說。
I would like to speak to you as a father.

779
01:05:59,363 --> 01:06:00,147
來吧。
Come on.

780
01:06:00,272 --> 01:06:02,282
我理解你們的心情。
I understand your pain.

781
01:06:02,407 --> 01:06:04,551
我兒子也在學校裡面。
My son is in that school as well.

782
01:06:04,676 --> 01:06:09,415
我會盡我的一切能力，把他和所有人都安全送回家。
And I will do everything in my power to
bring him and everyone else home safe.

783
01:06:10,582 --> 01:06:12,752
布萊克，如果你在看，
Blake, if you're watching,

784
01:06:14,586 --> 01:06:16,186
我愛你，兒子。
I love you son.

785
01:06:19,158 --> 01:06:21,568
這是個考驗我們所有人的時刻。
This is a trying time for all of us.

786
01:06:21,693 --> 01:06:25,305
我們在努力解決事情，要把麥可司小姐繩之以法的同時，
I ask for your patience and understanding
as we move to resolve this matter

787
01:06:25,430 --> 01:06:26,866
我請求你們要有耐心，並且給予我們諒解。
and bring Miss Michaels to justice.

788
01:06:26,991 --> 01:06:29,402
溫蒂，妳得來看看這個。
Wendy, you need to see this.

789
01:06:32,371 --> 01:06:34,173
這是來自學校內部的。
This was taken from
inside the high school.

790
01:06:34,298 --> 01:06:37,610
對，毫無疑問，這是安全警衛在打通過考試的學生。
Yeah, that's definitely a DPC
guard hitting a passing student.

791
01:06:37,735 --> 01:06:39,311
說不通啊。
This doesn't add up.

792
01:06:39,436 --> 01:06:41,714
這個來源是誰？
Who's the source on this?

793
01:06:46,800 --> 01:06:49,500
-凱倫
幹得好！這是我的直接專線，
將會播出你找到的所有資料。
-溫蒂

794
01:06:51,223 --> 01:06:56,103
這視頻是個學生給我們的，源自願景高中內部。
This footage was sent to us by a student
source inside Vista Point High.

795
01:06:56,228 --> 01:06:57,828
凱倫？
Kellan?

796
01:07:20,452 --> 01:07:21,595
Hello.

797
01:07:21,720 --> 01:07:23,355
所有單位趕去伺服器室。
All units converge to the server room.

798
01:07:23,480 --> 01:07:25,080
我們找到她了。
We have her.

799
01:07:46,445 --> 01:07:47,621
注意。
Attention.

800
01:07:47,746 --> 01:07:51,725
我剛收到立刻把這些學生轉到休息廳的命令。
I was just told to move these students
to the recreation hall immediately.

801
01:07:51,850 --> 01:07:53,586
我沒收到。
I didn't hear that.

802
01:07:53,711 --> 01:07:58,465
除非梅森‧康有命令，否則這些學生就得待在這裡。
The students are staying until
Mason King says otherwise.

803
01:07:58,590 --> 01:08:02,903
我剛收到把所有人轉移到休息廳的命令，不得延誤。
I was just told to take everyone to the
recreation hall without any hold ups.

804
01:08:03,028 --> 01:08:04,296
所以，開始行動。
So, let's get moving.

805
01:08:04,421 --> 01:08:06,021
解除禁制。
Undo the restraints.

806
01:08:07,899 --> 01:08:11,971
不行，沒有梅森‧康的直接命令，什麼事都不許做。
No, we do don't do anything without
direct confirmation from Mason King.

807
01:08:12,096 --> 01:08:13,873
表明你的身份，馬上。
Identify yourself now.

808
01:08:15,040 --> 01:08:15,916
當然。
Of course.

809
01:08:16,041 --> 01:08:17,843
抱歉，我給你看證件。
I'm sorry, let me show
you the confirmation.

810
01:08:19,278 --> 01:08:20,878
他不是警衛！
He's not a guard!

811
01:08:39,431 --> 01:08:40,941
我有證據。
I have proof.

812
01:08:41,066 --> 01:08:42,468
我通過了考試。
I passed that test.

813
01:08:42,593 --> 01:08:44,670
恭喜。
Congratulations.

814
01:08:53,879 --> 01:08:55,982
把她帶去削減處。
Take her to the thinning.

815
01:09:04,500 --> 01:09:12,000
他們不相信我。
你是我唯一信任的，能解決這件事的人。
如果壞事發生了，請你保護柯琳和喬伊的安全。
-萊娜

816
01:09:25,077 --> 01:09:26,677
我操。
Holy shit.

817
01:09:39,958 --> 01:09:40,592
好，壓制他。
Good, get him down.

818
01:09:40,717 --> 01:09:42,703
拿掉他的面罩。
Get his mask.

819
01:09:47,499 --> 01:09:49,977
我不管視頻從哪來的，我們要立刻時況播出。
I don't care where you pull the
graphics from, we're going live now.

820
01:09:50,102 --> 01:09:52,012
溫蒂，這還沒有經過公司的允許。
Wendy, this hasn't been
approved by the network.

821
01:09:52,137 --> 01:09:53,339
卡爾，所以這才叫突發性重大新聞。
Karl, it's called
breaking news for a reason.

822
01:09:53,464 --> 01:09:55,608
我們開始，馬上。
We're going with this, now.

823
01:09:58,410 --> 01:10:00,520
3, 2
Three, two.

824
01:10:18,997 --> 01:10:20,666
不，不，別抓萊娜。
No, no, not Laina.

825
01:10:25,103 --> 01:10:28,107
不到一小時前，瑞丁州長宣佈了一個狀況
Less than an hour ago, Governor
Redding announced a situation

826
01:10:28,232 --> 01:10:32,978
願景高中內部，有一個未通過考試的危險學生，萊娜‧麥可司
inside Vista Point High involving a
dangerous failed student, Laina Michaels,

827
01:10:33,103 --> 01:10:38,417
她大肆破壞校園，製造多起恐怖事件。
said to be wreaking havoc on campus
leaving behind her a trail of terror.

828
01:10:50,128 --> 01:10:52,464
就在剛剛，我們收到了官方的證據資料
Just moments ago, we received
official documentation

829
01:10:52,589 --> 01:10:57,044
顯示學校內部，對於考試成績作假，
from inside the high school
revealing falsified test scores,

830
01:10:57,169 --> 01:11:02,942
對於可能的特定學生，讓其避免受到削減
possibly to favor or target specific
students to evade or endure the thinning.

831
01:11:04,476 --> 01:11:06,953
受到錯誤指控其未通過考試，
Among those wrongfully
accused of failing the exam,

832
01:11:07,078 --> 01:11:10,590
萊娜‧麥可司，其實是學校中最高分的幾名學生之一。
Laina Michaels, received one of
the highest scores in the school.

833
01:11:10,715 --> 01:11:13,060
布萊克‧瑞丁，迪恩‧瑞丁州長之子
Blake Redding, son of
governor Dean Redding

834
01:11:13,185 --> 01:11:17,990
是願景高中得分最低者，卻獲得了通過。
passed the exam, despite having the
lowest score at Vista Point High.

835
01:11:22,794 --> 01:11:23,904
嗨。
Hi.

836
01:11:24,029 --> 01:11:25,939
你不是說情況已經控制住了？
I thought you said that you had
the situation under control.

837
01:11:26,064 --> 01:11:26,765
額，情況改變了。
Well, the situation's changing.

838
01:11:26,890 --> 01:11:27,941
沒錯。
Yes it has.

839
01:11:28,066 --> 01:11:29,935
我開始覺得我騎錯馬了。
I'm starting to think I
backed the wrong horse.

840
01:11:30,060 --> 01:11:32,905
山道沃眾議員可不是為了來攪這些麻煩的。
Congressman Sandoval doesn't come
with these kinds of problems.

841
01:11:33,030 --> 01:11:33,814
喬吉娜。
Georgina.

842
01:11:33,939 --> 01:11:35,048
別叫我。
Don't Georgina me.

843
01:11:35,173 --> 01:11:37,684
把事情搞定，否則你的資金就沒了。
Fix it or you won't have enough
money to run for city comptroller.

844
01:11:37,809 --> 01:11:40,479
這個爆炸性的發展，
This explosive development calls everything

845
01:11:40,604 --> 01:11:43,449
把今天州長辦公室說的一切事情，都加上了問號。
said today by the governor's
office into question

846
01:11:43,574 --> 01:11:46,552
並顯示一個極大的醜聞正在上演。
and reveals a larger scandal at play.

847
01:11:50,121 --> 01:11:51,898
這下糟了。
This is bad.

848
01:11:52,023 --> 01:11:52,933
這下糟了。
This is bad.

849
01:11:53,058 --> 01:11:55,060
你必須要把事情結束掉。
You got to shut it down.

850
01:11:56,228 --> 01:11:59,632
迪恩，沒戲了，你必須放那女孩走。
Dean, it's over, you
got to let the girl go.

851
01:12:00,799 --> 01:12:02,468
你必須把事情結束，立刻。
You need to shut this down, right now.

852
01:12:02,593 --> 01:12:05,604
他媽的，迪恩，你聽到我說的了嗎？
Goddammit, Dean, are
you listening to me?

853
01:12:05,729 --> 01:12:07,714
結束了。
It's over.

854
01:12:07,839 --> 01:12:09,675
沒棋可走了。
There's no more moves.

855
01:12:12,544 --> 01:12:15,155
還有一步棋。
There's one more move.

856
01:12:15,280 --> 01:12:17,591
不，拜託。
No, please.

857
01:12:17,716 --> 01:12:19,316
不，不！
No, no!

858
01:12:26,725 --> 01:12:29,228
長官，一切都在控制下了。
Sir, everything is in order.

859
01:12:30,629 --> 01:12:34,467
一如往常，我需要你的指示讓它成為正式的官方命令。
As always, I need the word
from you to make it official.

860
01:12:35,700 --> 01:12:39,104
我們允許開始消減行動了嗎？
Are we approved to commence the thinning?

861
01:12:41,773 --> 01:12:45,911
長官，我們允許開始消減行動了嗎？
Sir, are we approved to commence the thinning?

862
01:12:46,036 --> 01:12:47,636
不。
No.

863
01:12:49,681 --> 01:12:51,517
要做些改變。
There's been a change.

864
01:12:52,851 --> 01:12:54,586
我們需要更正名單。
We need to revise the list.

865
01:12:54,711 --> 01:12:55,662
長官？
Sir?

866
01:12:55,787 --> 01:12:58,224
這是命令。
That's an order.

867
01:13:19,778 --> 01:13:24,283
所有被釋放的學生，可以自由去休息廳。
All released students are free
to proceed to the recreation hall.

868
01:13:24,408 --> 01:13:27,753
恭喜，你通過了。
Congratulations, you've passed.

869
01:13:42,701 --> 01:13:44,301
照新名單執行。
Round them up.

870
01:13:48,640 --> 01:13:49,608
怎麼回事？
What's going on?

871
01:13:49,733 --> 01:13:50,609
走。
Let's go.

872
01:13:50,734 --> 01:13:51,518
布萊克。
Blake.

873
01:13:51,643 --> 01:13:52,611
布萊克，現在是怎麼了？
Blake what's happening?

874
01:13:52,736 --> 01:13:53,520
沒關係。
It's okay.

875
01:13:53,645 --> 01:13:54,521
不，怎麼一回事？
No, what's going on?

876
01:13:54,646 --> 01:13:55,314
沒關係，是我做的。
It's okay, I did this.

877
01:13:55,439 --> 01:13:56,315
把她弄出去。
Get her out of here.

878
01:13:56,440 --> 01:13:57,224
布萊克，不要！
Blake, no!

879
01:13:57,349 --> 01:13:58,317
把她弄出去！
Get her out of here!

880
01:13:58,442 --> 01:14:00,961
放開我，不！
Put me down, no!

881
01:14:01,086 --> 01:14:02,087
讓開。
Out of the way.

882
01:14:02,212 --> 01:14:04,097
偉德‧佛瑞門，該走了。
Wade Freeman, time to go.

883
01:14:04,222 --> 01:14:05,265
放開我，兄弟。
Get off me, bro.

884
01:14:05,390 --> 01:14:07,125
兄弟，那是我投球的手臂，兄弟。
Bro, that's my throwing arm, bro.

885
01:14:07,250 --> 01:14:08,760
你知道我是誰嗎？
Do you know who I am?

886
01:14:08,885 --> 01:14:11,196
偉德‧佛瑞門，你個臭婊子。
Wade Freeman, you bitch.

887
01:15:55,734 --> 01:15:56,544
都結束了。
It's all over.

888
01:15:56,669 --> 01:15:58,645
學校的封鎖柵升起來了。
The school-wide lock
down has been lifted

889
01:15:58,770 --> 01:16:00,439
在經過這奧斯丁市，艱辛漫長的一天之後，
and passing students have been reunited

890
01:16:00,564 --> 01:16:05,744
通過考試的學生們再度與他們的家人團聚。
with their loved ones after what has
been a long, trying day, here in Austin.

891
01:16:18,156 --> 01:16:21,460
一如既往，我們的心也應該與那些分數敬陪末座
As always, our hearts go out to the
families of the failing students

892
01:16:21,585 --> 01:16:24,137
未通過考試的學生的家人們在一起。
who scored in the lowest percentile.

893
01:16:24,262 --> 01:16:27,466
安全警衛的隊長，梅森‧康，已經被逮捕接受偵訊。
The head of the DPC, Mason King,
has been taken in for questioning

894
01:16:27,591 --> 01:16:30,343
釐清他和變更考試結果之間的關聯。
in connection with the
altered test scores.

895
01:16:30,468 --> 01:16:34,147
我對於梅森‧康的犯罪行為非常驚愕。
I am appalled by the alleged
criminal action of Mr. King.

896
01:16:34,272 --> 01:16:36,642
明天早晨，我被指派為特別委員
As of tomorrow morning, I am
appointing a special committee

897
01:16:36,767 --> 01:16:40,420
去徹底調查願景高中到底發生了什麼事。
to fully investigate what
really happened at Vista Point.

898
01:16:40,545 --> 01:16:44,124
如果梅森‧康先生有罪，他將會為他的罪行付出代價。
If Mr. King is guilty, he will
dearly pay for his unlawful actions.

899
01:16:44,249 --> 01:16:46,351
早期的報告顯示出
Earlier reports indicating
a scandal involving

900
01:16:46,476 --> 01:16:48,695
瑞丁州長也涉入了考試結果造假的醜聞。
Governor Redding
falsifying test information

901
01:16:48,820 --> 01:16:51,223
使得他這位極有希望當選總統的人，名譽掃地。
were discredited when the
presidential hopeful revealed

902
01:16:51,348 --> 01:16:55,494
他的兒子布萊克，也是未通過考試的學生之一。
his son Blake was among this
year's failing students.

903
01:16:55,619 --> 01:16:58,230
我的兒子，雖然我是如此地愛他，
My son, as much as I love him,

904
01:17:00,031 --> 01:17:04,411
但他與你們任何一位的兒女，並無不同。
is no different than any
of your sons or daughters.

905
01:17:04,536 --> 01:17:06,238
我不是個虛假的人。
I'm not a hypocrite.

906
01:17:07,338 --> 01:17:09,749
法律之前，人人平等。
The laws apply to all of us.

907
01:17:09,874 --> 01:17:12,811
對我來說，那並不比任何人容易。
It just doesn't make it any easier.

908
01:17:15,313 --> 01:17:16,982
今天我失去了我的兒子。
I lost my son today.

909
01:17:20,084 --> 01:17:24,256
但我心中明白，他的死，是為了一個目標。
But I know in my heart
that he died for a purpose.

910
01:17:25,824 --> 01:17:27,359
所有沉淪的學生們，都是為了一個終極目的而犧牲。
All of our fallen students have
made the ultimate sacrifice

911
01:17:27,484 --> 01:17:30,395
為了確保能有一個更美好的明天。
in the name of ensuring
a better tomorrow

912
01:17:30,520 --> 01:17:33,832
那使得美國的未來更光明。
and in keeping America's future bright.

913
01:17:38,403 --> 01:17:42,775
我要為了感謝他們的勇氣而默哀。
I'd like to take a moment and
thank them for their courage.

914
01:17:58,590 --> 01:18:00,467
停住。
Hold it.

915
01:18:00,592 --> 01:18:02,192
Ok，一切安全。
Okay, they're all clear.

916
01:18:05,000 --> 01:18:09,000
危險
通電鐵絲網

