1
00:04:25,800 --> 00:04:27,650
早上好 詹姆斯
Good Morning, James!

2
00:04:27,670 --> 00:04:29,250
您感覺怎么樣
How're you feeling?

3
00:04:29,280 --> 00:04:30,590
等下 什么鬼
Wait, what?

4
00:04:30,610 --> 00:04:33,340
您現在感到疑惑很正常
It's perfectly normal to feel confused.

5
00:04:33,360 --> 00:04:37,160
您剛從120年的休眠中醒來
You've just spent a 120 years in suspended animation.

6
00:04:37,810 --> 00:04:38,890
什么
What?

7
00:04:38,910 --> 00:04:40,820
沒關系的 詹姆斯
It's okay, James.

8
00:04:40,850 --> 00:04:41,960
我叫吉姆
It's Jim.

9
00:04:41,980 --> 00:04:43,370
吉姆
Jim.

10
00:04:43,790 --> 00:04:45,440
深呼吸
Just breathe.

11
00:04:45,470 --> 00:04:46,960
一切正常
Everything is okay.

12
00:04:46,980 --> 00:04:48,110
我在哪
Where am I?

13
00:04:48,140 --> 00:04:50,320
您是星際飛船阿瓦隆號上的一名乘客
You're a passenger on the Starship Avalon.

14
00:04:50,340 --> 00:04:54,130
這是新家園公司的首架星際班機
The Homestead Company's premier interstellar star liner.

15
00:04:55,180 --> 00:04:59,100
此次從地球啟航的遠行即將結束 將抵達您的新家園
We've nearly completed the voyage from Earth to your new home,

16
00:04:59,120 --> 00:05:02,020
殖民行星 新家園Ⅱ號
the colony world of Homestead Ⅱ.

17
00:05:02,300 --> 00:05:03,540
一個全新的世界
A new world.

18
00:05:03,570 --> 00:05:05,050
全新的開始
A fresh start.

19
00:05:05,080 --> 00:05:06,880
成長的空間
Room to grow.

20
00:05:06,910 --> 00:05:08,250
好美
Oh, yeah.

21
00:05:08,280 --> 00:05:10,410
阿瓦隆號就快落地了
The Avalon is on final approach.

22
00:05:10,440 --> 00:05:12,780
在接下來的四個月中 請您盡情享受
For the next 4 months, you'll enjoy space travel

23
00:05:12,800 --> 00:05:15,050
奢華的星際旅行
at it's most luxurious.

24
00:05:15,070 --> 00:05:17,740
我們有美食 樂趣 朋友
Food. Fun. Friends.

25
00:05:17,760 --> 00:05:18,930
我的朋友們
My friends.

26
00:05:18,960 --> 00:05:20,450
是的 吉姆
That's right, Jim.

27
00:05:20,470 --> 00:05:22,160
您的身份手環在您的手腕上
The I.D. Band on your wrist

28
00:05:22,160 --> 00:05:24,730
身份手環可以帶您進入阿瓦隆的各個房間
is your key to the wonders of the Avalon.

29
00:05:26,200 --> 00:05:28,110
您很健康 吉姆
You're in perfect health, Jim.

30
00:05:28,140 --> 00:05:31,280
現在請您去您的客艙休息一下吧
Let's get you to your cabin where you can get some rest.

31
00:05:38,500 --> 00:05:42,580
您可能還有一些休眠后遺癥
You maybe experiencing post-hibernation sickness.

32
00:05:43,710 --> 00:05:46,210
您的房門會自動亮起
Your door will illuminate for you.

33
00:05:49,270 --> 00:05:50,700
歡迎來到您的客艙
Welcome to your cabin.

34
00:05:50,730 --> 00:05:53,090
降落之前 這里就是您暫時的家了
Your home until we make landfall.

35
00:05:53,110 --> 00:05:54,510
在接下來的四個月中
Over the next 4 months,

36
00:05:54,510 --> 00:05:57,500
您可以為您在新家園Ⅱ號的新生活做準備
you'll prepare for your new life on Homestead Ⅱ.

37
00:05:57,520 --> 00:06:00,610
見見同行旅客 參加技能培訓
Meet you fellow passengers, take skill building classes

38
00:06:00,640 --> 00:06:03,010
學會如何在殖民行星生活
and learn about colonial living.

39
00:06:03,220 --> 00:06:05,630
您和其他工程師以及技術貿易人員
You've been assigned to Learning group 38,

40
00:06:05,660 --> 00:06:09,010
被分配到了38號學習小組
for passengers with engineering and technical trade skills.

41
00:06:09,030 --> 00:06:12,110
請掃描您的身份手環來領取您的行李
Please scan your I.D. To confirm luggage delivery.

42
00:06:13,000 --> 00:06:17,600
吉姆 請掃描您的身份手環來領取您的行李
Jim, please scan your I.D. To confirm luggage delivery.

43
00:06:21,850 --> 00:06:24,320
為了幫助您從休眠狀態恢復過來
To help you recover from hibernation,

44
00:06:24,320 --> 00:06:26,590
請您多喝水
be sure to drink plenty of fluids.

45
00:06:27,990 --> 00:06:30,720
愿您在阿瓦隆號新家園公司星際飛船
Enjoy the rest of your voyage on the Avalon,

46
00:06:30,740 --> 00:06:33,560
度過一段愉快的旅程
a Homestead Company Starship.

47
00:06:35,460 --> 00:06:36,800
各位早上好
Good morning one and all.

48
00:06:36,830 --> 00:06:39,630
又是個在阿瓦隆號上美好的早晨
It's a beautiful morning here on the Starship Avalon.

49
00:06:39,650 --> 00:06:42,390
無論怎樣 請不要想家 這兒就是新家
Whatever you do don't get homesick, get Homestead.

50
00:06:42,420 --> 00:06:45,600
讓我們先來聽首我以前在地球上最喜歡的歌吧
Let start things off with one of my favorite back on Earth.

51
00:06:51,740 --> 00:06:53,340
不行
No.

52
00:06:56,210 --> 00:06:57,250
太蠢了
It's stupid.

53
00:07:01,520 --> 00:07:04,990
叫我吉姆就好 我有一件酷酷的夾克
Just call me... call me Jim. You got a cool jacket.

54
00:07:18,930 --> 00:07:20,990
乘客們 您們好
Hello, Passengers.

55
00:07:21,240 --> 00:07:23,920
大家請坐
Will you all please take a seat.

56
00:07:24,520 --> 00:07:27,110
歡迎大家 38號學習小組的成員們
Welcome, Learning group 38.

57
00:07:27,140 --> 00:07:30,460
接下來給您做殖民行星生活簡介
Your introduction to colonial life.

58
00:07:30,690 --> 00:07:32,730
地球是一個繁榮的星球
Earth is a prosperous planet.

59
00:07:32,750 --> 00:07:34,900
它是文明的發源地
The cradle of civilization.

60
00:07:34,930 --> 00:07:40,470
但同時 地球有人口過剩 生活成本增加 能力被高估等問題
But for many, it's also overpopulated. Over-priced. Overrated.

61
00:07:40,490 --> 00:07:43,090
抱歉 我覺得我可能來錯房間了
I'm sorry, I think I maybe in the wrong...

62
00:07:43,120 --> 00:07:44,930
- 請在介紹結束之后問問題 - 抱歉
- Hold all questions till the end, please. - Oh, sorry.

63
00:07:44,960 --> 00:07:47,550
殖民行星給了我們另一個選擇
The Colonies offer an alternative.

64
00:07:47,580 --> 00:07:49,340
- 一個更好的生活 - 其他人在哪
- A better way of life. - Where are all the other...

65
00:07:49,370 --> 00:07:53,770
新家園Ⅱ號是所有殖民行星中最美麗的行星
And there's no colony more beautiful than Homestead Ⅱ,

66
00:07:53,790 --> 00:07:57,220
- 殖民世界的珍寶 - 抱歉
- the Jewel of the Occupied Worlds. - I'm sorry.

67
00:07:57,400 --> 00:07:59,000
其他人都在哪里
Where IS everybody?

68
00:07:59,030 --> 00:08:01,110
我們都在阿瓦隆星際飛船上
We're all on the Starship Avalon.

69
00:08:01,140 --> 00:08:02,490
但這兒就我一個人啊
But I'm the only one here.

70
00:08:02,520 --> 00:08:07,170
這里一共有5000名乘客和258名乘務員
There are 5,000 passengers and 258 crew members.

71
00:08:07,200 --> 00:08:08,940
那我怎么一個人
So why am I alone?

72
00:08:08,970 --> 00:08:11,460
我們同在這里
We're all in this together.

73
00:08:13,160 --> 00:08:14,770
有人嗎
Hello?

74
00:08:15,950 --> 00:08:17,720
有人在嗎
Anybody here?

75
00:08:17,740 --> 00:08:19,300
有人嗎
Hello?

76
00:08:30,090 --> 00:08:33,150
請系好安全帶 并縛緊所有松動的部分
Please buckle up and secure any loose items.

77
00:08:33,170 --> 00:08:37,350
乘坐此部電梯會經歷一小會兒的失重
This elevator will experience a momentary lapse in gravity.

78
00:08:59,950 --> 00:09:01,970
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

79
00:09:16,730 --> 00:09:20,670
您好 歡迎來到阿瓦隆號的中央大廳 我能幫助您嗎
Hello.Welcome to the Grand Concourse aboard the Avalon, can I help you?

80
00:09:21,120 --> 00:09:23,200
我要和人說話
I need to talk to a person.

81
00:09:23,350 --> 00:09:24,810
一個大活人 拜托了
A real live person, please.

82
00:09:24,830 --> 00:09:27,840
什么樣的人呢 私人教練 旅行計劃員 還是理療師
What sort of person? Personal trainer? Travel planner? Therapist?

83
00:09:27,860 --> 00:09:30,260
我也不知道 管事的人
I don't know. Somebody in charge.

84
00:09:30,280 --> 00:09:32,460
您指飛船乘務處理處吧
The Ship Steward handles passenger affairs.

85
00:09:32,460 --> 00:09:34,430
位于中央大廳三層
It's on level 3 of the Grand Concourse.

86
00:09:34,450 --> 00:09:36,530
- 謝謝 - 非常樂意為您服務
- Thank you. - Happy to help!

87
00:09:41,940 --> 00:09:43,200
糟糕
Not good.

88
00:09:43,230 --> 00:09:44,730
- 你好 - 誰在操控飛船
- Hello! - Who's flying the ship?

89
00:09:44,760 --> 00:09:47,200
機組人員 機長 飛行員 首席駕駛員
The flight crew, the Captain, the Pilot, the Chief Navigator...

90
00:09:47,230 --> 00:09:48,750
我要見機長
I want to speak to the Captain.

91
00:09:48,780 --> 00:09:50,540
機長通常不直接受理乘客的問題
The Captain rarely handles passenger queries directly.

92
00:09:50,560 --> 00:09:53,250
緊急事件 拜托了
It's an emergency, please.

93
00:09:53,280 --> 00:09:56,700
機長通常在控制中心的連接橋上
The Captain is usually found on the Bridge, in the Command Ring.

94
00:10:06,840 --> 00:10:10,330
通過連接橋需要特別授權
Bridge access requires special authorization.

95
00:10:11,980 --> 00:10:15,760
通過連接橋需要特殊授權
Bridge access requires special authorization.

96
00:10:17,770 --> 00:10:19,820
開什么玩笑
You got to be kidding me.

97
00:10:33,490 --> 00:10:36,080
歡迎來到瞭望臺
Welcome to the Observatory.

98
00:10:37,580 --> 00:10:39,590
您想看什么
What can I show you?

99
00:10:40,290 --> 00:10:42,640
我們不是快降落了嗎
We're supposed to land soon,

100
00:10:45,290 --> 00:10:48,160
但只有我一個人醒來了
I'm... I'm the only one awake.

101
00:10:48,190 --> 00:10:51,790
我不明白 您想看點什么
I don't understand. What can I show you?

102
00:10:52,410 --> 00:10:53,750
給我看新家園Ⅱ號
Show me Homestead Ⅱ.

103
00:10:53,770 --> 00:10:57,150
新家園Ⅱ號是巴克蒂星系的第四顆行星
Homestead Ⅱ is the 4th planet in the Bhakti system.

104
00:10:57,180 --> 00:10:59,320
好吧 我們現在在哪
Right. And where are we?

105
00:10:59,350 --> 00:11:02,510
我們還在從地球到新家園Ⅱ號的路上
We're in transit from Earth to Homestead Ⅱ.

106
00:11:02,550 --> 00:11:06,020
- 我們大約于90年后到達 - 什么
- We will arrive in approximately 90 years. - What?

107
00:11:06,040 --> 00:11:10,350
我們將在90年3周1天后到達新家園Ⅱ號
We arrive at Homestead Ⅱ in 90 years, 3 weeks and 1 day.

108
00:11:10,380 --> 00:11:12,840
什么 我們離開地球多久了
No. Wait. How long ago did we leave Earth?

109
00:11:12,860 --> 00:11:16,050
大約三十年
Approximately 30 years ago.

110
00:11:19,450 --> 00:11:21,470
我醒得太早了
I woke up too soon.

111
00:11:24,020 --> 00:11:25,180
您好
Hello.

112
00:11:25,200 --> 00:11:26,740
我怎么向地球發信息
How do I send a message to Earth?

113
00:11:26,760 --> 00:11:29,460
星際信息將由激光發送
Interstellar messages are sent by laser array.

114
00:11:29,460 --> 00:11:31,160
這項服務很貴
This is an expensive service.

115
00:11:31,190 --> 00:11:33,490
- 有本事咬我啊 - 非常樂意為您服務
- Bite me. - Happy to help!

116
00:11:35,580 --> 00:11:36,910
您要聯絡的星球和聯絡人是
Planet and connection?

117
00:11:36,930 --> 00:11:38,930
地球 新家園公司
Earth. The HomeStead Company.

118
00:11:38,960 --> 00:11:43,520
新家園公司有30826位聯系人
There are 30,826 contacts listed under HomeStead Company?

119
00:11:43,520 --> 00:11:47,060
我是新家園Ⅱ號的移民 這里有緊急情況
I'm emigrating to Homestead Ⅱ and I have an emergency.

120
00:11:47,060 --> 00:11:49,830
- 我找到一個客服熱線 - 就它了
- I have a Customer Help Line. - Sounds about right.

121
00:11:49,850 --> 00:11:51,560
開始錄制信息
Begin message.

122
00:11:52,020 --> 00:11:54,950
嗨 我是吉姆 普勒斯頓
Hi. I'm Jim Preston.

123
00:11:55,520 --> 00:11:57,600
我是阿瓦隆號上的一名乘客
I'm a passenger on the Avalon.

124
00:11:57,950 --> 00:11:59,390
我
I uh...

125
00:12:02,240 --> 00:12:04,970
我覺得我的休眠艙出問題了
I think something went wrong with my hibernation pod.

126
00:12:05,000 --> 00:12:06,660
我醒早了
I woke up too soon.

127
00:12:06,680 --> 00:12:10,350
醒得太早了
And I mean... way too soon.

128
00:12:10,380 --> 00:12:13,210
就我一個人醒了
Nobody else is awake. And...

129
00:12:13,590 --> 00:12:15,450
我不知道怎么再回到休眠狀態
I don't know how to get back to sleep.

130
00:12:15,480 --> 00:12:18,870
問題是 還有90年才降落
And the thing is, there's 90 years to go.

131
00:12:21,930 --> 00:12:24,470
照這個速度下去 我
At this rate, I'm...

132
00:12:28,100 --> 00:12:30,560
抱歉 我在試著找到底出了什么問題
I'm sorry, I'm trying to fix this. I...

133
00:12:30,580 --> 00:12:33,410
或許我遺漏了什么 我需要幫助
Maybe I missed something. I could use a hand.

134
00:12:34,210 --> 00:12:35,800
就這樣
That's all.

135
00:12:36,680 --> 00:12:38,200
謝謝
Thank you.

136
00:12:38,920 --> 00:12:40,780
信息已發送
Message sent.

137
00:12:42,640 --> 00:12:43,600
真棒
Outstanding.

138
00:12:43,630 --> 00:12:47,120
- 信息將會在19年后到達 - 什么
- Message will arrive in 19 years. - Wait, what?

139
00:12:47,150 --> 00:12:51,800
- 最快您將在55年后到收到回復 - 55年
- Earliest reply in 55 years. - 55 years.

140
00:12:52,160 --> 00:12:54,360
給您帶來了不便很抱歉
We apologize for the delay.

141
00:12:54,380 --> 00:12:57,260
總共6012美金
That will be $6012 dollars.

142
00:13:10,950 --> 00:13:12,860
- 下午好 - 我的天啊
- Afternoon. - Oh man.

143
00:13:12,890 --> 00:13:15,220
還能見到個人簡直太好了
It's good to see another face.

144
00:13:15,250 --> 00:13:16,810
我以為就我一個人醒著
I thought I was the only one awake!

145
00:13:16,840 --> 00:13:20,070
誰要在這么好的時候睡覺啊
Who want's to sleep on a beautiful day like this?

146
00:13:20,090 --> 00:13:23,260
我的意思是我們遇到麻煩了 我們不應該在這的
Oh, I mean we're in trouble, we're not suppose to be here.

147
00:13:23,290 --> 00:13:25,320
你不想的話我不會說出去的
Well, I won't tell if you don't.

148
00:13:25,660 --> 00:13:27,990
- 什么 - 我們之間的小秘密
- Huh? - Our little secret.

149
00:13:29,430 --> 00:13:31,370
喝點什么嗎
What can I get for you?

150
00:13:31,400 --> 00:13:34,470
- 什么 - 你看起來像是喜歡喝威士忌的
- What? - You look like a whiskey man.

151
00:13:34,490 --> 00:13:35,850
好吧
Okay.

152
00:13:39,640 --> 00:13:42,110
原來是個機器
Oh, you're a robot.

153
00:13:42,930 --> 00:13:45,790
嚴格來說是機器人
Android, technically.

154
00:13:47,500 --> 00:13:49,340
我叫亞瑟
Arthur's the name.

155
00:13:49,630 --> 00:13:52,080
- 吉姆 - 很高興認識你 吉姆
- Jim. - Please to meet you, Jim.

156
00:13:57,950 --> 00:14:00,350
你對這艘船了解多少
How much do you know about this ship?

157
00:14:00,370 --> 00:14:02,960
不太多 我只知道一點點
I don't know. I know some things.

158
00:14:02,960 --> 00:14:05,290
如果我的休眠艙發生故障了怎么辦
What do I do if my hibernation pod malfunctions?

159
00:14:05,310 --> 00:14:07,910
休眠艙有自動防故障裝置
Oh. Hibernation pods are fail-safe.

160
00:14:07,940 --> 00:14:10,950
- 休眠艙從不出現故障 - 我醒早了
- They never malfunction. - Well, I woke up early.

161
00:14:10,970 --> 00:14:12,720
這不可能
Can't happen.

162
00:14:12,740 --> 00:14:14,740
還有多久我們才能到達新家園Ⅱ號
How long until we get to Homestead Ⅱ?

163
00:14:14,770 --> 00:14:16,510
還要90年左右
About 90 years or so.

164
00:14:16,530 --> 00:14:18,700
那所有乘客會在什么時候醒來
And when are all the passengers supposed to wake up?

165
00:14:18,730 --> 00:14:21,070
到達前4個月
Not until the last 4 months.

166
00:14:21,520 --> 00:14:26,520
我就在這坐著和你一起過上90年怎么樣
How is it that I'm sitting here with you with 90 years to go?

167
00:14:30,320 --> 00:14:32,670
你不可能出現在這里
It's not possible for you to be here.

168
00:14:34,800 --> 00:14:36,410
然而我在
Well, I am.

169
00:14:40,970 --> 00:14:43,740
早上好 阿瓦隆飛船又迎來了美好的一天
Good morning, it's a beautiful day here on the Avalon.

170
00:14:43,760 --> 00:14:47,860
所以醒來吧 天氣晴朗 是時候放松和享受了
So wake up, sunshine. It's time to relax and enjoy your stay.

171
00:14:58,020 --> 00:15:00,280
請選擇一款飲品
Please make a selection.

172
00:15:01,610 --> 00:15:03,200
對不起 摩卡卡布奇諾
Sorry. The Mocha Cappuccino

173
00:15:03,200 --> 00:15:05,920
只提供給貴賓艙乘客
Extreme is reserved for gold-class passengers.

174
00:15:05,940 --> 00:15:06,970
對不起 摩卡卡布奇諾
Sorry. The Mocha Cappuccino

175
00:15:06,970 --> 00:15:08,710
只提供給貴賓艙乘客
Extreme is reserved for gold-class passengers.

176
00:15:08,730 --> 00:15:11,020
我要一杯摩卡卡布奇諾 賬單記到我房間賬上 謝謝
I want the Mocha Cappuccino Extreme, bill my room please.

177
00:15:11,050 --> 00:15:12,900
購買食品可在飛船上的
Food can be purchase in the ship's...

178
00:15:12,930 --> 00:15:14,320
對不起 法式烤
Sorry. The French Roast...

179
00:15:14,350 --> 00:15:16,300
對不起 南瓜風味
Sorry. The Pumpkin Spice...

180
00:15:16,320 --> 00:15:17,500
對不起 香草茶
Sorry. Vanilla Chai...

181
00:15:17,530 --> 00:15:18,830
對不起 對不起
Sorry. Sorry.

182
00:15:18,850 --> 00:15:20,680
對不起 對不 對不起
Sorr... Sorr... Sorry.

183
00:15:21,150 --> 00:15:24,340
- 大杯黑咖 請享用您的咖啡 - 奶油 糖
- Large coffee. Please enjoy your coffee. - Cream. Sugar.

184
00:15:24,360 --> 00:15:26,140
真的嗎
Oh, really?

185
00:16:46,860 --> 00:16:51,000
訪問機組人員艙需要特殊授權
Crew podroom access requires special authorization.

186
00:17:34,420 --> 00:17:35,920
中央大
Grand Conc...

187
00:17:35,940 --> 00:17:37,030
正在下行
Going down.

188
00:17:37,060 --> 00:17:39,220
請選 層樓
Please make... Level...

189
00:17:40,630 --> 00:17:42,470
中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

190
00:17:42,500 --> 00:17:46,210
我完蛋了 亞瑟 真的完蛋了
I'm screwed, Arthur. Completely and ridiculously screwed.

191
00:17:46,230 --> 00:17:50,630
別這樣想 要知道守得云開見月明
Come on, now. Every cloud has a silver lining.

192
00:17:51,860 --> 00:17:54,920
看來我要老死在這里了
Guess, I am going to die of old age on this ship!

193
00:17:54,950 --> 00:17:56,810
人終有一死
Oh, we all die.

194
00:17:56,840 --> 00:17:59,540
就連機器人最后也會被扔到垃圾堆
Even androids end up on the scrap heap.

195
00:17:59,940 --> 00:18:03,260
這里就我一個客人 為什么你老是在擦玻璃杯
I'm your only customer, why are you always polishing a glass?

196
00:18:03,420 --> 00:18:04,970
生意技巧
Trick of the trade.

197
00:18:05,000 --> 00:18:07,780
如果酒保傻站在這里 就會讓客人緊張
Makes people nervous when a bartender just stands there.

198
00:18:07,800 --> 00:18:11,770
那就傳授點酒保的智慧給我 我迷失太空里了
So, lay some bartender wisdom on me. I'm lost in space here.

199
00:18:13,400 --> 00:18:16,100
你待在你不想待的地方
You're not where you want to be.

200
00:18:16,120 --> 00:18:19,550
你覺得你應該在別處才對
You feel like you're supposed to be somewhere else.

201
00:18:23,000 --> 00:18:24,530
- 你說得對 - 那么
- You said it. - Well.

202
00:18:24,550 --> 00:18:28,480
想象一下你只要動動手指就能到達你想去的地方
Say you could snap your fingers and be wherever you wanted to be.

203
00:18:28,500 --> 00:18:32,190
我敢說哪怕這樣你還是會無可適從
I'll bet you'd still feel this way. Not in the right place.

204
00:18:32,220 --> 00:18:36,000
關鍵在于 你不能總是糾結自己應該去哪
Point is, you can't get so hung up on where you'd rather be

205
00:18:36,020 --> 00:18:38,770
而忘了怎樣活在當下
that you forget how to make the most of where you are.

206
00:18:38,790 --> 00:18:40,390
你想告訴我什么
What are you telling me?

207
00:18:40,410 --> 00:18:44,340
別再擔心你不能控制的事了
Take a break from worrying about what you can't control.

208
00:18:45,560 --> 00:18:47,200
活在當下
Live a little.

209
00:18:47,360 --> 00:18:49,120
活在當下
Live a little.

210
00:18:58,190 --> 00:19:02,110
- 歡迎來到維也納套房 - 哇
- Welcome to the Vienna suite. - Oh.

211
00:19:02,150 --> 00:19:03,730
噢耶
Oh yeah.

212
00:19:03,880 --> 00:19:06,750
哈哈哈哈
Huh. Ha ha ha.

213
00:19:08,530 --> 00:19:10,160
不會吧
What?

214
00:19:10,920 --> 00:19:12,490
噢
Oh.

215
00:19:17,230 --> 00:19:18,880
加油 吉姆 加油 吉姆
Go, Jim! Go, Jim!

216
00:19:18,900 --> 00:19:19,620
耶
Yeah!

217
00:19:19,650 --> 00:19:22,240
來兩份大蝦 三份
Make that a double jumbo shrimp. Triple.

218
00:19:22,270 --> 00:19:24,510
非常感謝
Thank you very much.

219
00:19:24,920 --> 00:19:26,220
跳舞
Dance off.

220
00:19:26,240 --> 00:19:27,360
玩家1 吉姆
Player 1 jim

221
00:19:28,270 --> 00:19:29,860
好
Alright.

222
00:19:31,420 --> 00:19:33,630
我跳得跟你完全一樣啊
I did exactly what you just did.

223
00:19:38,550 --> 00:19:40,290
大杯黑咖
Large coffee.

224
00:19:44,290 --> 00:19:46,370
一杯瑪格麗塔 謝謝
A margarita, please.

225
00:19:46,400 --> 00:19:48,320
你點了太多了 先生
You have had many, Senor.

226
00:19:48,340 --> 00:19:51,760
埃克托 拜托再來一份
Oh Hector, please. Another one.

227
00:19:51,780 --> 00:19:53,380
好的 先生
Yes, Senor.

228
00:19:53,580 --> 00:19:55,170
謝謝
Thank you.

229
00:19:56,570 --> 00:20:00,170
加油 吉姆 加油 吉姆
Go, Jim! Go, Jim!

230
00:20:06,660 --> 00:20:08,930
滾開
Get out of here!

231
00:20:10,110 --> 00:20:11,900
回來 嘿
Come back. Hey.

232
00:20:14,060 --> 00:20:15,540
過來
Come here.

233
00:20:46,570 --> 00:20:48,180
該死
Damn!

234
00:21:10,830 --> 00:21:12,670
歡迎 吉姆
Welcome, Jim.

235
00:21:13,940 --> 00:21:18,430
請注意屏幕上的安全提示
Please turn your attention to the screens displaying safety tips.

236
00:21:18,460 --> 00:21:20,160
太空宇航服專為
These space suits are designed

237
00:21:20,160 --> 00:21:22,660
抵擋太空內惡劣環境而設計
to withstand the harsh environment of space.

238
00:21:22,700 --> 00:21:24,910
碳化纖維和聚酰胺的材質
The carbon fiber and polyamide

239
00:21:24,910 --> 00:21:29,110
使航空服持久耐用且不易變形
construction means your suit is inflexible and endurable.

240
00:21:40,980 --> 00:21:44,850
請記住 您的航空服就是您的生命
Remember, your space suit is your life line.

241
00:21:53,030 --> 00:21:56,910
請滑動右邊的把手釋放氣壓
Slide the handle on the right to release the air pressure.

242
00:21:58,410 --> 00:22:00,460
您的磁力靴已經啟用
Your magnetic boots are now engaged.

243
00:22:00,490 --> 00:22:03,910
可通過手臂上的控制板關閉磁力附著
They can be deactivated using the control panel on your arm.

244
00:22:03,940 --> 00:22:07,230
按下紅色按鈕開啟艙門
Press the red button to open the air lock door.

245
00:22:10,400 --> 00:22:12,510
祝您玩得開心
Have a wonderful time.

246
00:22:19,800 --> 00:22:21,760
安全繩就位
Tether attached.

247
00:23:49,170 --> 00:23:51,200
歡迎回來 吉姆
Welcome back, Jim.

248
00:23:54,320 --> 00:23:56,140
期待您再次光臨
We hope you decide to join

249
00:23:56,140 --> 00:23:59,420
我們的奇幻之旅
us again soon for another thrilling experience.

250
00:24:22,880 --> 00:24:25,260
祝您旅途愉快
Have a wonderful time.

251
00:25:45,530 --> 00:25:47,600
奧羅拉
Aurora.

252
00:25:48,670 --> 00:25:51,190
搜索乘客簡介
Searching passenger profiles.

253
00:25:51,210 --> 00:25:52,970
我叫奧羅拉 萊恩
I'm Aurora Lane.

254
00:25:53,000 --> 00:25:56,300
1456號乘客 我是個作家
Passenger 1456. I'm a writer.

255
00:25:56,320 --> 00:25:59,380
我認為我們講故事就是為了讓彼此不再孤單
I think we tell each other stories to know we're not alone.

256
00:25:59,400 --> 00:26:00,710
為了建立聯系
To make contact.

257
00:26:00,750 --> 00:26:04,130
你的父親是作家奧利弗 萊恩 普利策獎獲得者
Your father was Oliver Lane, the Pulitzer Prize-winning author.

258
00:26:04,160 --> 00:26:05,470
毫無壓力 對吧
No pressure, right?

259
00:26:05,500 --> 00:26:07,410
我爸爸曾經說過
My Dad used to say:

260
00:26:07,430 --> 00:26:11,250
如果你過著平凡的生活 那么你的故事也不過如此
"If you live an ordinary life, all you have are ordinary stories.

261
00:26:11,280 --> 00:26:13,790
你必須勇于冒險生活
You have to live a life of adventure."

262
00:26:14,870 --> 00:26:16,440
所以
So.

263
00:26:16,900 --> 00:26:18,520
我來了
Here I am.

264
00:26:24,730 --> 00:26:26,250
早上好
Good morning.

265
00:26:28,820 --> 00:26:32,510
各方面  我們都將從頭開始
We're starting over... in every way.

266
00:26:32,530 --> 00:26:35,130
我將要弄明白在哪里生活 如何生活
I'll have to figure out where to live, how to live,

267
00:26:35,150 --> 00:26:36,450
誰將成為我的朋友
who my friends will be.

268
00:26:36,480 --> 00:26:38,050
這種感覺就像開學第一天
It's like the first day at school.

269
00:26:38,070 --> 00:26:41,240
只不過這趟校車要開120年才能到達
And this school bus took 120 years to get there.

270
00:26:43,380 --> 00:26:45,500
我們在創造一種文化
We're creating a culture.

271
00:26:45,520 --> 00:26:46,870
你真幽默
You're funny.

272
00:26:46,870 --> 00:26:48,150
你有試過讀到
Do you ever read something

273
00:26:48,150 --> 00:26:50,120
像是專門為你而寫的東西嗎
and feel like it's written just for you?

274
00:26:50,150 --> 00:26:52,160
我不怎么讀東西
I don't do a lot of reading.

275
00:26:52,190 --> 00:26:54,150
她人真好
She's good.

276
00:26:54,620 --> 00:26:56,150
那人是誰
Who's that?

277
00:26:56,180 --> 00:26:57,780
奧羅拉
Aurora.

278
00:26:57,810 --> 00:27:00,900
那個睡美人
Ah. The sleeping girl.

279
00:27:05,370 --> 00:27:07,300
我不是說宇宙是完全邪惡的
You know, I'm not saying the universe is evil

280
00:27:07,320 --> 00:27:09,370
但確實還有種討人厭的幽默感
but it sure has a nasty sense of humor.

281
00:27:09,390 --> 00:27:10,430
怎么說
How is that?

282
00:27:10,470 --> 00:27:15,310
你要飛到另一個星球 卻要死在途中
You get to fly to another planet, but you'll die along the way.

283
00:27:16,420 --> 00:27:19,160
現在又讓你遇到你的命中注定
And you find the perfect woman

284
00:27:20,250 --> 00:27:22,130
近在眼前
right in front of you.

285
00:27:23,190 --> 00:27:25,660
卻觸不可及
Yet, she's completely out of reach.

286
00:27:28,570 --> 00:27:30,730
是的 我會想念紐約
Yeah, I'll miss New York city.

287
00:27:30,750 --> 00:27:32,900
給我一杯咖啡 以及一片克萊斯勒大廈景色
Give me a cup of coffee and a view of the Chrysler Building,

288
00:27:32,930 --> 00:27:34,590
我可以寫上一整天
and I can write all day.

289
00:27:34,610 --> 00:27:36,800
新家園Ⅱ號上有咖啡吧
You do have coffee on Homestead Ⅱ, right?

290
00:27:36,820 --> 00:27:38,020
那里最好有咖啡 如果沒有
They better have coffee, if they

291
00:27:38,020 --> 00:27:40,030
我們又要掉頭飛回地球去了
don't they have to turn around and come back to Earth.

292
00:27:41,520 --> 00:27:44,220
地球有什么讓你眷念的嗎
Is there anything you regret leaving behind?

293
00:27:44,480 --> 00:27:48,990
有啊 我會想念秋天的中央公園
Yeah, I'll miss the trees in Central Park turning in the Fall.

294
00:27:49,480 --> 00:27:52,950
我會想念喧鬧的人群
I'll miss the crowd, all the voices.

295
00:28:00,890 --> 00:28:03,280
如果你被困在一個荒蕪的孤島
Say you were trapped on a desert island,

296
00:28:03,310 --> 00:28:05,940
你有能力讓一個人來陪你
you had the power to wish somebody there with you.

297
00:28:05,960 --> 00:28:07,930
然后不再孤單
You wouldn't be alone anymore.

298
00:28:08,640 --> 00:28:11,070
但你卻會連累那個人一起困在這個孤島
But you'd be stranding a person on the island.

299
00:28:11,100 --> 00:28:13,500
你怎么做 你會許那種愿嗎
How do you... Would you make the wish?

300
00:28:13,530 --> 00:28:16,050
我不知道 我從沒去過島嶼
I don't know. I've never been on an island.

301
00:28:16,050 --> 00:28:18,040
好吧 對
Okay, well... Yeah.

302
00:28:19,010 --> 00:28:20,630
當我沒說
Forget the island.

303
00:28:21,210 --> 00:28:25,840
假設你想通了如何做某件事
Let's say you figured out how to do something

304
00:28:25,860 --> 00:28:27,660
會使你的生活大大改善
that would make your life a million times better.

305
00:28:27,680 --> 00:28:30,300
但你知道這么做是錯的 而且沒有后悔藥吃
But you knew it was wrong, and there's no taking it back.

306
00:28:30,320 --> 00:28:31,720
你會怎么做決定
How do you do the math?

307
00:28:31,750 --> 00:28:34,730
吉姆 這不是機器人能回答的問題
Jim. These are not robot questions.

308
00:28:40,240 --> 00:28:42,810
- 我知道怎么喚醒奧羅拉 - 喔
- I know how to wake Aurora up. - Oh.

309
00:28:42,830 --> 00:28:45,970
這看起來是個好主意 你會有個同伴了
Well, that seems like a fine idea. You could use some company.

310
00:28:46,000 --> 00:28:48,550
我會讓她的余生都在這艘飛船上度過
I'd be stranding her on this ship for the rest of her life!

311
00:28:48,570 --> 00:28:51,430
哦 那你不能那么做
Oh. Well, you can't do that.

312
00:28:52,310 --> 00:28:53,780
我該怎么辦
What am I going to do?

313
00:28:53,810 --> 00:28:55,130
我在這里陪你呢
I'm here for you.

314
00:28:55,150 --> 00:28:57,590
亞瑟 你是臺機器
Arthur, you're a machine.

315
00:29:00,390 --> 00:29:01,260
看吧
See.

316
00:29:01,260 --> 00:29:01,300
看到沒 你感覺不到 你是沒有感情的
See, you can't feel that, you don't have feelings.

317
00:29:07,380 --> 00:29:08,550
看見了吧
You see?

318
00:29:08,550 --> 00:29:10,240
你不會受傷
That doesn't hurt.

319
00:29:10,270 --> 00:29:12,250
你甚至都不會介意
And you don't even mind.

320
00:29:12,740 --> 00:29:15,550
而她 是人類
She... A person.

321
00:29:22,130 --> 00:29:23,560
別再想那件事了
Don't even think about it.

322
00:29:23,580 --> 00:29:25,270
別再提奧羅拉
No more Aurora talk.

323
00:29:25,290 --> 00:29:26,940
這事兒過去了
I'm over it.

324
00:29:27,030 --> 00:29:28,700
我得向前看
I'm moving on.

325
00:29:31,290 --> 00:29:32,880
我要怎么做 坐下來想一想嗎
What am I going to do? I'm going to sit and thinking about it?

326
00:29:32,900 --> 00:29:34,430
我不會  不能再想這件事了
I'm not going to... I can't think about it.

327
00:29:34,430 --> 00:29:35,750
所以我不去做 就這樣
So I'm not going to, that's the deal.

328
00:29:35,770 --> 00:29:38,400
我決定了 我知道我在做什么
I've made my decision. I know what I'm doing.

329
00:29:38,400 --> 00:29:40,250
就是中斷這個想法
I just cut it off.

330
00:29:42,080 --> 00:29:43,050
我不 不再
I'm not... No more.

331
00:29:43,080 --> 00:29:44,710
你不會再聽到我提起她了
You won't hear me bring up her name again.

332
00:29:44,740 --> 00:29:46,940
我甚至永遠也不會再提起她了
I'll never even mention her name again.

333
00:29:46,970 --> 00:29:48,390
結束了
Done.

334
00:29:50,540 --> 00:29:52,390
我不能那么做
I can't do it.

335
00:29:57,340 --> 00:29:59,360
我要剃掉我的胡子
I'm shaving off my beard.

336
00:30:09,900 --> 00:30:11,750
求你了 不要那么做
Please don't do it.

337
00:32:03,940 --> 00:32:05,550
早上好 奧羅拉
Good morning, Aurora.

338
00:32:05,550 --> 00:32:07,400
你感覺怎么樣
How're you feeling?

339
00:32:07,800 --> 00:32:10,550
您現在感到困惑很正常
It's perfectly normal to feel confused.

340
00:32:10,580 --> 00:32:14,260
您剛從120年的休眠中醒來
You've just spent a 120 years in suspended animation.

341
00:33:02,200 --> 00:33:04,330
中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

342
00:33:04,350 --> 00:33:05,900
有人嗎
Hello?

343
00:33:09,270 --> 00:33:11,020
有人嗎
Anybody?

344
00:33:19,720 --> 00:33:21,410
你好
Hello.

345
00:33:24,490 --> 00:33:26,140
你好
Hi.

346
00:33:28,360 --> 00:33:30,780
你是旅客還是乘務員
Are you passenger or crew?

347
00:33:32,700 --> 00:33:34,350
旅客
Passenger.

348
00:33:34,350 --> 00:33:35,700
吉姆 普勒斯頓
Jim Preston.

349
00:33:35,720 --> 00:33:37,610
奧羅拉 萊恩
Aurora Lane.

350
00:33:38,720 --> 00:33:40,640
你知道怎么回事嗎
Do you know what's going on?

351
00:33:40,670 --> 00:33:43,170
我不知為何醒了過來
Nobody else from my row woke up.

352
00:33:43,840 --> 00:33:44,930
我也是
Same for me.

353
00:33:44,950 --> 00:33:48,570
乘務員應該早于我們一個月醒來 但是
The crew's supposed to wake up a month before we do. But...

354
00:33:48,600 --> 00:33:50,510
我沒找到他們
I haven't seen them.

355
00:33:53,440 --> 00:33:55,540
乘務員仍然在沉睡
The crew is still asleep.

356
00:33:56,980 --> 00:33:59,610
你是說還沒人醒過來
Are you saying nobody's awake?

357
00:33:59,610 --> 00:34:00,940
只有我
Just me.

358
00:34:00,990 --> 00:34:02,300
只有你
Just you?

359
00:34:02,330 --> 00:34:04,090
準確說只有我們
It's just us.

360
00:34:04,490 --> 00:34:07,500
但幾周后飛船就應該降落了啊
But somebody's got to land the ship in a few weeks.

361
00:34:07,530 --> 00:34:11,180
我們將在大概89年后到達
We will arrive in approximately 89 years.

362
00:34:11,210 --> 00:34:13,600
89年
89 years?

363
00:34:15,470 --> 00:34:18,770
其他旅客都不會在最近醒來
The other passengers aren't late waking up.

364
00:34:19,860 --> 00:34:21,890
是我們太早了
We were early.

365
00:34:25,990 --> 00:34:28,470
我們 我們需要援助
We... We need help.

366
00:34:28,490 --> 00:34:30,300
乘務員都在哪
Where's the crew?

367
00:34:30,330 --> 00:34:33,090
乘務員都在防護休眠室
The crew's in a secured hibernation room.

368
00:34:33,120 --> 00:34:36,670
所有重要的東西 操作系統 反應堆 引擎
Everything important, the controls, the reactors, the engines,

369
00:34:36,690 --> 00:34:40,120
所有這些都在這個防火墻后面 沒辦法過去
it's all behind firewalls, there's no way through.

370
00:34:50,300 --> 00:34:52,790
你醒了多久了
How long have you been awake?

371
00:34:53,320 --> 00:34:55,620
一年零三周
1 year and 3 weeks.

372
00:34:55,840 --> 00:34:59,170
不 不 不 不
No. No, no, no.

373
00:34:59,330 --> 00:35:01,460
不 這不可能
No, this can't be happening.

374
00:35:01,490 --> 00:35:03,720
我們必須回去休眠
We have to go back to sleep.

375
00:35:03,750 --> 00:35:05,810
奧羅拉 我們做不到
Aurora, we can't.

376
00:35:08,010 --> 00:35:09,810
我們只要回到休眠艙里
We just have to get back to our pods

377
00:35:09,830 --> 00:35:11,720
再重新啟動
and start them up again.

378
00:35:12,630 --> 00:35:15,440
我找不到我的休眠艙了 我找不到我的休眠艙了
I can't find my pod. I can't find my pod.

379
00:35:15,460 --> 00:35:17,770
我找不到我的休眠艙了 我們這是在哪兒
I can't find my pod. Where are we?

380
00:35:17,800 --> 00:35:19,530
沒事的
It doesn't matter.

381
00:35:20,650 --> 00:35:21,940
- 奧羅拉 - 我找不到了
- Aurora. - I can't find it.

382
00:35:21,960 --> 00:35:23,720
- 停下 - 我找不到哪一個是我的了
- Stop. - I can't find which one is mine.

383
00:35:23,740 --> 00:35:25,320
- 停下 - 怎么才能知道哪個是我的
- Stop. - How do I know which one is mine?

384
00:35:25,350 --> 00:35:26,490
- 我會幫你的 - 我不能
- I'll help you. - I can't...

385
00:35:26,520 --> 00:35:29,530
冷靜 沒事的
Stop. It doesn't matter.

386
00:35:31,820 --> 00:35:35,670
讓人進入休眠需要特殊的設備
Putting somebody into hibernation requires special equipment.

387
00:35:35,700 --> 00:35:37,520
還記得整個休眠過程中
Remember the facility where they

388
00:35:37,520 --> 00:35:40,240
他們讓我們通過的那個裝置嗎
put us under all the procedures we went through.

389
00:35:40,270 --> 00:35:42,610
這些休眠艙只是用來保證我們的休眠狀態的
These pods are designed to keep us in hibernation,

390
00:35:42,640 --> 00:35:44,160
它們會在正確的時間喚醒我們
they'll wake us up at the right time

391
00:35:44,190 --> 00:35:46,010
但是卻不能讓我們重新休眠
but they can't put us back to sleep.

392
00:35:46,030 --> 00:35:49,270
你覺得沒辦法重新回到休眠
You don't think there's a way back into hibernation.

393
00:35:50,270 --> 00:35:51,620
是的
No.

394
00:35:51,650 --> 00:35:53,670
但一定會有辦法的
But there has to be.

395
00:35:54,080 --> 00:35:56,160
必須得有
There has to be.

396
00:36:04,420 --> 00:36:07,970
九點了 休息時間到了
9 o'clock. Bedtime.

397
00:36:12,060 --> 00:36:15,400
我知道我應該想辦法解決問題
I know I should be working the problem but...

398
00:36:15,700 --> 00:36:18,140
但是我已經睜不開眼了
I can't even keep my eyes open.

399
00:36:18,730 --> 00:36:20,640
你才剛剛從休眠中蘇醒
You just came out of hibernation.

400
00:36:20,660 --> 00:36:22,970
還需要幾天時間來恢復
It's going to be a couple of days before you're 100%.

401
00:36:23,000 --> 00:36:25,070
你應該去休息一下
You should get some rest.

402
00:36:25,580 --> 00:36:27,750
我想我不得不去了
I think I'm going to have to.

403
00:36:28,610 --> 00:36:31,470
- 我送你回客艙吧 - 不用了
- I'll walk you to your cabin. - No, it's okay.

404
00:36:31,500 --> 00:36:33,270
我沒事的
I'll be alright.

405
00:36:34,140 --> 00:36:35,790
好吧
Okay.

406
00:36:38,570 --> 00:36:40,470
晚安 奧羅拉
Good night, Aurora.

407
00:36:41,970 --> 00:36:45,530
一年多 難以想象
More than a year. I can't imagine.

408
00:36:46,060 --> 00:36:48,280
這段時間你一定很難熬吧
It must have been so hard for you.

409
00:36:48,440 --> 00:36:50,070
是的
It was.

410
00:36:50,090 --> 00:36:51,870
晚安 吉姆
Good night, Jim.

411
00:36:53,580 --> 00:36:56,910
請系好安全帶并縛緊所有松動的部分
Please buckle up and secure any loose items.

412
00:36:59,620 --> 00:37:02,540
- 威士忌 純的 - 沒問題
- Whiskey. Neat. - Sure thing.

413
00:37:08,190 --> 00:37:10,070
今天過的怎么樣
How's your day been?

414
00:37:10,940 --> 00:37:12,530
奧羅拉醒了
Aurora's awake.

415
00:37:12,550 --> 00:37:14,680
恭喜了
Congratulations.

416
00:37:16,240 --> 00:37:18,220
你看起來并不高興
You don't look happy.

417
00:37:21,980 --> 00:37:23,990
亞瑟 你能保守秘密嗎
Arthur, can you keep a secret?

418
00:37:24,020 --> 00:37:28,520
吉姆 我不僅僅是個酒保 我是個紳士
Jim, I'm not just a bartender, I'm a gentleman.

419
00:37:28,550 --> 00:37:31,280
不要告訴奧羅拉 是我喚醒了她
Don't tell Aurora that I woke her up.

420
00:37:33,170 --> 00:37:36,070
她覺得那是一個意外事故 讓我來跟她說
She thinks it was an accident. Let me tell her.

421
00:37:36,090 --> 00:37:37,800
當然
Of course.

422
00:37:50,700 --> 00:37:53,190
怎么可能沒有辦法讓人重新進入休眠呢
How can there be no way to put someone back into hibernation?

423
00:37:53,220 --> 00:37:54,680
如果休眠艙壞掉了呢
What if a pod breaks down?

424
00:37:54,700 --> 00:37:56,040
幾千次飛行中
No hibernation pod has

425
00:37:56,050 --> 00:37:59,150
尚未有一個休眠艙發生故障
malfunctioned in thousands of interstellar flights.

426
00:37:59,500 --> 00:38:02,170
然而 我醒了
Well, I'm awake.

427
00:38:02,200 --> 00:38:05,010
休眠艙是萬無一失的
Hibernation pods are fail-safe.

428
00:38:05,030 --> 00:38:07,370
早上好 你吃早飯了嗎
Good morning. Have you eaten?

429
00:38:07,390 --> 00:38:09,470
沒有 我餓死了
No, I'm starving.

430
00:38:09,490 --> 00:38:11,830
這是天下最蠢的機器了
And this is the dumbest machine.

431
00:38:11,850 --> 00:38:13,720
非常樂意為您服務
Happy to help!

432
00:38:26,110 --> 00:38:28,470
黃金級早餐
Gold-class breakfast.

433
00:38:38,680 --> 00:38:40,890
你的品位很簡樸呀
Well, you're a man of simple tastes.

434
00:38:40,920 --> 00:38:43,400
我可不是一個黃金級乘客
I'm not a gold-class passenger.

435
00:38:45,380 --> 00:38:47,570
法國泡芙早餐不是我等之人可以享受的起
French Breakfast Puff is above my pay grade.

436
00:38:47,590 --> 00:38:49,290
什么 你一直就吃這個
What? This whole time?

437
00:38:49,310 --> 00:38:51,070
- 是的 - 我幫你點些別的吧
- Yeah. - What can I get you?

438
00:38:51,100 --> 00:38:53,010
- 不 不用了 沒事 - 別說了
- No. No, I'm fine, - Stop it.

439
00:38:53,040 --> 00:38:55,230
真的 好吧
really... Okay.

440
00:38:56,560 --> 00:38:58,290
給你
Here you go.

441
00:39:03,040 --> 00:39:04,440
是啊
Yeah.

442
00:39:04,460 --> 00:39:06,170
你看 我在想
So, I was thinking.

443
00:39:06,190 --> 00:39:07,920
或許可以換種方式休眠
Maybe there's another way to go to sleep.

444
00:39:07,920 --> 00:39:08,980
治療艙怎么樣
What about the infirmary?

445
00:39:09,000 --> 00:39:11,410
我檢查過了 那只是些掃描儀和自動診斷機
I've checked it out. It's just scanners and an autodoc.

446
00:39:11,430 --> 00:39:13,870
貨物艙中或許會有其它的休眠艙
There could be another hibernation machine in the cargo hold.

447
00:39:13,870 --> 00:39:15,260
我也想過了
I've had that thought too.

448
00:39:15,280 --> 00:39:16,510
然后我看了貨物清單
And then I read the manifests.

449
00:39:16,510 --> 00:39:19,000
只有些農業用具 機器和商用貨物
It's mostly farming stuff, machines and trade goods,

450
00:39:19,020 --> 00:39:21,340
工程電腦上的備用零件
replacement parts for computers in Engineering.

451
00:39:21,360 --> 00:39:23,670
我們是不可能在箱子中翻出一個休眠艙的
We're not going to find a hibernation facility in a box.

452
00:39:23,700 --> 00:39:25,390
- 我們可以自己造 - 不能
- We can build our own. - We can't.

453
00:39:25,390 --> 00:39:29,190
- 吉米 你都還沒試過 - 我任何方法都用遍了
- Jim, you're not even trying! - I have tried everything.

454
00:39:29,220 --> 00:39:31,230
花了一年多時間
For over a year.

455
00:39:32,340 --> 00:39:34,260
任何方法都用遍了
I tried everything.

456
00:39:36,620 --> 00:39:38,830
好吧 我現在還不想放棄
Oh well, I'm not ready to give up.

457
00:39:47,530 --> 00:39:49,490
治療艙
Infirmary.

458
00:39:57,020 --> 00:39:59,790
那有研究論文 任何技術文檔嗎
What about research articles, any kind of technical documents?

459
00:39:59,810 --> 00:40:02,530
休眠技術是一項專利
Hibernation technology is proprietary.

460
00:40:02,550 --> 00:40:04,020
下面的這些文章
The following articles

461
00:40:04,020 --> 00:40:07,020
研究的主體僅處于理論階段
deal with the subject on a theoretical level.

462
00:40:49,730 --> 00:40:52,820
新建文件 我的旅程
New file. My Voyage.

463
00:40:52,990 --> 00:40:56,990
我帶著一個想法和一個目的地登上阿瓦隆號
I boarded the Avalon with an idea, a destination.

464
00:40:57,460 --> 00:41:01,650
然而現在 兩者都遙不可及
Both now, out of reach.

465
00:41:03,340 --> 00:41:05,740
我已經蘇醒7天了
I've been awake for 7 days,

466
00:41:05,770 --> 00:41:08,340
醒得太早了
awake far too soon...

467
00:41:08,360 --> 00:41:11,210
甚至我可能余生都要在這里度過了
and I may well spend the rest of my life here...

468
00:41:11,240 --> 00:41:15,490
在一個1000公尺長的鋼鐵世界里度過
...in a steel world a 1,000 meters long.

469
00:41:16,670 --> 00:41:18,700
除我之外 還有個人也醒著
There's another passenger awake.

470
00:41:18,730 --> 00:41:21,590
一個叫吉姆 普勒斯頓的機修工
A mechanic named Jim Preston.

471
00:41:23,260 --> 00:41:26,050
他貌似已經接受了命運的安排
He seems to have accepted our fate.

472
00:41:26,630 --> 00:41:28,660
但是我很害怕
But I'm scared.

473
00:41:29,380 --> 00:41:31,960
我努力保持鎮靜
I'm fighting to stay calm.

474
00:41:33,960 --> 00:41:39,180
其他乘客們還要再睡90年才會醒
All the other passengers will sleep for another 90 years.

475
00:41:39,820 --> 00:41:45,360
而我卻在這艘飛行的船里 荒廢余生
While I live out my life on this ship... traveling forever...

476
00:41:45,970 --> 00:41:47,900
永遠到不了終點
never arriving.

477
00:41:48,490 --> 00:41:51,410
我僅有的慰藉 卻是一個陌生人
My only companion, a total stranger.

478
00:42:00,180 --> 00:42:01,950
為什么你要這么做
Why did you do it?

479
00:42:04,100 --> 00:42:05,720
做什么
Do what?

480
00:42:06,580 --> 00:42:09,220
移民 離開地球
Emigrate. Leave Earth.

481
00:42:10,090 --> 00:42:12,050
我在采訪你
I'm interviewing you.

482
00:42:12,080 --> 00:42:12,990
你在干什么
You're what?

483
00:42:13,010 --> 00:42:14,460
你是在整個太空旅行史上
You're the first hibernation

484
00:42:14,460 --> 00:42:16,470
第一例休眠失敗者
failure in the history of space travel.

485
00:42:16,490 --> 00:42:18,440
這會讓你被載入史冊
That makes you a story.

486
00:42:18,550 --> 00:42:21,170
- 那你要把這故事說給誰呢 - 子孫后代
- Who are you going to tell? - Posterity.

487
00:42:21,190 --> 00:42:24,570
那你為什么放棄你在地球上的生活呢
So why did you give up your life on Earth?

488
00:42:24,590 --> 00:42:26,250
120年的休眠
A 120 years space hibernation

489
00:42:26,250 --> 00:42:29,040
意味著你再也無法見到你的親朋好友了
means you never see your family or friends again.

490
00:42:29,040 --> 00:42:32,750
你醒來的地方是另一個世紀 陌生的星球
You'll wake up in a new century, on a new planet.

491
00:42:32,890 --> 00:42:35,190
簡直就是終極的自殺行為
It's the ultimate geographical suicide.

492
00:42:35,220 --> 00:42:37,440
那我也可以問你同樣的問題
Well, I could ask you the same thing.

493
00:42:37,460 --> 00:42:39,410
但這是我的采訪
But it's my interview.

494
00:42:39,750 --> 00:42:41,770
你是在逃避什么嗎
Were you running away from something?

495
00:42:41,800 --> 00:42:43,220
不是
No.

496
00:42:43,550 --> 00:42:45,690
- 一切都很好 - 那是什么
- Everything was okay. - So?

497
00:42:45,960 --> 00:42:48,620
我想我只是想要一個全新的世界 我不確定 一個全新的開始吧
I guess I just wanted a new world. I don't know, a fresh start.

498
00:42:48,650 --> 00:42:50,730
那是新家園公司的廣告上說的
That's HomeStead Company advertising.

499
00:42:50,760 --> 00:42:52,220
- 是嗎 - 吉姆
- Is it? - Jim.

500
00:42:52,250 --> 00:42:55,020
我 我知道 我想你是對的
I... I know. I guess, you're right.

501
00:42:59,640 --> 00:43:01,390
在地球上 每當東西出現故障了
Back on Earth, when something breaks,

502
00:43:01,390 --> 00:43:02,950
你不去修理它 而是換一個新的
you don't fix it, you replace it.

503
00:43:03,420 --> 00:43:06,220
在殖民星 他們有很多問題需要解決
In the colonies, they have problems to solve.

504
00:43:06,250 --> 00:43:08,400
我可以解決的問題
They're my kind of problems.

505
00:43:09,590 --> 00:43:11,800
機修工不再是無足輕重
And the mechanic is somebody.

506
00:43:11,820 --> 00:43:14,310
一個新的世界等待著我去創建
It's a new world still being built.

507
00:43:16,270 --> 00:43:18,550
我可以建造一個新家園 住進去
I can build a house and live in it.

508
00:43:23,280 --> 00:43:26,260
開放的國家 發展的空間
Open country, room to grow.

509
00:43:26,280 --> 00:43:27,890
你又回到宣傳語上了
Now you're back to slogans.

510
00:43:27,910 --> 00:43:30,060
宣傳語就不能是真的嗎
Can't slogans be true?

511
00:43:31,280 --> 00:43:32,350
你知道新家園公司打造
Do you know how much

512
00:43:32,350 --> 00:43:34,820
第一個殖民星球花了多少錢嗎
Homestead Company's made off its first planet?

513
00:43:34,840 --> 00:43:37,030
八千萬億美元
8 quadrillion dollars.

514
00:43:37,060 --> 00:43:39,750
八千萬億啊
That's 8 million billions.

515
00:43:39,770 --> 00:43:42,510
星球殖民現在是最大的生意了
Colony planets are the biggest business now.

516
00:43:42,680 --> 00:43:44,460
你付的是全價嗎
Did you pay full price for your ticket?

517
00:43:44,480 --> 00:43:46,900
不是  我跟他們做了個好交易
No, I'm in a desirable trade.

518
00:43:46,920 --> 00:43:50,630
也就是說他們會實現你的夢想
So they fill your head with dreams,

519
00:43:50,660 --> 00:43:53,460
并給你折扣票價 而你過去增加他們星球的人口
discount your ticket, and you fly off to populate their planet

520
00:43:53,480 --> 00:43:54,470
并在余生里給新家園
and give HomeStead 20% of

521
00:43:54,470 --> 00:43:56,490
上交20%的收入
everything that you made for the rest of your life.

522
00:43:56,510 --> 00:43:59,800
更不用說 你在這艘華麗的船上的生活費用
Not to mention the debt you run up on this fancy starship.

523
00:43:59,820 --> 00:44:02,930
所以你在兒看到的 只是5000個失敗者么
So all you see here is 5,000 suckers?

524
00:44:03,090 --> 00:44:06,830
依我看新家園公司沒有任何底線
I see zeroes on the HomeStead Company's bottom line.

525
00:44:06,850 --> 00:44:10,380
我看到的是 5000個男女在改變他們的人生
I see 5,000 men and women changing their lives.

526
00:44:10,630 --> 00:44:13,480
每個人都有不同的原因 你并不了解這些人
for 5,000 different reasons. You don't know these people.

527
00:44:13,500 --> 00:44:16,710
我是一個記者 我了解人
I'm a journalist. I know people.

528
00:44:18,050 --> 00:44:19,790
真的嗎
Really?

529
00:44:19,810 --> 00:44:21,230
這個
This one.

530
00:44:21,260 --> 00:44:24,410
他是一個銀行家 教師還是一個園丁
Is he a banker, a teacher or a gardener?

531
00:44:25,350 --> 00:44:27,960
- 銀行家 - 他是一個園丁
- Banker. - He's a gardener.

532
00:44:28,740 --> 00:44:34,750
還有她 她叫麥迪遜 唐娜還是羅拉
And her, is she a Maddison, Donna or Lola?

533
00:44:35,470 --> 00:44:37,820
“唐娜”這個名字對她的頭發來說好嚴肅
Donna's too serious for that hair.

534
00:44:37,840 --> 00:44:39,450
羅拉
Lola.

535
00:44:39,590 --> 00:44:41,950
- 麥迪遜 - 草
- Maddison. - Shit.

536
00:44:43,770 --> 00:44:44,820
好的
Alright.

537
00:44:44,850 --> 00:44:46,910
廚師 會計還是助產士
Chef, accountant or midwife?

538
00:44:46,940 --> 00:44:47,930
她肯定是助產士
She has to be a midwife.

539
00:44:47,930 --> 00:44:49,630
你不可能是亂編出來的
There's no way you just made that one up.

540
00:44:49,660 --> 00:44:51,460
他是助產士
She's a midwife.

541
00:44:52,450 --> 00:44:54,690
很高興知道他們還需要助產士
Good to know they still have midwives.

542
00:44:56,690 --> 00:44:59,700
我喜歡她 我們會做朋友的
I like her. We would be friends.

543
00:44:59,730 --> 00:45:01,670
你覺得你可以預見未來嗎
You think you can see that?

544
00:45:01,690 --> 00:45:03,410
你不可以嗎
Don't you?

545
00:45:05,200 --> 00:45:06,640
我可以
I do.

546
00:45:06,670 --> 00:45:08,440
往返票
A round trip ticket.

547
00:45:08,470 --> 00:45:10,960
對 我飛到新家園2號
That's right. I was going to fly to Homestead Ⅱ,

548
00:45:10,980 --> 00:45:13,160
住上一年 然后又返回地球
live for a year and then right back to Earth.

549
00:45:13,180 --> 00:45:14,960
我不明白 我為了新的人生離開地球
I don't get it. I left Earth for a new life.

550
00:45:14,990 --> 00:45:16,560
但你最終又回到開始的地方
But you end up back where you started.

551
00:45:16,560 --> 00:45:20,610
我最終會在未來 250年后的未來
I end up in the future. 250 years in the future.

552
00:45:20,630 --> 00:45:22,240
地球 那兒還是
On Earth, which is still

553
00:45:22,240 --> 00:45:25,110
文明的中心 無論你喜歡不喜歡
the center of civilization, like it or not.

554
00:45:25,650 --> 00:45:26,990
而我會是唯一一個
And I would be the only writer

555
00:45:26,990 --> 00:45:29,270
去往殖民地又回來的作家
that ever travel to the colony world and come back.

556
00:45:29,300 --> 00:45:31,160
我會有一個獨一無二的故事
I'll have a story no one else can tell.

557
00:45:31,190 --> 00:45:32,760
什么故事
What story?

558
00:45:32,780 --> 00:45:35,220
人類飛往星際的旅行
Humanity's flight to the stars.

559
00:45:35,250 --> 00:45:37,310
人類歷史上最大的移民
The greatest migration in human history.

560
00:45:37,320 --> 00:45:38,970
會是最受歡迎的的故事
It's the biggest story there is.

561
00:45:38,990 --> 00:45:40,700
但你并不會知道 是誰在讀你的故事
But you won't know any of the people who were reading it.

562
00:45:40,730 --> 00:45:42,600
但反正會有人讀的
But they'd be reading it.

563
00:45:44,960 --> 00:45:46,960
好吧 本會有人讀的
Well, they would have been.

564
00:45:48,170 --> 00:45:49,930
我現在是寫不成了
I'll never write it now.

565
00:45:49,950 --> 00:45:52,380
我也不知道 以后會不會有機會寫了
I don't know if I'll ever write again.

566
00:45:54,220 --> 00:45:57,940
吉姆 我想不出任何辦法
Jim, I can't think of anything else to try

567
00:45:57,970 --> 00:46:00,060
來拯救我們
...to save us.

568
00:46:01,450 --> 00:46:04,150
我甚至都再也不想去想這些問題了
And I don't even want to think about it anymore.

569
00:46:06,390 --> 00:46:08,750
這兒還有什么事情可以做嗎
What is there to do around here?

570
00:46:10,750 --> 00:46:13,650
- 你是認真的嗎 - 我非常認真
- Are you serious? - I'm dead serious.

571
00:46:13,660 --> 00:46:15,320
雙人模式
Partner mode.

572
00:46:16,860 --> 00:46:18,780
來吧 快來雙人模式
Come on, get in partner mode.

573
00:46:25,210 --> 00:46:28,990
你就站在這里 然后重復他們的動作
You just stand here, and then we repeat what they do.

574
00:46:36,580 --> 00:46:38,760
還有別的我們可以做的事情嗎
Is there anything else we can do?

575
00:46:38,780 --> 00:46:39,990
- 快來吧 - 好吧
- Just do the... - Okay.

576
00:46:40,010 --> 00:46:41,440
- 你不愿意的話可以不做 - 好吧
- You don't have to. - Okay.

577
00:46:41,470 --> 00:46:42,560
弱爆了
Beat down.

578
00:46:42,590 --> 00:46:44,090
嘿
Hey.

579
00:46:44,110 --> 00:46:46,020
來吧 讓我們看看..
Here we go. Let's see if... Oh.

580
00:46:46,040 --> 00:46:47,980
哇 哇哦
Whoa! Whoa!

581
00:46:48,460 --> 00:46:50,690
噢 你在笑什么
Oh. Why are you smiling?

582
00:46:50,710 --> 00:46:52,920
我領先兩分了
I'm up 2 points.

583
00:46:53,200 --> 00:46:54,610
這位可愛的女士是誰
Who's the lovely lady?

584
00:46:54,640 --> 00:46:56,000
這位是奧羅拉
This is Aurora.

585
00:46:56,030 --> 00:46:58,890
奧羅拉女士 榮幸
Aurora. A pleasure.

586
00:47:01,680 --> 00:47:03,820
-你跳得很棒 -好吧 再來一次
- You did great! - Okay. One more time.

587
00:47:03,840 --> 00:47:05,230
再來一次 這次準行
One more time. Let's see it.

588
00:47:11,280 --> 00:47:12,620
噢
Oh!

589
00:47:16,830 --> 00:47:18,690
- 耶 -哇
- YES! - Woo!

590
00:47:21,200 --> 00:47:23,220
對不起我之前一個月都沒穿褲子
Sorry I didn't wear pants for a month.

591
00:47:23,240 --> 00:47:25,640
確切來說是7個星期又2天
That's 7 weeks and 2 days, to be exact.

592
00:47:25,670 --> 00:47:27,170
這位男士沒有什么羞恥心
The man has no shame.

593
00:47:27,190 --> 00:47:30,570
你在穿褲子方面并沒有什么話語權 亞瑟
Well, you're a little lacking in that area yourself, Arthur.

594
00:47:33,010 --> 00:47:37,310
我嘲笑了一個男人不穿褲子 才想起來我自己連腿都沒有
I laughed at a man with no pants until I realised I have no legs.

595
00:47:43,280 --> 00:47:46,260
有時候 我差點忘了我的人生已經毀了
For a minute, I almost forgot my life isn't ruined.

596
00:47:46,280 --> 00:47:47,830
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

597
00:47:48,140 --> 00:47:50,010
你抱歉什么
What for?

598
00:47:50,870 --> 00:47:52,590
我去睡覺了
I'm going to go to bed.

599
00:47:53,320 --> 00:47:54,850
- 晚安 - 好
- Good night. - Alright.

600
00:47:54,880 --> 00:47:56,800
晚安 奧羅拉
Good night, Aurora.

601
00:47:59,480 --> 00:48:02,220
她太贊了
She is wonderful.

602
00:48:02,640 --> 00:48:04,650
明智之選
Excellent choice.

603
00:49:31,970 --> 00:49:33,440
你好
Hello.

604
00:49:33,730 --> 00:49:35,220
你好
Hi.

605
00:49:35,300 --> 00:49:37,050
這個給你
Here you go.

606
00:49:42,690 --> 00:49:44,710
他在約我嗎
Is he asking me on a date?

607
00:49:46,590 --> 00:49:48,350
你需要筆嗎
Do you need a pen?

608
00:50:00,890 --> 00:50:03,150
她似乎沒有很意外
She didn't seem that impressed.

609
00:50:20,830 --> 00:50:23,240
“我很樂意” 她說“我很樂意”
"Love to." She wrote "Love to".

610
00:50:31,020 --> 00:50:33,180
您有一位訪客
You have a visitor.

611
00:50:51,280 --> 00:50:52,400
天啊
Wow.

612
00:50:52,420 --> 00:50:54,700
你打扮得很帥嘛
You clean up pretty good yourself.

613
00:50:55,480 --> 00:50:58,690
- 你去買購物了 - 我去購..健身了
- You went shopping. - I went shop... lifting.

614
00:51:03,610 --> 00:51:05,960
晚上好 我能為你們做些什么
Evening. What can I get for you?

615
00:51:05,980 --> 00:51:08,630
我要一杯曼哈頓酒 謝謝
I'll have a Manhattan, please.

616
00:51:09,460 --> 00:51:11,870
- 威士忌加冰 - 稍等
- Whiskey rocks. - Coming up.

617
00:51:19,700 --> 00:51:21,520
今晚兩位看起來很棒啊
You two look fine this evening.

618
00:51:21,540 --> 00:51:23,030
謝謝 亞瑟
Thank you, Arthur.

619
00:51:23,050 --> 00:51:24,650
我們在約會呢
We're on a date!

620
00:51:24,670 --> 00:51:26,740
不錯嘛
Very nice.

621
00:51:26,760 --> 00:51:28,930
你竟然花了這么久才開口
Took you long enough to ask.

622
00:51:28,930 --> 00:51:30,620
我想給你多一些空間
I was giving you space.

623
00:51:30,650 --> 00:51:31,980
噢
Oh.

624
00:51:32,090 --> 00:51:36,090
空間 是我在這里唯一不想多要的東西
Space, the one thing I do not need more of.

625
00:51:39,100 --> 00:51:41,050
非常感謝
Thank you very much.

626
00:51:42,080 --> 00:51:43,480
這頓飯真不錯
That was so good.

627
00:51:43,500 --> 00:51:45,450
那當然 預訂這里的位子可不容易
Well, it wasn't easy getting a reservation.

628
00:51:45,480 --> 00:51:47,970
他們也許已經盼著我們趕緊離開了
They probably going to want us to give up our table.

629
00:51:48,000 --> 00:51:51,430
- 我看到好幾個服務員的臉色很臭了 - 今晚這里人真多
- Getting a lot of dirty looks. - Very popular tonight.

630
00:51:52,990 --> 00:51:54,610
你的書寫得怎么樣
So how's your book coming?

631
00:51:54,640 --> 00:51:57,050
現在還沒有什么頭緒
I don't really know what it is yet.

632
00:51:57,690 --> 00:52:00,340
我父親是從他的人生開始寫的
My dad, he started to write about his life, but...

633
00:52:00,370 --> 00:52:02,390
畢竟他是一個有故事的人
he had stories. He...

634
00:52:02,720 --> 00:52:05,340
他去過南極洲探險
sailed around Antarctica. He...

635
00:52:05,370 --> 00:52:09,270
當過戰地記者 他...有他的情人們
was a war reporter. He... had lovers.

636
00:52:09,310 --> 00:52:11,500
他也寫過他女兒
He wrote about his daughter.

637
00:52:11,530 --> 00:52:13,290
- 他寫過你 - 對
- He wrote about you? - No.

638
00:52:13,320 --> 00:52:15,290
我是讀著他書里的自己長大的
I grew up reading about myself in his books.

639
00:52:15,320 --> 00:52:16,810
感覺怎么樣
How was that?

640
00:52:17,590 --> 00:52:18,940
有時候并不好受
Not always easy.

641
00:52:18,960 --> 00:52:21,870
有點超過了一個人需要了解自身的程度
A little more than you wanted to know about yourself.

642
00:52:21,890 --> 00:52:27,260
在我17歲的時候 他犯了心臟病
I mean, when I was 17, he had a heart attack.

643
00:52:28,450 --> 00:52:30,460
我一直留著他的書
I-I just keep that.

644
00:52:30,960 --> 00:52:32,850
故事結束
End of story.

645
00:52:35,550 --> 00:52:38,650
對不起 話題太沉重了
Oh, so serious. I'm sorry.

646
00:52:38,660 --> 00:52:39,870
我們需要更多的酒
We need more wine.

647
00:52:39,890 --> 00:52:42,140
我很愿意了解你的人生
I like to hear about your life.

648
00:52:43,140 --> 00:52:44,640
謝謝
Thanks.

649
00:52:46,780 --> 00:52:48,260
我們來這里做什么
Why are we here?

650
00:52:48,280 --> 00:52:49,860
等會你就知道了
You'll see.

651
00:52:51,530 --> 00:52:53,360
城里最棒的演出
Best show in town.

652
00:52:56,940 --> 00:52:58,960
你之前試過嗎
So you've done this before?

653
00:52:58,990 --> 00:53:00,700
沒錯
Oh yeah.

654
00:53:00,730 --> 00:53:02,150
這安全嗎
And it's safe?

655
00:53:02,170 --> 00:53:03,700
不
No.

656
00:53:04,630 --> 00:53:06,410
是相當安全
Reasonably safe.

657
00:53:07,740 --> 00:53:10,480
穿上吧 你是下一個
Hop in. You're next.

658
00:53:11,550 --> 00:53:13,470
我的裙子怎么辦
What about my dress?

659
00:53:15,690 --> 00:53:17,470
哦對
Right.

660
00:53:19,690 --> 00:53:21,510
轉過去
Turn around.

661
00:53:52,060 --> 00:53:53,860
安全繩就位
Tether attached.

662
00:54:34,570 --> 00:54:36,180
你想干什么
What are you doing?

663
00:54:36,520 --> 00:54:38,320
你相信我嗎
Do you trust me?

664
00:55:24,940 --> 00:55:26,750
謝謝你
Thank you.

665
00:56:15,420 --> 00:56:18,300
你是我見過最美的女人
You're the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.

666
00:56:21,360 --> 00:56:23,380
勾走了我的魂
You kill me.

667
00:57:05,580 --> 00:57:07,430
你還好嗎
You okay?

668
00:57:07,640 --> 00:57:09,050
嗯
Yeah.

669
00:57:10,770 --> 00:57:12,460
我很好
I am fine.

670
00:57:12,620 --> 00:57:14,150
我只是
It's just...

671
00:57:21,620 --> 00:57:23,470
嗯 我懂的
Yeah, I know.

672
00:57:39,090 --> 00:57:41,830
我正在跟一個人約會
So, I'm seeing someone.

673
00:57:41,860 --> 00:57:43,730
你怎么也猜不到是誰
You'll never guess who.

674
00:57:44,970 --> 00:57:46,280
我們是當世間只剩下兩個人時
We're the last 2 people

675
00:57:46,280 --> 00:57:48,670
才可能在一起的兩個人
in the world who ever get to get together.

676
00:57:48,700 --> 00:57:50,440
而現在
But here we are.

677
00:57:50,440 --> 00:57:52,420
我們正是這世間僅剩的兩個人
The last 2 people in the world.

678
00:57:52,450 --> 00:57:53,550
你剛剛說什么
What did you say?

679
00:57:53,570 --> 00:57:55,810
我在寫作 亞瑟 噓
I'm writing, Arthur, hush.

680
00:57:56,150 --> 00:57:59,350
吉姆和我活在一種意外的幸福中
Jim and I live in an accidental happiness.

681
00:57:59,380 --> 00:58:02,460
如同海上失事的漂流者 在陌生的海岸重建新家園
Like castaways making their home on strange shores.

682
00:58:02,490 --> 00:58:04,640
“陌生的海岸”我喜歡這里
"Strange shores". I love it.

683
00:58:04,660 --> 00:58:06,140
真的嗎 你不用哄我
You do? You don't have to say that.

684
00:58:06,160 --> 00:58:08,570
- 我知道 - 你不吃這個吧
- I know. - You're not going to eat this?

685
00:58:10,750 --> 00:58:12,750
你覺得那個可疑嗎
That seemed fishy to you?

686
00:58:14,370 --> 00:58:15,870
接著看
Keep reading.

687
00:58:15,890 --> 00:58:17,420
有趣的是
It's funny.

688
00:58:17,440 --> 00:58:19,660
我們都懷有夢想
We all have dreams.

689
00:58:20,040 --> 00:58:23,980
我們曾計劃未來 以為自己是命運的舵手
We planned our futures like we're the captains of our fates.

690
00:58:24,150 --> 00:58:25,850
然而我們只是命運的乘客
But we are passengers.

691
00:58:25,870 --> 00:58:28,590
隨命運而去
We go where fate takes us.

692
00:58:31,360 --> 00:58:32,380
亞瑟
Arthur!

693
00:58:32,410 --> 00:58:34,390
這不是我們計劃中的人生
This isn't the life we planned.

694
00:58:34,420 --> 00:58:36,200
但這就是我們的人生
But it's ours.

695
00:58:36,220 --> 00:58:38,800
這是我生命中第一次
And for the first time in my life,

696
00:58:38,830 --> 00:58:41,020
不再感到孤獨
I don't feel

697
00:58:43,310 --> 00:58:45,840
我們原本不會遇見彼此的
We weren't supposed to find each other,

698
00:58:47,040 --> 00:58:48,730
但是我們還是相遇了
but we did.

699
00:58:49,360 --> 00:58:52,500
他讓我覺得我的生命還沒有結束
He makes me feel like my life isn't over.

700
00:58:52,650 --> 00:58:54,840
而是剛剛開始
Like it's just beginning.

701
00:58:55,410 --> 00:58:56,550
今天過得怎么樣
How was your day?

702
00:58:56,570 --> 00:58:58,880
挺好的 我寫了幾頁
Good, I wrote a few pages.

703
00:58:58,910 --> 00:59:01,270
你發現有什么能幫我們的東西了嗎
Did you find anything that can help us?

704
00:59:04,590 --> 00:59:07,070
- 發現了 - 這些是真的嗎
- I did. - Are they real?

705
00:59:07,090 --> 00:59:09,300
我親自剪下來的
I cut them myself.

706
00:59:12,410 --> 00:59:15,950
對于兩個不幸的人來說 我們已經很幸運了
You know for 2 unlucky people, we sure got pretty lucky.

707
00:59:20,780 --> 00:59:22,230
注意
Attention.

708
00:59:22,260 --> 00:59:25,980
你可能想來瞭望區看看
You may wish to proceed to a Viewing Area.

709
00:59:25,990 --> 00:59:30,220
我們馬上要和大角星擦過
The Avalon will slingshot around the star Arcturus.

710
00:59:31,260 --> 00:59:33,420
我的天
Oh my god...

711
01:00:08,140 --> 01:00:10,250
太奇妙了
That was amazing.

712
01:00:11,830 --> 01:00:13,990
我們就像是一個巨星
We were a giant.

713
01:00:18,150 --> 01:00:20,520
這個宇宙是給你的禮物
The universe is a present to you.

714
01:00:20,720 --> 01:00:22,200
什么
What?

715
01:00:23,270 --> 01:00:25,390
生日快樂
Happy birthday.

716
01:00:31,930 --> 01:00:40,540
祝你生日快樂 祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you... Happy birthday to you...

717
01:00:40,560 --> 01:00:44,910
祝奧羅拉生日快樂
Happy birthday, dear Aurora...

718
01:00:44,940 --> 01:00:49,360
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you.

719
01:00:51,110 --> 01:00:53,130
生日酒敬過生日的你
A birthday drink for the birthday girl.

720
01:00:53,160 --> 01:00:54,350
你都不問問我身份證上多大了嗎
Aren't you going to ask for my I.D.?

721
01:00:54,350 --> 01:00:55,510
我可能還不能喝酒呢
I might not be old enough to drink.

722
01:00:55,540 --> 01:00:58,470
噢 我不會在一個紳士面前問你的年齡的
Oh, I'd never ask your age in front of a gentleman.

723
01:00:58,500 --> 01:00:59,930
吉姆可不是什么紳士
Jim is no gentleman.

724
01:00:59,950 --> 01:01:02,800
不管怎樣 我和吉姆之間是沒有什么秘密的
Anyway there's no secrets between me and Jim.

725
01:01:03,710 --> 01:01:05,060
真的嗎
Is that so?

726
01:01:05,080 --> 01:01:08,790
你聽到她說的了 我馬上回來
You heard the lady. I will be right back.

727
01:01:22,960 --> 01:01:25,610
這杯生日酒太完美了 謝謝你
This is a perfect birthday drink, thank you.

728
01:01:25,640 --> 01:01:28,810
我還記得一年前的這天
I remember this day, a year ago.

729
01:01:28,840 --> 01:01:31,740
吉姆是如此的想見你
Jim was so looking forward to meeting you.

730
01:01:32,150 --> 01:01:33,560
什么
What?

731
01:01:33,870 --> 01:01:35,830
他怎么會想見我
How could he be looking forward to it?

732
01:01:35,850 --> 01:01:39,370
噢 他考慮了好幾個月到底要不要喚醒你
Oh, he spent months deciding whether to wake you up.

733
01:01:39,400 --> 01:01:42,410
他不停地跟我談論你
He couldn't stop talking about you.

734
01:01:46,170 --> 01:01:48,280
是吉姆喚醒我的
Jim woke me up.

735
01:01:48,740 --> 01:01:50,230
沒錯啊
Oh, yes.

736
01:01:50,760 --> 01:01:53,660
他說這是他這輩子最難做的決定
He said it was the hardest decision of his life,

737
01:01:53,690 --> 01:01:56,800
但我覺得現在挺好的
but I see it worked out just fine.

738
01:02:08,730 --> 01:02:10,240
什么
What?

739
01:02:12,600 --> 01:02:14,870
是你把我喚醒了嗎
Did you wake me up?

740
01:02:22,170 --> 01:02:24,170
是的 是我做的
Yes. I woke you up.

741
01:02:28,080 --> 01:02:29,830
你怎么能
How...

742
01:02:30,050 --> 01:02:32,030
你怎么能這么做
How could you do it?

743
01:02:34,420 --> 01:02:36,260
我試過不要那么做
I tried not to.

744
01:02:42,460 --> 01:02:44,500
我真覺得惡心
I'm going to be sick.

745
01:02:45,060 --> 01:02:47,180
我看不出來
I can't see!

746
01:02:48,420 --> 01:02:50,200
奧羅拉 求求你
Aurora, please.

747
01:02:50,230 --> 01:02:53,400
離我遠點
Stay away from me!

748
01:02:56,110 --> 01:02:59,330
我要離開這個飛船 我要離開這個飛船
I got to get off this ship. I got to get off this ship.

749
01:02:59,350 --> 01:03:00,850
我要離開這兒
I got to get off.

750
01:04:16,030 --> 01:04:18,150
我能和你談談嗎
Can I talk to you?

751
01:05:46,160 --> 01:05:48,010
奧羅拉
Aurora.

752
01:05:48,250 --> 01:05:51,550
我不知道說什么才能讓你感覺好點
I know nothing I can say will make this okay.

753
01:05:51,750 --> 01:05:53,740
但請聽我說
But please listen.

754
01:05:53,760 --> 01:05:55,790
我太孤獨了
I was so alone

755
01:05:56,160 --> 01:05:58,150
很長時間都是我一個人
for so long.

756
01:05:59,250 --> 01:06:01,660
我感覺自己好像從世界上消失了
I felt like I was disappearing.

757
01:06:02,290 --> 01:06:05,670
第一次見到你的那天晚上 我正準備
The night I first saw you, I was ready to...

758
01:06:08,650 --> 01:06:10,750
是你救了我
You saved my life.

759
01:06:13,040 --> 01:06:16,220
我知道沒有我沒有合適的借口
And I know that's no excuse for what I did.

760
01:06:17,540 --> 01:06:19,670
我讀了你寫的所有東西
I read everything you wrote.

761
01:06:19,700 --> 01:06:23,360
我愛上了你的聲音
And I fell in love with your voice

762
01:06:23,380 --> 01:06:26,480
也愛上了你思維的方式
and with the way your mind works.

763
01:06:26,510 --> 01:06:28,770
愛上了你
I fell in love with you.

764
01:06:29,950 --> 01:06:31,870
突然
And all of a sudden,

765
01:06:32,050 --> 01:06:35,960
我感覺自己沒有被困在這兒了
it was like I wasn't trapped anymore.

766
01:06:36,040 --> 01:06:39,510
我了無目的的人生突然有了活下去的意義
My pointless life suddenly had meaning.

767
01:06:41,750 --> 01:06:43,930
我希望這一切都沒有發生
And I wish I could take it back.

768
01:06:45,310 --> 01:06:47,090
但是我做不到
But I can't.

769
01:06:48,430 --> 01:06:49,960
奧羅拉 我不想失去你
Aurora, I don't want to lose you.

770
01:06:49,980 --> 01:06:52,350
我才不在乎
I don't care !!!

771
01:06:52,380 --> 01:06:54,580
我不在乎你想要什么
I don't care what you want!

772
01:06:54,600 --> 01:06:57,340
也不在乎你為什么喚醒我
I don't care why you woke me up!

773
01:06:57,750 --> 01:07:00,860
你奪走了我的人生
You took my life!

774
01:07:23,420 --> 01:07:24,970
請耐心等待
Please standby.

775
01:07:25,000 --> 01:07:28,700
組件的控制中心正在重新啟動
Your suite's control center is rebooting.

776
01:07:47,640 --> 01:07:49,550
診斷系統故障
Diagnostic system failure

777
01:08:03,440 --> 01:08:05,560
亞瑟 我好羨慕你
I envy you, Arthur.

778
01:08:06,150 --> 01:08:07,370
為什么
How so?

779
01:08:07,400 --> 01:08:09,420
你是有目的的
You have a purpose.

780
01:08:11,660 --> 01:08:13,680
你總是很開心
You're always happy.

781
01:08:14,020 --> 01:08:16,410
你的書怎么樣了
How's your book coming along?

782
01:08:16,580 --> 01:08:18,930
我以前從沒有寫過自己
I've never written about me before.

783
01:08:18,950 --> 01:08:20,880
我覺得這是我最好的作品了
I think it's some of the best work I've ever done,

784
01:08:20,900 --> 01:08:23,390
但是我不知道我為什么寫它
and I don't even know why I'm doing it.

785
01:08:24,090 --> 01:08:27,160
只有一個人可以讀它 但我卻不愿讓他讀
There's only one person who could read it and I can't stand him.

786
01:08:27,190 --> 01:08:31,300
大家都說時間可以治愈一切
They say time heals all wounds.

787
01:08:33,870 --> 01:08:36,430
破碎的心沒那么容易治愈 亞瑟
Broken hearts aren't that simple, Arthur.

788
01:08:39,060 --> 01:08:41,370
你不會明白的
You wouldn't understand.

789
01:08:42,190 --> 01:08:43,990
亞瑟
Arthur!

790
01:08:48,220 --> 01:08:50,180
周二 亞瑟是我的
Tuesday is my day with Arthur.

791
01:08:50,210 --> 01:08:52,110
今天周三
It's Wednesday.

792
01:08:59,720 --> 01:09:01,510
酒吧是你們的了
The bar is all yours.

793
01:09:09,870 --> 01:09:12,220
你要什么 威士忌嗎
What will you have? Whiskey?

794
01:09:12,990 --> 01:09:14,480
咖啡
Coffee.

795
01:09:14,500 --> 01:09:16,550
- 奧羅拉 我們愛你 - 奧羅拉 我們愛你
- Aurora, we love you! - Aurora, we love you!

796
01:09:16,570 --> 01:09:19,160
沒有你我們該怎么辦呢 我們會想你的
What are we going to do without you? We'll miss you.

797
01:09:21,310 --> 01:09:22,750
這是我認識的最勇敢的女人
This is the bravest woman I know.

798
01:09:22,770 --> 01:09:24,330
- 嗨 奧羅拉 - 嗨 奧羅拉
- Hi, Aurora! - Hi, Aurora!

799
01:09:24,350 --> 01:09:28,080
我保證我每天都會想你的
I promise that I will think of you every day.

800
01:09:28,100 --> 01:09:30,210
當你醒來的時候 我就已經離開了
When you wake up I'll be gone,

801
01:09:30,240 --> 01:09:33,440
但是要記住我永遠不會忘了你
but just know that I will never forget you.

802
01:09:33,860 --> 01:09:35,770
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend.

803
01:09:36,710 --> 01:09:39,220
我知道你在這兒一直都不開心
You're never happy here, I know.

804
01:09:39,520 --> 01:09:41,900
對你來說這些并不足夠
Nothing was ever enough for you.

805
01:09:43,360 --> 01:09:45,800
你知道 你不一定非要離開的 你可以
You know, you don't have to go. You could-

806
01:09:45,830 --> 01:09:48,850
你可以在這里做任何你想做的事情
You could do whatever it is you have to do right here.

807
01:09:50,720 --> 01:09:51,980
但是
But...

808
01:09:52,010 --> 01:09:55,780
既然你要走了 我想送你幾句祝福
Since you're going, here's my wish.

809
01:09:57,450 --> 01:10:01,750
希望你最終能遇見一個可以填滿你內心的人 并且
I hope you finally find someone who fills your heart. And...

810
01:10:02,440 --> 01:10:04,620
希望你能讓他走進你心里
I hope you let him in.

811
01:10:05,810 --> 01:10:07,400
我希望你能知道
I hope you realized you

812
01:10:07,410 --> 01:10:10,660
你沒必要做一些非常厲害的事讓自己覺得開心
don't have to do something amazing to be happy.

813
01:10:12,260 --> 01:10:13,560
走吧
Go.

814
01:10:13,580 --> 01:10:15,230
祝你愉快
Have fun.

815
01:10:15,690 --> 01:10:17,700
抓住機遇
Take chances.

816
01:10:19,150 --> 01:10:21,460
嗯 就這樣
Um, okay.

817
01:10:22,410 --> 01:10:24,410
愛你哦 奧羅拉
I love you, Aurora.

818
01:10:24,680 --> 01:10:26,070
拜
Bye.

819
01:10:28,870 --> 01:10:30,680
早上好 亞瑟
Morning, Arthur!

820
01:10:30,830 --> 01:10:31,860
請來杯咖啡
Coffee please.

821
01:10:31,890 --> 01:10:33,300
馬上來
Coming up.

822
01:10:38,670 --> 01:10:40,920
你要弄臟我的吧臺嗎
Are you soiling my bar stool?

823
01:10:40,940 --> 01:10:44,100
要想做成一件事你必須親力親為
You want to make things, you got to get your hands dirty.

824
01:10:44,200 --> 01:10:47,430
- 那你一直在做什么呢 - 改良
- And what have you been making? - Improvements.

825
01:10:48,060 --> 01:10:50,270
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

826
01:11:17,260 --> 01:11:19,190
到達一層
First floor.

827
01:11:31,810 --> 01:11:33,880
黃金級早餐
Gold-class breakfast.

828
01:11:33,910 --> 01:11:35,270
啊
Huh!

829
01:11:49,820 --> 01:11:52,430
我是船長 格斯 曼庫索
This is Deck Chief Gus Mancuso.

830
01:11:53,340 --> 01:11:56,570
是哪個家伙在我的飛船上種了棵樹
Who the hell planted a tree on my ship?

831
01:12:17,920 --> 01:12:20,480
- 是誰干的 - 是我
- Who did that? - I did.

832
01:12:20,510 --> 01:12:21,750
你是誰
Who are you?

833
01:12:21,770 --> 01:12:23,470
我是吉姆 普勒斯頓
Jim Preston.

834
01:12:24,610 --> 01:12:26,170
奧羅拉 萊恩
Aurora Lane.

835
01:12:26,200 --> 01:12:27,630
其他人也蘇醒了嗎
Anybody else awake?

836
01:12:27,660 --> 01:12:29,360
只有我們兩個
Just me and him.

837
01:12:29,680 --> 01:12:32,010
我們離開多久了
How far along are we?

838
01:12:32,040 --> 01:12:34,190
到現在88年了
88 years to go.

839
01:12:41,840 --> 01:12:44,010
休眠艙故障
Hibernation failure.

840
01:12:44,960 --> 01:12:46,700
據他們所講這是不可能的
They said that couldn't happen.

841
01:12:46,730 --> 01:12:50,770
但是現在有三個人蘇醒 三個休眠艙故障
But 3 people, 3 pod failures.

842
01:12:55,240 --> 01:12:57,960
你想象不到我花費多長時間想闖進這里的
You have no idea how long I've been trying to get in there.

843
01:12:57,990 --> 01:13:00,630
你現在進來了 不能亂動任何東西
Now that you're in. Don't touch anything.

844
01:13:00,660 --> 01:13:02,160
這就是你工作的地方
This is where you work?

845
01:13:02,180 --> 01:13:04,820
不 這里是乘務員的 我是船長
No, this is flight crew, I'm a Deck Chief.

846
01:13:05,520 --> 01:13:08,420
操作系統 并行服務器 導航計算機
OPS, Navigation comp.

847
01:13:10,580 --> 01:13:13,120
未授權人員
Unauthorized personnel.

848
01:13:13,990 --> 01:13:15,480
抱歉
Sorry.

849
01:13:17,140 --> 01:13:20,400
如果我猜的沒錯的話 我們仍在軌道上
If I'm reading this right, we're still on course.

850
01:13:20,430 --> 01:13:23,180
所以不管飛船出了什么問題 導航還是在運行中的
So whatever's wrong with the ship, NavComp's still on the job.

851
01:13:23,200 --> 01:13:24,740
飛船出故障了嗎
There's something wrong with the ship?

852
01:13:24,760 --> 01:13:26,430
三個休眠艙出現故障 是的
3 pod failures? Yeah.

853
01:13:26,460 --> 01:13:29,280
某個地方出現了問題 但問題究竟在哪兒
There's something wrong. Question is what.

854
01:13:31,760 --> 01:13:33,390
奇了怪了
That's strange.

855
01:13:33,420 --> 01:13:34,160
我應該可以
I should be getting

856
01:13:34,160 --> 01:13:35,980
把整個飛船徹底檢查一遍
diagnostics from all over the ship right here,

857
01:13:36,000 --> 01:13:38,290
問題是沒有數據
but there's no data.

858
01:13:39,740 --> 01:13:41,610
只能手動檢查整個系統
Got to check all the systems manually.

859
01:13:41,640 --> 01:13:43,470
我們就不能將飛船掉頭 返回地球嗎
Can't we turn the ship around? Go back to Earth?

860
01:13:43,490 --> 01:13:45,180
不行 我們行駛速度是二分之一光速
No, we're doing 50% of lightspeed.

861
01:13:45,210 --> 01:13:47,460
返回將花費我們同樣時間
Turning back would take just as much time as going on.

862
01:13:47,480 --> 01:13:49,290
好吧 那我們必須的做點兒什么
Well, there's got to be something we can do!

863
01:13:49,310 --> 01:13:52,050
不行 我們還是按原計劃飛行
Sorry, we're going where we're going.

864
01:13:54,590 --> 01:13:56,060
你還好嗎
You okay?

865
01:13:56,630 --> 01:13:58,360
休眠緩沖
Hibernation hangover.

866
01:13:58,380 --> 01:14:00,170
一直都這樣
Get it all the time.

867
01:14:00,320 --> 01:14:02,230
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

868
01:14:02,260 --> 01:14:05,980
兩年了 你還種其他樹了嗎
2 years, huh? Any more trees I need to know about?

869
01:14:06,010 --> 01:14:07,410
小心
Look out!

870
01:14:11,750 --> 01:14:13,460
這種事從沒發生過
I've never seen this happen before.

871
01:14:13,470 --> 01:14:15,400
這些機器已經崩潰了
Those robots have been breaking down.

872
01:14:15,420 --> 01:14:18,590
這是第15個
This guy makes 15?

873
01:14:18,690 --> 01:14:19,650
15個了
15.

874
01:14:19,680 --> 01:14:21,360
今天早餐吧臺出故障了
The breakfast bar went crazy today.

875
01:14:21,390 --> 01:14:22,460
還有電梯
And the elevator.

876
01:14:22,480 --> 01:14:25,450
上周我的門壞了 我被困在客艙里了兩天
Last week my door broke. I was trapped in my cabin for 2 days.

877
01:14:25,470 --> 01:14:27,090
真的么
You were?

878
01:14:27,240 --> 01:14:30,520
這些都未曾出現過 至少在這個飛船上沒有
Things like that don't happen. Not on this ship.

879
01:14:30,540 --> 01:14:33,820
每個飛行艙有60個這樣的科技站
There are 60 of these tech-stations on every deck.

880
01:14:33,840 --> 01:14:35,580
這是對接縫
Docking slats.

881
01:14:35,600 --> 01:14:37,330
數據可以自動接收 懂了嗎
Data sinks automatically, you got it?

882
01:14:37,350 --> 01:14:39,050
- 懂 - 那就好
- Mm. - Yeah. - Okay.

883
01:14:39,080 --> 01:14:41,380
你負責一 二 飛行艙 你三四飛行艙
You take decks 1 and 2. You take decks 3 and 4.

884
01:14:41,410 --> 01:14:45,590
我到休眠站查看一下我們的休眠艙
I'm going down to the Hibernation Bay, to check our pods.

885
01:14:46,000 --> 01:14:48,110
現在可有看頭了
Now that should be interesting.

886
01:14:58,270 --> 01:15:00,790
你現在不是應該在飛行艙檢查嗎
Aren't you supposed to be making your rounds.

887
01:15:01,120 --> 01:15:03,040
我檢查完了
I finished.

888
01:15:05,150 --> 01:15:07,220
我查看了你的休眠艙
I checked your pod.

889
01:15:07,930 --> 01:15:10,550
問題很簡單 記錄芯片燒毀了
The problem's very simple. The clock chips burned out.

890
01:15:10,570 --> 01:15:13,390
這不應該啊 但這個比較簡單
It ain't supposed to happen, but pretty simple.

891
01:15:13,420 --> 01:15:15,080
我的休眠艙比較復雜
My pod's more complicated.

892
01:15:15,100 --> 01:15:17,940
同時發生了一系列系統故障
A bunch of system failures, it all happened at the same time,

893
01:15:17,970 --> 01:15:20,530
整個系統就亂了套
the whole damn thing went haywire.

894
01:15:22,170 --> 01:15:24,460
這也是導致我不舒服的原因
Which explains why I'm feeling so bad.

895
01:15:24,490 --> 01:15:26,780
但是奧羅拉的休眠艙
But Aurora's pod...

896
01:15:29,970 --> 01:15:32,080
是你打開的吧
You did this.

897
01:15:34,100 --> 01:15:35,150
是的
Yeah.

898
01:15:35,190 --> 01:15:37,480
我總覺得你和奧羅拉困在一起
All this time, I'm thinking you're one lucky son of a bitch

899
01:15:37,500 --> 01:15:39,700
真他媽的走運
to get stuck with Aurora.

900
01:15:42,500 --> 01:15:45,080
但并不是幸運吧
It wasn't luck, was it?

901
01:15:45,100 --> 01:15:46,260
不是
No.

902
01:15:46,290 --> 01:15:47,960
她發現了
She knows?

903
01:15:47,990 --> 01:15:49,950
是的
She knows.

904
01:15:51,220 --> 01:15:52,970
你一個人多久了
How long were you alone?

905
01:15:52,990 --> 01:15:54,720
一年
A year.

906
01:15:58,020 --> 01:15:59,830
現在還是一樣
Still...

907
01:16:01,190 --> 01:16:03,000
該死
Damn.

908
01:16:21,180 --> 01:16:23,030
跟吉姆的一樣
Same as Jim's.

909
01:16:23,610 --> 01:16:25,680
系統關閉了
System shut downs.

910
01:16:25,700 --> 01:16:28,430
所有地方 但是出現沒有必然的關聯
Everywhere, but no apparent connection.

911
01:16:29,960 --> 01:16:32,570
你看到休眠艙了
You saw the hibernation pods?

912
01:16:32,630 --> 01:16:34,370
看到了
I saw.

913
01:16:35,660 --> 01:16:37,670
你也知道了
So you know.

914
01:16:38,560 --> 01:16:40,530
吉姆干的好事
What Jim did.

915
01:16:42,380 --> 01:16:44,280
是的
Yeah.

916
01:16:44,780 --> 01:16:46,120
然后呢
And?

917
01:16:46,140 --> 01:16:49,090
- 這不歸我管 - 他喚醒了我
- It's not my duty... - He woke me up!

918
01:16:49,110 --> 01:16:51,820
- 他奪走了我的生命 - 我知道 我也很抱歉
- He took away my life! - I know and I'm sorry.

919
01:16:51,840 --> 01:16:54,860
- 可是我還有事 - 這是謀殺
- But there's work I like... - It's murder!

920
01:16:57,440 --> 01:16:59,030
你說的沒錯 奧羅拉
You're right, Aurora.

921
01:16:59,050 --> 01:17:00,440
但是溺水的人
But the drowning man will

922
01:17:00,440 --> 01:17:02,770
總是試圖拉其他人下水
always try to drag somebody down with him.

923
01:17:02,810 --> 01:17:06,450
這種做法是錯誤的 可是他也快要溺水而亡了
It ain't right, but the man is drowning.

924
01:17:07,450 --> 01:17:09,570
這是第16個
This one makes 16.

925
01:17:12,500 --> 01:17:14,220
沒錯
Yeah.

926
01:17:16,200 --> 01:17:18,650
嘿 你還好嗎
Hey. Are you okay?

927
01:17:20,410 --> 01:17:23,100
- 你應該去休息 - 沒錯
- You should go rest. - Yeah.

928
01:17:23,770 --> 01:17:26,230
那就休息幾個小時之后
But just for a couple of hours and then,

929
01:17:26,230 --> 01:17:28,570
我們重回今天早上的問題
back at it first thing in the morning.

930
01:18:21,430 --> 01:18:24,350
重力消失
Gravity loss

931
01:19:32,290 --> 01:19:33,810
重力啟動
Gravity drive

932
01:19:33,830 --> 01:19:34,990
重力啟動
Gravity drive

933
01:20:15,250 --> 01:20:17,090
剛重力消失的時候我在游泳
I was in the pool when the gravity gave out.

934
01:20:17,120 --> 01:20:18,150
你沒事吧
Are you okay?

935
01:20:18,180 --> 01:20:19,870
我們得去找格斯
We need to find Gus.

936
01:20:21,260 --> 01:20:23,590
格斯 格斯
Gus! Gus!

937
01:20:23,850 --> 01:20:25,150
重力消失說明
Gravity loss means that whatever

938
01:20:25,150 --> 01:20:27,140
飛船重要部位出了問題
is wrong is starting to hit the big ticket items.

939
01:20:27,160 --> 01:20:28,830
這可不妙
Not good.

940
01:20:29,410 --> 01:20:31,490
每一次失靈都是部件燒毀
Every failure is a burnout process,

941
01:20:31,490 --> 01:20:33,920
所有部件都處于超載狀態
everything on board is thinking too hard.

942
01:20:34,370 --> 01:20:35,980
怎么會這樣
Why?

943
01:20:36,550 --> 01:20:39,020
計算機顯示了故障發生的整個過程
Computer, display these failures over time.

944
01:20:39,040 --> 01:20:41,650
現實時間線
Processing timeline.

945
01:20:42,640 --> 01:20:44,780
級聯失效
Cascade failure.

946
01:20:45,240 --> 01:20:47,900
2年前開始出現了功率驟增
It started 2 years ago, power surge.

947
01:20:48,570 --> 01:20:51,230
1天中出現了17個故障
17 failures in 1 day.

948
01:20:51,460 --> 01:20:53,780
包括1498號休眠艙
Including hibernation pod 1498.

949
01:20:53,800 --> 01:20:55,430
就是我
That's me.

950
01:20:55,460 --> 01:20:57,130
把我喚醒了
Woke me up.

951
01:20:58,650 --> 01:21:01,180
- 那天發生了什么 - 一些大問題
- What happened that day? - Something big.

952
01:21:01,210 --> 01:21:03,690
某處的主要系統宕機了
A major system went down somewhere.

953
01:21:04,060 --> 01:21:06,060
飛船上的其它組件都試圖分擔負荷
Everything else on board is trying to pick up the load

954
01:21:06,090 --> 01:21:07,860
但實在是杯水車薪
but the load's too heavy.

955
01:21:07,870 --> 01:21:10,170
不論如何我們都要找到問題所在
Whatever started this we got to find it.

956
01:21:10,190 --> 01:21:13,360
- 要修復它 - 問題有多嚴重呢
- And fix it. - How bad can this get?

957
01:21:13,840 --> 01:21:16,120
對現有數據進行風險分析
Give me a risk analysis based on this data.

958
01:21:16,150 --> 01:21:17,800
運算進行中
Extrapolating.

959
01:21:17,830 --> 01:21:20,300
將造成航行中止
Emission critical failure is imminent.

960
01:21:20,330 --> 01:21:23,650
將失效的系統 生命維持系統 聚變反應堆
Failing systems: Life support. Fusion reactor.

961
01:21:23,680 --> 01:21:25,530
我們困在這了
So we're stranded...

962
01:21:25,550 --> 01:21:26,760
離子推進器
Ion drive.

963
01:21:26,780 --> 01:21:28,980
船要沉了
... on a sinking ship.

964
01:21:37,070 --> 01:21:39,070
到達主工程區
Main Engineering.

965
01:21:39,090 --> 01:21:42,480
能夠造成這種重創的情況并不多
Not a lot of things big enough to hit this ship that hard.

966
01:21:44,980 --> 01:21:48,370
我們只能自己排查 去找到問題了
With diagnostics out, we'll have to find it ourselves.

967
01:21:48,380 --> 01:21:50,250
從哪里開始
Where do we start?

968
01:21:50,880 --> 01:21:52,300
格斯
Gus!

969
01:21:55,970 --> 01:21:59,470
掃描完畢 分析數據
Scan complete. Analyzing data.

970
01:22:00,840 --> 01:22:02,730
發現612個疾病
612 disorders found

971
01:22:02,730 --> 01:22:04,750
系統說我出了什么問題
What does it say is wrong with me?

972
01:22:04,770 --> 01:22:06,250
一點小問題
It's a few things.

973
01:22:06,280 --> 01:22:09,300
發現你得了612個病
612 disorders found.

974
01:22:09,330 --> 01:22:11,250
讓我出去
Get me out of here.

975
01:22:25,260 --> 01:22:26,900
診斷結果是什么
What's the prognosis?

976
01:22:26,920 --> 01:22:28,490
沒有醫生在場
Critical diagnosis cannot

977
01:22:28,490 --> 01:22:31,260
不可與患者討論病情
be discussed without a doctor on attendance.

978
01:22:31,280 --> 01:22:35,290
重寫我的權限 身份2317
Override on my authority, I.D. 2317.

979
01:22:35,310 --> 01:22:36,580
顯示結果
Lay it on me, doc.

980
01:22:36,600 --> 01:22:38,520
全身性系統壞死
Pan-systemic necrosis.

981
01:22:38,550 --> 01:22:41,570
進行性器官衰竭 誘因未知
Progressive organ failure. Cause unknown.

982
01:22:41,590 --> 01:22:44,130
該死的休眠艙 就是它導致的
My goofy hibernation pod, that's the cause.

983
01:22:44,150 --> 01:22:47,220
- 治療方法是什么 - 有多種方法
- What's the treatment? - Various treatments are possible.

984
01:22:47,250 --> 01:22:50,590
但對延長患者壽命無明顯作用
None will meaningfully extend the patient's life.

985
01:22:53,450 --> 01:22:54,730
我還能活多久
How long have I got?

986
01:22:54,760 --> 01:22:58,220
你的生命正在終結
Your end of life transition is already under way.

987
01:22:58,820 --> 01:23:00,790
這些藥物會緩解
These sedatives will alleviate

988
01:23:00,790 --> 01:23:03,410
你最后時間的痛苦
your suffering during these final hours.

989
01:23:20,470 --> 01:23:22,010
格斯
Gus?

990
01:23:26,710 --> 01:23:28,810
我想一個人靜靜
I need a minute.

991
01:23:58,120 --> 01:24:00,970
航行遇到困難
We are experiencing difficulties in flight.

992
01:24:01,000 --> 01:24:03,270
- 格斯 - 格斯
- Gus! - Gus!

993
01:24:03,290 --> 01:24:04,260
他會去哪里
Where can he be?

994
01:24:04,280 --> 01:24:07,680
為了您的安全 請您回到房間
For your own safety, please return to your cabins.

995
01:24:10,800 --> 01:24:13,720
航行遇到困難
We are experiencing difficulties in flight.

996
01:24:13,880 --> 01:24:17,620
為了您的安全 請回到您的房間
For your own safety, please return to your cabins.

997
01:24:17,650 --> 01:24:20,380
我應該把藥帶著的
Should have took the damn pills.

998
01:24:20,380 --> 01:24:23,500
- 我去幫你拿 - 不 陪我留下
- I'll go get them. - No, stay here with me

999
01:24:24,520 --> 01:24:26,240
坐下吧
Sit.

1000
01:24:30,560 --> 01:24:33,290
你們要相互照顧
You two take care of each other.

1001
01:24:42,210 --> 01:24:44,520
我的身份手環
My I.D..

1002
01:24:45,430 --> 01:24:48,440
能讓你去船上任何地方
Get you where you need to go.

1003
01:24:49,100 --> 01:24:51,290
修好它
Fix the ship.

1004
01:24:52,040 --> 01:24:54,660
找出故障所在
Find out what's wrong with her.

1005
01:24:57,260 --> 01:24:59,290
我看起來怎么樣
How do I look?

1006
01:24:59,640 --> 01:25:02,110
您看起來很英俊
You look magnificent.

1007
01:25:02,670 --> 01:25:05,860
女士們都喜歡穿制服的男人
Ladies love a dressed man.

1008
01:25:14,210 --> 01:25:16,280
我們現在該怎么辦
What do we do now?

1009
01:25:22,760 --> 01:25:24,470
這可糟透了
This can't be good.

1010
01:25:27,490 --> 01:25:29,150
我要回工程區
I'm going back to Engineering.

1011
01:25:29,180 --> 01:25:31,120
你能修好嗎
Can you fix this?

1012
01:25:31,310 --> 01:25:32,990
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.

1013
01:25:36,170 --> 01:25:37,670
我們走
Let's go!

1014
01:25:59,920 --> 01:26:01,390
亞瑟
Arthur!

1015
01:26:16,870 --> 01:26:18,290
走
Let's go!

1016
01:26:21,550 --> 01:26:23,660
到達主工程區
Main Engineering.

1017
01:26:23,760 --> 01:26:25,620
我們能不能再叫醒一些人
Can't we wake up some of the crew?

1018
01:26:25,650 --> 01:26:27,020
他們需要很長時間才能適應
It will take them take too long to recover,

1019
01:26:27,020 --> 01:26:28,040
沒那么多時間了
we don't have that kind of time.

1020
01:26:28,070 --> 01:26:30,230
我們到底要找什么
What are we even looking for?

1021
01:26:30,430 --> 01:26:32,340
故障點
Something broken.

1022
01:26:32,610 --> 01:26:34,180
大的故障點
Something big.

1023
01:26:34,340 --> 01:26:35,940
來吧
Come on!

1024
01:26:37,360 --> 01:26:39,670
- 這壞了嗎 - 看起來是好的
- Is it broken? - It seems okay.

1025
01:26:39,700 --> 01:26:40,780
下一個看什么
What next?

1026
01:26:40,810 --> 01:26:43,010
動力裝置 這邊
Power Plant. This way.

1027
01:26:48,780 --> 01:26:50,590
快啊
Come on.

1028
01:26:50,770 --> 01:26:52,500
整個都關閉了 肯定出了什么問題
Whole section's closed off. Something's wrong.

1029
01:26:52,530 --> 01:26:54,320
我們就是在找問題啊
We're looking for wrong.

1030
01:26:54,340 --> 01:26:56,080
想辦法打開它
Try to open it.

1031
01:27:07,380 --> 01:27:08,780
警告
Warning.

1032
01:27:09,220 --> 01:27:12,640
壓力艙門鎖定
Pressure door. Lock down initiated.

1033
01:27:15,160 --> 01:27:16,900
請關閉艙門
Please secure all doors.

1034
01:27:16,920 --> 01:27:18,950
抓緊
Hold on!

1035
01:27:21,050 --> 01:27:23,880
警告 氧量降至危險值
Warning. Dangerous oxygen level.

1036
01:27:23,910 --> 01:27:26,260
請關閉艙門
Please secure all doors.

1037
01:27:35,340 --> 01:27:39,720
氧量降至危險值 請關閉艙門
Dangerous oxygen level. Please secure all doors.

1038
01:27:43,790 --> 01:27:45,860
抓住這個
Grab it!

1039
01:27:51,970 --> 01:27:55,200
增壓艙加壓失敗
Pressurizing cabin unsuccessful.

1040
01:28:03,460 --> 01:28:05,550
壓力正常
Pressure normalized.

1041
01:28:06,120 --> 01:28:08,250
氧量恢復
Oxygen level restored.

1042
01:28:08,280 --> 01:28:10,160
已封閉
End lock down.

1043
01:28:10,190 --> 01:28:12,890
船上有一個洞
A hole in the ship.

1044
01:28:14,860 --> 01:28:16,720
不止一個
More than one.

1045
01:28:19,710 --> 01:28:20,640
怎么會這樣
How did that even happen?

1046
01:28:20,640 --> 01:28:22,160
飛船可能遭遇過隕石
This ship is supposed to be meteor-proof.

1047
01:28:22,180 --> 01:28:24,310
我猜有一塊貫穿了船體
I guess one got through.

1048
01:28:32,060 --> 01:28:33,520
很熱
It's hot!

1049
01:28:40,140 --> 01:28:42,160
我想我們找到問題了
I think we found it.

1050
01:28:51,720 --> 01:28:54,180
這是反應堆控制計算機
It's the reactor control computer.

1051
01:29:00,130 --> 01:29:01,770
兩年前就是它撞擊了我們
This is what hit us 2 years ago.

1052
01:29:01,790 --> 01:29:03,350
吉姆
Jim.

1053
01:29:03,890 --> 01:29:06,090
我們怎么可能修得好這個
How can we fix this?

1054
01:29:08,960 --> 01:29:09,990
我們要死了
We're going to die.

1055
01:29:10,010 --> 01:29:12,210
所有的組件都有備用的
There's replacement parts for everything.

1056
01:29:16,580 --> 01:29:17,810
打光
Light.

1057
01:29:17,830 --> 01:29:19,240
抱歉
Sorry.

1058
01:29:21,040 --> 01:29:22,160
一旦我取出這個模塊
As soon as I pull this module,

1059
01:29:22,160 --> 01:29:23,730
整個電腦就停機了
the entire computer is going to shut down.

1060
01:29:23,760 --> 01:29:25,570
然后會怎么樣
Well, what happens then?

1061
01:29:26,990 --> 01:29:29,560
我會盡快把新的換回去
I'll get it back up as quickly as I can.

1062
01:29:33,420 --> 01:29:34,950
快點
Hurry!

1063
01:29:37,110 --> 01:29:38,490
吉姆
Jim!

1064
01:29:41,190 --> 01:29:43,790
控制電腦已修復
Control computer restored.

1065
01:29:44,670 --> 01:29:46,740
排氣裝置異常
Venting reactor.

1066
01:29:48,480 --> 01:29:49,670
我們不是修好了嗎
But we fixed it!

1067
01:29:49,700 --> 01:29:53,870
反應堆排氣失敗 需手動操作
Reactor vent failed. Manual override required.

1068
01:29:59,150 --> 01:30:00,690
排氣失敗
Vent failure.

1069
01:30:00,720 --> 01:30:02,460
- 拜托 - 吉姆
- Come on! - Jim.

1070
01:30:06,850 --> 01:30:08,580
外門無響應
Outer door non-responsive.

1071
01:30:08,600 --> 01:30:10,650
這是什么意思
What does that mean?

1072
01:30:12,390 --> 01:30:14,170
外門卡住了
The outer door is jammed.

1073
01:30:14,190 --> 01:30:16,050
我們要打開那扇門讓反應堆冷卻
We got to open that door and cool the reactor down

1074
01:30:16,080 --> 01:30:17,990
否則整個飛船都要爆炸
or the whole ship's going to blow.

1075
01:30:18,020 --> 01:30:18,820
怎么打開
How?

1076
01:30:18,840 --> 01:30:20,440
我要去那里
I got to go out there.

1077
01:30:20,480 --> 01:30:22,550
從外面打開它
Open it from the outside.

1078
01:30:23,060 --> 01:30:25,470
我把門打開 然后去清理
I open the door I get cleared.

1079
01:30:25,680 --> 01:30:27,650
你負責排出熱氣
You blow that fire into space.

1080
01:30:27,680 --> 01:30:30,280
- 你去清理 - 你用無線和我聯絡
- You get cleared? - You can talk to me through this.

1081
01:30:30,280 --> 01:30:32,820
門開了你會怎么樣
What happens to you when that door opens?

1082
01:30:42,920 --> 01:30:45,420
我有防熱罩 應該沒事
Heat shield. It might help.

1083
01:30:53,790 --> 01:30:55,400
你可能需要這個
You might need this.

1084
01:31:09,010 --> 01:31:10,760
會沒事的
It's going to be okay.

1085
01:31:20,290 --> 01:31:21,840
我得走了
I better go.

1086
01:31:26,740 --> 01:31:28,180
吉姆
Jim.

1087
01:31:28,540 --> 01:31:30,020
吉姆
Jim.

1088
01:31:32,410 --> 01:31:34,140
一定要回來
Come back to me.

1089
01:31:35,680 --> 01:31:38,290
沒有你我沒法在這船上生活
I can't live on the ship without you.

1090
01:32:03,430 --> 01:32:06,050
警告 已達臨界溫度
Warning. Temperature critical.

1091
01:32:06,080 --> 01:32:07,440
啊
Ahhhh!

1092
01:32:19,350 --> 01:32:20,890
怎么了
What's wrong?

1093
01:32:21,690 --> 01:32:23,510
發生什么了 你還好嗎
What's the matter? Are you okay?

1094
01:32:23,540 --> 01:32:25,040
沒事 你繼續
Nothing. Go.

1095
01:32:25,070 --> 01:32:26,030
你確定嗎
You sure?

1096
01:32:26,060 --> 01:32:27,460
你去吧
Go.

1097
01:32:34,960 --> 01:32:36,770
我在通風管里
I'm in the vent tube.

1098
01:32:37,720 --> 01:32:40,720
新定位點 重置系繩
New anchor point. Reset tether.

1099
01:32:43,980 --> 01:32:45,630
我看到門了
I see the door.

1100
01:32:46,210 --> 01:32:48,630
溫度上升中
Temperature level rising.

1101
01:32:55,360 --> 01:32:58,290
警告 到達臨界溫度
Warning. Temperature critical.

1102
01:33:04,120 --> 01:33:06,640
外殼不穩定
Containment unstable.

1103
01:33:07,780 --> 01:33:08,960
你在哪
Where are you?

1104
01:33:08,990 --> 01:33:10,070
我在門這里
I'm at the door.

1105
01:33:10,090 --> 01:33:11,720
我準備好了 就等你了
I'm ready, just say when.

1106
01:33:11,740 --> 01:33:13,390
好了
There goes.

1107
01:33:16,330 --> 01:33:19,390
這門打不開 我要換條路
The door won't open. I'll have to bypass it.

1108
01:33:21,370 --> 01:33:23,860
溫度上升中
Temperature level rising.

1109
01:33:24,480 --> 01:33:25,810
吉姆 快點
Jim, come on!

1110
01:33:25,840 --> 01:33:27,580
拜托 快點
Please, hurry!

1111
01:33:27,600 --> 01:33:30,990
- 好的 我再試一次 - 你好了告訴我
- Okay, I'm trying it again. - Tell me when you're cleared.

1112
01:33:34,740 --> 01:33:35,440
不
No!

1113
01:33:35,460 --> 01:33:36,720
什么
What?

1114
01:33:37,520 --> 01:33:39,240
怎么了
What's going on?

1115
01:33:39,410 --> 01:33:40,910
吉姆
Jim?

1116
01:33:44,990 --> 01:33:46,050
吉姆
Jim!

1117
01:33:46,070 --> 01:33:48,200
這門沒法一直開著
The door won't stay open.

1118
01:33:49,190 --> 01:33:53,000
我可能要留在這里 按著這個門
I think I have to stay here, hold the door open.

1119
01:33:53,770 --> 01:33:55,050
不
No!

1120
01:33:55,080 --> 01:33:56,690
不行 快離開那
No way, get out of there!

1121
01:33:56,710 --> 01:33:58,280
不行
I can't.

1122
01:33:58,430 --> 01:33:59,940
吉姆
Jim...

1123
01:34:00,050 --> 01:34:01,870
我們快沒時間了
We're out of time.

1124
01:34:03,020 --> 01:34:04,730
外殼不穩定
Containment unstable.

1125
01:34:04,770 --> 01:34:06,300
吉姆
Jim?

1126
01:34:12,370 --> 01:34:14,280
反應堆排氣
Vent the reactor.

1127
01:34:20,200 --> 01:34:23,090
不行 你不懂
No, you don't understand!

1128
01:34:23,410 --> 01:34:26,170
如果我現在打開門你會死的
If I open the door right now it will kill you!

1129
01:34:26,190 --> 01:34:27,350
但愿不會
I'm hoping not.

1130
01:34:27,380 --> 01:34:29,250
回來 我們再想想其他辦法
Come back in, we'll think of something else.

1131
01:34:29,280 --> 01:34:31,200
沒有其他辦法了
There is nothing else.

1132
01:34:32,370 --> 01:34:33,840
吉姆
Jim!

1133
01:34:34,420 --> 01:34:36,240
- 沒事的 - 不 有事
- It's okay. - No, it's not okay!

1134
01:34:36,260 --> 01:34:39,470
- 奧羅拉 - 警告 溫度超過范圍
- Aurora - Warning. Temperature level exceeded.

1135
01:34:39,490 --> 01:34:42,050
這不是我預想要發生的事
This is not how I suppose is going to happen!

1136
01:34:42,780 --> 01:34:44,230
奧羅拉 這架飛船就要壞了
Aurora, this ship is going to go.

1137
01:34:44,250 --> 01:34:46,860
我不管 你死了 我也就死了
I don't care! You die, I die.

1138
01:34:47,140 --> 01:34:50,360
這架飛船上還有五千多名乘客 奧羅拉
There are 5,000 other people on this ship, Aurora.

1139
01:34:51,500 --> 01:34:53,460
我們必須得這樣做
We have to do this.

1140
01:34:54,030 --> 01:34:56,360
到達最大壓力值
Maximum pressure reached.

1141
01:34:59,530 --> 01:35:01,980
動手吧 現在
Do it. Now.

1142
01:35:02,810 --> 01:35:05,470
到達最大機艙壓力值
Maximum cabin pressure reached.

1143
01:35:26,510 --> 01:35:28,630
溫度下降中
Temperature dropping.

1144
01:35:30,010 --> 01:35:31,390
吉姆
Jim.

1145
01:35:49,430 --> 01:35:51,640
- 吉姆 - 排氣成功
- Jim. - Vent successful.

1146
01:35:51,670 --> 01:35:54,020
重啟程序中
Rebooting process initiated.

1147
01:35:54,050 --> 01:35:56,240
吉姆 拜托說句話
Jim, please say something.

1148
01:36:32,660 --> 01:36:35,160
宇航服壓力下降中
Suit pressure dropping.

1149
01:36:37,710 --> 01:36:40,880
馬上回到飛船
Return to ship immediately.

1150
01:36:41,900 --> 01:36:43,350
奧羅拉
Aurora.

1151
01:36:44,870 --> 01:36:46,110
成功了
It worked!

1152
01:36:46,130 --> 01:36:48,270
你做到了 你可以回來了
You did it, you can come in!

1153
01:36:48,440 --> 01:36:50,040
呃 那個
Yeah, about that...

1154
01:36:50,070 --> 01:36:51,830
怎么了 你受傷了嗎
What's the matter? Are you hurt?

1155
01:36:52,510 --> 01:36:54,380
我被炸離了管道
I got blown out of the tube.

1156
01:36:54,400 --> 01:36:55,280
什么
What?

1157
01:36:55,310 --> 01:36:58,180
我的系繩壞了 沒法回到飛船上了
My tether broke. I can't get back to the ship.

1158
01:36:58,930 --> 01:37:00,950
我出去 我出去拉你進來
I'll come out. I'll come out. I'll pull you in.

1159
01:37:00,970 --> 01:37:03,830
警告 氧氣到達臨界值
Warning. Oxygen level critical.

1160
01:37:03,860 --> 01:37:06,710
馬上回到飛船
Return to ship immediately.

1161
01:37:14,590 --> 01:37:17,460
奧羅拉 對不起
Aurora, I'm sorry...

1162
01:37:19,150 --> 01:37:20,390
所有的事情
... for everything.

1163
01:37:20,420 --> 01:37:22,250
閉嘴 我來了
Shut up, I'm coming.

1164
01:37:22,650 --> 01:37:27,380
我多希望我們在90年后再相遇
I wish we'd have met in 90 years.

1165
01:37:32,150 --> 01:37:35,780
我會 給你建個房子
I... I'd build you a house.

1166
01:37:39,940 --> 01:37:42,160
我會 看你寫的書
I'll read your book.

1167
01:37:44,400 --> 01:37:46,280
那該是多么美好
It's a good feeling.

1168
01:37:58,520 --> 01:37:59,770
系繩已連接
Tether attached.

1169
01:37:59,790 --> 01:38:02,060
定位吉姆 普勒斯頓
Locate Jim Preston.

1170
01:38:06,130 --> 01:38:09,140
吉姆 普勒斯頓 已定位
Jim Preston, located.

1171
01:38:09,710 --> 01:38:11,480
我來接你了
I'm coming to get you.

1172
01:38:36,040 --> 01:38:37,640
吉姆
Jim!

1173
01:39:37,310 --> 01:39:39,720
抱歉 病人已身亡
I'm sorry. The patient is dead.

1174
01:39:39,740 --> 01:39:41,200
那就復活他
Well, resuscitate him!

1175
01:39:41,220 --> 01:39:44,730
尸體手術須有授權醫療監督資格
Postmortem operations require authorized medical supervision.

1176
01:39:44,750 --> 01:39:46,430
不
No!

1177
01:39:54,800 --> 01:39:57,190
重寫 重寫我的資格
Override! Override on my authority!

1178
01:39:57,210 --> 01:40:00,600
身份 17
I.D. 17...

1179
01:40:02,040 --> 01:40:03,450
2

1180
01:40:03,780 --> 01:40:05,540
2

1181
01:40:05,990 --> 01:40:07,120
2317

1182
01:40:07,140 --> 01:40:10,070
2317 I.D.2317

1183
01:40:17,890 --> 01:40:19,720
不建議用多個步驟
Multiple procedures are not recommended.

1184
01:40:19,740 --> 01:40:21,260
重寫
Override!

1185
01:40:21,290 --> 01:40:22,920
快做 就現在
Do it, now!

1186
01:40:22,950 --> 01:40:24,600
執行中
Executing.

1187
01:41:23,940 --> 01:41:25,210
吉姆
Jim.

1188
01:41:27,290 --> 01:41:28,810
吉姆
Jim.

1189
01:41:56,510 --> 01:41:58,830
你把我救回來了
You brought me back.

1190
01:41:58,850 --> 01:42:00,440
是啊
Yeah.

1191
01:42:24,350 --> 01:42:25,190
謝謝
Thank you.

1192
01:42:25,190 --> 01:42:26,600
別動
Be still.

1193
01:42:26,630 --> 01:42:28,240
好的
Of course.

1194
01:43:13,200 --> 01:43:15,400
我要給你看樣東西
There's something I have to show you.

1195
01:43:15,420 --> 01:43:18,600
在命令模式中 這個醫療艙有個選項
In Command mode, it turns out the autodoc has a option

1196
01:43:18,620 --> 01:43:21,200
叫安定和暫停
called "Stabilize and Suspend".

1197
01:43:21,230 --> 01:43:24,070
它能停止一切代謝活動
It stops all metabolic activity.

1198
01:43:25,750 --> 01:43:26,980
你在說什么
What are you saying?

1199
01:43:27,010 --> 01:43:29,530
是格斯的主意 就像休眠一樣
It's Gus' idea. It can be like hibernation.

1200
01:43:29,550 --> 01:43:32,560
在醫療艙內 你可以重回休眠
Inside the autodoc, you can go back to sleep.

1201
01:43:36,730 --> 01:43:38,930
但是只有一個醫療艙
But there's only one autodoc.

1202
01:43:42,930 --> 01:43:44,340
是的
Yeah.

1203
01:43:46,490 --> 01:43:48,920
所以你要躺進里面
And you're going to lay down in it,

1204
01:43:49,030 --> 01:43:50,830
進入休眠
and fall asleep.

1205
01:43:51,610 --> 01:43:53,880
然后你會在新家園Ⅱ號醒來
And you'll wake up on Homestead Ⅱ,

1206
01:43:53,900 --> 01:43:55,930
繼續寫你的書
and you'll write you book.

1207
01:43:57,350 --> 01:44:00,800
你會完成你的旅行 完成你最初打算做的事情
You finish your journey. You do what you set out to do.

1208
01:44:09,110 --> 01:44:11,080
那你就孤身一人了
You'll be alone.

1209
01:44:12,150 --> 01:44:16,200
我以前也孤身一人 我會沒事的
I've been alone before and I'll be fine.

1210
01:44:17,250 --> 01:44:19,610
但是我就永遠都見不到你了
But I'll never see you again.

1211
01:44:22,740 --> 01:44:24,630
我會去見你的
I'll come and visit you.

1212
01:45:07,340 --> 01:45:09,870
星期二 亞瑟是我的
Tuesday is my day with Arthur.

1213
01:45:11,290 --> 01:45:12,950
一如既往的美麗
Lovely as ever.

1214
01:45:12,980 --> 01:45:15,300
謝謝你 亞瑟 你看起來也很帥
Thank you, Arthur. You're looking very well yourself.

1215
01:45:15,330 --> 01:45:17,100
多虧了你
Thanks to you.

1216
01:45:18,090 --> 01:45:19,630
那是什么
What's that?

1217
01:45:21,690 --> 01:45:24,680
我很久之前就想給你的東西
Something I wanted to give you for a long time.

1218
01:45:31,000 --> 01:45:33,030
很漂亮
It's beautiful.

1219
01:45:45,620 --> 01:45:48,420
這么久才開口
Took you long enough to ask.

1220
01:45:50,960 --> 01:45:54,350
香檳 我還是等等吧
Champagne. I'll wait.

1221
01:46:11,100 --> 01:46:12,980
多好的生活啊
Hell of a life.

1222
01:46:15,490 --> 01:46:17,390
多好的生活
Hell of a life.

1223
01:46:48,420 --> 01:46:51,810
船員喚醒程序初始化
Crew wake up process initiated.

1224
01:46:52,470 --> 01:46:52,510
同行伙伴們
My fellow passengers,

1225
01:46:54,530 --> 01:46:56,190
如果你們看到了這個
if you are reading this,

1226
01:46:56,190 --> 01:46:59,850
說明阿瓦隆號已經到達了目的地
then the starship Avalon has reached its destination.

1227
01:46:59,870 --> 01:47:01,980
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

1228
01:47:02,170 --> 01:47:04,580
當你們沉睡時 發生了許多事情
A lot happened while you slept.

1229
01:47:11,700 --> 01:47:13,560
有位朋友曾說
A friend once said,

1230
01:47:13,580 --> 01:47:16,840
不可總惦記著目的地
"You can't get so hung up on where you'd rather be

1231
01:47:16,860 --> 01:47:20,410
卻忘了去感受當下
that you forget to make the most of where you are.

1232
01:47:20,970 --> 01:47:23,430
我們曾一度迷失
We got lost along the way

1233
01:47:23,980 --> 01:47:25,990
但幸好我們找到了彼此
but we found each other.

1234
01:47:26,320 --> 01:47:28,170
一起創造出
And we made a life.

1235
01:47:28,170 --> 01:47:32,040
一段美妙的人生
A beautiful life... together.

