1
00:04:24,430 --> 00:04:26,280
早上好 詹姆斯
Good Morning, James!

2
00:04:26,300 --> 00:04:27,880
您感覺怎么樣
How're you feeling?

3
00:04:27,910 --> 00:04:29,220
等下 什么鬼
Wait, what?

4
00:04:29,240 --> 00:04:31,970
您現在感到疑惑很正常
It's perfectly normal to feel confused.

5
00:04:31,990 --> 00:04:35,790
您剛從120年的休眠中醒來
You've just spent a 120 years in suspended animation.

6
00:04:36,440 --> 00:04:37,520
什么
What?

7
00:04:37,540 --> 00:04:39,450
沒關系的 詹姆斯
It's okay, James.

8
00:04:39,480 --> 00:04:40,590
我叫吉姆
It's Jim.

9
00:04:40,610 --> 00:04:42,000
吉姆
Jim.

10
00:04:42,420 --> 00:04:44,070
深呼吸
Just breathe.

11
00:04:44,100 --> 00:04:45,590
一切正常
Everything is okay.

12
00:04:45,610 --> 00:04:46,740
我在哪
Where am I?

13
00:04:46,770 --> 00:04:48,950
您是星際飛船阿瓦隆號上的一名乘客
You're a passenger on the Starship Avalon.

14
00:04:48,970 --> 00:04:52,760
這是新家園公司的首架星際班機
The Homestead Company's premier interstellar star liner.

15
00:04:53,810 --> 00:04:57,730
此次從地球啟航的遠行即將結束 將抵達您的新家園
We've nearly completed the voyage from Earth to your new home,

16
00:04:57,750 --> 00:05:00,650
殖民行星 新家園Ⅱ號
the colony world of Homestead Ⅱ.

17
00:05:00,930 --> 00:05:02,170
一個全新的世界
A new world.

18
00:05:02,200 --> 00:05:03,680
全新的開始
A fresh start.

19
00:05:03,710 --> 00:05:05,510
成長的空間
Room to grow.

20
00:05:05,540 --> 00:05:06,880
好美
Oh, yeah.

21
00:05:06,910 --> 00:05:09,040
阿瓦隆號就快落地了
The Avalon is on final approach.

22
00:05:09,070 --> 00:05:11,410
在接下來的四個月中 請您盡情享受
For the next 4 months, you'll enjoy space travel

23
00:05:11,430 --> 00:05:13,680
奢華的星際旅行
at it's most luxurious.

24
00:05:13,700 --> 00:05:16,370
我們有美食 樂趣 朋友
Food. Fun. Friends.

25
00:05:16,390 --> 00:05:17,560
我的朋友們
My friends.

26
00:05:17,590 --> 00:05:19,080
是的 吉姆
That's right, Jim.

27
00:05:19,100 --> 00:05:20,790
您的身份手環在您的手腕上
The I.D. Band on your wrist

28
00:05:20,790 --> 00:05:23,360
身份手環可以帶您進入阿瓦隆的各個房間
is your key to the wonders of the Avalon.

29
00:05:24,830 --> 00:05:26,740
您很健康 吉姆
You're in perfect health, Jim.

30
00:05:26,770 --> 00:05:29,910
現在請您去您的客艙休息一下吧
Let's get you to your cabin where you can get some rest.

31
00:05:37,130 --> 00:05:41,210
您可能還有一些休眠后遺癥
You maybe experiencing post-hibernation sickness.

32
00:05:42,340 --> 00:05:44,840
您的房門會自動亮起
Your door will illuminate for you.

33
00:05:47,900 --> 00:05:49,330
歡迎來到您的客艙
Welcome to your cabin.

34
00:05:49,360 --> 00:05:51,720
降落之前 這里就是您暫時的家了
Your home until we make landfall.

35
00:05:51,740 --> 00:05:53,140
在接下來的四個月中
Over the next 4 months,

36
00:05:53,140 --> 00:05:56,130
您可以為您在新家園Ⅱ號的新生活做準備
you'll prepare for your new life on Homestead Ⅱ.

37
00:05:56,150 --> 00:05:59,240
見見同行旅客 參加技能培訓
Meet you fellow passengers, take skill building classes

38
00:05:59,270 --> 00:06:01,640
學會如何在殖民行星生活
and learn about colonial living.

39
00:06:01,850 --> 00:06:04,260
您和其他工程師以及技術貿易人員
You've been assigned to Learning group 38,

40
00:06:04,290 --> 00:06:07,640
被分配到了38號學習小組
for passengers with engineering and technical trade skills.

41
00:06:07,660 --> 00:06:10,740
請掃描您的身份手環來領取您的行李
Please scan your I.D. To confirm luggage delivery.

42
00:06:11,630 --> 00:06:16,230
吉姆 請掃描您的身份手環來領取您的行李
Jim, please scan your I.D. To confirm luggage delivery.

43
00:06:20,480 --> 00:06:22,950
為了幫助您從休眠狀態恢復過來
To help you recover from hibernation,

44
00:06:22,950 --> 00:06:25,220
請您多喝水
be sure to drink plenty of fluids.

45
00:06:26,620 --> 00:06:29,350
愿您在阿瓦隆號新家園公司星際飛船
Enjoy the rest of your voyage on the Avalon,

46
00:06:29,370 --> 00:06:32,190
度過一段愉快的旅程
a Homestead Company Starship.

47
00:06:34,090 --> 00:06:35,430
各位早上好
Good morning one and all.

48
00:06:35,460 --> 00:06:38,260
又是個在阿瓦隆號上美好的早晨
It's a beautiful morning here on the Starship Avalon.

49
00:06:38,280 --> 00:06:41,020
無論怎樣 請不要想家 這兒就是新家
Whatever you do don't get homesick, get Homestead.

50
00:06:41,050 --> 00:06:44,230
讓我們先來聽首我以前在地球上最喜歡的歌吧
Let start things off with one of my favorite back on Earth.

51
00:06:50,370 --> 00:06:51,970
不行
No.

52
00:06:54,840 --> 00:06:55,880
太蠢了
It's stupid.

53
00:07:00,150 --> 00:07:03,620
叫我吉姆就好 我有一件酷酷的夾克
Just call me... call me Jim. You got a cool jacket.

54
00:07:17,560 --> 00:07:19,620
乘客們 您們好
Hello, Passengers.

55
00:07:19,870 --> 00:07:22,550
大家請坐
Will you all please take a seat.

56
00:07:23,150 --> 00:07:25,740
歡迎大家 38號學習小組的成員們
Welcome, Learning group 38.

57
00:07:25,770 --> 00:07:29,090
接下來給您做殖民行星生活簡介
Your introduction to colonial life.

58
00:07:29,320 --> 00:07:31,360
地球是一個繁榮的星球
Earth is a prosperous planet.

59
00:07:31,380 --> 00:07:33,530
它是文明的發源地
The cradle of civilization.

60
00:07:33,560 --> 00:07:39,100
但同時 地球有人口過剩 生活成本增加 能力被高估等問題
But for many, it's also overpopulated. Over-priced. Overrated.

61
00:07:39,120 --> 00:07:41,720
抱歉 我覺得我可能來錯房間了
I'm sorry, I think I maybe in the wrong...

62
00:07:41,750 --> 00:07:43,560
- 請在介紹結束之后問問題 - 抱歉
- Hold all questions till the end, please. - Oh, sorry.

63
00:07:43,590 --> 00:07:46,180
殖民行星給了我們另一個選擇
The Colonies offer an alternative.

64
00:07:46,210 --> 00:07:47,970
- 一個更好的生活 - 其他人在哪
- A better way of life. - Where are all the other...

65
00:07:48,000 --> 00:07:52,400
新家園Ⅱ號是所有殖民行星中最美麗的行星
And there's no colony more beautiful than Homestead Ⅱ,

66
00:07:52,420 --> 00:07:55,850
- 殖民世界的珍寶 - 抱歉
- the Jewel of the Occupied Worlds. - I'm sorry.

67
00:07:56,030 --> 00:07:57,630
其他人都在哪里
Where IS everybody?

68
00:07:57,660 --> 00:07:59,740
我們都在阿瓦隆星際飛船上
We're all on the Starship Avalon.

69
00:07:59,770 --> 00:08:01,120
但這兒就我一個人啊
But I'm the only one here.

70
00:08:01,150 --> 00:08:05,800
這里一共有5000名乘客和258名乘務員
There are 5,000 passengers and 258 crew members.

71
00:08:05,830 --> 00:08:07,570
那我怎么一個人
So why am I alone?

72
00:08:07,600 --> 00:08:10,090
我們同在這里
We're all in this together.

73
00:08:11,790 --> 00:08:13,400
有人嗎
Hello?

74
00:08:14,580 --> 00:08:16,350
有人在嗎
Anybody here?

75
00:08:16,370 --> 00:08:17,930
有人嗎
Hello?

76
00:08:28,720 --> 00:08:31,780
請系好安全帶 并縛緊所有松動的部分
Please buckle up and secure any loose items.

77
00:08:31,800 --> 00:08:35,980
乘坐此部電梯會經歷一小會兒的失重
This elevator will experience a momentary lapse in gravity.

78
00:08:58,580 --> 00:09:00,600
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

79
00:09:15,360 --> 00:09:19,300
您好 歡迎來到阿瓦隆號的中央大廳 我能幫助您嗎
Hello.Welcome to the Grand Concourse aboard the Avalon, can I help you?

80
00:09:19,750 --> 00:09:21,830
我要和人說話
I need to talk to a person.

81
00:09:21,980 --> 00:09:23,440
一個大活人 拜托了
A real live person, please.

82
00:09:23,460 --> 00:09:26,470
什么樣的人呢 私人教練 旅行計劃員 還是理療師
What sort of person? Personal trainer? Travel planner? Therapist?

83
00:09:26,490 --> 00:09:28,890
我也不知道 管事的人
I don't know. Somebody in charge.

84
00:09:28,910 --> 00:09:31,090
您指飛船乘務處理處吧
The Ship Steward handles passenger affairs.

85
00:09:31,090 --> 00:09:33,060
位于中央大廳三層
It's on level 3 of the Grand Concourse.

86
00:09:33,080 --> 00:09:35,160
- 謝謝 - 非常樂意為您服務
- Thank you. - Happy to help!

87
00:09:40,570 --> 00:09:41,830
糟糕
Not good.

88
00:09:41,860 --> 00:09:43,360
- 你好 - 誰在操控飛船
- Hello! - Who's flying the ship?

89
00:09:43,390 --> 00:09:45,830
機組人員 機長 飛行員 首席駕駛員
The flight crew, the Captain, the Pilot, the Chief Navigator...

90
00:09:45,860 --> 00:09:47,380
我要見機長
I want to speak to the Captain.

91
00:09:47,410 --> 00:09:49,170
機長通常不直接受理乘客的問題
The Captain rarely handles passenger queries directly.

92
00:09:49,190 --> 00:09:51,880
緊急事件 拜托了
It's an emergency, please.

93
00:09:51,910 --> 00:09:55,330
機長通常在控制中心的連接橋上
The Captain is usually found on the Bridge, in the Command Ring.

94
00:10:05,470 --> 00:10:08,960
通過連接橋需要特別授權
Bridge access requires special authorization.

95
00:10:10,610 --> 00:10:14,390
通過連接橋需要特殊授權
Bridge access requires special authorization.

96
00:10:16,400 --> 00:10:18,450
開什么玩笑
You got to be kidding me.

97
00:10:32,120 --> 00:10:34,710
歡迎來到瞭望臺
Welcome to the Observatory.

98
00:10:36,210 --> 00:10:38,220
您想看什么
What can I show you?

99
00:10:38,920 --> 00:10:41,270
我們不是快降落了嗎
We're supposed to land soon,

100
00:10:43,920 --> 00:10:46,790
但只有我一個人醒來了
I'm... I'm the only one awake.

101
00:10:46,820 --> 00:10:50,420
我不明白 您想看點什么
I don't understand. What can I show you?

102
00:10:51,040 --> 00:10:52,380
給我看新家園Ⅱ號
Show me Homestead Ⅱ.

103
00:10:52,400 --> 00:10:55,780
新家園Ⅱ號是巴克蒂星系的第四顆行星
Homestead Ⅱ is the 4th planet in the Bhakti system.

104
00:10:55,810 --> 00:10:57,950
好吧 我們現在在哪
Right. And where are we?

105
00:10:57,980 --> 00:11:01,140
我們還在從地球到新家園Ⅱ號的路上
We're in transit from Earth to Homestead Ⅱ.

106
00:11:01,180 --> 00:11:04,650
- 我們大約于90年后到達 - 什么
- We will arrive in approximately 90 years. - What?

107
00:11:04,670 --> 00:11:08,980
我們將在90年3周1天后到達新家園Ⅱ號
We arrive at Homestead Ⅱ in 90 years, 3 weeks and 1 day.

108
00:11:09,010 --> 00:11:11,470
什么 我們離開地球多久了
No. Wait. How long ago did we leave Earth?

109
00:11:11,490 --> 00:11:14,680
大約三十年
Approximately 30 years ago.

110
00:11:18,080 --> 00:11:20,100
我醒得太早了
I woke up too soon.

111
00:11:22,650 --> 00:11:23,810
您好
Hello.

112
00:11:23,830 --> 00:11:25,370
我怎么向地球發信息
How do I send a message to Earth?

113
00:11:25,390 --> 00:11:28,090
星際信息將由激光發送
Interstellar messages are sent by laser array.

114
00:11:28,090 --> 00:11:29,790
這項服務很貴
This is an expensive service.

115
00:11:29,820 --> 00:11:32,120
- 有本事咬我啊 - 非常樂意為您服務
- Bite me. - Happy to help!

116
00:11:34,210 --> 00:11:35,540
您要聯絡的星球和聯絡人是
Planet and connection?

117
00:11:35,560 --> 00:11:37,560
地球 新家園公司
Earth. The HomeStead Company.

118
00:11:37,590 --> 00:11:42,150
新家園公司有30826位聯系人
There are 30,826 contacts listed under HomeStead Company?

119
00:11:42,150 --> 00:11:45,690
我是新家園Ⅱ號的移民 這里有緊急情況
I'm emigrating to Homestead Ⅱ and I have an emergency.

120
00:11:45,690 --> 00:11:48,460
- 我找到一個客服熱線 - 就它了
- I have a Customer Help Line. - Sounds about right.

121
00:11:48,480 --> 00:11:50,190
開始錄制信息
Begin message.

122
00:11:50,650 --> 00:11:53,580
嗨 我是吉姆 普勒斯頓
Hi. I'm Jim Preston.

123
00:11:54,150 --> 00:11:56,230
我是阿瓦隆號上的一名乘客
I'm a passenger on the Avalon.

124
00:11:56,580 --> 00:11:58,020
我
I uh...

125
00:12:00,870 --> 00:12:03,600
我覺得我的休眠艙出問題了
I think something went wrong with my hibernation pod.

126
00:12:03,630 --> 00:12:05,290
我醒早了
I woke up too soon.

127
00:12:05,310 --> 00:12:08,980
醒得太早了
And I mean... way too soon.

128
00:12:09,010 --> 00:12:11,840
就我一個人醒了
Nobody else is awake. And...

129
00:12:12,220 --> 00:12:14,080
我不知道怎么再回到休眠狀態
I don't know how to get back to sleep.

130
00:12:14,110 --> 00:12:17,500
問題是 還有90年才降落
And the thing is, there's 90 years to go.

131
00:12:20,560 --> 00:12:23,100
照這個速度下去 我
At this rate, I'm...

132
00:12:26,730 --> 00:12:29,190
抱歉 我在試著找到底出了什么問題
I'm sorry, I'm trying to fix this. I...

133
00:12:29,210 --> 00:12:32,040
或許我遺漏了什么 我需要幫助
Maybe I missed something. I could use a hand.

134
00:12:32,840 --> 00:12:34,430
就這樣
That's all.

135
00:12:35,310 --> 00:12:36,830
謝謝
Thank you.

136
00:12:37,550 --> 00:12:39,410
信息已發送
Message sent.

137
00:12:41,270 --> 00:12:42,230
真棒
Outstanding.

138
00:12:42,260 --> 00:12:45,750
- 信息將會在19年后到達 - 什么
- Message will arrive in 19 years. - Wait, what?

139
00:12:45,780 --> 00:12:50,430
- 最快您將在55年后到收到回復 - 55年
- Earliest reply in 55 years. - 55 years.

140
00:12:50,790 --> 00:12:52,990
給您帶來了不便很抱歉
We apologize for the delay.

141
00:12:53,010 --> 00:12:55,890
總共6012美金
That will be $6012 dollars.

142
00:13:09,580 --> 00:13:11,490
- 下午好 - 我的天啊
- Afternoon. - Oh man.

143
00:13:11,520 --> 00:13:13,850
還能見到個人簡直太好了
It's good to see another face.

144
00:13:13,880 --> 00:13:15,440
我以為就我一個人醒著
I thought I was the only one awake!

145
00:13:15,470 --> 00:13:18,700
誰要在這么好的時候睡覺啊
Who want's to sleep on a beautiful day like this?

146
00:13:18,720 --> 00:13:21,890
我的意思是我們遇到麻煩了 我們不應該在這的
Oh, I mean we're in trouble, we're not suppose to be here.

147
00:13:21,920 --> 00:13:23,950
你不想的話我不會說出去的
Well, I won't tell if you don't.

148
00:13:24,290 --> 00:13:26,620
- 什么 - 我們之間的小秘密
- Huh? - Our little secret.

149
00:13:28,060 --> 00:13:30,000
喝點什么嗎
What can I get for you?

150
00:13:30,030 --> 00:13:33,100
- 什么 - 你看起來像是喜歡喝威士忌的
- What? - You look like a whiskey man.

151
00:13:33,120 --> 00:13:34,480
好吧
Okay.

152
00:13:38,270 --> 00:13:40,740
原來是個機器
Oh, you're a robot.

153
00:13:41,560 --> 00:13:44,420
嚴格來說是機器人
Android, technically.

154
00:13:46,130 --> 00:13:47,970
我叫亞瑟
Arthur's the name.

155
00:13:48,260 --> 00:13:50,710
- 吉姆 - 很高興認識你 吉姆
- Jim. - Please to meet you, Jim.

156
00:13:56,580 --> 00:13:58,980
你對這艘船了解多少
How much do you know about this ship?

157
00:13:59,000 --> 00:14:01,590
不太多 我只知道一點點
I don't know. I know some things.

158
00:14:01,590 --> 00:14:03,920
如果我的休眠艙發生故障了怎么辦
What do I do if my hibernation pod malfunctions?

159
00:14:03,940 --> 00:14:06,540
休眠艙有自動防故障裝置
Oh. Hibernation pods are fail-safe.

160
00:14:06,570 --> 00:14:09,580
- 休眠艙從不出現故障 - 我醒早了
- They never malfunction. - Well, I woke up early.

161
00:14:09,600 --> 00:14:11,350
這不可能
Can't happen.

162
00:14:11,370 --> 00:14:13,370
還有多久我們才能到達新家園Ⅱ號
How long until we get to Homestead Ⅱ?

163
00:14:13,400 --> 00:14:15,140
還要90年左右
About 90 years or so.

164
00:14:15,160 --> 00:14:17,330
那所有乘客會在什么時候醒來
And when are all the passengers supposed to wake up?

165
00:14:17,360 --> 00:14:19,700
到達前4個月
Not until the last 4 months.

166
00:14:20,150 --> 00:14:25,150
我就在這坐著和你一起過上90年怎么樣
How is it that I'm sitting here with you with 90 years to go?

167
00:14:28,950 --> 00:14:31,300
你不可能出現在這里
It's not possible for you to be here.

168
00:14:33,430 --> 00:14:35,040
然而我在
Well, I am.

169
00:14:39,600 --> 00:14:42,370
早上好 阿瓦隆飛船又迎來了美好的一天
Good morning, it's a beautiful day here on the Avalon.

170
00:14:42,390 --> 00:14:46,490
所以醒來吧 天氣晴朗 是時候放松和享受了
So wake up, sunshine. It's time to relax and enjoy your stay.

171
00:14:56,650 --> 00:14:58,910
請選擇一款飲品
Please make a selection.

172
00:15:00,240 --> 00:15:01,830
對不起 摩卡卡布奇諾
Sorry. The Mocha Cappuccino

173
00:15:01,830 --> 00:15:04,550
只提供給貴賓艙乘客
Extreme is reserved for gold-class passengers.

174
00:15:04,570 --> 00:15:05,600
對不起 摩卡卡布奇諾
Sorry. The Mocha Cappuccino

175
00:15:05,600 --> 00:15:07,340
只提供給貴賓艙乘客
Extreme is reserved for gold-class passengers.

176
00:15:07,360 --> 00:15:09,650
我要一杯摩卡卡布奇諾 賬單記到我房間賬上 謝謝
I want the Mocha Cappuccino Extreme, bill my room please.

177
00:15:09,680 --> 00:15:11,530
購買食品可在飛船上的
Food can be purchase in the ship's...

178
00:15:11,560 --> 00:15:12,950
對不起 法式烤
Sorry. The French Roast...

179
00:15:12,980 --> 00:15:14,930
對不起 南瓜風味
Sorry. The Pumpkin Spice...

180
00:15:14,950 --> 00:15:16,130
對不起 香草茶
Sorry. Vanilla Chai...

181
00:15:16,160 --> 00:15:17,460
對不起 對不起
Sorry. Sorry.

182
00:15:17,480 --> 00:15:19,310
對不起 對不 對不起
Sorr... Sorr... Sorry.

183
00:15:19,780 --> 00:15:22,970
- 大杯黑咖 請享用您的咖啡 - 奶油 糖
- Large coffee. Please enjoy your coffee. - Cream. Sugar.

184
00:15:22,990 --> 00:15:24,770
真的嗎
Oh, really?

185
00:16:45,490 --> 00:16:49,630
訪問機組人員艙需要特殊授權
Crew podroom access requires special authorization.

186
00:17:33,050 --> 00:17:34,550
中央大
Grand Conc...

187
00:17:34,570 --> 00:17:35,660
正在下行
Going down.

188
00:17:35,690 --> 00:17:37,850
請選 層樓
Please make... Level...

189
00:17:39,260 --> 00:17:41,100
中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

190
00:17:41,130 --> 00:17:44,840
我完蛋了 亞瑟 真的完蛋了
I'm screwed, Arthur. Completely and ridiculously screwed.

191
00:17:44,860 --> 00:17:49,260
別這樣想 要知道守得云開見月明
Come on, now. Every cloud has a silver lining.

192
00:17:50,490 --> 00:17:53,550
看來我要老死在這里了
Guess, I am going to die of old age on this ship!

193
00:17:53,580 --> 00:17:55,440
人終有一死
Oh, we all die.

194
00:17:55,470 --> 00:17:58,170
就連機器人最后也會被扔到垃圾堆
Even androids end up on the scrap heap.

195
00:17:58,570 --> 00:18:01,890
這里就我一個客人 為什么你老是在擦玻璃杯
I'm your only customer, why are you always polishing a glass?

196
00:18:02,050 --> 00:18:03,600
生意技巧
Trick of the trade.

197
00:18:03,630 --> 00:18:06,410
如果酒保傻站在這里 就會讓客人緊張
Makes people nervous when a bartender just stands there.

198
00:18:06,430 --> 00:18:10,400
那就傳授點酒保的智慧給我 我迷失太空里了
So, lay some bartender wisdom on me. I'm lost in space here.

199
00:18:12,030 --> 00:18:14,730
你待在你不想待的地方
You're not where you want to be.

200
00:18:14,750 --> 00:18:18,180
你覺得你應該在別處才對
You feel like you're supposed to be somewhere else.

201
00:18:21,630 --> 00:18:23,160
- 你說得對 - 那么
- You said it. - Well.

202
00:18:23,180 --> 00:18:27,110
想象一下你只要動動手指就能到達你想去的地方
Say you could snap your fingers and be wherever you wanted to be.

203
00:18:27,130 --> 00:18:30,820
我敢說哪怕這樣你還是會無可適從
I'll bet you'd still feel this way. Not in the right place.

204
00:18:30,850 --> 00:18:34,630
關鍵在于 你不能總是糾結自己應該去哪
Point is, you can't get so hung up on where you'd rather be

205
00:18:34,650 --> 00:18:37,400
而忘了怎樣活在當下
that you forget how to make the most of where you are.

206
00:18:37,420 --> 00:18:39,020
你想告訴我什么
What are you telling me?

207
00:18:39,040 --> 00:18:42,970
別再擔心你不能控制的事了
Take a break from worrying about what you can't control.

208
00:18:44,190 --> 00:18:45,830
活在當下
Live a little.

209
00:18:45,990 --> 00:18:47,750
活在當下
Live a little.

210
00:18:56,820 --> 00:19:00,740
- 歡迎來到維也納套房 - 哇
- Welcome to the Vienna suite. - Oh.

211
00:19:00,780 --> 00:19:02,360
噢耶
Oh yeah.

212
00:19:02,510 --> 00:19:05,380
哈哈哈哈
Huh. Ha ha ha.

213
00:19:07,160 --> 00:19:08,790
不會吧
What?

214
00:19:09,550 --> 00:19:11,120
噢
Oh.

215
00:19:15,860 --> 00:19:17,510
加油 吉姆 加油 吉姆
Go, Jim! Go, Jim!

216
00:19:17,530 --> 00:19:18,250
耶
Yeah!

217
00:19:18,280 --> 00:19:20,870
來兩份大蝦 三份
Make that a double jumbo shrimp. Triple.

218
00:19:20,900 --> 00:19:23,140
非常感謝
Thank you very much.

219
00:19:23,550 --> 00:19:24,850
跳舞
Dance off.

220
00:19:24,870 --> 00:19:25,990
玩家1 吉姆
Player 1 jim

221
00:19:26,900 --> 00:19:28,490
好
Alright.

222
00:19:30,050 --> 00:19:32,260
我跳得跟你完全一樣啊
I did exactly what you just did.

223
00:19:37,180 --> 00:19:38,920
大杯黑咖
Large coffee.

224
00:19:42,920 --> 00:19:45,000
一杯瑪格麗塔 謝謝
A margarita, please.

225
00:19:45,030 --> 00:19:46,950
你點了太多了 先生
You have had many, Senor.

226
00:19:46,970 --> 00:19:50,390
埃克托 拜托再來一份
Oh Hector, please. Another one.

227
00:19:50,410 --> 00:19:52,010
好的 先生
Yes, Senor.

228
00:19:52,210 --> 00:19:53,800
謝謝
Thank you.

229
00:19:55,200 --> 00:19:58,800
加油 吉姆 加油 吉姆
Go, Jim! Go, Jim!

230
00:20:05,290 --> 00:20:07,560
滾開
Get out of here!

231
00:20:08,740 --> 00:20:10,530
回來 嘿
Come back. Hey.

232
00:20:12,690 --> 00:20:14,170
過來
Come here.

233
00:20:45,200 --> 00:20:46,810
該死
Damn!

234
00:21:09,460 --> 00:21:11,300
歡迎 吉姆
Welcome, Jim.

235
00:21:12,570 --> 00:21:17,060
請注意屏幕上的安全提示
Please turn your attention to the screens displaying safety tips.

236
00:21:17,090 --> 00:21:18,790
太空宇航服專為
These space suits are designed

237
00:21:18,790 --> 00:21:21,290
抵擋太空內惡劣環境而設計
to withstand the harsh environment of space.

238
00:21:21,330 --> 00:21:23,540
碳化纖維和聚酰胺的材質
The carbon fiber and polyamide

239
00:21:23,540 --> 00:21:27,740
使航空服持久耐用且不易變形
construction means your suit is inflexible and endurable.

240
00:21:39,610 --> 00:21:43,480
請記住 您的航空服就是您的生命
Remember, your space suit is your life line.

241
00:21:51,660 --> 00:21:55,540
請滑動右邊的把手釋放氣壓
Slide the handle on the right to release the air pressure.

242
00:21:57,040 --> 00:21:59,090
您的磁力靴已經啟用
Your magnetic boots are now engaged.

243
00:21:59,120 --> 00:22:02,540
可通過手臂上的控制板關閉磁力附著
They can be deactivated using the control panel on your arm.

244
00:22:02,570 --> 00:22:05,860
按下紅色按鈕開啟艙門
Press the red button to open the air lock door.

245
00:22:09,030 --> 00:22:11,140
祝您玩得開心
Have a wonderful time.

246
00:22:18,430 --> 00:22:20,390
安全繩就位
Tether attached.

247
00:23:47,800 --> 00:23:49,830
歡迎回來 吉姆
Welcome back, Jim.

248
00:23:52,950 --> 00:23:54,770
期待您再次光臨
We hope you decide to join

249
00:23:54,770 --> 00:23:58,050
我們的奇幻之旅
us again soon for another thrilling experience.

250
00:24:21,510 --> 00:24:23,890
祝您旅途愉快
Have a wonderful time.

251
00:25:44,160 --> 00:25:46,230
奧羅拉
Aurora.

252
00:25:47,300 --> 00:25:49,820
搜索乘客簡介
Searching passenger profiles.

253
00:25:49,840 --> 00:25:51,600
我叫奧羅拉 萊恩
I'm Aurora Lane.

254
00:25:51,630 --> 00:25:54,930
1456號乘客 我是個作家
Passenger 1456. I'm a writer.

255
00:25:54,950 --> 00:25:58,010
我認為我們講故事就是為了讓彼此不再孤單
I think we tell each other stories to know we're not alone.

256
00:25:58,030 --> 00:25:59,340
為了建立聯系
To make contact.

257
00:25:59,380 --> 00:26:02,760
你的父親是作家奧利弗 萊恩 普利策獎獲得者
Your father was Oliver Lane, the Pulitzer Prize-winning author.

258
00:26:02,790 --> 00:26:04,100
毫無壓力 對吧
No pressure, right?

259
00:26:04,130 --> 00:26:06,040
我爸爸曾經說過
My Dad used to say:

260
00:26:06,060 --> 00:26:09,880
如果你過著平凡的生活 那么你的故事也不過如此
"If you live an ordinary life, all you have are ordinary stories.

261
00:26:09,910 --> 00:26:12,420
你必須勇于冒險生活
You have to live a life of adventure."

262
00:26:13,500 --> 00:26:15,070
所以
So.

263
00:26:15,530 --> 00:26:17,150
我來了
Here I am.

264
00:26:23,360 --> 00:26:24,880
早上好
Good morning.

265
00:26:27,450 --> 00:26:31,140
各方面  我們都將從頭開始
We're starting over... in every way.

266
00:26:31,160 --> 00:26:33,760
我將要弄明白在哪里生活 如何生活
I'll have to figure out where to live, how to live,

267
00:26:33,780 --> 00:26:35,080
誰將成為我的朋友
who my friends will be.

268
00:26:35,110 --> 00:26:36,680
這種感覺就像開學第一天
It's like the first day at school.

269
00:26:36,700 --> 00:26:39,870
只不過這趟校車要開120年才能到達
And this school bus took 120 years to get there.

270
00:26:42,010 --> 00:26:44,130
我們在創造一種文化
We're creating a culture.

271
00:26:44,150 --> 00:26:45,500
你真幽默
You're funny.

272
00:26:45,500 --> 00:26:46,780
你有試過讀到
Do you ever read something

273
00:26:46,780 --> 00:26:48,750
像是專門為你而寫的東西嗎
and feel like it's written just for you?

274
00:26:48,780 --> 00:26:50,790
我不怎么讀東西
I don't do a lot of reading.

275
00:26:50,820 --> 00:26:52,780
她人真好
She's good.

276
00:26:53,250 --> 00:26:54,780
那人是誰
Who's that?

277
00:26:54,810 --> 00:26:56,410
奧羅拉
Aurora.

278
00:26:56,440 --> 00:26:59,530
那個睡美人
Ah. The sleeping girl.

279
00:27:04,000 --> 00:27:05,930
我不是說宇宙是完全邪惡的
You know, I'm not saying the universe is evil

280
00:27:05,950 --> 00:27:08,000
但確實還有種討人厭的幽默感
but it sure has a nasty sense of humor.

281
00:27:08,020 --> 00:27:09,060
怎么說
How is that?

282
00:27:09,100 --> 00:27:13,940
你要飛到另一個星球 卻要死在途中
You get to fly to another planet, but you'll die along the way.

283
00:27:15,050 --> 00:27:17,790
現在又讓你遇到你的命中注定
And you find the perfect woman

284
00:27:18,880 --> 00:27:20,760
近在眼前
right in front of you.

285
00:27:21,820 --> 00:27:24,290
卻觸不可及
Yet, she's completely out of reach.

286
00:27:27,200 --> 00:27:29,360
是的 我會想念紐約
Yeah, I'll miss New York city.

287
00:27:29,380 --> 00:27:31,530
給我一杯咖啡 以及一片克萊斯勒大廈景色
Give me a cup of coffee and a view of the Chrysler Building,

288
00:27:31,560 --> 00:27:33,220
我可以寫上一整天
and I can write all day.

289
00:27:33,240 --> 00:27:35,430
新家園Ⅱ號上有咖啡吧
You do have coffee on Homestead Ⅱ, right?

290
00:27:35,450 --> 00:27:36,650
那里最好有咖啡 如果沒有
They better have coffee, if they

291
00:27:36,650 --> 00:27:38,660
我們又要掉頭飛回地球去了
don't they have to turn around and come back to Earth.

292
00:27:40,150 --> 00:27:42,850
地球有什么讓你眷念的嗎
Is there anything you regret leaving behind?

293
00:27:43,110 --> 00:27:47,620
有啊 我會想念秋天的中央公園
Yeah, I'll miss the trees in Central Park turning in the Fall.

294
00:27:48,110 --> 00:27:51,580
我會想念喧鬧的人群
I'll miss the crowd, all the voices.

295
00:27:59,520 --> 00:28:01,910
如果你被困在一個荒蕪的孤島
Say you were trapped on a desert island,

296
00:28:01,940 --> 00:28:04,570
你有能力讓一個人來陪你
you had the power to wish somebody there with you.

297
00:28:04,590 --> 00:28:06,560
然后不再孤單
You wouldn't be alone anymore.

298
00:28:07,270 --> 00:28:09,700
但你卻會連累那個人一起困在這個孤島
But you'd be stranding a person on the island.

299
00:28:09,730 --> 00:28:12,130
你怎么做 你會許那種愿嗎
How do you... Would you make the wish?

300
00:28:12,160 --> 00:28:14,680
我不知道 我從沒去過島嶼
I don't know. I've never been on an island.

301
00:28:14,680 --> 00:28:16,670
好吧 對
Okay, well... Yeah.

302
00:28:17,640 --> 00:28:19,260
當我沒說
Forget the island.

303
00:28:19,840 --> 00:28:24,470
假設你想通了如何做某件事
Let's say you figured out how to do something

304
00:28:24,490 --> 00:28:26,290
會使你的生活大大改善
that would make your life a million times better.

305
00:28:26,310 --> 00:28:28,930
但你知道這么做是錯的 而且沒有后悔藥吃
But you knew it was wrong, and there's no taking it back.

306
00:28:28,950 --> 00:28:30,350
你會怎么做決定
How do you do the math?

307
00:28:30,380 --> 00:28:33,360
吉姆 這不是機器人能回答的問題
Jim. These are not robot questions.

308
00:28:38,870 --> 00:28:41,440
- 我知道怎么喚醒奧羅拉 - 喔
- I know how to wake Aurora up. - Oh.

309
00:28:41,460 --> 00:28:44,600
這看起來是個好主意 你會有個同伴了
Well, that seems like a fine idea. You could use some company.

310
00:28:44,630 --> 00:28:47,180
我會讓她的余生都在這艘飛船上度過
I'd be stranding her on this ship for the rest of her life!

311
00:28:47,200 --> 00:28:50,060
哦 那你不能那么做
Oh. Well, you can't do that.

312
00:28:50,940 --> 00:28:52,410
我該怎么辦
What am I going to do?

313
00:28:52,440 --> 00:28:53,760
我在這里陪你呢
I'm here for you.

314
00:28:53,780 --> 00:28:56,220
亞瑟 你是臺機器
Arthur, you're a machine.

315
00:28:59,020 --> 00:28:59,890
看吧
See.

316
00:28:59,890 --> 00:28:59,930
看到沒 你感覺不到 你是沒有感情的
See, you can't feel that, you don't have feelings.

317
00:29:06,010 --> 00:29:07,180
看見了吧
You see?

318
00:29:07,180 --> 00:29:08,870
你不會受傷
That doesn't hurt.

319
00:29:08,900 --> 00:29:10,880
你甚至都不會介意
And you don't even mind.

320
00:29:11,370 --> 00:29:14,180
而她 是人類
She... A person.

321
00:29:20,760 --> 00:29:22,190
別再想那件事了
Don't even think about it.

322
00:29:22,210 --> 00:29:23,900
別再提奧羅拉
No more Aurora talk.

323
00:29:23,920 --> 00:29:25,570
這事兒過去了
I'm over it.

324
00:29:25,660 --> 00:29:27,330
我得向前看
I'm moving on.

325
00:29:29,920 --> 00:29:31,510
我要怎么做 坐下來想一想嗎
What am I going to do? I'm going to sit and thinking about it?

326
00:29:31,530 --> 00:29:33,060
我不會  不能再想這件事了
I'm not going to... I can't think about it.

327
00:29:33,060 --> 00:29:34,380
所以我不去做 就這樣
So I'm not going to, that's the deal.

328
00:29:34,400 --> 00:29:37,030
我決定了 我知道我在做什么
I've made my decision. I know what I'm doing.

329
00:29:37,030 --> 00:29:38,880
就是中斷這個想法
I just cut it off.

330
00:29:40,710 --> 00:29:41,680
我不 不再
I'm not... No more.

331
00:29:41,710 --> 00:29:43,340
你不會再聽到我提起她了
You won't hear me bring up her name again.

332
00:29:43,370 --> 00:29:45,570
我甚至永遠也不會再提起她了
I'll never even mention her name again.

333
00:29:45,600 --> 00:29:47,020
結束了
Done.

334
00:29:49,170 --> 00:29:51,020
我不能那么做
I can't do it.

335
00:29:55,970 --> 00:29:57,990
我要剃掉我的胡子
I'm shaving off my beard.

336
00:30:08,530 --> 00:30:10,380
求你了 不要那么做
Please don't do it.

337
00:32:02,570 --> 00:32:04,180
早上好 奧羅拉
Good morning, Aurora.

338
00:32:04,180 --> 00:32:06,030
你感覺怎么樣
How're you feeling?

339
00:32:06,430 --> 00:32:09,180
您現在感到困惑很正常
It's perfectly normal to feel confused.

340
00:32:09,210 --> 00:32:12,890
您剛從120年的休眠中醒來
You've just spent a 120 years in suspended animation.

341
00:33:00,830 --> 00:33:02,960
中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

342
00:33:02,980 --> 00:33:04,530
有人嗎
Hello?

343
00:33:07,900 --> 00:33:09,650
有人嗎
Anybody?

344
00:33:18,350 --> 00:33:20,040
你好
Hello.

345
00:33:23,120 --> 00:33:24,770
你好
Hi.

346
00:33:26,990 --> 00:33:29,410
你是旅客還是乘務員
Are you passenger or crew?

347
00:33:31,330 --> 00:33:32,980
旅客
Passenger.

348
00:33:32,980 --> 00:33:34,330
吉姆 普勒斯頓
Jim Preston.

349
00:33:34,350 --> 00:33:36,240
奧羅拉 萊恩
Aurora Lane.

350
00:33:37,350 --> 00:33:39,270
你知道怎么回事嗎
Do you know what's going on?

351
00:33:39,300 --> 00:33:41,800
我不知為何醒了過來
Nobody else from my row woke up.

352
00:33:42,470 --> 00:33:43,560
我也是
Same for me.

353
00:33:43,580 --> 00:33:47,200
乘務員應該早于我們一個月醒來 但是
The crew's supposed to wake up a month before we do. But...

354
00:33:47,230 --> 00:33:49,140
我沒找到他們
I haven't seen them.

355
00:33:52,070 --> 00:33:54,170
乘務員仍然在沉睡
The crew is still asleep.

356
00:33:55,610 --> 00:33:58,240
你是說還沒人醒過來
Are you saying nobody's awake?

357
00:33:58,240 --> 00:33:59,570
只有我
Just me.

358
00:33:59,620 --> 00:34:00,930
只有你
Just you?

359
00:34:00,960 --> 00:34:02,720
準確說只有我們
It's just us.

360
00:34:03,120 --> 00:34:06,130
但幾周后飛船就應該降落了啊
But somebody's got to land the ship in a few weeks.

361
00:34:06,160 --> 00:34:09,810
我們將在大概89年后到達
We will arrive in approximately 89 years.

362
00:34:09,840 --> 00:34:12,230
89年
89 years?

363
00:34:14,100 --> 00:34:17,400
其他旅客都不會在最近醒來
The other passengers aren't late waking up.

364
00:34:18,490 --> 00:34:20,520
是我們太早了
We were early.

365
00:34:24,620 --> 00:34:27,100
我們 我們需要援助
We... We need help.

366
00:34:27,120 --> 00:34:28,930
乘務員都在哪
Where's the crew?

367
00:34:28,960 --> 00:34:31,720
乘務員都在防護休眠室
The crew's in a secured hibernation room.

368
00:34:31,750 --> 00:34:35,300
所有重要的東西 操作系統 反應堆 引擎
Everything important, the controls, the reactors, the engines,

369
00:34:35,320 --> 00:34:38,750
所有這些都在這個防火墻后面 沒辦法過去
it's all behind firewalls, there's no way through.

370
00:34:48,930 --> 00:34:51,420
你醒了多久了
How long have you been awake?

371
00:34:51,950 --> 00:34:54,250
一年零三周
1 year and 3 weeks.

372
00:34:54,470 --> 00:34:57,800
不 不 不 不
No. No, no, no.

373
00:34:57,960 --> 00:35:00,090
不 這不可能
No, this can't be happening.

374
00:35:00,120 --> 00:35:02,350
我們必須回去休眠
We have to go back to sleep.

375
00:35:02,380 --> 00:35:04,440
奧羅拉 我們做不到
Aurora, we can't.

376
00:35:06,640 --> 00:35:08,440
我們只要回到休眠艙里
We just have to get back to our pods

377
00:35:08,460 --> 00:35:10,350
再重新啟動
and start them up again.

378
00:35:11,260 --> 00:35:14,070
我找不到我的休眠艙了 我找不到我的休眠艙了
I can't find my pod. I can't find my pod.

379
00:35:14,090 --> 00:35:16,400
我找不到我的休眠艙了 我們這是在哪兒
I can't find my pod. Where are we?

380
00:35:16,430 --> 00:35:18,160
沒事的
It doesn't matter.

381
00:35:19,280 --> 00:35:20,570
- 奧羅拉 - 我找不到了
- Aurora. - I can't find it.

382
00:35:20,590 --> 00:35:22,350
- 停下 - 我找不到哪一個是我的了
- Stop. - I can't find which one is mine.

383
00:35:22,370 --> 00:35:23,950
- 停下 - 怎么才能知道哪個是我的
- Stop. - How do I know which one is mine?

384
00:35:23,980 --> 00:35:25,120
- 我會幫你的 - 我不能
- I'll help you. - I can't...

385
00:35:25,150 --> 00:35:28,160
冷靜 沒事的
Stop. It doesn't matter.

386
00:35:30,450 --> 00:35:34,300
讓人進入休眠需要特殊的設備
Putting somebody into hibernation requires special equipment.

387
00:35:34,330 --> 00:35:36,150
還記得整個休眠過程中
Remember the facility where they

388
00:35:36,150 --> 00:35:38,870
他們讓我們通過的那個裝置嗎
put us under all the procedures we went through.

389
00:35:38,900 --> 00:35:41,240
這些休眠艙只是用來保證我們的休眠狀態的
These pods are designed to keep us in hibernation,

390
00:35:41,270 --> 00:35:42,790
它們會在正確的時間喚醒我們
they'll wake us up at the right time

391
00:35:42,820 --> 00:35:44,640
但是卻不能讓我們重新休眠
but they can't put us back to sleep.

392
00:35:44,660 --> 00:35:47,900
你覺得沒辦法重新回到休眠
You don't think there's a way back into hibernation.

393
00:35:48,900 --> 00:35:50,250
是的
No.

394
00:35:50,280 --> 00:35:52,300
但一定會有辦法的
But there has to be.

395
00:35:52,710 --> 00:35:54,790
必須得有
There has to be.

396
00:36:03,050 --> 00:36:06,600
九點了 休息時間到了
9 o'clock. Bedtime.

397
00:36:10,690 --> 00:36:14,030
我知道我應該想辦法解決問題
I know I should be working the problem but...

398
00:36:14,330 --> 00:36:16,770
但是我已經睜不開眼了
I can't even keep my eyes open.

399
00:36:17,360 --> 00:36:19,270
你才剛剛從休眠中蘇醒
You just came out of hibernation.

400
00:36:19,290 --> 00:36:21,600
還需要幾天時間來恢復
It's going to be a couple of days before you're 100%.

401
00:36:21,630 --> 00:36:23,700
你應該去休息一下
You should get some rest.

402
00:36:24,210 --> 00:36:26,380
我想我不得不去了
I think I'm going to have to.

403
00:36:27,240 --> 00:36:30,100
- 我送你回客艙吧 - 不用了
- I'll walk you to your cabin. - No, it's okay.

404
00:36:30,130 --> 00:36:31,900
我沒事的
I'll be alright.

405
00:36:32,770 --> 00:36:34,420
好吧
Okay.

406
00:36:37,200 --> 00:36:39,100
晚安 奧羅拉
Good night, Aurora.

407
00:36:40,600 --> 00:36:44,160
一年多 難以想象
More than a year. I can't imagine.

408
00:36:44,690 --> 00:36:46,910
這段時間你一定很難熬吧
It must have been so hard for you.

409
00:36:47,070 --> 00:36:48,700
是的
It was.

410
00:36:48,720 --> 00:36:50,500
晚安 吉姆
Good night, Jim.

411
00:36:52,210 --> 00:36:55,540
請系好安全帶并縛緊所有松動的部分
Please buckle up and secure any loose items.

412
00:36:58,250 --> 00:37:01,170
- 威士忌 純的 - 沒問題
- Whiskey. Neat. - Sure thing.

413
00:37:06,820 --> 00:37:08,700
今天過的怎么樣
How's your day been?

414
00:37:09,570 --> 00:37:11,160
奧羅拉醒了
Aurora's awake.

415
00:37:11,180 --> 00:37:13,310
恭喜了
Congratulations.

416
00:37:14,870 --> 00:37:16,850
你看起來并不高興
You don't look happy.

417
00:37:20,610 --> 00:37:22,620
亞瑟 你能保守秘密嗎
Arthur, can you keep a secret?

418
00:37:22,650 --> 00:37:27,150
吉姆 我不僅僅是個酒保 我是個紳士
Jim, I'm not just a bartender, I'm a gentleman.

419
00:37:27,180 --> 00:37:29,910
不要告訴奧羅拉 是我喚醒了她
Don't tell Aurora that I woke her up.

420
00:37:31,800 --> 00:37:34,700
她覺得那是一個意外事故 讓我來跟她說
She thinks it was an accident. Let me tell her.

421
00:37:34,720 --> 00:37:36,430
當然
Of course.

422
00:37:49,330 --> 00:37:51,820
怎么可能沒有辦法讓人重新進入休眠呢
How can there be no way to put someone back into hibernation?

423
00:37:51,850 --> 00:37:53,310
如果休眠艙壞掉了呢
What if a pod breaks down?

424
00:37:53,330 --> 00:37:54,670
幾千次飛行中
No hibernation pod has

425
00:37:54,680 --> 00:37:57,780
尚未有一個休眠艙發生故障
malfunctioned in thousands of interstellar flights.

426
00:37:58,130 --> 00:38:00,800
然而 我醒了
Well, I'm awake.

427
00:38:00,830 --> 00:38:03,640
休眠艙是萬無一失的
Hibernation pods are fail-safe.

428
00:38:03,660 --> 00:38:06,000
早上好 你吃早飯了嗎
Good morning. Have you eaten?

429
00:38:06,020 --> 00:38:08,100
沒有 我餓死了
No, I'm starving.

430
00:38:08,120 --> 00:38:10,460
這是天下最蠢的機器了
And this is the dumbest machine.

431
00:38:10,480 --> 00:38:12,350
非常樂意為您服務
Happy to help!

432
00:38:24,740 --> 00:38:27,100
黃金級早餐
Gold-class breakfast.

433
00:38:37,310 --> 00:38:39,520
你的品位很簡樸呀
Well, you're a man of simple tastes.

434
00:38:39,550 --> 00:38:42,030
我可不是一個黃金級乘客
I'm not a gold-class passenger.

435
00:38:44,010 --> 00:38:46,200
法國泡芙早餐不是我等之人可以享受的起
French Breakfast Puff is above my pay grade.

436
00:38:46,220 --> 00:38:47,920
什么 你一直就吃這個
What? This whole time?

437
00:38:47,940 --> 00:38:49,700
- 是的 - 我幫你點些別的吧
- Yeah. - What can I get you?

438
00:38:49,730 --> 00:38:51,640
- 不 不用了 沒事 - 別說了
- No. No, I'm fine, - Stop it.

439
00:38:51,670 --> 00:38:53,860
真的 好吧
really... Okay.

440
00:38:55,190 --> 00:38:56,920
給你
Here you go.

441
00:39:01,670 --> 00:39:03,070
是啊
Yeah.

442
00:39:03,090 --> 00:39:04,800
你看 我在想
So, I was thinking.

443
00:39:04,820 --> 00:39:06,550
或許可以換種方式休眠
Maybe there's another way to go to sleep.

444
00:39:06,550 --> 00:39:07,610
治療艙怎么樣
What about the infirmary?

445
00:39:07,630 --> 00:39:10,040
我檢查過了 那只是些掃描儀和自動診斷機
I've checked it out. It's just scanners and an autodoc.

446
00:39:10,060 --> 00:39:12,500
貨物艙中或許會有其它的休眠艙
There could be another hibernation machine in the cargo hold.

447
00:39:12,500 --> 00:39:13,890
我也想過了
I've had that thought too.

448
00:39:13,910 --> 00:39:15,140
然后我看了貨物清單
And then I read the manifests.

449
00:39:15,140 --> 00:39:17,630
只有些農業用具 機器和商用貨物
It's mostly farming stuff, machines and trade goods,

450
00:39:17,650 --> 00:39:19,970
工程電腦上的備用零件
replacement parts for computers in Engineering.

451
00:39:19,990 --> 00:39:22,300
我們是不可能在箱子中翻出一個休眠艙的
We're not going to find a hibernation facility in a box.

452
00:39:22,330 --> 00:39:24,020
- 我們可以自己造 - 不能
- We can build our own. - We can't.

453
00:39:24,020 --> 00:39:27,820
- 吉米 你都還沒試過 - 我任何方法都用遍了
- Jim, you're not even trying! - I have tried everything.

454
00:39:27,850 --> 00:39:29,860
花了一年多時間
For over a year.

455
00:39:30,970 --> 00:39:32,890
任何方法都用遍了
I tried everything.

456
00:39:35,250 --> 00:39:37,460
好吧 我現在還不想放棄
Oh well, I'm not ready to give up.

457
00:39:46,160 --> 00:39:48,120
治療艙
Infirmary.

458
00:39:55,650 --> 00:39:58,420
那有研究論文 任何技術文檔嗎
What about research articles, any kind of technical documents?

459
00:39:58,440 --> 00:40:01,160
休眠技術是一項專利
Hibernation technology is proprietary.

460
00:40:01,180 --> 00:40:02,650
下面的這些文章
The following articles

461
00:40:02,650 --> 00:40:05,650
研究的主體僅處于理論階段
deal with the subject on a theoretical level.

462
00:40:48,360 --> 00:40:51,450
新建文件 我的旅程
New file. My Voyage.

463
00:40:51,620 --> 00:40:55,620
我帶著一個想法和一個目的地登上阿瓦隆號
I boarded the Avalon with an idea, a destination.

464
00:40:56,090 --> 00:41:00,280
然而現在 兩者都遙不可及
Both now, out of reach.

465
00:41:01,970 --> 00:41:04,370
我已經蘇醒7天了
I've been awake for 7 days,

466
00:41:04,400 --> 00:41:06,970
醒得太早了
awake far too soon...

467
00:41:06,990 --> 00:41:09,840
甚至我可能余生都要在這里度過了
and I may well spend the rest of my life here...

468
00:41:09,870 --> 00:41:14,120
在一個1000公尺長的鋼鐵世界里度過
...in a steel world a 1,000 meters long.

469
00:41:15,300 --> 00:41:17,330
除我之外 還有個人也醒著
There's another passenger awake.

470
00:41:17,360 --> 00:41:20,220
一個叫吉姆 普勒斯頓的機修工
A mechanic named Jim Preston.

471
00:41:21,890 --> 00:41:24,680
他貌似已經接受了命運的安排
He seems to have accepted our fate.

472
00:41:25,260 --> 00:41:27,290
但是我很害怕
But I'm scared.

473
00:41:28,010 --> 00:41:30,590
我努力保持鎮靜
I'm fighting to stay calm.

474
00:41:32,590 --> 00:41:37,810
其他乘客們還要再睡90年才會醒
All the other passengers will sleep for another 90 years.

475
00:41:38,450 --> 00:41:43,990
而我卻在這艘飛行的船里 荒廢余生
While I live out my life on this ship... traveling forever...

476
00:41:44,600 --> 00:41:46,530
永遠到不了終點
never arriving.

477
00:41:47,120 --> 00:41:50,040
我僅有的慰藉 卻是一個陌生人
My only companion, a total stranger.

478
00:41:58,810 --> 00:42:00,580
為什么你要這么做
Why did you do it?

479
00:42:02,730 --> 00:42:04,350
做什么
Do what?

480
00:42:05,210 --> 00:42:07,850
移民 離開地球
Emigrate. Leave Earth.

481
00:42:08,720 --> 00:42:10,680
我在采訪你
I'm interviewing you.

482
00:42:10,710 --> 00:42:11,620
你在干什么
You're what?

483
00:42:11,640 --> 00:42:13,090
你是在整個太空旅行史上
You're the first hibernation

484
00:42:13,090 --> 00:42:15,100
第一例休眠失敗者
failure in the history of space travel.

485
00:42:15,120 --> 00:42:17,070
這會讓你被載入史冊
That makes you a story.

486
00:42:17,180 --> 00:42:19,800
- 那你要把這故事說給誰呢 - 子孫后代
- Who are you going to tell? - Posterity.

487
00:42:19,820 --> 00:42:23,200
那你為什么放棄你在地球上的生活呢
So why did you give up your life on Earth?

488
00:42:23,220 --> 00:42:24,880
120年的休眠
A 120 years space hibernation

489
00:42:24,880 --> 00:42:27,670
意味著你再也無法見到你的親朋好友了
means you never see your family or friends again.

490
00:42:27,670 --> 00:42:31,380
你醒來的地方是另一個世紀 陌生的星球
You'll wake up in a new century, on a new planet.

491
00:42:31,520 --> 00:42:33,820
簡直就是終極的自殺行為
It's the ultimate geographical suicide.

492
00:42:33,850 --> 00:42:36,070
那我也可以問你同樣的問題
Well, I could ask you the same thing.

493
00:42:36,090 --> 00:42:38,040
但這是我的采訪
But it's my interview.

494
00:42:38,380 --> 00:42:40,400
你是在逃避什么嗎
Were you running away from something?

495
00:42:40,430 --> 00:42:41,850
不是
No.

496
00:42:42,180 --> 00:42:44,320
- 一切都很好 - 那是什么
- Everything was okay. - So?

497
00:42:44,590 --> 00:42:47,250
我想我只是想要一個全新的世界 我不確定 一個全新的開始吧
I guess I just wanted a new world. I don't know, a fresh start.

498
00:42:47,280 --> 00:42:49,360
那是新家園公司的廣告上說的
That's HomeStead Company advertising.

499
00:42:49,390 --> 00:42:50,850
- 是嗎 - 吉姆
- Is it? - Jim.

500
00:42:50,880 --> 00:42:53,650
我 我知道 我想你是對的
I... I know. I guess, you're right.

501
00:42:58,270 --> 00:43:00,020
在地球上 每當東西出現故障了
Back on Earth, when something breaks,

502
00:43:00,020 --> 00:43:01,580
你不去修理它 而是換一個新的
you don't fix it, you replace it.

503
00:43:02,050 --> 00:43:04,850
在殖民星 他們有很多問題需要解決
In the colonies, they have problems to solve.

504
00:43:04,880 --> 00:43:07,030
我可以解決的問題
They're my kind of problems.

505
00:43:08,220 --> 00:43:10,430
機修工不再是無足輕重
And the mechanic is somebody.

506
00:43:10,450 --> 00:43:12,940
一個新的世界等待著我去創建
It's a new world still being built.

507
00:43:14,900 --> 00:43:17,180
我可以建造一個新家園 住進去
I can build a house and live in it.

508
00:43:21,910 --> 00:43:24,890
開放的國家 發展的空間
Open country, room to grow.

509
00:43:24,910 --> 00:43:26,520
你又回到宣傳語上了
Now you're back to slogans.

510
00:43:26,540 --> 00:43:28,690
宣傳語就不能是真的嗎
Can't slogans be true?

511
00:43:29,910 --> 00:43:30,980
你知道新家園公司打造
Do you know how much

512
00:43:30,980 --> 00:43:33,450
第一個殖民星球花了多少錢嗎
Homestead Company's made off its first planet?

513
00:43:33,470 --> 00:43:35,660
八千萬億美元
8 quadrillion dollars.

514
00:43:35,690 --> 00:43:38,380
八千萬億啊
That's 8 million billions.

515
00:43:38,400 --> 00:43:41,140
星球殖民現在是最大的生意了
Colony planets are the biggest business now.

516
00:43:41,310 --> 00:43:43,090
你付的是全價嗎
Did you pay full price for your ticket?

517
00:43:43,110 --> 00:43:45,530
不是  我跟他們做了個好交易
No, I'm in a desirable trade.

518
00:43:45,550 --> 00:43:49,260
也就是說他們會實現你的夢想
So they fill your head with dreams,

519
00:43:49,290 --> 00:43:52,090
并給你折扣票價 而你過去增加他們星球的人口
discount your ticket, and you fly off to populate their planet

520
00:43:52,110 --> 00:43:53,100
并在余生里給新家園
and give HomeStead 20% of

521
00:43:53,100 --> 00:43:55,120
上交20%的收入
everything that you made for the rest of your life.

522
00:43:55,140 --> 00:43:58,430
更不用說 你在這艘華麗的船上的生活費用
Not to mention the debt you run up on this fancy starship.

523
00:43:58,450 --> 00:44:01,560
所以你在兒看到的 只是5000個失敗者么
So all you see here is 5,000 suckers?

524
00:44:01,720 --> 00:44:05,460
依我看新家園公司沒有任何底線
I see zeroes on the HomeStead Company's bottom line.

525
00:44:05,480 --> 00:44:09,010
我看到的是 5000個男女在改變他們的人生
I see 5,000 men and women changing their lives.

526
00:44:09,260 --> 00:44:12,110
每個人都有不同的原因 你并不了解這些人
for 5,000 different reasons. You don't know these people.

527
00:44:12,130 --> 00:44:15,340
我是一個記者 我了解人
I'm a journalist. I know people.

528
00:44:16,680 --> 00:44:18,420
真的嗎
Really?

529
00:44:18,440 --> 00:44:19,860
這個
This one.

530
00:44:19,890 --> 00:44:23,040
他是一個銀行家 教師還是一個園丁
Is he a banker, a teacher or a gardener?

531
00:44:23,980 --> 00:44:26,590
- 銀行家 - 他是一個園丁
- Banker. - He's a gardener.

532
00:44:27,370 --> 00:44:33,380
還有她 她叫麥迪遜 唐娜還是羅拉
And her, is she a Maddison, Donna or Lola?

533
00:44:34,100 --> 00:44:36,450
“唐娜”這個名字對她的頭發來說好嚴肅
Donna's too serious for that hair.

534
00:44:36,470 --> 00:44:38,080
羅拉
Lola.

535
00:44:38,220 --> 00:44:40,580
- 麥迪遜 - 草
- Maddison. - Shit.

536
00:44:42,400 --> 00:44:43,450
好的
Alright.

537
00:44:43,480 --> 00:44:45,540
廚師 會計還是助產士
Chef, accountant or midwife?

538
00:44:45,570 --> 00:44:46,560
她肯定是助產士
She has to be a midwife.

539
00:44:46,560 --> 00:44:48,260
你不可能是亂編出來的
There's no way you just made that one up.

540
00:44:48,290 --> 00:44:50,090
他是助產士
She's a midwife.

541
00:44:51,080 --> 00:44:53,320
很高興知道他們還需要助產士
Good to know they still have midwives.

542
00:44:55,320 --> 00:44:58,330
我喜歡她 我們會做朋友的
I like her. We would be friends.

543
00:44:58,360 --> 00:45:00,300
你覺得你可以預見未來嗎
You think you can see that?

544
00:45:00,320 --> 00:45:02,040
你不可以嗎
Don't you?

545
00:45:03,830 --> 00:45:05,270
我可以
I do.

546
00:45:05,300 --> 00:45:07,070
往返票
A round trip ticket.

547
00:45:07,100 --> 00:45:09,590
對 我飛到新家園2號
That's right. I was going to fly to Homestead Ⅱ,

548
00:45:09,610 --> 00:45:11,790
住上一年 然后又返回地球
live for a year and then right back to Earth.

549
00:45:11,810 --> 00:45:13,590
我不明白 我為了新的人生離開地球
I don't get it. I left Earth for a new life.

550
00:45:13,620 --> 00:45:15,190
但你最終又回到開始的地方
But you end up back where you started.

551
00:45:15,190 --> 00:45:19,240
我最終會在未來 250年后的未來
I end up in the future. 250 years in the future.

552
00:45:19,260 --> 00:45:20,870
地球 那兒還是
On Earth, which is still

553
00:45:20,870 --> 00:45:23,740
文明的中心 無論你喜歡不喜歡
the center of civilization, like it or not.

554
00:45:24,280 --> 00:45:25,620
而我會是唯一一個
And I would be the only writer

555
00:45:25,620 --> 00:45:27,900
去往殖民地又回來的作家
that ever travel to the colony world and come back.

556
00:45:27,930 --> 00:45:29,790
我會有一個獨一無二的故事
I'll have a story no one else can tell.

557
00:45:29,820 --> 00:45:31,390
什么故事
What story?

558
00:45:31,410 --> 00:45:33,850
人類飛往星際的旅行
Humanity's flight to the stars.

559
00:45:33,880 --> 00:45:35,940
人類歷史上最大的移民
The greatest migration in human history.

560
00:45:35,950 --> 00:45:37,600
會是最受歡迎的的故事
It's the biggest story there is.

561
00:45:37,620 --> 00:45:39,330
但你并不會知道 是誰在讀你的故事
But you won't know any of the people who were reading it.

562
00:45:39,360 --> 00:45:41,230
但反正會有人讀的
But they'd be reading it.

563
00:45:43,590 --> 00:45:45,590
好吧 本會有人讀的
Well, they would have been.

564
00:45:46,800 --> 00:45:48,560
我現在是寫不成了
I'll never write it now.

565
00:45:48,580 --> 00:45:51,010
我也不知道 以后會不會有機會寫了
I don't know if I'll ever write again.

566
00:45:52,850 --> 00:45:56,570
吉姆 我想不出任何辦法
Jim, I can't think of anything else to try

567
00:45:56,600 --> 00:45:58,690
來拯救我們
...to save us.

568
00:46:00,080 --> 00:46:02,780
我甚至都再也不想去想這些問題了
And I don't even want to think about it anymore.

569
00:46:05,020 --> 00:46:07,380
這兒還有什么事情可以做嗎
What is there to do around here?

570
00:46:09,380 --> 00:46:12,280
- 你是認真的嗎 - 我非常認真
- Are you serious? - I'm dead serious.

571
00:46:12,290 --> 00:46:13,950
雙人模式
Partner mode.

572
00:46:15,490 --> 00:46:17,410
來吧 快來雙人模式
Come on, get in partner mode.

573
00:46:23,840 --> 00:46:27,620
你就站在這里 然后重復他們的動作
You just stand here, and then we repeat what they do.

574
00:46:35,210 --> 00:46:37,390
還有別的我們可以做的事情嗎
Is there anything else we can do?

575
00:46:37,410 --> 00:46:38,620
- 快來吧 - 好吧
- Just do the... - Okay.

576
00:46:38,640 --> 00:46:40,070
- 你不愿意的話可以不做 - 好吧
- You don't have to. - Okay.

577
00:46:40,100 --> 00:46:41,190
弱爆了
Beat down.

578
00:46:41,220 --> 00:46:42,720
嘿
Hey.

579
00:46:42,740 --> 00:46:44,650
來吧 讓我們看看..
Here we go. Let's see if... Oh.

580
00:46:44,670 --> 00:46:46,610
哇 哇哦
Whoa! Whoa!

581
00:46:47,090 --> 00:46:49,320
噢 你在笑什么
Oh. Why are you smiling?

582
00:46:49,340 --> 00:46:51,550
我領先兩分了
I'm up 2 points.

583
00:46:51,830 --> 00:46:53,240
這位可愛的女士是誰
Who's the lovely lady?

584
00:46:53,270 --> 00:46:54,630
這位是奧羅拉
This is Aurora.

585
00:46:54,660 --> 00:46:57,520
奧羅拉女士 榮幸
Aurora. A pleasure.

586
00:47:00,310 --> 00:47:02,450
-你跳得很棒 -好吧 再來一次
- You did great! - Okay. One more time.

587
00:47:02,470 --> 00:47:03,860
再來一次 這次準行
One more time. Let's see it.

588
00:47:09,910 --> 00:47:11,250
噢
Oh!

589
00:47:15,460 --> 00:47:17,320
- 耶 -哇
- YES! - Woo!

590
00:47:19,830 --> 00:47:21,850
對不起我之前一個月都沒穿褲子
Sorry I didn't wear pants for a month.

591
00:47:21,870 --> 00:47:24,270
確切來說是7個星期又2天
That's 7 weeks and 2 days, to be exact.

592
00:47:24,300 --> 00:47:25,800
這位男士沒有什么羞恥心
The man has no shame.

593
00:47:25,820 --> 00:47:29,200
你在穿褲子方面并沒有什么話語權 亞瑟
Well, you're a little lacking in that area yourself, Arthur.

594
00:47:31,640 --> 00:47:35,940
我嘲笑了一個男人不穿褲子 才想起來我自己連腿都沒有
I laughed at a man with no pants until I realised I have no legs.

595
00:47:41,910 --> 00:47:44,890
有時候 我差點忘了我的人生已經毀了
For a minute, I almost forgot my life isn't ruined.

596
00:47:44,910 --> 00:47:46,460
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

597
00:47:46,770 --> 00:47:48,640
你抱歉什么
What for?

598
00:47:49,500 --> 00:47:51,220
我去睡覺了
I'm going to go to bed.

599
00:47:51,950 --> 00:47:53,480
- 晚安 - 好
- Good night. - Alright.

600
00:47:53,510 --> 00:47:55,430
晚安 奧羅拉
Good night, Aurora.

601
00:47:58,110 --> 00:48:00,850
她太贊了
She is wonderful.

602
00:48:01,270 --> 00:48:03,280
明智之選
Excellent choice.

603
00:49:30,600 --> 00:49:32,070
你好
Hello.

604
00:49:32,360 --> 00:49:33,850
你好
Hi.

605
00:49:33,930 --> 00:49:35,680
這個給你
Here you go.

606
00:49:41,320 --> 00:49:43,340
他在約我嗎
Is he asking me on a date?

607
00:49:45,220 --> 00:49:46,980
你需要筆嗎
Do you need a pen?

608
00:49:59,520 --> 00:50:01,780
她似乎沒有很意外
She didn't seem that impressed.

609
00:50:19,460 --> 00:50:21,870
“我很樂意” 她說“我很樂意”
"Love to." She wrote "Love to".

610
00:50:29,650 --> 00:50:31,810
您有一位訪客
You have a visitor.

611
00:50:49,910 --> 00:50:51,030
天啊
Wow.

612
00:50:51,050 --> 00:50:53,330
你打扮得很帥嘛
You clean up pretty good yourself.

613
00:50:54,110 --> 00:50:57,320
- 你去買購物了 - 我去購..健身了
- You went shopping. - I went shop... lifting.

614
00:51:02,240 --> 00:51:04,590
晚上好 我能為你們做些什么
Evening. What can I get for you?

615
00:51:04,610 --> 00:51:07,260
我要一杯曼哈頓酒 謝謝
I'll have a Manhattan, please.

616
00:51:08,090 --> 00:51:10,500
- 威士忌加冰 - 稍等
- Whiskey rocks. - Coming up.

617
00:51:18,330 --> 00:51:20,150
今晚兩位看起來很棒啊
You two look fine this evening.

618
00:51:20,170 --> 00:51:21,660
謝謝 亞瑟
Thank you, Arthur.

619
00:51:21,680 --> 00:51:23,280
我們在約會呢
We're on a date!

620
00:51:23,300 --> 00:51:25,370
不錯嘛
Very nice.

621
00:51:25,390 --> 00:51:27,560
你竟然花了這么久才開口
Took you long enough to ask.

622
00:51:27,560 --> 00:51:29,250
我想給你多一些空間
I was giving you space.

623
00:51:29,280 --> 00:51:30,610
噢
Oh.

624
00:51:30,720 --> 00:51:34,720
空間 是我在這里唯一不想多要的東西
Space, the one thing I do not need more of.

625
00:51:37,730 --> 00:51:39,680
非常感謝
Thank you very much.

626
00:51:40,710 --> 00:51:42,110
這頓飯真不錯
That was so good.

627
00:51:42,130 --> 00:51:44,080
那當然 預訂這里的位子可不容易
Well, it wasn't easy getting a reservation.

628
00:51:44,110 --> 00:51:46,600
他們也許已經盼著我們趕緊離開了
They probably going to want us to give up our table.

629
00:51:46,630 --> 00:51:50,060
- 我看到好幾個服務員的臉色很臭了 - 今晚這里人真多
- Getting a lot of dirty looks. - Very popular tonight.

630
00:51:51,620 --> 00:51:53,240
你的書寫得怎么樣
So how's your book coming?

631
00:51:53,270 --> 00:51:55,680
現在還沒有什么頭緒
I don't really know what it is yet.

632
00:51:56,320 --> 00:51:58,970
我父親是從他的人生開始寫的
My dad, he started to write about his life, but...

633
00:51:59,000 --> 00:52:01,020
畢竟他是一個有故事的人
he had stories. He...

634
00:52:01,350 --> 00:52:03,970
他去過南極洲探險
sailed around Antarctica. He...

635
00:52:04,000 --> 00:52:07,900
當過戰地記者 他...有他的情人們
was a war reporter. He... had lovers.

636
00:52:07,940 --> 00:52:10,130
他也寫過他女兒
He wrote about his daughter.

637
00:52:10,160 --> 00:52:11,920
- 他寫過你 - 對
- He wrote about you? - No.

638
00:52:11,950 --> 00:52:13,920
我是讀著他書里的自己長大的
I grew up reading about myself in his books.

639
00:52:13,950 --> 00:52:15,440
感覺怎么樣
How was that?

640
00:52:16,220 --> 00:52:17,570
有時候并不好受
Not always easy.

641
00:52:17,590 --> 00:52:20,500
有點超過了一個人需要了解自身的程度
A little more than you wanted to know about yourself.

642
00:52:20,520 --> 00:52:25,890
在我17歲的時候 他犯了心臟病
I mean, when I was 17, he had a heart attack.

643
00:52:27,080 --> 00:52:29,090
我一直留著他的書
I-I just keep that.

644
00:52:29,590 --> 00:52:31,480
故事結束
End of story.

645
00:52:34,180 --> 00:52:37,280
對不起 話題太沉重了
Oh, so serious. I'm sorry.

646
00:52:37,290 --> 00:52:38,500
我們需要更多的酒
We need more wine.

647
00:52:38,520 --> 00:52:40,770
我很愿意了解你的人生
I like to hear about your life.

648
00:52:41,770 --> 00:52:43,270
謝謝
Thanks.

649
00:52:45,410 --> 00:52:46,890
我們來這里做什么
Why are we here?

650
00:52:46,910 --> 00:52:48,490
等會你就知道了
You'll see.

651
00:52:50,160 --> 00:52:51,990
城里最棒的演出
Best show in town.

652
00:52:55,570 --> 00:52:57,590
你之前試過嗎
So you've done this before?

653
00:52:57,620 --> 00:52:59,330
沒錯
Oh yeah.

654
00:52:59,360 --> 00:53:00,780
這安全嗎
And it's safe?

655
00:53:00,800 --> 00:53:02,330
不
No.

656
00:53:03,260 --> 00:53:05,040
是相當安全
Reasonably safe.

657
00:53:06,370 --> 00:53:09,110
穿上吧 你是下一個
Hop in. You're next.

658
00:53:10,180 --> 00:53:12,100
我的裙子怎么辦
What about my dress?

659
00:53:14,320 --> 00:53:16,100
哦對
Right.

660
00:53:18,320 --> 00:53:20,140
轉過去
Turn around.

661
00:53:50,690 --> 00:53:52,490
安全繩就位
Tether attached.

662
00:54:33,200 --> 00:54:34,810
你想干什么
What are you doing?

663
00:54:35,150 --> 00:54:36,950
你相信我嗎
Do you trust me?

664
00:55:23,570 --> 00:55:25,380
謝謝你
Thank you.

665
00:56:14,050 --> 00:56:16,930
你是我見過最美的女人
You're the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.

666
00:56:19,990 --> 00:56:22,010
勾走了我的魂
You kill me.

667
00:57:04,210 --> 00:57:06,060
你還好嗎
You okay?

668
00:57:06,270 --> 00:57:07,680
嗯
Yeah.

669
00:57:09,400 --> 00:57:11,090
我很好
I am fine.

670
00:57:11,250 --> 00:57:12,780
我只是
It's just...

671
00:57:20,250 --> 00:57:22,100
嗯 我懂的
Yeah, I know.

672
00:57:37,720 --> 00:57:40,460
我正在跟一個人約會
So, I'm seeing someone.

673
00:57:40,490 --> 00:57:42,360
你怎么也猜不到是誰
You'll never guess who.

674
00:57:43,600 --> 00:57:44,910
我們是當世間只剩下兩個人時
We're the last 2 people

675
00:57:44,910 --> 00:57:47,300
才可能在一起的兩個人
in the world who ever get to get together.

676
00:57:47,330 --> 00:57:49,070
而現在
But here we are.

677
00:57:49,070 --> 00:57:51,050
我們正是這世間僅剩的兩個人
The last 2 people in the world.

678
00:57:51,080 --> 00:57:52,180
你剛剛說什么
What did you say?

679
00:57:52,200 --> 00:57:54,440
我在寫作 亞瑟 噓
I'm writing, Arthur, hush.

680
00:57:54,780 --> 00:57:57,980
吉姆和我活在一種意外的幸福中
Jim and I live in an accidental happiness.

681
00:57:58,010 --> 00:58:01,090
如同海上失事的漂流者 在陌生的海岸重建新家園
Like castaways making their home on strange shores.

682
00:58:01,120 --> 00:58:03,270
“陌生的海岸”我喜歡這里
"Strange shores". I love it.

683
00:58:03,290 --> 00:58:04,770
真的嗎 你不用哄我
You do? You don't have to say that.

684
00:58:04,790 --> 00:58:07,200
- 我知道 - 你不吃這個吧
- I know. - You're not going to eat this?

685
00:58:09,380 --> 00:58:11,380
你覺得那個可疑嗎
That seemed fishy to you?

686
00:58:13,000 --> 00:58:14,500
接著看
Keep reading.

687
00:58:14,520 --> 00:58:16,050
有趣的是
It's funny.

688
00:58:16,070 --> 00:58:18,290
我們都懷有夢想
We all have dreams.

689
00:58:18,670 --> 00:58:22,610
我們曾計劃未來 以為自己是命運的舵手
We planned our futures like we're the captains of our fates.

690
00:58:22,780 --> 00:58:24,480
然而我們只是命運的乘客
But we are passengers.

691
00:58:24,500 --> 00:58:27,220
隨命運而去
We go where fate takes us.

692
00:58:29,990 --> 00:58:31,010
亞瑟
Arthur!

693
00:58:31,040 --> 00:58:33,020
這不是我們計劃中的人生
This isn't the life we planned.

694
00:58:33,050 --> 00:58:34,830
但這就是我們的人生
But it's ours.

695
00:58:34,850 --> 00:58:37,430
這是我生命中第一次
And for the first time in my life,

696
00:58:37,460 --> 00:58:39,650
不再感到孤獨
I don't feel

697
00:58:41,940 --> 00:58:44,470
我們原本不會遇見彼此的
We weren't supposed to find each other,

698
00:58:45,670 --> 00:58:47,360
但是我們還是相遇了
but we did.

699
00:58:47,990 --> 00:58:51,130
他讓我覺得我的生命還沒有結束
He makes me feel like my life isn't over.

700
00:58:51,280 --> 00:58:53,470
而是剛剛開始
Like it's just beginning.

701
00:58:54,040 --> 00:58:55,180
今天過得怎么樣
How was your day?

702
00:58:55,200 --> 00:58:57,510
挺好的 我寫了幾頁
Good, I wrote a few pages.

703
00:58:57,540 --> 00:58:59,900
你發現有什么能幫我們的東西了嗎
Did you find anything that can help us?

704
00:59:03,220 --> 00:59:05,700
- 發現了 - 這些是真的嗎
- I did. - Are they real?

705
00:59:05,720 --> 00:59:07,930
我親自剪下來的
I cut them myself.

706
00:59:11,040 --> 00:59:14,580
對于兩個不幸的人來說 我們已經很幸運了
You know for 2 unlucky people, we sure got pretty lucky.

707
00:59:19,410 --> 00:59:20,860
注意
Attention.

708
00:59:20,890 --> 00:59:24,610
你可能想來瞭望區看看
You may wish to proceed to a Viewing Area.

709
00:59:24,620 --> 00:59:28,850
我們馬上要和大角星擦過
The Avalon will slingshot around the star Arcturus.

710
00:59:29,890 --> 00:59:32,050
我的天
Oh my god...

711
01:00:06,770 --> 01:00:08,880
太奇妙了
That was amazing.

712
01:00:10,460 --> 01:00:12,620
我們就像是一個巨星
We were a giant.

713
01:00:16,780 --> 01:00:19,150
這個宇宙是給你的禮物
The universe is a present to you.

714
01:00:19,350 --> 01:00:20,830
什么
What?

715
01:00:21,900 --> 01:00:24,020
生日快樂
Happy birthday.

716
01:00:30,560 --> 01:00:39,170
祝你生日快樂 祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you... Happy birthday to you...

717
01:00:39,190 --> 01:00:43,540
祝奧羅拉生日快樂
Happy birthday, dear Aurora...

718
01:00:43,570 --> 01:00:47,990
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you.

719
01:00:49,740 --> 01:00:51,760
生日酒敬過生日的你
A birthday drink for the birthday girl.

720
01:00:51,790 --> 01:00:52,980
你都不問問我身份證上多大了嗎
Aren't you going to ask for my I.D.?

721
01:00:52,980 --> 01:00:54,140
我可能還不能喝酒呢
I might not be old enough to drink.

722
01:00:54,170 --> 01:00:57,100
噢 我不會在一個紳士面前問你的年齡的
Oh, I'd never ask your age in front of a gentleman.

723
01:00:57,130 --> 01:00:58,560
吉姆可不是什么紳士
Jim is no gentleman.

724
01:00:58,580 --> 01:01:01,430
不管怎樣 我和吉姆之間是沒有什么秘密的
Anyway there's no secrets between me and Jim.

725
01:01:02,340 --> 01:01:03,690
真的嗎
Is that so?

726
01:01:03,710 --> 01:01:07,420
你聽到她說的了 我馬上回來
You heard the lady. I will be right back.

727
01:01:21,590 --> 01:01:24,240
這杯生日酒太完美了 謝謝你
This is a perfect birthday drink, thank you.

728
01:01:24,270 --> 01:01:27,440
我還記得一年前的這天
I remember this day, a year ago.

729
01:01:27,470 --> 01:01:30,370
吉姆是如此的想見你
Jim was so looking forward to meeting you.

730
01:01:30,780 --> 01:01:32,190
什么
What?

731
01:01:32,500 --> 01:01:34,460
他怎么會想見我
How could he be looking forward to it?

732
01:01:34,480 --> 01:01:38,000
噢 他考慮了好幾個月到底要不要喚醒你
Oh, he spent months deciding whether to wake you up.

733
01:01:38,030 --> 01:01:41,040
他不停地跟我談論你
He couldn't stop talking about you.

734
01:01:44,800 --> 01:01:46,910
是吉姆喚醒我的
Jim woke me up.

735
01:01:47,370 --> 01:01:48,860
沒錯啊
Oh, yes.

736
01:01:49,390 --> 01:01:52,290
他說這是他這輩子最難做的決定
He said it was the hardest decision of his life,

737
01:01:52,320 --> 01:01:55,430
但我覺得現在挺好的
but I see it worked out just fine.

738
01:02:07,360 --> 01:02:08,870
什么
What?

739
01:02:11,230 --> 01:02:13,500
是你把我喚醒了嗎
Did you wake me up?

740
01:02:20,800 --> 01:02:22,800
是的 是我做的
Yes. I woke you up.

741
01:02:26,710 --> 01:02:28,460
你怎么能
How...

742
01:02:28,680 --> 01:02:30,660
你怎么能這么做
How could you do it?

743
01:02:33,050 --> 01:02:34,890
我試過不要那么做
I tried not to.

744
01:02:41,090 --> 01:02:43,130
我真覺得惡心
I'm going to be sick.

745
01:02:43,690 --> 01:02:45,810
我看不出來
I can't see!

746
01:02:47,050 --> 01:02:48,830
奧羅拉 求求你
Aurora, please.

747
01:02:48,860 --> 01:02:52,030
離我遠點
Stay away from me!

748
01:02:54,740 --> 01:02:57,960
我要離開這個飛船 我要離開這個飛船
I got to get off this ship. I got to get off this ship.

749
01:02:57,980 --> 01:02:59,480
我要離開這兒
I got to get off.

750
01:04:14,660 --> 01:04:16,780
我能和你談談嗎
Can I talk to you?

751
01:05:44,790 --> 01:05:46,640
奧羅拉
Aurora.

752
01:05:46,880 --> 01:05:50,180
我不知道說什么才能讓你感覺好點
I know nothing I can say will make this okay.

753
01:05:50,380 --> 01:05:52,370
但請聽我說
But please listen.

754
01:05:52,390 --> 01:05:54,420
我太孤獨了
I was so alone

755
01:05:54,790 --> 01:05:56,780
很長時間都是我一個人
for so long.

756
01:05:57,880 --> 01:06:00,290
我感覺自己好像從世界上消失了
I felt like I was disappearing.

757
01:06:00,920 --> 01:06:04,300
第一次見到你的那天晚上 我正準備
The night I first saw you, I was ready to...

758
01:06:07,280 --> 01:06:09,380
是你救了我
You saved my life.

759
01:06:11,670 --> 01:06:14,850
我知道沒有我沒有合適的借口
And I know that's no excuse for what I did.

760
01:06:16,170 --> 01:06:18,300
我讀了你寫的所有東西
I read everything you wrote.

761
01:06:18,330 --> 01:06:21,990
我愛上了你的聲音
And I fell in love with your voice

762
01:06:22,010 --> 01:06:25,110
也愛上了你思維的方式
and with the way your mind works.

763
01:06:25,140 --> 01:06:27,400
愛上了你
I fell in love with you.

764
01:06:28,580 --> 01:06:30,500
突然
And all of a sudden,

765
01:06:30,680 --> 01:06:34,590
我感覺自己沒有被困在這兒了
it was like I wasn't trapped anymore.

766
01:06:34,670 --> 01:06:38,140
我了無目的的人生突然有了活下去的意義
My pointless life suddenly had meaning.

767
01:06:40,380 --> 01:06:42,560
我希望這一切都沒有發生
And I wish I could take it back.

768
01:06:43,940 --> 01:06:45,720
但是我做不到
But I can't.

769
01:06:47,060 --> 01:06:48,590
奧羅拉 我不想失去你
Aurora, I don't want to lose you.

770
01:06:48,610 --> 01:06:50,980
我才不在乎
I don't care !!!

771
01:06:51,010 --> 01:06:53,210
我不在乎你想要什么
I don't care what you want!

772
01:06:53,230 --> 01:06:55,970
也不在乎你為什么喚醒我
I don't care why you woke me up!

773
01:06:56,380 --> 01:06:59,490
你奪走了我的人生
You took my life!

774
01:07:22,050 --> 01:07:23,600
請耐心等待
Please standby.

775
01:07:23,630 --> 01:07:27,330
組件的控制中心正在重新啟動
Your suite's control center is rebooting.

776
01:07:46,270 --> 01:07:48,180
診斷系統故障
Diagnostic system failure

777
01:08:02,070 --> 01:08:04,190
亞瑟 我好羨慕你
I envy you, Arthur.

778
01:08:04,780 --> 01:08:06,000
為什么
How so?

779
01:08:06,030 --> 01:08:08,050
你是有目的的
You have a purpose.

780
01:08:10,290 --> 01:08:12,310
你總是很開心
You're always happy.

781
01:08:12,650 --> 01:08:15,040
你的書怎么樣了
How's your book coming along?

782
01:08:15,210 --> 01:08:17,560
我以前從沒有寫過自己
I've never written about me before.

783
01:08:17,580 --> 01:08:19,510
我覺得這是我最好的作品了
I think it's some of the best work I've ever done,

784
01:08:19,530 --> 01:08:22,020
但是我不知道我為什么寫它
and I don't even know why I'm doing it.

785
01:08:22,720 --> 01:08:25,790
只有一個人可以讀它 但我卻不愿讓他讀
There's only one person who could read it and I can't stand him.

786
01:08:25,820 --> 01:08:29,930
大家都說時間可以治愈一切
They say time heals all wounds.

787
01:08:32,500 --> 01:08:35,060
破碎的心沒那么容易治愈 亞瑟
Broken hearts aren't that simple, Arthur.

788
01:08:37,690 --> 01:08:40,000
你不會明白的
You wouldn't understand.

789
01:08:40,820 --> 01:08:42,620
亞瑟
Arthur!

790
01:08:46,850 --> 01:08:48,810
周二 亞瑟是我的
Tuesday is my day with Arthur.

791
01:08:48,840 --> 01:08:50,740
今天周三
It's Wednesday.

792
01:08:58,350 --> 01:09:00,140
酒吧是你們的了
The bar is all yours.

793
01:09:08,500 --> 01:09:10,850
你要什么 威士忌嗎
What will you have? Whiskey?

794
01:09:11,620 --> 01:09:13,110
咖啡
Coffee.

795
01:09:13,130 --> 01:09:15,180
- 奧羅拉 我們愛你 - 奧羅拉 我們愛你
- Aurora, we love you! - Aurora, we love you!

796
01:09:15,200 --> 01:09:17,790
沒有你我們該怎么辦呢 我們會想你的
What are we going to do without you? We'll miss you.

797
01:09:19,940 --> 01:09:21,380
這是我認識的最勇敢的女人
This is the bravest woman I know.

798
01:09:21,400 --> 01:09:22,960
- 嗨 奧羅拉 - 嗨 奧羅拉
- Hi, Aurora! - Hi, Aurora!

799
01:09:22,980 --> 01:09:26,710
我保證我每天都會想你的
I promise that I will think of you every day.

800
01:09:26,730 --> 01:09:28,840
當你醒來的時候 我就已經離開了
When you wake up I'll be gone,

801
01:09:28,870 --> 01:09:32,070
但是要記住我永遠不會忘了你
but just know that I will never forget you.

802
01:09:32,490 --> 01:09:34,400
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend.

803
01:09:35,340 --> 01:09:37,850
我知道你在這兒一直都不開心
You're never happy here, I know.

804
01:09:38,150 --> 01:09:40,530
對你來說這些并不足夠
Nothing was ever enough for you.

805
01:09:41,990 --> 01:09:44,430
你知道 你不一定非要離開的 你可以
You know, you don't have to go. You could-

806
01:09:44,460 --> 01:09:47,480
你可以在這里做任何你想做的事情
You could do whatever it is you have to do right here.

807
01:09:49,350 --> 01:09:50,610
但是
But...

808
01:09:50,640 --> 01:09:54,410
既然你要走了 我想送你幾句祝福
Since you're going, here's my wish.

809
01:09:56,080 --> 01:10:00,380
希望你最終能遇見一個可以填滿你內心的人 并且
I hope you finally find someone who fills your heart. And...

810
01:10:01,070 --> 01:10:03,250
希望你能讓他走進你心里
I hope you let him in.

811
01:10:04,440 --> 01:10:06,030
我希望你能知道
I hope you realized you

812
01:10:06,040 --> 01:10:09,290
你沒必要做一些非常厲害的事讓自己覺得開心
don't have to do something amazing to be happy.

813
01:10:10,890 --> 01:10:12,190
走吧
Go.

814
01:10:12,210 --> 01:10:13,860
祝你愉快
Have fun.

815
01:10:14,320 --> 01:10:16,330
抓住機遇
Take chances.

816
01:10:17,780 --> 01:10:20,090
嗯 就這樣
Um, okay.

817
01:10:21,040 --> 01:10:23,040
愛你哦 奧羅拉
I love you, Aurora.

818
01:10:23,310 --> 01:10:24,700
拜
Bye.

819
01:10:27,500 --> 01:10:29,310
早上好 亞瑟
Morning, Arthur!

820
01:10:29,460 --> 01:10:30,490
請來杯咖啡
Coffee please.

821
01:10:30,520 --> 01:10:31,930
馬上來
Coming up.

822
01:10:37,300 --> 01:10:39,550
你要弄臟我的吧臺嗎
Are you soiling my bar stool?

823
01:10:39,570 --> 01:10:42,730
要想做成一件事你必須親力親為
You want to make things, you got to get your hands dirty.

824
01:10:42,830 --> 01:10:46,060
- 那你一直在做什么呢 - 改良
- And what have you been making? - Improvements.

825
01:10:46,690 --> 01:10:48,900
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

826
01:11:15,890 --> 01:11:17,820
到達一層
First floor.

827
01:11:30,440 --> 01:11:32,510
黃金級早餐
Gold-class breakfast.

828
01:11:32,540 --> 01:11:33,900
啊
Huh!

829
01:11:48,450 --> 01:11:51,060
我是船長 格斯 曼庫索
This is Deck Chief Gus Mancuso.

830
01:11:51,970 --> 01:11:55,200
是哪個家伙在我的飛船上種了棵樹
Who the hell planted a tree on my ship?

831
01:12:16,550 --> 01:12:19,110
- 是誰干的 - 是我
- Who did that? - I did.

832
01:12:19,140 --> 01:12:20,380
你是誰
Who are you?

833
01:12:20,400 --> 01:12:22,100
我是吉姆 普勒斯頓
Jim Preston.

834
01:12:23,240 --> 01:12:24,800
奧羅拉 萊恩
Aurora Lane.

835
01:12:24,830 --> 01:12:26,260
其他人也蘇醒了嗎
Anybody else awake?

836
01:12:26,290 --> 01:12:27,990
只有我們兩個
Just me and him.

837
01:12:28,310 --> 01:12:30,640
我們離開多久了
How far along are we?

838
01:12:30,670 --> 01:12:32,820
到現在88年了
88 years to go.

839
01:12:40,489 --> 01:12:42,659
休眠艙故障
Hibernation failure.

840
01:12:43,609 --> 01:12:45,349
據他們所講這是不可能的
They said that couldn't happen.

841
01:12:45,379 --> 01:12:49,419
但是現在有三個人蘇醒 三個休眠艙故障
But 3 people, 3 pod failures.

842
01:12:53,889 --> 01:12:56,609
你想象不到我花費多長時間想闖進這里的
You have no idea how long I've been trying to get in there.

843
01:12:56,639 --> 01:12:59,279
你現在進來了 不能亂動任何東西
Now that you're in. Don't touch anything.

844
01:12:59,309 --> 01:13:00,809
這就是你工作的地方
This is where you work?

845
01:13:00,829 --> 01:13:03,469
不 這里是乘務員的 我是船長
No, this is flight crew, I'm a Deck Chief.

846
01:13:04,169 --> 01:13:07,069
操作系統 并行服務器 導航計算機
OPS, Navigation comp.

847
01:13:09,229 --> 01:13:11,769
未授權人員
Unauthorized personnel.

848
01:13:12,639 --> 01:13:14,129
抱歉
Sorry.

849
01:13:15,789 --> 01:13:19,049
如果我猜的沒錯的話 我們仍在軌道上
If I'm reading this right, we're still on course.

850
01:13:19,079 --> 01:13:21,829
所以不管飛船出了什么問題 導航還是在運行中的
So whatever's wrong with the ship, NavComp's still on the job.

851
01:13:21,849 --> 01:13:23,389
飛船出故障了嗎
There's something wrong with the ship?

852
01:13:23,409 --> 01:13:25,079
三個休眠艙出現故障 是的
3 pod failures? Yeah.

853
01:13:25,109 --> 01:13:27,929
某個地方出現了問題 但問題究竟在哪兒
There's something wrong. Question is what.

854
01:13:30,409 --> 01:13:32,039
奇了怪了
That's strange.

855
01:13:32,069 --> 01:13:32,809
我應該可以
I should be getting

856
01:13:32,809 --> 01:13:34,629
把整個飛船徹底檢查一遍
diagnostics from all over the ship right here,

857
01:13:34,649 --> 01:13:36,939
問題是沒有數據
but there's no data.

858
01:13:38,389 --> 01:13:40,259
只能手動檢查整個系統
Got to check all the systems manually.

859
01:13:40,289 --> 01:13:42,119
我們就不能將飛船掉頭 返回地球嗎
Can't we turn the ship around? Go back to Earth?

860
01:13:42,139 --> 01:13:43,829
不行 我們行駛速度是二分之一光速
No, we're doing 50% of lightspeed.

861
01:13:43,859 --> 01:13:46,109
返回將花費我們同樣時間
Turning back would take just as much time as going on.

862
01:13:46,129 --> 01:13:47,939
好吧 那我們必須的做點兒什么
Well, there's got to be something we can do!

863
01:13:47,959 --> 01:13:50,699
不行 我們還是按原計劃飛行
Sorry, we're going where we're going.

864
01:13:53,239 --> 01:13:54,709
你還好嗎
You okay?

865
01:13:55,279 --> 01:13:57,009
休眠緩沖
Hibernation hangover.

866
01:13:57,029 --> 01:13:58,819
一直都這樣
Get it all the time.

867
01:13:58,969 --> 01:14:00,879
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

868
01:14:00,909 --> 01:14:04,629
兩年了 你還種其他樹了嗎
2 years, huh? Any more trees I need to know about?

869
01:14:04,659 --> 01:14:06,059
小心
Look out!

870
01:14:10,399 --> 01:14:12,109
這種事從沒發生過
I've never seen this happen before.

871
01:14:12,119 --> 01:14:14,049
這些機器已經崩潰了
Those robots have been breaking down.

872
01:14:14,069 --> 01:14:17,239
這是第15個
This guy makes 15?

873
01:14:17,339 --> 01:14:18,299
15個了
15.

874
01:14:18,329 --> 01:14:20,009
今天早餐吧臺出故障了
The breakfast bar went crazy today.

875
01:14:20,039 --> 01:14:21,109
還有電梯
And the elevator.

876
01:14:21,129 --> 01:14:24,099
上周我的門壞了 我被困在客艙里了兩天
Last week my door broke. I was trapped in my cabin for 2 days.

877
01:14:24,119 --> 01:14:25,739
真的么
You were?

878
01:14:25,889 --> 01:14:29,169
這些都未曾出現過 至少在這個飛船上沒有
Things like that don't happen. Not on this ship.

879
01:14:29,189 --> 01:14:32,469
每個飛行艙有60個這樣的科技站
There are 60 of these tech-stations on every deck.

880
01:14:32,489 --> 01:14:34,229
這是對接縫
Docking slats.

881
01:14:34,249 --> 01:14:35,979
數據可以自動接收 懂了嗎
Data sinks automatically, you got it?

882
01:14:35,999 --> 01:14:37,699
- 懂 - 那就好
- Mm. - Yeah. - Okay.

883
01:14:37,729 --> 01:14:40,029
你負責一 二 飛行艙 你三四飛行艙
You take decks 1 and 2. You take decks 3 and 4.

884
01:14:40,059 --> 01:14:44,239
我到休眠站查看一下我們的休眠艙
I'm going down to the Hibernation Bay, to check our pods.

885
01:14:44,649 --> 01:14:46,759
現在可有看頭了
Now that should be interesting.

886
01:14:56,919 --> 01:14:59,439
你現在不是應該在飛行艙檢查嗎
Aren't you supposed to be making your rounds.

887
01:14:59,769 --> 01:15:01,689
我檢查完了
I finished.

888
01:15:03,799 --> 01:15:05,869
我查看了你的休眠艙
I checked your pod.

889
01:15:06,579 --> 01:15:09,199
問題很簡單 記錄芯片燒毀了
The problem's very simple. The clock chips burned out.

890
01:15:09,219 --> 01:15:12,039
這不應該啊 但這個比較簡單
It ain't supposed to happen, but pretty simple.

891
01:15:12,069 --> 01:15:13,729
我的休眠艙比較復雜
My pod's more complicated.

892
01:15:13,749 --> 01:15:16,589
同時發生了一系列系統故障
A bunch of system failures, it all happened at the same time,

893
01:15:16,619 --> 01:15:19,179
整個系統就亂了套
the whole damn thing went haywire.

894
01:15:20,819 --> 01:15:23,109
這也是導致我不舒服的原因
Which explains why I'm feeling so bad.

895
01:15:23,139 --> 01:15:25,429
但是奧羅拉的休眠艙
But Aurora's pod...

896
01:15:28,619 --> 01:15:30,729
是你打開的吧
You did this.

897
01:15:32,749 --> 01:15:33,799
是的
Yeah.

898
01:15:33,839 --> 01:15:36,129
我總覺得你和奧羅拉困在一起
All this time, I'm thinking you're one lucky son of a bitch

899
01:15:36,149 --> 01:15:38,349
真他媽的走運
to get stuck with Aurora.

900
01:15:41,149 --> 01:15:43,729
但并不是幸運吧
It wasn't luck, was it?

901
01:15:43,749 --> 01:15:44,909
不是
No.

902
01:15:44,939 --> 01:15:46,609
她發現了
She knows?

903
01:15:46,639 --> 01:15:48,599
是的
She knows.

904
01:15:49,869 --> 01:15:51,619
你一個人多久了
How long were you alone?

905
01:15:51,639 --> 01:15:53,369
一年
A year.

906
01:15:56,669 --> 01:15:58,479
現在還是一樣
Still...

907
01:15:59,839 --> 01:16:01,649
該死
Damn.

908
01:16:19,829 --> 01:16:21,679
跟吉姆的一樣
Same as Jim's.

909
01:16:22,259 --> 01:16:24,329
系統關閉了
System shut downs.

910
01:16:24,349 --> 01:16:27,079
所有地方 但是出現沒有必然的關聯
Everywhere, but no apparent connection.

911
01:16:28,609 --> 01:16:31,219
你看到休眠艙了
You saw the hibernation pods?

912
01:16:31,279 --> 01:16:33,019
看到了
I saw.

913
01:16:34,309 --> 01:16:36,319
你也知道了
So you know.

914
01:16:37,209 --> 01:16:39,179
吉姆干的好事
What Jim did.

915
01:16:41,029 --> 01:16:42,929
是的
Yeah.

916
01:16:43,429 --> 01:16:44,769
然后呢
And?

917
01:16:44,789 --> 01:16:47,739
- 這不歸我管 - 他喚醒了我
- It's not my duty... - He woke me up!

918
01:16:47,759 --> 01:16:50,469
- 他奪走了我的生命 - 我知道 我也很抱歉
- He took away my life! - I know and I'm sorry.

919
01:16:50,489 --> 01:16:53,509
- 可是我還有事 - 這是謀殺
- But there's work I like... - It's murder!

920
01:16:56,089 --> 01:16:57,679
你說的沒錯 奧羅拉
You're right, Aurora.

921
01:16:57,699 --> 01:16:59,089
但是溺水的人
But the drowning man will

922
01:16:59,089 --> 01:17:01,419
總是試圖拉其他人下水
always try to drag somebody down with him.

923
01:17:01,459 --> 01:17:05,099
這種做法是錯誤的 可是他也快要溺水而亡了
It ain't right, but the man is drowning.

924
01:17:06,099 --> 01:17:08,219
這是第16個
This one makes 16.

925
01:17:11,149 --> 01:17:12,869
沒錯
Yeah.

926
01:17:14,849 --> 01:17:17,299
嘿 你還好嗎
Hey. Are you okay?

927
01:17:19,059 --> 01:17:21,749
- 你應該去休息 - 沒錯
- You should go rest. - Yeah.

928
01:17:22,419 --> 01:17:24,879
那就休息幾個小時之后
But just for a couple of hours and then,

929
01:17:24,879 --> 01:17:27,219
我們重回今天早上的問題
back at it first thing in the morning.

930
01:18:20,079 --> 01:18:22,999
重力消失
Gravity loss

931
01:19:30,939 --> 01:19:32,459
重力啟動
Gravity drive

932
01:19:32,479 --> 01:19:33,639
重力啟動
Gravity drive

933
01:20:13,899 --> 01:20:15,739
剛重力消失的時候我在游泳
I was in the pool when the gravity gave out.

934
01:20:15,769 --> 01:20:16,799
你沒事吧
Are you okay?

935
01:20:16,829 --> 01:20:18,519
我們得去找格斯
We need to find Gus.

936
01:20:19,909 --> 01:20:22,239
格斯 格斯
Gus! Gus!

937
01:20:22,499 --> 01:20:23,799
重力消失說明
Gravity loss means that whatever

938
01:20:23,799 --> 01:20:25,789
飛船重要部位出了問題
is wrong is starting to hit the big ticket items.

939
01:20:25,809 --> 01:20:27,479
這可不妙
Not good.

940
01:20:28,059 --> 01:20:30,139
每一次失靈都是部件燒毀
Every failure is a burnout process,

941
01:20:30,139 --> 01:20:32,569
所有部件都處于超載狀態
everything on board is thinking too hard.

942
01:20:33,019 --> 01:20:34,629
怎么會這樣
Why?

943
01:20:35,199 --> 01:20:37,669
計算機顯示了故障發生的整個過程
Computer, display these failures over time.

944
01:20:37,689 --> 01:20:40,299
現實時間線
Processing timeline.

945
01:20:41,289 --> 01:20:43,429
級聯失效
Cascade failure.

946
01:20:43,889 --> 01:20:46,549
2年前開始出現了功率驟增
It started 2 years ago, power surge.

947
01:20:47,219 --> 01:20:49,879
1天中出現了17個故障
17 failures in 1 day.

948
01:20:50,109 --> 01:20:52,429
包括1498號休眠艙
Including hibernation pod 1498.

949
01:20:52,449 --> 01:20:54,079
就是我
That's me.

950
01:20:54,109 --> 01:20:55,779
把我喚醒了
Woke me up.

951
01:20:57,299 --> 01:20:59,829
- 那天發生了什么 - 一些大問題
- What happened that day? - Something big.

952
01:20:59,859 --> 01:21:02,339
某處的主要系統宕機了
A major system went down somewhere.

953
01:21:02,709 --> 01:21:04,709
飛船上的其它組件都試圖分擔負荷
Everything else on board is trying to pick up the load

954
01:21:04,739 --> 01:21:06,509
但實在是杯水車薪
but the load's too heavy.

955
01:21:06,519 --> 01:21:08,819
不論如何我們都要找到問題所在
Whatever started this we got to find it.

956
01:21:08,839 --> 01:21:12,009
- 要修復它 - 問題有多嚴重呢
- And fix it. - How bad can this get?

957
01:21:12,489 --> 01:21:14,769
對現有數據進行風險分析
Give me a risk analysis based on this data.

958
01:21:14,799 --> 01:21:16,449
運算進行中
Extrapolating.

959
01:21:16,479 --> 01:21:18,949
將造成航行中止
Emission critical failure is imminent.

960
01:21:18,979 --> 01:21:22,299
將失效的系統 生命維持系統 聚變反應堆
Failing systems: Life support. Fusion reactor.

961
01:21:22,329 --> 01:21:24,179
我們困在這了
So we're stranded...

962
01:21:24,199 --> 01:21:25,409
離子推進器
Ion drive.

963
01:21:25,429 --> 01:21:27,629
船要沉了
... on a sinking ship.

964
01:21:35,719 --> 01:21:37,719
到達主工程區
Main Engineering.

965
01:21:37,739 --> 01:21:41,129
能夠造成這種重創的情況并不多
Not a lot of things big enough to hit this ship that hard.

966
01:21:43,629 --> 01:21:47,019
我們只能自己排查 去找到問題了
With diagnostics out, we'll have to find it ourselves.

967
01:21:47,029 --> 01:21:48,899
從哪里開始
Where do we start?

968
01:21:49,529 --> 01:21:50,949
格斯
Gus!

969
01:21:54,619 --> 01:21:58,119
掃描完畢 分析數據
Scan complete. Analyzing data.

970
01:21:59,489 --> 01:22:01,379
發現612個疾病
612 disorders found

971
01:22:01,379 --> 01:22:03,399
系統說我出了什么問題
What does it say is wrong with me?

972
01:22:03,419 --> 01:22:04,899
一點小問題
It's a few things.

973
01:22:04,929 --> 01:22:07,949
發現你得了612個病
612 disorders found.

974
01:22:07,979 --> 01:22:09,899
讓我出去
Get me out of here.

975
01:22:23,909 --> 01:22:25,549
診斷結果是什么
What's the prognosis?

976
01:22:25,569 --> 01:22:27,139
沒有醫生在場
Critical diagnosis cannot

977
01:22:27,139 --> 01:22:29,909
不可與患者討論病情
be discussed without a doctor on attendance.

978
01:22:29,929 --> 01:22:33,939
重寫我的權限 身份2317
Override on my authority, I.D. 2317.

979
01:22:33,959 --> 01:22:35,229
顯示結果
Lay it on me, doc.

980
01:22:35,249 --> 01:22:37,169
全身性系統壞死
Pan-systemic necrosis.

981
01:22:37,199 --> 01:22:40,219
進行性器官衰竭 誘因未知
Progressive organ failure. Cause unknown.

982
01:22:40,239 --> 01:22:42,779
該死的休眠艙 就是它導致的
My goofy hibernation pod, that's the cause.

983
01:22:42,799 --> 01:22:45,869
- 治療方法是什么 - 有多種方法
- What's the treatment? - Various treatments are possible.

984
01:22:45,899 --> 01:22:49,239
但對延長患者壽命無明顯作用
None will meaningfully extend the patient's life.

985
01:22:52,099 --> 01:22:53,379
我還能活多久
How long have I got?

986
01:22:53,409 --> 01:22:56,869
你的生命正在終結
Your end of life transition is already under way.

987
01:22:57,469 --> 01:22:59,439
這些藥物會緩解
These sedatives will alleviate

988
01:22:59,439 --> 01:23:02,059
你最后時間的痛苦
your suffering during these final hours.

989
01:23:19,119 --> 01:23:20,659
格斯
Gus?

990
01:23:25,359 --> 01:23:27,459
我想一個人靜靜
I need a minute.

991
01:23:56,769 --> 01:23:59,619
航行遇到困難
We are experiencing difficulties in flight.

992
01:23:59,649 --> 01:24:01,919
- 格斯 - 格斯
- Gus! - Gus!

993
01:24:01,939 --> 01:24:02,909
他會去哪里
Where can he be?

994
01:24:02,929 --> 01:24:06,329
為了您的安全 請您回到房間
For your own safety, please return to your cabins.

995
01:24:09,449 --> 01:24:12,369
航行遇到困難
We are experiencing difficulties in flight.

996
01:24:12,529 --> 01:24:16,269
為了您的安全 請回到您的房間
For your own safety, please return to your cabins.

997
01:24:16,299 --> 01:24:19,029
我應該把藥帶著的
Should have took the damn pills.

998
01:24:19,029 --> 01:24:22,149
- 我去幫你拿 - 不 陪我留下
- I'll go get them. - No, stay here with me

999
01:24:23,169 --> 01:24:24,889
坐下吧
Sit.

1000
01:24:29,209 --> 01:24:31,939
你們要相互照顧
You two take care of each other.

1001
01:24:40,859 --> 01:24:43,169
我的身份手環
My I.D..

1002
01:24:44,079 --> 01:24:47,089
能讓你去船上任何地方
Get you where you need to go.

1003
01:24:47,749 --> 01:24:49,939
修好它
Fix the ship.

1004
01:24:50,689 --> 01:24:53,309
找出故障所在
Find out what's wrong with her.

1005
01:24:55,909 --> 01:24:57,939
我看起來怎么樣
How do I look?

1006
01:24:58,289 --> 01:25:00,759
您看起來很英俊
You look magnificent.

1007
01:25:01,319 --> 01:25:04,509
女士們都喜歡穿制服的男人
Ladies love a dressed man.

1008
01:25:12,859 --> 01:25:14,929
我們現在該怎么辦
What do we do now?

1009
01:25:21,409 --> 01:25:23,119
這可糟透了
This can't be good.

1010
01:25:26,139 --> 01:25:27,799
我要回工程區
I'm going back to Engineering.

1011
01:25:27,829 --> 01:25:29,769
你能修好嗎
Can you fix this?

1012
01:25:29,959 --> 01:25:31,639
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.

1013
01:25:34,819 --> 01:25:36,319
我們走
Let's go!

1014
01:25:58,569 --> 01:26:00,039
亞瑟
Arthur!

1015
01:26:15,519 --> 01:26:16,939
走
Let's go!

1016
01:26:20,199 --> 01:26:22,309
到達主工程區
Main Engineering.

1017
01:26:22,409 --> 01:26:24,269
我們能不能再叫醒一些人
Can't we wake up some of the crew?

1018
01:26:24,299 --> 01:26:25,669
他們需要很長時間才能適應
It will take them take too long to recover,

1019
01:26:25,669 --> 01:26:26,689
沒那么多時間了
we don't have that kind of time.

1020
01:26:26,719 --> 01:26:28,879
我們到底要找什么
What are we even looking for?

1021
01:26:29,079 --> 01:26:30,989
故障點
Something broken.

1022
01:26:31,259 --> 01:26:32,829
大的故障點
Something big.

1023
01:26:32,989 --> 01:26:34,589
來吧
Come on!

1024
01:26:36,009 --> 01:26:38,319
- 這壞了嗎 - 看起來是好的
- Is it broken? - It seems okay.

1025
01:26:38,349 --> 01:26:39,429
下一個看什么
What next?

1026
01:26:39,459 --> 01:26:41,659
動力裝置 這邊
Power Plant. This way.

1027
01:26:47,429 --> 01:26:49,239
快啊
Come on.

1028
01:26:49,419 --> 01:26:51,149
整個都關閉了 肯定出了什么問題
Whole section's closed off. Something's wrong.

1029
01:26:51,179 --> 01:26:52,969
我們就是在找問題啊
We're looking for wrong.

1030
01:26:52,989 --> 01:26:54,729
想辦法打開它
Try to open it.

1031
01:27:06,029 --> 01:27:07,429
警告
Warning.

1032
01:27:07,869 --> 01:27:11,289
壓力艙門鎖定
Pressure door. Lock down initiated.

1033
01:27:13,809 --> 01:27:15,549
請關閉艙門
Please secure all doors.

1034
01:27:15,569 --> 01:27:17,599
抓緊
Hold on!

1035
01:27:19,699 --> 01:27:22,529
警告 氧量降至危險值
Warning. Dangerous oxygen level.

1036
01:27:22,559 --> 01:27:24,909
請關閉艙門
Please secure all doors.

1037
01:27:33,989 --> 01:27:38,369
氧量降至危險值 請關閉艙門
Dangerous oxygen level. Please secure all doors.

1038
01:27:42,439 --> 01:27:44,509
抓住這個
Grab it!

1039
01:27:50,619 --> 01:27:53,849
增壓艙加壓失敗
Pressurizing cabin unsuccessful.

1040
01:28:02,109 --> 01:28:04,199
壓力正常
Pressure normalized.

1041
01:28:04,769 --> 01:28:06,899
氧量恢復
Oxygen level restored.

1042
01:28:06,929 --> 01:28:08,809
已封閉
End lock down.

1043
01:28:08,839 --> 01:28:11,539
船上有一個洞
A hole in the ship.

1044
01:28:13,509 --> 01:28:15,369
不止一個
More than one.

1045
01:28:18,359 --> 01:28:19,289
怎么會這樣
How did that even happen?

1046
01:28:19,289 --> 01:28:20,809
飛船可能遭遇過隕石
This ship is supposed to be meteor-proof.

1047
01:28:20,829 --> 01:28:22,959
我猜有一塊貫穿了船體
I guess one got through.

1048
01:28:30,709 --> 01:28:32,169
很熱
It's hot!

1049
01:28:38,789 --> 01:28:40,809
我想我們找到問題了
I think we found it.

1050
01:28:50,369 --> 01:28:52,829
這是反應堆控制計算機
It's the reactor control computer.

1051
01:28:58,779 --> 01:29:00,419
兩年前就是它撞擊了我們
This is what hit us 2 years ago.

1052
01:29:00,439 --> 01:29:01,999
吉姆
Jim.

1053
01:29:02,539 --> 01:29:04,739
我們怎么可能修得好這個
How can we fix this?

1054
01:29:07,609 --> 01:29:08,639
我們要死了
We're going to die.

1055
01:29:08,659 --> 01:29:10,859
所有的組件都有備用的
There's replacement parts for everything.

1056
01:29:15,229 --> 01:29:16,459
打光
Light.

1057
01:29:16,479 --> 01:29:17,889
抱歉
Sorry.

1058
01:29:19,689 --> 01:29:20,809
一旦我取出這個模塊
As soon as I pull this module,

1059
01:29:20,809 --> 01:29:22,379
整個電腦就停機了
the entire computer is going to shut down.

1060
01:29:22,409 --> 01:29:24,219
然后會怎么樣
Well, what happens then?

1061
01:29:25,639 --> 01:29:28,209
我會盡快把新的換回去
I'll get it back up as quickly as I can.

1062
01:29:32,069 --> 01:29:33,599
快點
Hurry!

1063
01:29:35,759 --> 01:29:37,139
吉姆
Jim!

1064
01:29:39,839 --> 01:29:42,439
控制電腦已修復
Control computer restored.

1065
01:29:43,319 --> 01:29:45,389
排氣裝置異常
Venting reactor.

1066
01:29:47,129 --> 01:29:48,319
我們不是修好了嗎
But we fixed it!

1067
01:29:48,349 --> 01:29:52,519
反應堆排氣失敗 需手動操作
Reactor vent failed. Manual override required.

1068
01:29:57,799 --> 01:29:59,339
排氣失敗
Vent failure.

1069
01:29:59,369 --> 01:30:01,109
- 拜托 - 吉姆
- Come on! - Jim.

1070
01:30:05,499 --> 01:30:07,229
外門無響應
Outer door non-responsive.

1071
01:30:07,249 --> 01:30:09,299
這是什么意思
What does that mean?

1072
01:30:11,039 --> 01:30:12,819
外門卡住了
The outer door is jammed.

1073
01:30:12,839 --> 01:30:14,699
我們要打開那扇門讓反應堆冷卻
We got to open that door and cool the reactor down

1074
01:30:14,729 --> 01:30:16,639
否則整個飛船都要爆炸
or the whole ship's going to blow.

1075
01:30:16,669 --> 01:30:17,469
怎么打開
How?

1076
01:30:17,489 --> 01:30:19,089
我要去那里
I got to go out there.

1077
01:30:19,129 --> 01:30:21,199
從外面打開它
Open it from the outside.

1078
01:30:21,709 --> 01:30:24,119
我把門打開 然后去清理
I open the door I get cleared.

1079
01:30:24,329 --> 01:30:26,299
你負責排出熱氣
You blow that fire into space.

1080
01:30:26,329 --> 01:30:28,929
- 你去清理 - 你用無線和我聯絡
- You get cleared? - You can talk to me through this.

1081
01:30:28,929 --> 01:30:31,469
門開了你會怎么樣
What happens to you when that door opens?

1082
01:30:41,569 --> 01:30:44,069
我有防熱罩 應該沒事
Heat shield. It might help.

1083
01:30:52,439 --> 01:30:54,049
你可能需要這個
You might need this.

1084
01:31:07,659 --> 01:31:09,409
會沒事的
It's going to be okay.

1085
01:31:18,939 --> 01:31:20,489
我得走了
I better go.

1086
01:31:25,389 --> 01:31:26,829
吉姆
Jim.

1087
01:31:27,189 --> 01:31:28,669
吉姆
Jim.

1088
01:31:31,059 --> 01:31:32,789
一定要回來
Come back to me.

1089
01:31:34,329 --> 01:31:36,939
沒有你我沒法在這船上生活
I can't live on the ship without you.

1090
01:32:02,079 --> 01:32:04,699
警告 已達臨界溫度
Warning. Temperature critical.

1091
01:32:04,729 --> 01:32:06,089
啊
Ahhhh!

1092
01:32:17,999 --> 01:32:19,539
怎么了
What's wrong?

1093
01:32:20,339 --> 01:32:22,159
發生什么了 你還好嗎
What's the matter? Are you okay?

1094
01:32:22,189 --> 01:32:23,689
沒事 你繼續
Nothing. Go.

1095
01:32:23,719 --> 01:32:24,679
你確定嗎
You sure?

1096
01:32:24,709 --> 01:32:26,109
你去吧
Go.

1097
01:32:33,609 --> 01:32:35,419
我在通風管里
I'm in the vent tube.

1098
01:32:36,369 --> 01:32:39,369
新定位點 重置系繩
New anchor point. Reset tether.

1099
01:32:42,629 --> 01:32:44,279
我看到門了
I see the door.

1100
01:32:44,859 --> 01:32:47,279
溫度上升中
Temperature level rising.

1101
01:32:54,009 --> 01:32:56,939
警告 到達臨界溫度
Warning. Temperature critical.

1102
01:33:02,769 --> 01:33:05,289
外殼不穩定
Containment unstable.

1103
01:33:06,429 --> 01:33:07,609
你在哪
Where are you?

1104
01:33:07,639 --> 01:33:08,719
我在門這里
I'm at the door.

1105
01:33:08,739 --> 01:33:10,369
我準備好了 就等你了
I'm ready, just say when.

1106
01:33:10,389 --> 01:33:12,039
好了
There goes.

1107
01:33:14,979 --> 01:33:18,039
這門打不開 我要換條路
The door won't open. I'll have to bypass it.

1108
01:33:20,019 --> 01:33:22,509
溫度上升中
Temperature level rising.

1109
01:33:23,129 --> 01:33:24,459
吉姆 快點
Jim, come on!

1110
01:33:24,489 --> 01:33:26,229
拜托 快點
Please, hurry!

1111
01:33:26,249 --> 01:33:29,639
- 好的 我再試一次 - 你好了告訴我
- Okay, I'm trying it again. - Tell me when you're cleared.

1112
01:33:33,389 --> 01:33:34,089
不
No!

1113
01:33:34,109 --> 01:33:35,369
什么
What?

1114
01:33:36,169 --> 01:33:37,889
怎么了
What's going on?

1115
01:33:38,059 --> 01:33:39,559
吉姆
Jim?

1116
01:33:43,639 --> 01:33:44,699
吉姆
Jim!

1117
01:33:44,719 --> 01:33:46,849
這門沒法一直開著
The door won't stay open.

1118
01:33:47,839 --> 01:33:51,649
我可能要留在這里 按著這個門
I think I have to stay here, hold the door open.

1119
01:33:52,419 --> 01:33:53,699
不
No!

1120
01:33:53,729 --> 01:33:55,339
不行 快離開那
No way, get out of there!

1121
01:33:55,359 --> 01:33:56,929
不行
I can't.

1122
01:33:57,079 --> 01:33:58,589
吉姆
Jim...

1123
01:33:58,699 --> 01:34:00,519
我們快沒時間了
We're out of time.

1124
01:34:01,669 --> 01:34:03,379
外殼不穩定
Containment unstable.

1125
01:34:03,419 --> 01:34:04,949
吉姆
Jim?

1126
01:34:11,019 --> 01:34:12,929
反應堆排氣
Vent the reactor.

1127
01:34:18,849 --> 01:34:21,739
不行 你不懂
No, you don't understand!

1128
01:34:22,059 --> 01:34:24,819
如果我現在打開門你會死的
If I open the door right now it will kill you!

1129
01:34:24,839 --> 01:34:25,999
但愿不會
I'm hoping not.

1130
01:34:26,029 --> 01:34:27,899
回來 我們再想想其他辦法
Come back in, we'll think of something else.

1131
01:34:27,929 --> 01:34:29,849
沒有其他辦法了
There is nothing else.

1132
01:34:31,019 --> 01:34:32,489
吉姆
Jim!

1133
01:34:33,069 --> 01:34:34,889
- 沒事的 - 不 有事
- It's okay. - No, it's not okay!

1134
01:34:34,909 --> 01:34:38,119
- 奧羅拉 - 警告 溫度超過范圍
- Aurora - Warning. Temperature level exceeded.

1135
01:34:38,139 --> 01:34:40,699
這不是我預想要發生的事
This is not how I suppose is going to happen!

1136
01:34:41,429 --> 01:34:42,879
奧羅拉 這架飛船就要壞了
Aurora, this ship is going to go.

1137
01:34:42,899 --> 01:34:45,509
我不管 你死了 我也就死了
I don't care! You die, I die.

1138
01:34:45,789 --> 01:34:49,009
這架飛船上還有五千多名乘客 奧羅拉
There are 5,000 other people on this ship, Aurora.

1139
01:34:50,149 --> 01:34:52,109
我們必須得這樣做
We have to do this.

1140
01:34:52,679 --> 01:34:55,009
到達最大壓力值
Maximum pressure reached.

1141
01:34:58,179 --> 01:35:00,629
動手吧 現在
Do it. Now.

1142
01:35:01,459 --> 01:35:04,119
到達最大機艙壓力值
Maximum cabin pressure reached.

1143
01:35:25,159 --> 01:35:27,279
溫度下降中
Temperature dropping.

1144
01:35:28,659 --> 01:35:30,039
吉姆
Jim.

1145
01:35:48,079 --> 01:35:50,289
- 吉姆 - 排氣成功
- Jim. - Vent successful.

1146
01:35:50,319 --> 01:35:52,669
重啟程序中
Rebooting process initiated.

1147
01:35:52,699 --> 01:35:54,889
吉姆 拜托說句話
Jim, please say something.

1148
01:36:31,309 --> 01:36:33,809
宇航服壓力下降中
Suit pressure dropping.

1149
01:36:36,359 --> 01:36:39,529
馬上回到飛船
Return to ship immediately.

1150
01:36:40,549 --> 01:36:41,999
奧羅拉
Aurora.

1151
01:36:43,519 --> 01:36:44,759
成功了
It worked!

1152
01:36:44,779 --> 01:36:46,919
你做到了 你可以回來了
You did it, you can come in!

1153
01:36:47,089 --> 01:36:48,689
呃 那個
Yeah, about that...

1154
01:36:48,719 --> 01:36:50,479
怎么了 你受傷了嗎
What's the matter? Are you hurt?

1155
01:36:51,159 --> 01:36:53,029
我被炸離了管道
I got blown out of the tube.

1156
01:36:53,049 --> 01:36:53,929
什么
What?

1157
01:36:53,959 --> 01:36:56,829
我的系繩壞了 沒法回到飛船上了
My tether broke. I can't get back to the ship.

1158
01:36:57,579 --> 01:36:59,599
我出去 我出去拉你進來
I'll come out. I'll come out. I'll pull you in.

1159
01:36:59,619 --> 01:37:02,479
警告 氧氣到達臨界值
Warning. Oxygen level critical.

1160
01:37:02,509 --> 01:37:05,359
馬上回到飛船
Return to ship immediately.

1161
01:37:13,239 --> 01:37:16,109
奧羅拉 對不起
Aurora, I'm sorry...

1162
01:37:17,799 --> 01:37:19,039
所有的事情
... for everything.

1163
01:37:19,069 --> 01:37:20,899
閉嘴 我來了
Shut up, I'm coming.

1164
01:37:21,299 --> 01:37:26,029
我多希望我們在90年后再相遇
I wish we'd have met in 90 years.

1165
01:37:30,799 --> 01:37:34,429
我會 給你建個房子
I... I'd build you a house.

1166
01:37:38,589 --> 01:37:40,809
我會 看你寫的書
I'll read your book.

1167
01:37:43,049 --> 01:37:44,929
那該是多么美好
It's a good feeling.

1168
01:37:57,169 --> 01:37:58,419
系繩已連接
Tether attached.

1169
01:37:58,439 --> 01:38:00,709
定位吉姆 普勒斯頓
Locate Jim Preston.

1170
01:38:04,779 --> 01:38:07,789
吉姆 普勒斯頓 已定位
Jim Preston, located.

1171
01:38:08,359 --> 01:38:10,129
我來接你了
I'm coming to get you.

1172
01:38:34,689 --> 01:38:36,289
吉姆
Jim!

1173
01:39:35,959 --> 01:39:38,369
抱歉 病人已身亡
I'm sorry. The patient is dead.

1174
01:39:38,389 --> 01:39:39,849
那就復活他
Well, resuscitate him!

1175
01:39:39,869 --> 01:39:43,379
尸體手術須有授權醫療監督資格
Postmortem operations require authorized medical supervision.

1176
01:39:43,399 --> 01:39:45,079
不
No!

1177
01:39:53,449 --> 01:39:55,839
重寫 重寫我的資格
Override! Override on my authority!

1178
01:39:55,859 --> 01:39:59,249
身份 17
I.D. 17...

1179
01:40:00,689 --> 01:40:02,099
2

1180
01:40:02,429 --> 01:40:04,189
2

1181
01:40:04,639 --> 01:40:05,769
2317

1182
01:40:05,789 --> 01:40:08,719
2317 I.D.2317

1183
01:40:16,539 --> 01:40:18,369
不建議用多個步驟
Multiple procedures are not recommended.

1184
01:40:18,389 --> 01:40:19,909
重寫
Override!

1185
01:40:19,939 --> 01:40:21,569
快做 就現在
Do it, now!

1186
01:40:21,599 --> 01:40:23,249
執行中
Executing.

1187
01:41:22,589 --> 01:41:23,859
吉姆
Jim.

1188
01:41:25,939 --> 01:41:27,459
吉姆
Jim.

1189
01:41:55,159 --> 01:41:57,479
你把我救回來了
You brought me back.

1190
01:41:57,499 --> 01:41:59,089
是啊
Yeah.

1191
01:42:22,999 --> 01:42:23,839
謝謝
Thank you.

1192
01:42:23,839 --> 01:42:25,249
別動
Be still.

1193
01:42:25,279 --> 01:42:26,889
好的
Of course.

1194
01:43:11,849 --> 01:43:14,049
我要給你看樣東西
There's something I have to show you.

1195
01:43:14,069 --> 01:43:17,249
在命令模式中 這個醫療艙有個選項
In Command mode, it turns out the autodoc has a option

1196
01:43:17,269 --> 01:43:19,849
叫安定和暫停
called "Stabilize and Suspend".

1197
01:43:19,879 --> 01:43:22,719
它能停止一切代謝活動
It stops all metabolic activity.

1198
01:43:24,399 --> 01:43:25,629
你在說什么
What are you saying?

1199
01:43:25,659 --> 01:43:28,179
是格斯的主意 就像休眠一樣
It's Gus' idea. It can be like hibernation.

1200
01:43:28,199 --> 01:43:31,209
在醫療艙內 你可以重回休眠
Inside the autodoc, you can go back to sleep.

1201
01:43:35,379 --> 01:43:37,579
但是只有一個醫療艙
But there's only one autodoc.

1202
01:43:41,579 --> 01:43:42,989
是的
Yeah.

1203
01:43:45,139 --> 01:43:47,569
所以你要躺進里面
And you're going to lay down in it,

1204
01:43:47,679 --> 01:43:49,479
進入休眠
and fall asleep.

1205
01:43:50,259 --> 01:43:52,529
然后你會在新家園Ⅱ號醒來
And you'll wake up on Homestead Ⅱ,

1206
01:43:52,549 --> 01:43:54,579
繼續寫你的書
and you'll write you book.

1207
01:43:55,999 --> 01:43:59,449
你會完成你的旅行 完成你最初打算做的事情
You finish your journey. You do what you set out to do.

1208
01:44:07,759 --> 01:44:09,729
那你就孤身一人了
You'll be alone.

1209
01:44:10,799 --> 01:44:14,849
我以前也孤身一人 我會沒事的
I've been alone before and I'll be fine.

1210
01:44:15,899 --> 01:44:18,259
但是我就永遠都見不到你了
But I'll never see you again.

1211
01:44:21,389 --> 01:44:23,279
我會去見你的
I'll come and visit you.

1212
01:45:05,989 --> 01:45:08,519
星期二 亞瑟是我的
Tuesday is my day with Arthur.

1213
01:45:09,939 --> 01:45:11,599
一如既往的美麗
Lovely as ever.

1214
01:45:11,629 --> 01:45:13,949
謝謝你 亞瑟 你看起來也很帥
Thank you, Arthur. You're looking very well yourself.

1215
01:45:13,979 --> 01:45:15,749
多虧了你
Thanks to you.

1216
01:45:16,739 --> 01:45:18,279
那是什么
What's that?

1217
01:45:20,339 --> 01:45:23,329
我很久之前就想給你的東西
Something I wanted to give you for a long time.

1218
01:45:29,649 --> 01:45:31,679
很漂亮
It's beautiful.

1219
01:45:44,269 --> 01:45:47,069
這么久才開口
Took you long enough to ask.

1220
01:45:49,609 --> 01:45:52,999
香檳 我還是等等吧
Champagne. I'll wait.

1221
01:46:09,749 --> 01:46:11,629
多好的生活啊
Hell of a life.

1222
01:46:14,139 --> 01:46:16,039
多好的生活
Hell of a life.

1223
01:46:47,069 --> 01:46:50,459
船員喚醒程序初始化
Crew wake up process initiated.

1224
01:46:51,119 --> 01:46:51,159
同行伙伴們
My fellow passengers,

1225
01:46:53,179 --> 01:46:54,839
如果你們看到了這個
if you are reading this,

1226
01:46:54,839 --> 01:46:58,499
說明阿瓦隆號已經到達了目的地
then the starship Avalon has reached its destination.

1227
01:46:58,519 --> 01:47:00,629
到達中央大廳
Grand Concourse.

1228
01:47:00,819 --> 01:47:03,229
當你們沉睡時 發生了許多事情
A lot happened while you slept.

1229
01:47:10,349 --> 01:47:12,209
有位朋友曾說
A friend once said,

1230
01:47:12,229 --> 01:47:15,489
不可總惦記著目的地
"You can't get so hung up on where you'd rather be

1231
01:47:15,509 --> 01:47:19,059
卻忘了去感受當下
that you forget to make the most of where you are.

1232
01:47:19,619 --> 01:47:22,079
我們曾一度迷失
We got lost along the way

1233
01:47:22,629 --> 01:47:24,639
但幸好我們找到了彼此
but we found each other.

1234
01:47:24,969 --> 01:47:26,819
一起創造出
And we made a life.

1235
01:47:26,819 --> 01:47:30,689
一段美妙的人生
A beautiful life... together.

