1
00:00:31,231 --> 00:00:38,337
麗塔 麗塔
Rita. Rita!

2
00:00:43,810 --> 00:00:45,777
噢不是吧 伙計們
Aw come on, guys!

3
00:00:51,151 --> 00:00:53,952
拜托 這不是惡作劇的時候
Come on, I'm not in the mood!

4
00:01:00,161 --> 00:01:01,927
一點都不好玩
This isn't funny!

5
00:01:06,699 --> 00:01:09,000
高明都算不上
This isn't even clever!

6
00:01:14,275 --> 00:01:18,545
蘭迪你大爺的 我給你買新地毯還不行嗎
Damn it Randy, I'll buy you a new carpet all right?

7
00:01:18,546 --> 00:01:20,964
我向你道歉不行嗎
Sorry.

8
00:01:20,965 --> 00:01:28,445
嘿你要是想嚇我 那你應該綁我綁得更結實些
Hey if you wanted to scare me you could've tied me up better.

9
00:01:31,425 --> 00:01:39,425
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.

10
00:01:56,616 --> 00:01:58,016
不是吧
Come on.

11
00:03:07,187 --> 00:03:08,187
有人嗎
Hello?

12
00:03:08,788 --> 00:03:09,988
有人嗎
Hello?

13
00:03:12,458 --> 00:03:14,192
有人能聽見我說話嗎
Can anyone hear me?

14
00:03:15,728 --> 00:03:17,697
我被困在不知是哪里的一座木屋里了
I'm trapped in a cabin somewhere,

15
00:03:17,698 --> 00:03:20,200
我不確定具體地址
I don't really know where it is.

16
00:03:20,201 --> 00:03:22,567
我周圍有
I'm surrounded by...

17
00:03:24,537 --> 00:03:25,737
好多樹
Trees.

18
00:03:26,639 --> 00:03:28,106
救命
Mayday.

19
00:03:28,541 --> 00:03:30,643
我不知道我身在何處 拜托
I don't know where I am, please,

20
00:03:30,644 --> 00:03:32,944
如果有人能聽到我說話 請救救我
if anyone can hear me, please help.

21
00:03:49,429 --> 00:03:51,129
思考 細想一下
Think, think, okay.

22
00:03:52,833 --> 00:03:56,201
我接了麗塔，對 喝了一杯
Picked up Rita, okay, I had a drink.

23
00:03:58,004 --> 00:04:00,005
喝了兩杯
I had two drinks.

24
00:04:00,506 --> 00:04:03,008
然后 然后回了家
Then then I came home.

25
00:04:04,978 --> 00:04:06,578
我到底到家了嗎
Did I get home?

26
00:04:09,682 --> 00:04:11,049
我醉了嗎
Was I drunk?

27
00:04:12,318 --> 00:04:14,787
不 不 不 不 不 不 拜托 拜托 拜托
No, no, no, no, no, no, come on, come on, come on.

28
00:04:14,788 --> 00:04:16,723
保持鎮定 好嗎
Don't lose it, all right?

29
00:04:16,724 --> 00:04:18,791
好 好吧
Okay, all right.

30
00:04:18,792 --> 00:04:19,792
好吧 對
Okay, good.

31
00:04:19,793 --> 00:04:21,793
我先查查有什么
Let's see what...

32
00:04:22,262 --> 00:04:25,630
好吧
Okay.

33
00:05:31,998 --> 00:05:35,266
可不是得鎖著嘛
Of course.

34
00:05:48,916 --> 00:05:50,450
喂
Hello?

35
00:05:50,451 --> 00:05:51,751
喂
Hello?

36
00:05:51,752 --> 00:05:54,119
萊斯特
Lester.

37
00:05:54,821 --> 00:05:56,556
你誰啊
Who is this?

38
00:05:56,557 --> 00:05:59,926
朋友們管你叫萊斯
Your friends call you les.

39
00:05:59,927 --> 00:06:01,226
你是誰
Who is this?

40
00:06:02,528 --> 00:06:05,665
聽著先生 幫幫忙 我需要幫助 我被困在一處木屋了
Look mister, please, I need help, I'm trapped in a cabin

41
00:06:05,666 --> 00:06:06,999
完全不知道這是哪兒
and I have no idea where I am.

42
00:06:07,000 --> 00:06:10,970
我想你用GPS定位一下 就能找到我了
I think maybe if you GPS it, though, you'll be able to find me.

43
00:06:10,971 --> 00:06:14,140
你要是在打斷我說話 事可就難辦了
It's going to be very difficult if you keep interruptin', les.

44
00:06:14,141 --> 00:06:16,909
現在冷靜點 能做到嗎
Now calm down, can you do that?

45
00:06:16,910 --> 00:06:18,176
是的 好的
Yes, yes.

46
00:06:19,579 --> 00:06:23,149
好的 不如你先坐下來
Good, now how 'bout you take a seat right there?

47
00:06:23,150 --> 00:06:24,817
好
Yes.

48
00:06:24,818 --> 00:06:27,453
你這人挺愛安逸的 不是嗎
You know all about comfort, don't you?

49
00:06:27,454 --> 00:06:29,787
自滿 溺于安逸
Complacency, ease, goin'

50
00:06:29,788 --> 00:06:34,259
去鎮上一玩就是晚上九十點之類的事
out on the town dressed to the nines and such.

51
00:06:34,861 --> 00:06:37,463
容我先自我介紹
Allow me to introduce myself.

52
00:06:37,464 --> 00:06:39,364
你可以稱我為沃爾夫
You may call me wolf.

53
00:06:43,002 --> 00:06:44,202
沃爾夫
Wolf?

54
00:06:44,904 --> 00:06:47,338
CNN里的沃爾夫那個沃爾夫
Wolf like the guy on CNN?

55
00:06:49,842 --> 00:06:53,344
不錯 就是CNN那個沃爾夫
Yeah, just like the guy on CNN.

56
00:06:54,781 --> 00:06:57,817
是我把你弄到這兒的 萊斯特
I have brought you here, Lester.

57
00:06:57,818 --> 00:07:00,753
你把我弄到這的
You brought me here?

58
00:07:00,754 --> 00:07:02,054
到底他媽的為了什么
What the hell for?

59
00:07:02,055 --> 00:07:03,956
閉嘴行嗎
Would you hush up?

60
00:07:03,957 --> 00:07:06,492
我明白你的處境
I know we about your situation.

61
00:07:06,493 --> 00:07:08,060
聽著 你要什么我都給你
Look, I'll pay you whatever you want.

62
00:07:08,061 --> 00:07:12,130
你要什么我家里人都會給你的
My family will give you whatever you want.

63
00:07:13,866 --> 00:07:15,266
喂
Hello?

64
00:07:16,803 --> 00:07:18,002
沃爾夫
Wolf?

65
00:08:34,280 --> 00:08:35,915
我不想弄什么把戲
I was hopin' I wouldn't have to pull

66
00:08:35,916 --> 00:08:39,919
來把你困住 萊斯特
some cuyon parlor trick to keep ya here, Lester.

67
00:08:39,920 --> 00:08:42,053
你讓我很難辦
You rushed my hand.

68
00:08:42,788 --> 00:08:45,732
就像我說你不停打斷我說話
As I was sayin' before you interrupted,

69
00:08:45,733 --> 00:08:48,526
事兒就不好弄了
it makes conversation very difficult.

70
00:08:49,161 --> 00:08:52,130
你到底想怎樣
Just tell me what you want.

71
00:08:52,999 --> 00:08:55,190
這是你生平第一次
That's the first time you ever

72
00:08:55,191 --> 00:08:58,771
嚇怕了 是吧 公子哥
been scared for your life, isn't it silver spoon?

73
00:08:58,772 --> 00:09:00,338
公子哥
Silver spoon?

74
00:09:02,041 --> 00:09:05,811
我讓你看看什么叫公子哥 你個變態
I'll give you silver spoon, you psycho.

75
00:09:05,812 --> 00:09:09,815
有膽你怎么不出現 我要好好教訓你
Why don't you come in here and I'll knock you so hard.

76
00:09:09,816 --> 00:09:12,218
我家人會要你好看
My family is going to sue your ass.

77
00:09:12,219 --> 00:09:14,053
聽明白了嗎
Do you get that?

78
00:09:14,054 --> 00:09:19,759
我叔叔是猶太律師 哥們 那意味著你要把牢底坐穿
My uncle is a Jewish lawyer, my friend, that means jail time!

79
00:09:19,760 --> 00:09:21,961
到時候你會嘗盡老二的滋味
You could get real acquainted with bubba.

80
00:09:21,962 --> 00:09:24,931
現在覺著自己了不起了是嗎
Feel like a big man now?

81
00:09:24,932 --> 00:09:27,967
你既然讓事情難辦 那我就來和你談談規矩
Now you tried to rush off before I could tell you the rules.

82
00:09:27,968 --> 00:09:31,302
所有事 都有規矩
Now in ever sport, there's rules.

83
00:09:31,837 --> 00:09:33,338
打算聽了嗎
Ready to listen?

84
00:09:40,880 --> 00:09:42,080
是的   
Yes.

85
00:09:42,748 --> 00:09:44,415
非常棒
Tres bon.

86
00:09:45,618 --> 00:09:49,387
你到這步田地 萊斯 是因為你罪孽深重
You are here les because you have sinned.

87
00:09:50,256 --> 00:09:53,658
你犯下的罪過嚴重到無以復加
Well you committed the worst sin a boy like you can commit.

88
00:09:55,695 --> 00:09:57,528
不 負 責 任
Irre-sponsi-bili-Ty.

89
00:10:03,669 --> 00:10:05,905
你虛度生命
You've wasted your life.

90
00:10:05,906 --> 00:10:12,211
你不過是你老爹公司里的一個中層經理
That's all you is, a middle manager at papa's company.

91
00:10:12,212 --> 00:10:15,081
還活在過去兄弟會光輝燦爛的日子里
Still livin' in the glory days of your frat house.

92
00:10:15,082 --> 00:10:16,909
女人的玩物
Women's objects,

93
00:10:16,910 --> 00:10:22,622
手上戴名表這點也很典型
classic that's an awful nice watch you're wearin'.

94
00:10:22,623 --> 00:10:24,657
你爸爸也有一塊 對吧
Daddy get that, too?

95
00:10:24,658 --> 00:10:28,129
一個男人像你這樣活著
When a boy like you lives the way he does,

96
00:10:28,130 --> 00:10:30,361
他的生命就已經開始蛀朽
there's poison in his life.

97
00:10:31,063 --> 00:10:33,231
我就是你的抗毒血清
I'm the anti-venom.

98
00:10:34,634 --> 00:10:37,435
你到底在說什么
What are you talking about?

99
00:10:38,070 --> 00:10:40,038
爺們
Manhood.

100
00:10:41,807 --> 00:10:45,111
萊斯 你知道印第安人 有種儀式
Les, you know the Indians, they had these rituals

101
00:10:45,112 --> 00:10:49,081
把男孩們送到森林里去求生存
where they send their boys off in the woods to survive.

102
00:10:49,082 --> 00:10:53,051
如果他們還能活著回來的話
And when they came back and if they came back,

103
00:10:54,820 --> 00:10:58,589
他們就有資格被視作男人
they earned the right to be called a man.

104
00:10:59,291 --> 00:11:02,226
你肯定是在逗我
You've gotta be kidding me.

105
00:11:02,995 --> 00:11:06,098
你會明白的 萊斯
You will learn les.

106
00:11:06,099 --> 00:11:08,533
犧牲 榮譽 痛苦
Sacrifice, honor, pain...

107
00:11:11,704 --> 00:11:14,373
這些不再是順口溜而已
These ain't catch phrases no more.

108
00:11:14,374 --> 00:11:16,607
這是你的新生活
It is your new life.

109
00:11:20,146 --> 00:11:21,579
這到底怎么回事
What is this?

110
00:11:23,749 --> 00:11:28,286
萊斯 你要是試圖從木屋逃跑 我會宰了你
Les, if you try to leave the cabin, I'll kill you.

111
00:11:29,288 --> 00:11:32,789
要是你撞大運能過了我這關
And if by some miracle you get past me,

112
00:11:32,790 --> 00:11:35,393
大自然也不會放過你
the wilderness will kill you.

113
00:11:36,195 --> 00:11:39,658
離開這座山的辦法只有一個
Now there's only one way off this mountain,

114
00:11:39,659 --> 00:11:41,834
你最好聽清楚了
so you best listen closely.

115
00:11:41,835 --> 00:11:45,137
你得像個爺們 萊斯 不是像頭腦簡單四肢發達的運動員
You have to man-up les, not a mindless, wanna-be jock,

116
00:11:45,138 --> 00:11:50,209
而是像個真正的男人 能照顧自己的男人
but a real man, a who can take care of hisself.

117
00:11:50,210 --> 00:11:53,312
挨一拳還能繼續前進的男人
A man who can take a hit and keep moving.

118
00:11:53,313 --> 00:11:57,016
我會幫你做到的 萊斯
I will help you do that, les.

119
00:11:57,017 --> 00:11:58,383
我會好好幫你的
I will help.

120
00:12:00,786 --> 00:12:03,721
同樣的 我也會在那一刻了結你
I will just as soon end you, too.

121
00:12:05,124 --> 00:12:07,558
瞧吧 我就是獵人
You see, I am the hunter...

122
00:12:09,061 --> 00:12:13,165
但你連獵物都算不上 現在還不算
But I dare not even call you prey, no, not yet.

123
00:12:13,166 --> 00:12:15,801
獵物帶給獵人挑戰
Prey presents a challenge.

124
00:12:15,802 --> 00:12:17,503
所以讓我來幫忙吧 在這一切結束以后
So help me god, by the end of this,

125
00:12:17,504 --> 00:12:21,307
你就會成為一個具有挑戰性的獵物
you will present me with a challenge.

126
00:12:21,308 --> 00:12:25,209
要是壞了規矩 我就做了你
Try to break the rules and I'll end you.

127
00:12:26,178 --> 00:12:29,647
再敢從那條路跑出去 咱們就試試看
Run down that path again, find out.

128
00:12:31,383 --> 00:12:35,686
現在 今天剩下的時間 你就好好住下吧
Now, you have the rest of the day to settle in.

129
00:12:36,222 --> 00:12:37,622
珍惜吧
Use it.

130
00:12:38,257 --> 00:12:40,058
狩獵開始了
The hunt is on.

131
00:14:08,180 --> 00:14:12,717
拜托 能點著的
Come on, can do this.

132
00:14:29,034 --> 00:14:32,637
要是有人在聽 請回答我
If anyone is out there, please respond.

133
00:14:36,508 --> 00:14:40,344
要是有人在聽 請回答我
If anyone is out there, please respond.

134
00:15:02,468 --> 00:15:06,204
要是有人能聽見我說話 求求你 回答我
If anyone can hear me, please respond.

135
00:16:13,739 --> 00:16:14,939
沃爾夫
Wolf!

136
00:17:24,610 --> 00:17:26,844
靴子在哪
Where are the boots?

137
00:19:10,782 --> 00:19:13,851
干嘛
What?

138
00:19:16,455 --> 00:19:18,624
你昨天干了件非常不好的事
You did a very bad thing yesterday,

139
00:19:18,625 --> 00:19:20,191
試圖逃跑
tryin' to escape.

140
00:19:21,460 --> 00:19:23,828
你還試了給我一槍呢
You tried to shoot me.

141
00:19:24,630 --> 00:19:26,865
我不是試
I shot at you.

142
00:19:26,866 --> 00:19:29,535
區別很大 我來跟你保證
Big difference, let me assure you.

143
00:19:29,536 --> 00:19:31,670
昨晚你在
You were here last night.

144
00:19:31,671 --> 00:19:34,473
那你干嘛不一槍給我個痛快 硬漢兄
Why didn't you just finish it then, tough guy?

145
00:19:34,474 --> 00:19:37,876
你要真是給老獵手 干嘛不一槍要了我的命
If you're some hotshot hunter, why didn't you just kill me?

146
00:19:37,877 --> 00:19:41,645
聽著 你現在發現你孤立無援
Listen, you find yourself in a tootaloo,

147
00:19:41,646 --> 00:19:44,283
你沒人可求
you ain't gotta call nobody.

148
00:19:44,284 --> 00:19:47,486
只有你能弄清楚
It's up to you to figure it out.

149
00:19:47,487 --> 00:19:50,020
弄清楚什么
I find myself in a what?

150
00:19:50,722 --> 00:19:54,560
你會慢慢地被凍死
You're gonna slowly freeze to death.

151
00:19:54,561 --> 00:19:57,161
現在閉嘴聽我說
Now shut up and listen to me.

152
00:20:00,465 --> 00:20:01,665
好
Okay.

153
00:20:03,635 --> 00:20:07,706
屋里有個保險箱 相信你已經發現了
There's a safe, no doubt you found it by now.

154
00:20:07,707 --> 00:20:09,507
是的我看見了
I saw it, yeah.

155
00:20:10,709 --> 00:20:14,413
屋子里某處有保險箱密碼
Inside the cabin somewhere is the combination.

156
00:20:14,414 --> 00:20:16,848
你得找到打開它
You oughtta get to gettin'.

157
00:20:16,849 --> 00:20:18,816
找到密碼
Find the combo?

158
00:20:20,719 --> 00:20:22,809
好吧 那你看著我把這兒掀個底朝天
All right and after you amuse yourself

159
00:20:22,834 --> 00:20:25,274
爽到自己后 然后呢
watching me tear this place apart, what then?

160
00:20:25,299 --> 00:20:26,792
你會怎樣
What are you gonna do?

161
00:20:26,793 --> 00:20:28,493
殺了我嗎
Kill me?

162
00:20:28,494 --> 00:20:32,364
你干嘛不堂堂正正走進來像個男人一樣面對我
Why don't you just come in here and face me like a man?

163
00:20:32,365 --> 00:20:33,498
還是你是個膽小鬼
Or are you too scared?

164
00:20:33,499 --> 00:20:35,101
你干嘛不出現
Why don't you come in

165
00:20:35,102 --> 00:20:38,536
好讓我給你臉上狠狠來一拳
here so that I can pound your little face in?

166
00:21:10,502 --> 00:21:13,337
我受夠你的游戲了 王八蛋
I'm tired of your game, asshole.

167
00:21:34,793 --> 00:21:36,961
跑 跑 跑 跑
Run, run, run, run.

168
00:21:48,640 --> 00:21:50,074
萊斯
Les?

169
00:21:51,943 --> 00:21:54,612
你要是在 就說話
If you're there, pick up.

170
00:21:59,852 --> 00:22:01,653
我在呢 沃爾夫 你又在哪呢朋友
I'm here, wolf. Where are you friend?

171
00:22:01,654 --> 00:22:03,787
我已經把槍取回來了
I've got my gun back.

172
00:22:04,856 --> 00:22:07,659
真是要承認 你讓我驕傲啊 孩子
I have to admit, I'm right proud of you, boy.

173
00:22:07,660 --> 00:22:11,930
你這會兒肯定覺得自己了不得了 要干點大事兒了是嘛
You must feel like a big boy, goin' break the eggs and such.

174
00:22:11,931 --> 00:22:13,932
來吧沃爾夫 開始吧
Come on wolf, let's do this.

175
00:22:13,933 --> 00:22:15,667
開始 我等著你 沃爾夫
Let's do this, I'm waitin' for you, wolf.

176
00:22:15,668 --> 00:22:27,112
來啊 來宰了我 好吧你的重頭戲是什么 沃爾夫
Come on, come and kill me! Well, what's your endgame, wolf?

177
00:22:27,113 --> 00:22:28,584
你不會真認為把我困在這兒
Do you honestly think you

178
00:22:28,585 --> 00:22:31,115
然后還能一走了之吧
can just keep me here and get away with it?

179
00:22:33,485 --> 00:22:35,319
麗塔這姑娘怎么樣
How's Rita?

180
00:22:41,360 --> 00:22:42,360
麗塔
Rita?

181
00:22:43,995 --> 00:22:46,798
你女朋友
Your girlfriend?

182
00:22:46,799 --> 00:22:48,800
她在你手上
You have her?

183
00:22:48,801 --> 00:22:52,971
別緊張 我就隨口問問 不是嗎
Relax, I'm askin' about her, ain't I?

184
00:22:52,972 --> 00:22:55,239
這妞兒怎么樣 還不錯吧
How is she, doin' good?

185
00:22:57,409 --> 00:22:58,409
閉嘴
Shut up.

186
00:22:59,745 --> 00:23:02,914
瞧啊 這就是我們文化里扭曲的地方
Yeah, that's the twisted thing about our culture,

187
00:23:02,915 --> 00:23:05,684
我們不相信榮譽
we don't believe in honor.

188
00:23:05,685 --> 00:23:07,930
這詞沒了實義
It's a word without meanin'

189
00:23:07,931 --> 00:23:12,090
成了海軍廣告里的噱頭
that some of the marines use in their commercials.

190
00:23:12,091 --> 00:23:13,991
就是這樣
That's about it.

191
00:23:15,961 --> 00:23:18,096
麗塔很好
Rita's just fine.

192
00:23:18,097 --> 00:23:20,699
別自欺欺人了
Don't kid yourself.

193
00:23:20,700 --> 00:23:25,069
就在前幾天晚上 她還哭的傷心欲絕呢
She just busted into tears just a few night ago.

194
00:23:26,805 --> 00:23:28,493
等我從這出去
When I get out of here,

195
00:23:28,494 --> 00:23:31,576
我要一槍崩了你腦袋
I'm gonna put a bullet through your skull.

196
00:23:31,577 --> 00:23:33,912
大話說早了吧
That's a bold assumption.

197
00:23:33,913 --> 00:23:35,981
啥時候你能出去
When you get out?

198
00:23:35,982 --> 00:23:37,181
試試看 有膽的話
Try if.

199
00:23:38,049 --> 00:23:40,951
狼（同沃爾夫音）的狩獵還沒結束呢
The wolf ain't done hurtin'.

200
00:23:45,157 --> 00:23:47,291
我可不這么覺得
I don't think so.

201
00:23:48,894 --> 00:23:52,096
我就乖乖在這坐著等你
I'll sit right here and wait for you.

202
00:23:57,002 --> 00:23:58,770
那太糟了
That's too bad.

203
00:23:58,771 --> 00:24:03,874
我還剛在棚子那兒留了點小禮物給你呢
I just left a little present for you by the shed.

204
00:26:41,766 --> 00:26:43,500
加油寶貝
Come on baby.

205
00:26:51,009 --> 00:26:52,978
太棒了
That's good.

206
00:26:52,979 --> 00:26:55,445
太棒了 太棒了
That's good, that's good.

207
00:26:56,615 --> 00:26:59,983
耶 耶
Yes! Yes!

208
00:27:09,628 --> 00:27:10,628
嘿
Hey!

209
00:27:57,409 --> 00:27:58,675
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.

210
00:29:47,185 --> 00:29:48,585
生火
Fire.

211
00:29:57,929 --> 00:29:59,129
生火
Fire.

212
00:30:06,237 --> 00:30:11,525
對海軍來說 生火和保持火焰不熄滅的能力
The ability to start and maintain a fire is crucial

213
00:30:11,550 --> 00:30:16,837
在嚴寒氣候下的生存是極其關鍵的
to a marine's survival in the cold weather theater.

214
00:30:17,982 --> 00:30:20,885
可惜了 我不是海軍
Too bad I'm not a marine.

215
00:30:20,886 --> 00:30:24,621
你需要引火 需要找到一些能燒著的東西
You will need kindling, an ignition source,

216
00:30:26,057 --> 00:30:28,007
生火的燃料
fuel for the fire, a

217
00:30:28,008 --> 00:30:32,395
還有穩定的氧氣流 因為這樣就可以
steady oxygen flow and a means by which to...

218
00:30:35,366 --> 00:30:38,668
我要死了
I'm gonna die.

219
00:31:04,162 --> 00:31:06,397
好了 現在聽我說
All right, now you listen to me.

220
00:31:06,398 --> 00:31:09,334
好的獵手都知道 如果你想要捕食的話
If you want some prey and if you're some hotshot hunter,

221
00:31:09,335 --> 00:31:11,636
你就必須要讓我活下去
then you're gonna have to keep me alive.

222
00:31:11,637 --> 00:31:14,639
現在告訴我要怎么生火
Now tell me how to start the fire.

223
00:31:14,640 --> 00:31:16,174
我知道你可以看見我
I know you can see me.

224
00:31:16,175 --> 00:31:17,841
嘿 你看到了嗎
Hey, you see that?

225
00:31:18,543 --> 00:31:21,611
告訴我怎么生火
Tell me how to start the fire.

226
00:31:22,981 --> 00:31:24,883
我已經給你晚餐了
I gave you dinner,

227
00:31:24,884 --> 00:31:28,218
你還想讓我幫你煮熟嗎
now you want me to cook it for you, too?

228
00:31:29,221 --> 00:31:30,620
你怎么這么世故
Aren't you so suave?

229
00:31:38,930 --> 00:31:41,466
你想讓我活下去
Look, you want to keep me alive.

230
00:31:41,467 --> 00:31:43,200
多運動運動吧
More sporting.

231
00:31:44,235 --> 00:31:47,372
你根本就不知道什么是運動
You don't know nothin' about sportin'.

232
00:31:47,373 --> 00:31:51,309
可能 但是我可以對你猜出一二
Maybe, but I can take a few guesses about you.

233
00:31:51,310 --> 00:31:53,444
你不在周圍 我可以猜到
You aren't from around here, I can guess that.

234
00:31:53,445 --> 00:31:56,047
你那傻逼鄉巴佬口音說明
Not with that stupid hillbilly accent of yours

235
00:31:56,048 --> 00:31:58,349
你能一直呆在這里是受過訓練的
which means you trained to stay up here.

236
00:31:58,350 --> 00:31:59,712
你的槍法和求生技能都很高超
You're good with guns and survival.

237
00:31:59,737 --> 00:32:01,482
你給我的那本指南是海軍的
The manual you gave me is from the marines,

238
00:32:01,507 --> 00:32:03,421
還有那一點廣告
not to mention that little bit about commercials.

239
00:32:03,422 --> 00:32:06,658
所以 你是一名海軍 或者曾經是
So you're a marine, or were, at least.

240
00:32:06,659 --> 00:32:08,359
你可能就是一個總喜歡
You know you're probably some washed out old guy

241
00:32:08,360 --> 00:32:09,776
提起自己跟蹤富家子弟的光榮事跡
talkin' 'bout the glory

242
00:32:09,777 --> 00:32:12,363
的一個弱雞老頭子
days of 'nam who likes stalking rich kids!

243
00:32:12,364 --> 00:32:14,465
你整我就是覺得好玩 對不對
You're just havin' fun with me, aren't ya?

244
00:32:14,466 --> 00:32:15,960
我爸爸可能正把
My dad is probably dumping

245
00:32:15,961 --> 00:32:18,202
贖金轉到某個海外賬戶
ransom money into some offshore account

246
00:32:18,203 --> 00:32:20,638
直升機隨時都可能降落到這里來救我
and any day now a helicopter is going to land and save me

247
00:32:20,639 --> 00:32:23,374
在那之前你就盡管跟我周旋吧
and you're just screwin' with me til then.

248
00:32:23,375 --> 00:32:26,978
這 這就是綁架
Yeah, this, this is nothing but a ransom.

249
00:32:26,979 --> 00:32:30,747
你就是一個小偷 就這樣
You're a thief and that's all that it is.

250
00:32:32,116 --> 00:32:33,850
想吃東西嗎
Wanna eat?

251
00:32:34,585 --> 00:32:37,322
當然了 狼先生
Why yes, please, mister wolf.

252
00:32:37,323 --> 00:32:39,991
你叫我做什么我都做
I'll jump through whatever hoops you want me to.

253
00:32:39,992 --> 00:32:43,526
我還為你唱歌 為你跳舞
I'll sing and I'll dance for you, too.

254
00:32:48,667 --> 00:32:49,866
嘿
Hey!

255
00:32:51,302 --> 00:32:52,502
嘿 站住
Hey, stop!

256
00:32:53,438 --> 00:32:54,638
嘿
Hey!

257
00:32:55,139 --> 00:32:56,339
嘿 站住
Hey, stop!

258
00:32:58,476 --> 00:32:59,676
站住
Stop!

259
00:33:00,611 --> 00:33:01,811
等等
Wait!

260
00:33:05,683 --> 00:33:09,853
等等
Hold on a minute.

261
00:33:10,555 --> 00:33:11,755
嘿 冷靜
Hey, easy.

262
00:33:13,291 --> 00:33:14,491
聽著
Look...

263
00:33:16,094 --> 00:33:17,460
我被綁架了
I was taken.

264
00:33:18,396 --> 00:33:21,599
我正在找出去的路
I'm just looking for a way out of here.

265
00:33:21,600 --> 00:33:23,867
你會說英語嗎
Do you speak English?

266
00:33:25,104 --> 00:33:27,504
別緊張 別緊張 冷靜 冷靜
Easy, easy, easy, calm down, calm down.

267
00:33:29,208 --> 00:33:31,442
好了 好了 好了 好了
All right, all right, all right, all right.

268
00:33:31,443 --> 00:33:32,742
好 好
Okay, okay.

269
00:33:33,678 --> 00:33:35,512
好
All right.

270
00:33:36,615 --> 00:33:37,981
不好意思
Sorry buddy.

271
00:33:39,550 --> 00:33:40,950
好了
It's all right.

272
00:33:44,589 --> 00:33:46,624
你會說英語嗎
Do you know English?

273
00:33:46,625 --> 00:33:48,192
會
Yes.

274
00:33:48,193 --> 00:33:50,128
太好了
Thank god.

275
00:33:50,129 --> 00:33:51,328
好了
Okay.

276
00:33:52,597 --> 00:33:54,397
好了 我就是
Okay, I just...

277
00:33:55,633 --> 00:33:57,434
我被困在這了
I'm stuck here.

278
00:33:57,769 --> 00:33:59,969
我被綁來這里
I mean I was put here.

279
00:34:02,640 --> 00:34:03,840
好嗎
All right.

280
00:34:07,111 --> 00:34:09,479
我就是 那里有一個小木屋
I just, there's a cabin.

281
00:34:12,450 --> 00:34:13,684
什么
Hey, what?

282
00:34:13,685 --> 00:34:16,254
好了 好了 冷靜
All right, easy, easy.

283
00:34:16,255 --> 00:34:18,388
沒事 沒事
It's cool, it's cool.

284
00:34:19,424 --> 00:34:22,025
我在一張椅子上醒來然后
I woke up in a chair and I...

285
00:34:27,398 --> 00:34:29,766
你知道怎么做飯嗎
Do you know how to cook?

286
00:34:31,502 --> 00:34:34,539
然后我看到一只羊掛在樹上
Then I saw a sheep in the tree.

287
00:34:34,540 --> 00:34:37,575
我想遍了各種辦法把那只羊弄下來
I tried to cut it down the best I could.

288
00:34:37,576 --> 00:34:39,544
我覺得我看到你了
I think I saw you.

289
00:34:39,545 --> 00:34:40,745
我打算偷偷溜走
I was trying to sneak around.

290
00:34:40,746 --> 00:34:43,546
你什么時候醒的
When did you wake up?

291
00:34:44,248 --> 00:34:45,550
大概兩天前
About two days ago.

292
00:34:45,551 --> 00:34:47,318
好像是對的
Sounds about right.

293
00:34:47,319 --> 00:34:50,354
你在附近也有一個自己的小木屋嗎
Do you have your own cabin somewhere around here or?

294
00:34:50,355 --> 00:34:53,723
不 他幫我做了一個雪洞
No, he made a snow shelter for me.

295
00:34:55,259 --> 00:34:57,527
我就是在那醒來
That's where I've been.

296
00:34:58,696 --> 00:35:00,698
他告訴我怎么生火 怎么做矛
He told me how to make a fire and a spear.

297
00:35:00,699 --> 00:35:02,834
等等 你會生火
Whoa, hold on, you can make a fire?

298
00:35:02,835 --> 00:35:07,772
你會生火的話 我們就可以做飯了
Yeah. If you can make fire, then we can cook.

299
00:35:07,773 --> 00:35:10,807
我們就可以吃東西了 太棒了 我們走吧
We can eat, come on, come on, let's go.

300
00:35:12,177 --> 00:35:14,145
他為什么給你一個小木屋
Why did he give you a cabin?

301
00:35:14,146 --> 00:35:17,682
他想教我做一個真正的男人 你知道嗎
Well, he wanted to teach me to be a real man, you know?

302
00:35:17,683 --> 00:35:20,885
一個堅強 帥氣 充滿男子氣概的男人
Be all tough and cool and manly.

303
00:35:20,886 --> 00:35:23,788
不 我是說為什么他給你的是小木屋
No, why did he give you a cabin

304
00:35:23,789 --> 00:35:26,824
而我的就是地上的一個洞
and I get a hole in the ground?

305
00:35:26,825 --> 00:35:28,826
我不知道
I don't know.

306
00:35:28,827 --> 00:35:32,330
或許他不喜歡 我是說
Maybe he doesn't, I mean, you know,

307
00:35:32,331 --> 00:35:34,265
或許她不喜歡你這種類型
maybe he doesn't like your kind.

308
00:35:34,266 --> 00:35:35,465
我這種類型
My kind?

309
00:35:36,234 --> 00:35:38,536
對的 你是墨西哥人 對嗎
Well yeah, you're Mexican, right?

310
00:35:38,537 --> 00:35:41,606
你認真的嗎
Are you serious?

311
00:35:41,607 --> 00:35:43,141
我認真的
Yeah I'm serious.

312
00:35:43,142 --> 00:35:44,904
他想教你一些東西
Look, he's trying to teach you a lesson,

313
00:35:44,905 --> 00:35:46,711
所以他想教你什么呢
so what lesson is he trying to teach you?

314
00:35:46,712 --> 00:35:49,913
我是說 你有資格來這里嗎
I mean are you allowed to be here?

315
00:35:52,451 --> 00:35:54,285
不沒事的 我人很好的
No, it's cool. I'm cool.

316
00:35:54,286 --> 00:35:57,845
我來自橘子郡 我有兩個墨西哥朋友
Look, I'm from the oc, I got like two Mexican friends,

317
00:35:57,870 --> 00:36:00,324
他們有一百多個合法表親
they got like a hundred legal cousins.

318
00:36:00,325 --> 00:36:02,693
你有兩個墨西哥朋友
You have two Mexican friends?

319
00:36:02,694 --> 00:36:04,662
還真是多元文化啊
Multicultural.

320
00:36:04,663 --> 00:36:07,598
你認為我被關在這里是因為我是墨西哥人
You think I'm here because I'm Mexican?

321
00:36:07,599 --> 00:36:09,199
你這個混蛋
You're a jackass.

322
00:36:13,304 --> 00:36:17,507
他告訴我 我應該為自己而斗爭
He told me that I need to stand up for myself.

323
00:36:22,647 --> 00:36:23,847
我的錯
My bad.

324
00:36:30,755 --> 00:36:32,088
我要餓死了
I am starving.

325
00:36:34,892 --> 00:36:36,860
我濕光了
I am sopping wet.

326
00:36:38,462 --> 00:36:40,897
要凍死了
And I am freezing.

327
00:36:47,705 --> 00:36:50,139
來吧 生點火吧
Well, start us some fire.

328
00:36:56,747 --> 00:36:58,748
你要幫助吧
Do you need help?

329
00:37:00,651 --> 00:37:03,688
我想讓你走
I want you to go away.

330
00:37:03,689 --> 00:37:05,256
什么
What?

331
00:37:05,257 --> 00:37:07,758
如果你看到了怎么生火 我對你就沒有利用價值了
If you see how to make fire, I'm not useful to you.

332
00:37:07,759 --> 00:37:10,928
- 你就能把我趕出去了 - 拜托 你在開玩笑嗎 
- You can throw me out. - Come on, you've gotta be kidding.

333
00:37:10,929 --> 00:37:13,764
我不會做那種事的
I'm not going to do anything like that.

334
00:37:13,765 --> 00:37:16,566
你還想吃東西嗎
Do you want to eat?

335
00:37:20,538 --> 00:37:21,905
好吧
All right.

336
00:37:23,274 --> 00:37:24,908
消消氣
Cool your jets.

337
00:37:42,326 --> 00:37:44,762
你剛剛就在那里吧 對嗎
You're out there right now, aren't you?

338
00:37:44,763 --> 00:37:46,896
你在監視我們
You're watching us.

339
00:37:47,632 --> 00:37:50,300
你為什么把她送來這里 狼先生
Why'd you send her here, wolf?

340
00:37:56,741 --> 00:37:59,944
你現在或許能看見我
You can probably see me right now.

341
00:37:59,945 --> 00:38:01,844
她為什么會來這
Why is she here?

342
00:38:06,417 --> 00:38:09,553
不管為什么 她不會在這里呆太久的
For whatever reason, she isn't gonna stick around long.

343
00:38:09,554 --> 00:38:11,321
我會找出原因的
I'll figure it out.

344
00:38:13,791 --> 00:38:16,060
這不難的
It ain't hard.

345
00:38:16,061 --> 00:38:18,227
你說什么
What did you say?

346
00:38:19,630 --> 00:38:23,034
我說 找出她來這里的原因并不難
I say it ain't hard to figure out.

347
00:38:23,035 --> 00:38:26,035
我把她丟到這里是來殺你的
I sent her there to kill you.

348
00:38:27,772 --> 00:38:30,740
我怎么一點也不覺得驚奇呢
Why doesn't that surprise me?

349
00:38:36,380 --> 00:38:38,049
我不知道 狼先生
I can't tell, wolf.

350
00:38:38,050 --> 00:38:39,917
我不知道你到底是要殺我
I can't tell if you're trying to kill me

351
00:38:39,918 --> 00:38:42,251
還是要幫我
or tryin' to help me.

352
00:38:43,788 --> 00:38:47,925
那么 我還是給你一條更明確的信息吧
Well then, I better send you a clear message.

353
00:38:47,926 --> 00:38:50,293
好 你說吧
Yeah, and what's that?

354
00:38:53,731 --> 00:38:54,931
狼先生
Wolf?

355
00:38:56,767 --> 00:38:58,167
狼先生
Wolf?

356
00:39:17,888 --> 00:39:19,088
橘子郡
Oc?

357
00:39:23,762 --> 00:39:26,731
你是橘子郡的嗎
You're from orange county?

358
00:39:26,732 --> 00:39:27,930
是的
Yeah.

359
00:39:30,501 --> 00:39:34,872
本來我在那里有一個家庭 他們搬回去了
I had family there once, they've moved back.

360
00:39:34,873 --> 00:39:38,109
- 我本來想找一份實習 - 你怎么有我的靴子
- I was trying to get an internship - how did you get my boots?

361
00:39:40,778 --> 00:39:43,514
你穿的是我的靴子
You were wearing my boots.

362
00:39:43,515 --> 00:39:44,881
那個靴子
Those boots.

363
00:39:46,050 --> 00:39:48,151
怎么來的
How did you get them?

364
00:39:48,886 --> 00:39:50,987
我不明白
I don't understand.

365
00:39:57,962 --> 00:39:59,228
你知道嗎
You know...

366
00:40:01,966 --> 00:40:05,334
兩天前 我是一個完全不同的人
Two days ago, I was a different guy.

367
00:40:05,836 --> 00:40:07,171
這是最奇怪的事
You see that's the weird thing,

368
00:40:07,172 --> 00:40:09,440
我已經不知道我是誰了
I don't know who I am anymore.

369
00:40:09,441 --> 00:40:11,509
我也不知道你是誰
And I sure as hell don't know who you are.

370
00:40:11,510 --> 00:40:12,676
我叫維維安娜
My name is Viviana.

371
00:40:12,677 --> 00:40:14,310
我沒問你名字
I didn't ask.

372
00:40:15,045 --> 00:40:18,281
我問你怎么有我的靴子
I said how did you get my boots?

373
00:40:18,916 --> 00:40:21,150
這不是你的靴子
Those aren't your boots.

374
00:40:22,120 --> 00:40:24,020
他為什么讓你來這
Why did he send you?

375
00:40:24,990 --> 00:40:25,990
閉嘴
Shut up!

376
00:40:25,991 --> 00:40:27,425
狼為什么讓你來這里
Why did wolf send you?

377
00:40:27,426 --> 00:40:29,126
靴子是他給我的
He gave me the boots.

378
00:40:29,127 --> 00:40:30,561
繼續扯吧 維維安娜
Start talkin' Viviana.

379
00:40:30,562 --> 00:40:32,430
我告訴你了靴子是他給我的
I told you he gave me the boots.

380
00:40:32,431 --> 00:40:34,799
雖然我從沒碰過這些東西
You know I never touched one of these things,

381
00:40:34,800 --> 00:40:37,435
但既然我能把一只羊開膛破肚 我也一樣能把你開膛破肚
but I think if I can gut a sheep then I can gut you, too.

382
00:40:37,436 --> 00:40:38,436
不要
No!

383
00:40:39,470 --> 00:40:41,872
他告訴我要殺了你
He told me that I needed to kill that,

384
00:40:41,873 --> 00:40:43,135
要取走你的東西
that I need to take your things

385
00:40:43,136 --> 00:40:45,009
如果我不行動的話 我就得死
and I would die if I didn't action for myself.

386
00:40:45,010 --> 00:40:46,444
你
You?

387
00:40:46,445 --> 00:40:47,611
你要殺我
You kill me?

388
00:40:47,612 --> 00:40:48,879
你要殺我
You kill me?

389
00:40:48,880 --> 00:40:51,749
不 我
No, no I

390
00:40:51,750 --> 00:40:53,282
閉嘴
shut up!

391
00:40:56,520 --> 00:40:59,190
你玩得開心嗎
Are you enjoying the show?

392
00:41:00,125 --> 00:41:02,860
你瘋了嗎
Are you out of your mind?

393
00:41:02,861 --> 00:41:06,496
你來這里是來殺我的 所以我覺得這很公平
Well you're here to kill me, so I guess it's pretty fair.

394
00:41:19,677 --> 00:41:23,446
我們會死在這里 你知道嗎
We're gonna die out here, do you know that?

395
00:41:29,053 --> 00:41:30,053
對不起
Sorry.

396
00:41:32,957 --> 00:41:35,992
沒事 沒關系
Yeah, sure, it's all forgiven.

397
00:41:54,044 --> 00:41:58,581
我看到了 但我不敢相信
I see it, but I don't believe it.

398
00:41:59,717 --> 00:42:01,852
萊斯特在工作嗎
Is that Lester workin'?

399
00:42:01,853 --> 00:42:04,987
他真的在工作嗎
I mean is he actually workin'?

400
00:42:08,125 --> 00:42:10,060
笑吧 笑死你
Laugh it up, funny man.

401
00:42:10,061 --> 00:42:14,030
我在笑呢 我很喜歡
I am, I am enjoyin' the show.

402
00:42:14,999 --> 00:42:17,301
特別是昨晚那一幕
Especially the show last night.

403
00:42:17,302 --> 00:42:21,138
鑒于你是新手 我給你一些建議吧
Let me give you some advice since you're new to all this.

404
00:42:21,139 --> 00:42:25,374
下次你要恐嚇他人時 用火
Next time you wanna scare someone, use fire.

405
00:42:26,777 --> 00:42:29,980
他們的皮膚燒焦脫落氣泡
The thought of their skin peelin' back and bubblin' up,

406
00:42:29,981 --> 00:42:33,049
想想就激動
it's especially effective.

407
00:42:34,818 --> 00:42:37,021
你知道嗎 在昨天之前我從來沒有碰過女人
You know, I never touched a woman until last night?

408
00:42:37,022 --> 00:42:39,388
都是你逼我的
You made me do it, wolf.

409
00:42:43,028 --> 00:42:46,362
麗塔 麗塔可不同意啊
Rita, Rita would disagree.

410
00:42:48,966 --> 00:42:50,633
我沒有打她
I never hit her.

411
00:42:52,803 --> 00:42:55,039
你這輩子都沒有碰過麗塔
Nah, you never touched Rita in your life.

412
00:42:55,040 --> 00:42:56,941
你雨點般的拳頭落在的是
No, it was all them other whores

413
00:42:56,942 --> 00:42:59,043
其他賤人身上
you couldn't keep your hands off of.

414
00:42:59,044 --> 00:43:00,711
你對其他女性的態度
All them other ladies you've been,

415
00:43:00,712 --> 00:43:02,279
你的朋友們是怎么評價的
what do your friends call it?

416
00:43:02,280 --> 00:43:03,948
尖酸刻薄
Stabbing.

417
00:43:03,949 --> 00:43:07,483
這不重要 我會彌補我之前的過錯
It doesn't matter, I'm gonna fix it.

418
00:43:08,018 --> 00:43:09,353
好吧 現在就讓我希望
Well now I guess I shore hope

419
00:43:09,354 --> 00:43:10,955
你能走出這座山吧
you do get off this mountain

420
00:43:10,956 --> 00:43:12,990
因為這會值得一看的
because it would be a sight to see.

421
00:43:12,991 --> 00:43:18,095
你的肚子緊貼著地趴著祈求原諒
You crawlin' back on your little worm belly beggin' forgiveness.

422
00:43:18,096 --> 00:43:22,632
求你了哥們兒 求你了 我只是一時之間昏了頭
Please, baby, please, I swear it was a moment of weakness.

423
00:43:23,334 --> 00:43:26,103
你又能好到哪去
Well what about you?

424
00:43:26,104 --> 00:43:27,441
綁架一個無辜的墨西哥
Kidnapping some innocent Mexican

425
00:43:27,442 --> 00:43:29,239
女孩兒 把她扔到山頂上
girl and throwing her on top of a mountain.

426
00:43:29,240 --> 00:43:32,541
這可是一點紳士風度也沒有 沃爾夫 
That isn't too gentlemanly, wolf.

427
00:43:33,877 --> 00:43:35,378
確實是一件令人羞愧的事情 
Too shamae.

428
00:43:36,146 --> 00:43:39,337
但是不要忘了我們在這做的一切 
But let's not forget that this whole exercise

429
00:43:39,362 --> 00:43:42,319
都是為了你的成長
we're doin' out here is about you growin'.

430
00:43:42,320 --> 00:43:45,889
我還是覺得你是為了贖金
I still think it's a ransom.

431
00:43:45,890 --> 00:43:48,731
我爸會給你贖金 
I think my dad is paying you off and any day

432
00:43:48,756 --> 00:43:51,762
隨時都有可能 一架直升機就著陸在這來救我
now, a helicopter is going to land and save me.

433
00:43:51,763 --> 00:43:53,764
你覺得真是這樣嗎
Is that so?

434
00:43:53,765 --> 00:43:57,001
那你為什么在這砍樹枝呢
Why you out here loppin' up trees

435
00:43:57,002 --> 00:44:00,137
雖然我不是很確定你在外面做什么
I am not a lot definitive know about what you're doing out here.

436
00:44:00,138 --> 00:44:04,174
但是為了不讓你挨凍 我花了很多時間砍柴 
I spent so much time choppin' up wood so you could stay warm.

437
00:44:04,175 --> 00:44:07,411
我是為回家做好準備
I need to be ready for my trip back home.

438
00:44:07,412 --> 00:44:09,179
如果是這樣的話 
Well if that's the case,

439
00:44:09,180 --> 00:44:11,714
我給你準備了一雙很合適的鞋
I got a proper pair of boots for ya.

440
00:44:14,252 --> 00:44:17,655
我敢確定那不是個圈套
And I'm sure there's no catch.

441
00:44:17,656 --> 00:44:21,358
只用走幾步路 往北走一英里左右
Just a little walk, about a mile or so north.

442
00:44:21,359 --> 00:44:23,726
我把它放在一個小屋附近
I left 'em near a cabin.

443
00:44:24,728 --> 00:44:27,231
我覺得我還是呆在這比較好
I think I'll stay right here.

444
00:44:27,232 --> 00:44:29,465
膽小鬼
Bon shots.

445
00:44:58,962 --> 00:45:00,563
你在干什么呢
What's all this?

446
00:45:08,105 --> 00:45:10,340
臨時雪地靴
Expedient snow shoes?

447
00:45:13,410 --> 00:45:15,446
- 一起來制作吧 - 那就來吧
- Let's do it. - Just do it.

448
00:45:15,447 --> 00:45:17,381
這兒 不行不行 讓我來 我們只用 
Okay here, no, no, no, no. Let me... no, we just.

449
00:45:17,382 --> 00:45:19,749
等我一下啦
Just give me one second.

450
00:45:22,920 --> 00:45:24,988
你只用在這兒打一個雙結
It's just that you have to do a double knot here.

451
00:45:24,989 --> 00:45:26,300
恩 有打雙節的方法
Yeah, well there's a way

452
00:45:26,301 --> 00:45:28,759
只是很蠢而已
of doing a double knot and that's just silly.

453
00:45:28,760 --> 00:45:30,794
這是另一種結
This is another knot.

454
00:45:30,795 --> 00:45:33,396
好吧 這是雙結
Fine, it's a double knot.

455
00:45:42,973 --> 00:45:45,808
關于昨天晚上 我
Hey, so about last night I'm...

456
00:45:47,044 --> 00:45:49,345
我們來試一試 怎么樣
let's try them, okay?

457
00:45:51,215 --> 00:45:52,615
走吧
Come on.

458
00:46:59,149 --> 00:47:00,316
過來
Come here.

459
00:47:04,955 --> 00:47:06,155
快過來
Come here!

460
00:47:17,301 --> 00:47:21,203
你在發什么瘋
What is the matter with you?

461
00:47:23,440 --> 00:47:26,675
這根本就沒必要啊
That was completely unnecessary.

462
00:47:33,851 --> 00:47:35,751
我要去找一找那雙鞋
I'll take the bait.

463
00:47:56,440 --> 00:47:59,408
- 我真不覺得那樣 - 你真不覺得什么
- I really don't think - you don't think what?

464
00:48:04,448 --> 00:48:06,483
好了 我看到那個地方了
All right, I see that's the place.

465
00:48:06,484 --> 00:48:08,118
我總有一種不祥的預感
This doesn't feel right.

466
00:48:08,119 --> 00:48:10,419
一切當然不會安然無事
Of course it doesn't.

467
00:48:11,054 --> 00:48:12,289
不要去 求你了
Please don't go in there.

468
00:48:12,290 --> 00:48:13,738
聽著 我在外面走這么久
Look, I didn't walk all the

469
00:48:13,739 --> 00:48:16,260
不是為了好玩的 知道嗎
way out here just for the fun of it, all right?

470
00:48:16,261 --> 00:48:18,262
你就蹲在這就行了
Just stay down.

471
00:48:18,263 --> 00:48:19,695
聽我說
Listen to me.

472
00:48:20,898 --> 00:48:22,765
你要說什么 說什么
What? What?

473
00:48:27,204 --> 00:48:28,804
你放哨就行
Keep a lookout.

474
00:50:45,409 --> 00:50:47,413
你走不遠的 我不會呆在這的
You won't get far. I'm not staying here.

475
00:50:47,438 --> 00:50:49,613
我跟你說了去那不是一個好主意
I told you it was a bad idea to go there

476
00:50:49,614 --> 00:50:52,082
現在走不是一個好主意
and I'm telling you it's a bad idea to leave now.

477
00:50:52,083 --> 00:50:54,251
聽著 在晚上的話他就沒法追蹤我們 知道嗎
Look, he can't track us in the dark, all right?

478
00:50:54,252 --> 00:50:56,086
這對我們來說是有利條件 知道嗎
That gives us the advantage, okay?

479
00:50:56,087 --> 00:50:59,117
- 給了我們先行一步的優勢 - 我不想去
- Gives us a head start. - I don't wanna go.

480
00:50:59,142 --> 00:51:03,649
我可不想最后落得像小屋里面的那些人一樣的下場
Okay, I don't wanna end up like those guys in the cabin.

481
00:51:06,631 --> 00:51:10,032
你教教我怎么生火
You have to tell me how to make a fire.

482
00:51:14,604 --> 00:51:16,004
求你了
Please.

483
00:51:19,543 --> 00:51:20,811
你的手表是怎么回事
What's with the watch?

484
00:51:20,812 --> 00:51:23,146
維維安娜 如果我不會生火
Viviana, if I can't make a fire,

485
00:51:23,147 --> 00:51:24,614
那我會凍死的
then I'm going to freeze to death.

486
00:51:24,615 --> 00:51:26,516
反正你怎么樣都會死
You will anyway.

487
00:51:26,517 --> 00:51:28,518
晚上出去 
You're leaving at night.

488
00:51:28,519 --> 00:51:30,187
簡直蠢透了
This is so stupid.

489
00:51:30,188 --> 00:51:33,256
不 呆在這 才是蠢
No, staying here, that is stupid.

490
00:51:33,257 --> 00:51:35,858
晚上出去 是蠢上加蠢
Leaving at night, that's worse.

491
00:51:39,463 --> 00:51:42,132
告訴我怎么生火
Tell me how to make a fire.

492
00:51:42,133 --> 00:51:43,834
告訴我你手表的事  
Tell me about the watch.

493
00:51:43,835 --> 00:51:46,902
我可沒時間和你玩游戲
I don't have time for games.

494
00:51:50,307 --> 00:51:51,507
哦天
God!

495
00:51:55,413 --> 00:51:56,612
我怎么就攤上你了
Why you?

496
00:52:00,585 --> 00:52:03,253
這個手表是我爸給我的禮物 行了吧
The watch was a present from my old man all right?

497
00:52:03,254 --> 00:52:06,123
當時我找到了第一份工作 但很快就被開除了 
When I got my first job, but I got fired soon afterwards

498
00:52:06,124 --> 00:52:09,658
我爸用這個手表來提醒我
so he let me keep it to remind myself.

499
00:52:10,460 --> 00:52:12,629
提醒你什么
As a reminder of what?

500
00:52:12,630 --> 00:52:14,163
提醒我注意時間
Of the time.

501
00:52:14,798 --> 00:52:16,932
哦天 你是智障嗎
Jesus are you stupid?

502
00:52:23,206 --> 00:52:27,876
提醒我 我搞砸了所有的事 
As a reminder that I screw up everything.

503
00:52:36,853 --> 00:52:39,723
你的提燈里面有電池吧
You have a battery in your lantern.

504
00:52:39,724 --> 00:52:40,724
有 
Yeah.

505
00:52:41,892 --> 00:52:44,461
我給你一點這個 
I'll give you some of this.

506
00:52:44,462 --> 00:52:45,829
鋼絲絨嗎
Steel wool?

507
00:52:45,830 --> 00:52:47,029
沒錯
Yeah.

508
00:52:47,697 --> 00:52:48,997
你把他們放在一起磨擦
You rub them together.

509
00:52:51,669 --> 00:52:56,004
很不錯哦
That's cool.

510
00:53:02,679 --> 00:53:04,748
祝你好運 
Good luck.

511
00:53:04,749 --> 00:53:05,948
謝謝你
Thanks.

512
00:54:33,637 --> 00:54:34,836
快亮啊
Come on!

513
00:54:41,311 --> 00:54:42,578
天啊 不 
God, no.

514
00:55:00,730 --> 00:55:02,130
哦天
God.

515
00:55:56,519 --> 00:55:58,720
上帝 對不起 
I'm sorry, god, for...

516
00:56:01,691 --> 00:56:02,958
我為我過去所做的一切感到懺悔
Everything.

517
00:56:05,962 --> 00:56:09,031
爸 對不起 對不起我是
I'm sorry, dad, for being a...

518
00:56:10,734 --> 00:56:12,134
一個混帳兒子 
A terrible son.

519
00:56:30,387 --> 00:56:31,987
麗塔 對不起 
I'm sorry Rita.

520
00:56:35,392 --> 00:56:36,392
對不起
I'm sorry.

521
00:56:46,536 --> 00:56:47,736
管它媽的
Screw it.

522
00:57:23,941 --> 00:57:25,373
快開啊
Come on.

523
00:57:58,908 --> 00:58:00,275
維維安娜
Viviana!

524
00:58:01,010 --> 00:58:03,847
維維安娜  救我啊
Viviana! Help!

525
00:58:03,848 --> 00:58:05,949
啊 萊斯特 你還好嗎
My god, Lester, are you okay?

526
00:58:05,950 --> 00:58:08,751
- 啊 痛死了 - 哪里痛
- God, it hurts. - What hurts?

527
00:58:12,922 --> 00:58:16,458
不要碰 不要碰 不要不要
Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't.

528
00:58:18,529 --> 00:58:21,163
我好冷啊 我好冷啊
I'm freezing, I'm freezing.

529
00:58:24,902 --> 00:58:26,401
沒用
no use.

530
00:58:29,072 --> 00:58:30,438
沒事了
It's okay.

531
00:58:31,941 --> 00:58:33,743
啊 不要不要碰 對不起 
My god. - No, don't touch. - I'm sorry!

532
00:58:33,744 --> 00:58:34,911
對不起 對不起 
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.

533
00:58:34,912 --> 00:58:36,378
對不起
I'm so sorry.

534
00:58:41,918 --> 00:58:44,654
不要 不要碰它 好嗎 
Don't, don't touch it, all right?

535
00:58:44,655 --> 00:58:46,021
對不起 
I'm sorry.

536
00:59:00,537 --> 00:59:04,172
我就一蠢貨 
I am an idiot.

537
00:59:06,042 --> 00:59:08,745
雖然我不懂你在說什么
I have no idea what you said,

538
00:59:08,746 --> 00:59:11,479
但是我相信我確實是活該
but I'm sure that I deserve it.

539
00:59:27,130 --> 00:59:29,666
好吧 你個賤人
All right, you son of a bitch.

540
00:59:29,667 --> 00:59:32,168
昨晚有點忙嗎
Busy night?

541
00:59:32,169 --> 00:59:34,571
我得到教訓了
I've learned my lesson.

542
00:59:34,572 --> 00:59:37,173
大自然母親有時候是個死賤婊
Well mother nature's a tough bitch sometimes.

543
00:59:37,174 --> 00:59:40,109
你得小心她噢
You gotta watch out for her.

544
00:59:40,110 --> 00:59:42,178
你為什么不朝我開槍
Why didn't you shoot me?

545
00:59:42,179 --> 00:59:43,980
一個大個子腿被扎了一個洞
It takes a big man to crawl

546
00:59:43,981 --> 00:59:46,783
還要在雪地里爬一英里
a mile on the snow with a hole in his leg.

547
00:59:46,784 --> 00:59:49,150
老實說 確實很痛苦啊
Seriously, that's tough.

548
00:59:49,919 --> 00:59:52,288
你感覺怎么樣啊
How's it treating ya?

549
00:59:52,289 --> 00:59:55,024
我一定要勒死你
I'm going to strangle you.

550
00:59:55,025 --> 00:59:57,860
你們兩個都聽著
Hear you both together.

551
00:59:57,861 --> 01:00:00,663
我突然想起一次打獵 我傷到腳踝了
Now I remember once on a hunting trip, I busted my ankle...

552
01:00:00,664 --> 01:00:03,266
當他們往你得手臂里扎針的時候 
I'm going to enjoy the look on your face

553
01:00:03,267 --> 01:00:05,969
我會好好享受你臉上的表情 
when they shove that needle in your arm.

554
01:00:05,970 --> 01:00:08,866
我一定會帶著最大的笑臉好好的看著
I'm gonna sit back with the biggest smile.

555
01:00:08,891 --> 01:00:13,042
我想起一次打獵 我傷到腳踝了
I remember once on a hunting trip, I busted my ankle now.

556
01:00:13,043 --> 01:00:17,080
我在森林深處 周圍一個人都沒有
I was a long shot off in the woods with no one around...

557
01:00:17,081 --> 01:00:19,414
不要再說你那些陳芝麻爛骨頭的事情
stop with the anecdotes!

558
01:00:30,760 --> 01:00:32,460
沃爾夫 對不起
Wolf, I'm sorry.

559
01:00:38,101 --> 01:00:41,469
你的物資情況如何
How is your supplies doing?

560
01:00:42,105 --> 01:00:44,139
我不知道 為什么突然問這個
I don't know, why?

561
01:00:45,041 --> 01:00:47,377
你不用擔心那些有的沒的
Well, you shouldn't be worried about threats,

562
01:00:47,378 --> 01:00:51,680
應該多花時間想想關于那個密碼鎖的事情
and much more about a certain combination lock.

563
01:00:53,216 --> 01:00:54,549
密碼鎖
Combination?

564
01:01:00,323 --> 01:01:05,060
壁櫥里面有一個保險箱
There's a safe in the closet.

565
01:01:06,062 --> 01:01:09,431
你從來沒有看過怎么打開它嗎
And you never look how to open it?

566
01:01:16,406 --> 01:01:19,474
你覺得我從哪里開始比較好
Where do you want me to start?

567
01:01:20,243 --> 01:01:21,643
隨你
I don't care.

568
01:01:24,947 --> 01:01:26,147
那好
Okay.

569
01:01:26,983 --> 01:01:28,717
我就從外頭開始
I'll start outside.

570
01:02:17,333 --> 01:02:18,533
維維安娜
Viviana!

571
01:02:20,303 --> 01:02:21,971
你找到了嗎
Did you find it?

572
01:02:21,972 --> 01:02:24,273
不是 維維安娜  進屋里來
No, Viviana, get back inside!

573
01:02:24,274 --> 01:02:27,009
什么 快點進來
What? Just get back inside!

574
01:02:27,010 --> 01:02:29,077
快點 快點
Please, now!

575
01:02:31,515 --> 01:02:33,783
- 快點 - 我來啦
- Come on! - I'm coming.

576
01:02:33,784 --> 01:02:35,985
快點 快點 快點
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.

577
01:02:35,986 --> 01:02:37,118
怎么了
What happened?

578
01:02:38,322 --> 01:02:42,057
沒什么  我知道有不好的預感 
Nothing, I just I had a bad feeling.

579
01:02:42,892 --> 01:02:44,293
什么 
What?

580
01:02:44,294 --> 01:02:47,263
我昨天就有不好的預感 你不還是走了
I had a bad feeling yesterday and you walked off.

581
01:02:47,264 --> 01:02:48,431
真的嗎 真的嗎
Really, really?

582
01:02:48,432 --> 01:02:51,801
說這些還有用嗎
That's the productive thing to say?

583
01:02:51,802 --> 01:02:54,003
我只是想能做點什么
I was trying to help.

584
01:02:54,004 --> 01:02:57,240
哦 那好 對不起啦
Well, okay then, excuse me.

585
01:02:57,241 --> 01:02:59,976
我是維維安娜 我頭腦聰明四肢強健 
I'm Viviana, I'm so smart and strong

586
01:02:59,977 --> 01:03:01,944
我可以自己擺平沃爾夫 就是這樣
and I can handle wolf by myself, that's fine.

587
01:03:01,945 --> 01:03:05,313
我還在找密碼
I was still looking for the combo.

588
01:03:09,852 --> 01:03:13,588
沒錯 又厲害又堅定 就像我喜歡的那樣
Yep, nice and sturdy, just how I like ya.

589
01:03:25,035 --> 01:03:26,234
維維安娜
Viviana!

590
01:03:27,537 --> 01:03:28,837
維維安娜
Viviana.

591
01:03:30,273 --> 01:03:32,375
看我拿到了什么
Look what I got.

592
01:03:32,376 --> 01:03:35,743
猜我會拿這個來做什么
No, what am I gonna do with this?

593
01:03:42,218 --> 01:03:43,418
好吧
Fine.

594
01:03:53,529 --> 01:03:56,764
猜猜誰找到密碼啦
Guess who found the combination?

595
01:04:09,246 --> 01:04:10,612
快開吧
Come on.

596
01:04:18,255 --> 01:04:19,654
好啦
Yes.

597
01:04:20,356 --> 01:04:21,756
神啊
My god.

598
01:04:24,194 --> 01:04:25,393
主
Jesus.

599
01:04:36,339 --> 01:04:38,173
沃爾夫 謝謝你 
Thank you wolf.

600
01:04:46,182 --> 01:04:48,384
我們應該更早一點打開這個 
We should have opened this sooner.

601
01:04:48,385 --> 01:04:49,784
沒錯 
Yeah.

602
01:04:58,427 --> 01:04:59,627
啊 
Ouch.

603
01:05:02,398 --> 01:05:05,301
你得脫掉你的褲子 
You need to take off your pants.

604
01:05:05,302 --> 01:05:06,501
不行 
No.

605
01:05:08,037 --> 01:05:10,330
那我該怎么給你包繃帶呢
How am I supposed to put the bandage on?

606
01:05:10,355 --> 01:05:11,697
直接包在上面就可以了
Just put it on top.

607
01:05:15,379 --> 01:05:16,512
輕點
Be careful.

608
01:05:16,513 --> 01:05:18,746
我是輕輕的啊
I'm trying.

609
01:05:34,031 --> 01:05:36,098
- 好疼啊 - 閉嘴
- It hurts! - Shut up!

610
01:05:36,099 --> 01:05:37,266
什么 
What?

611
01:05:37,267 --> 01:05:38,766
你聽到了嗎 
You hear that?

612
01:05:42,306 --> 01:05:44,073
你聽到了嗎 
Do you hear that?

613
01:05:44,074 --> 01:05:45,273
不會吧 
No way.

614
01:05:45,675 --> 01:05:47,043
太好了 
Yeah!

615
01:05:47,044 --> 01:05:48,044
我猜對了
I was right.

616
01:05:51,380 --> 01:05:52,448
天上什么都沒有
I don't see anything.

617
01:05:53,417 --> 01:05:55,250
- 它到底在哪里 - 嘿
- Where is it? - Hey!

618
01:05:56,653 --> 01:05:59,754
救命
Help!

619
01:06:14,403 --> 01:06:15,603
沃爾夫
Wolf!

620
01:06:17,673 --> 01:06:18,873
沃爾夫
Wolf!

621
01:06:24,047 --> 01:06:27,450
好吧 你說他給過你什么東西
Okay, you said he gave you things.

622
01:06:27,451 --> 01:06:30,019
他留給我幾條指示
He left instructions for me.

623
01:06:30,020 --> 01:06:31,786
你見到他了嗎
Did you meet him?

624
01:06:34,423 --> 01:06:37,201
我們必須在他的博弈中角逐 才能打敗他
If we're gonna beat him, we have to do it at his own game.

625
01:06:37,226 --> 01:06:38,661
他是個危險分子
He's a very dangerous man.

626
01:06:38,662 --> 01:06:40,329
真的嗎
He's a dangerous man?

627
01:06:40,330 --> 01:06:42,830
別鬧了 講真 
Get out of town, no kidding.

628
01:06:43,632 --> 01:06:47,203
你能別這樣嗎
Would you stop doing that?

629
01:06:47,204 --> 01:06:49,937
- 怎樣 - 說話陰陽怪氣
- Doing what? - Talking like that.

630
01:06:50,740 --> 01:06:53,576
好 好 我明白了
All right, all right, all right, all right.

631
01:06:53,577 --> 01:06:55,011
就這樣
Okay.

632
01:06:55,012 --> 01:06:57,013
他認為自己是正確的
He thinks that what he's doing is right.

633
01:06:57,014 --> 01:06:58,781
對 好死不如賴活著
Yeah, well not dying is right for me,

634
01:06:58,782 --> 01:07:00,815
那我會安于現狀
so I'm gonna do that.

635
01:07:16,098 --> 01:07:18,700
我是在一個雪窟里清醒過來
I woke up in a snow cave.

636
01:07:20,302 --> 01:07:21,502
然后呢
Okay.

637
01:07:22,605 --> 01:07:24,473
這就是我們的逃生出口
That's our exit.

638
01:07:24,474 --> 01:07:26,642
我們要離開 就要建一個防雪棚
We need to leave now, we'll make a snow shelter.

639
01:07:26,643 --> 01:07:29,412
那好
Okay.

640
01:07:29,413 --> 01:07:30,679
是誰建造的雪窟
Okay, who built your snow cave?

641
01:07:30,680 --> 01:07:32,114
那個人
He did.

642
01:07:32,115 --> 01:07:34,483
那我們如何才能堆砌呢
And how are we supposed to build it?

643
01:07:34,484 --> 01:07:37,286
我們有手冊指導啊 對 就算我們有這個
We have the manual. Okay, we have the manual.

644
01:07:37,287 --> 01:07:39,455
現在我們只需要再有一百名海軍
All right, now all we need is 100 marines,

645
01:07:39,456 --> 01:07:42,725
一把鋤頭 幾個雪鏟 再來個挖土機就完美了
a pickax, some shovels, a bulldozer would be nice.

646
01:07:42,726 --> 01:07:44,560
聽著 他是受過訓練的 而我們則不然
Okay, look, he's trained, we're not.

647
01:07:44,561 --> 01:07:46,495
指導手冊還不如是用中文寫的呢 反正都那么沒用
That manual, it might as well be in Chinese.

648
01:07:46,496 --> 01:07:49,432
這不影響 我在那里存活了兩夜
It doesn't matter, I survived there for two nights.

649
01:07:49,433 --> 01:07:51,634
我覺得我們可以成功
I know we can do this.

650
01:07:51,635 --> 01:07:54,370
聽我說 我曾經有過嘗試 看到我的下場了嘛
Look, I tried this once before, okay? Look what happened.

651
01:07:54,371 --> 01:07:58,607
我差點掛了 這次我們也不會走狗屎運的
I almost died and this time, we might not be so lucky.

652
01:07:58,608 --> 01:08:01,510
那是因為你單獨行動 而且是在深夜離開
You left by yourself and you left at night.

653
01:08:01,511 --> 01:08:03,746
這次我們在白天出發 合作行動
This time we're leaving together and it's daytime.

654
01:08:03,747 --> 01:08:06,148
我們可以拼命步行 總歸會找到合適的地點
We can walk as far as we can and then we'll find a place

655
01:08:06,149 --> 01:08:07,650
建造雪窟
to build a snow cave.

656
01:08:07,651 --> 01:08:11,821
像我這樣在齊膝的雪地中 步履維艱
How am I supposed to trudge in knee-deep snow with this?

657
01:08:11,822 --> 01:08:14,256
我會幫你的
I'm gonna help you.

658
01:08:14,257 --> 01:08:16,192
你必須聽我的 萊斯特
You have to listen to me, Lester.

659
01:08:16,193 --> 01:08:17,626
這是我們唯一的機會
This is our only chance.

660
01:08:17,627 --> 01:08:20,162
這次我們要先發制人
For the first time, we're gonna be one step ahead of him.

661
01:08:20,163 --> 01:08:23,466
我之前說到 我們必須在他的博弈中戰勝他
You said it before, we have to beat him at his own game.

662
01:08:23,467 --> 01:08:24,768
事實如此 萊斯特
This is it, Lester.

663
01:08:24,793 --> 01:08:28,671
如果真的有人正在找你 他不會讓他們得逞
If someone's in fact looking for you, he won't let them save you.

664
01:08:28,672 --> 01:08:30,639
他會置你于死地
He will kill you.

665
01:08:30,640 --> 01:08:34,210
現在的天氣起了變化 這正是我們的好時機
And now that the weather is changing, we'll have a chance.

666
01:08:34,211 --> 01:08:37,011
他追蹤不到我們
He won't be able to track us.

667
01:08:37,646 --> 01:08:40,014
等一下
Just give me a minute.

668
01:08:53,496 --> 01:08:54,695
那好吧
Okay.

669
01:08:56,132 --> 01:08:58,300
你計劃是什么
How do you want to do this?

670
01:08:58,301 --> 01:08:59,600
一起行動
Together.

671
01:10:13,842 --> 01:10:17,413
我還以為白人熱衷于野營
I though white people go camping all the time.

672
01:10:17,414 --> 01:10:18,613
真的嗎
Don't you?

673
01:10:18,914 --> 01:10:20,114
種族偏見
Racist.

674
01:10:35,631 --> 01:10:36,998
我們開始吧
Here you go.

675
01:10:42,438 --> 01:10:44,895
好的 上面寫著我們
All right, it says that we

676
01:10:44,896 --> 01:10:49,244
需要用十字交叉的樹干做棚頂
need to criss-cross the branches for the roof.

677
01:10:49,269 --> 01:10:51,513
好
All right.

678
01:10:51,514 --> 01:10:52,815
我們需要嫩一些的樹枝
And then we need younger ones.

679
01:10:52,816 --> 01:10:54,950
-還需要嗎 -是的 然后把他們加長
- More? - Yeah, and make them longer.

680
01:10:54,951 --> 01:10:55,635
加長 好吧
Longer? Okay.

681
01:10:55,660 --> 01:10:57,686
然后他們可以從這頭搭到另一頭
So they go from one side to the other.

682
01:10:57,687 --> 01:10:59,787
好 好
All right, all right.

683
01:12:33,949 --> 01:12:35,149
嘿
Hey.

684
01:12:41,057 --> 01:12:42,256
你不能睡著
You can't.

685
01:12:54,370 --> 01:12:56,237
講講關于她的故事
Tell me about her.

686
01:12:58,507 --> 01:12:59,842
萊斯特
Lester?

687
01:13:02,711 --> 01:13:05,079
你不是有女朋友嗎
You have a girlfriend.

688
01:13:07,783 --> 01:13:09,183
是的
Yeah.

689
01:13:15,858 --> 01:13:17,358
她漂亮嗎
Is she pretty?

690
01:13:18,394 --> 01:13:20,161
她美艷動人
She's gorgeous.

691
01:13:25,868 --> 01:13:29,170
她對你很好嗎
Does she take good care of you?

692
01:13:31,673 --> 01:13:33,274
沒錯
Yeah, she does.

693
01:13:42,618 --> 01:13:44,719
她是個幸運的女孩兒
She's a lucky girl.

694
01:13:47,956 --> 01:13:50,191
那不一定
I wouldn't say so.

695
01:14:09,978 --> 01:14:11,547
維維安娜
Viviana!

696
01:14:11,548 --> 01:14:12,747
維維安娜
Viviana!

697
01:14:13,048 --> 01:14:14,116
快醒醒
Viviana wake up!

698
01:14:14,117 --> 01:14:15,217
火快熄滅了
The fire's almost out!

699
01:14:15,218 --> 01:14:16,852
什么
What?

700
01:14:16,853 --> 01:14:17,986
火苗零星了
It's almost dead.

701
01:14:17,987 --> 01:14:20,788
點燃樹枝
Light the sticks.

702
01:14:23,091 --> 01:14:26,862
它們不會燒著了 火焰溫度太低
They won't light, they won't light, they're too cold.

703
01:14:26,863 --> 01:14:29,130
借我用一下你的鋼絲絨
I need your steel wool.

704
01:14:30,232 --> 01:14:33,602
我的要留到最后 先用你的
We used mine last, where's yours?

705
01:14:33,603 --> 01:14:34,802
不行
No.

706
01:14:35,571 --> 01:14:37,673
我忘在小屋里了
I left it at the cabin.

707
01:14:49,685 --> 01:14:51,220
手冊上怎么說
What does it say?

708
01:14:51,221 --> 01:14:53,055
別 你干什么
No, what are you doing?

709
01:14:53,056 --> 01:14:56,058
聽著 我們別無選擇 好嗎 - 確實 但我們需要手冊
Look, we have no choice, all right? - Yeah, we need it!

710
01:14:56,059 --> 01:14:57,825
我們更需要火源
We need a fire.

711
01:15:08,070 --> 01:15:10,805
有用嗎
Is it working?

712
01:15:16,212 --> 01:15:18,479
好的
There we go.

713
01:15:19,581 --> 01:15:23,450
就這樣 點著了 點著了
There we go, it's catchin', it's catching.

714
01:17:02,118 --> 01:17:03,317
你聽到了嗎
Do you hear that?

715
01:17:48,797 --> 01:17:50,799
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.

716
01:17:50,800 --> 01:17:53,435
我們的行蹤 我們的行蹤暴露了
Our tracks, our tracks he's spot our tracks.

717
01:17:53,436 --> 01:17:54,670
是的 我們必須分頭行動
Okay we need to split up.

718
01:17:54,671 --> 01:17:57,371
走 快走 
Go, go, go, go, go. Go.

719
01:19:01,937 --> 01:19:05,207
快 快逃 
Come on, come on, come on, come on.

720
01:19:05,208 --> 01:19:09,111
萊斯特 
Lester! Look.

721
01:19:09,112 --> 01:19:10,778
快走
Okay, come on.

722
01:20:24,052 --> 01:20:27,154
維維安娜 我們得 維維安娜
Viviana, hey, we gotta Viviana?

723
01:20:29,324 --> 01:20:30,559
維維安娜
Viviana?

724
01:20:30,560 --> 01:20:31,893
醒醒
Wake up.

725
01:20:31,894 --> 01:20:33,494
維維安娜 不要
Viviana please.

726
01:20:34,062 --> 01:20:37,465
別 別死 維維安娜 求求你 醒一醒
No, no, no, no, no, no. Please Viviana, wake up.

727
01:20:37,466 --> 01:20:38,665
維維安娜
Viviana!

728
01:20:39,367 --> 01:20:40,868
維維安娜 醒醒
Viviana wake up!

729
01:20:41,603 --> 01:20:43,572
求你別離開
No, no please.

730
01:20:43,573 --> 01:20:45,040
求你 我一個人應付不來
Please, I don't know what to do.

731
01:20:45,041 --> 01:20:47,574
求求你告訴我該怎么辦
Please tell me what to do.

732
01:20:48,410 --> 01:20:52,713
維維安娜  別這樣 不要死
Viviana, please don't, please don't, please don't go.

733
01:20:53,348 --> 01:20:54,848
不要走
Please don't go.

734
01:20:55,383 --> 01:20:58,153
求你了 我不知道如何是好
Please I don't know what to do.

735
01:20:58,154 --> 01:21:00,721
怎么辦  求你你告訴我啊 
I don't know what to do, please tell me what to do.

736
01:21:01,390 --> 01:21:02,789
求你
Please.

737
01:21:03,592 --> 01:21:06,261
求你別拋下我孤身一人
Please, I don't want to be alone.

738
01:21:06,262 --> 01:21:09,396
別拋下我
Please don't leave me here alone.

739
01:23:45,120 --> 01:23:46,320
天吶
Boy.

740
01:23:48,023 --> 01:23:49,923
那時我僅16歲
No I was only 16.

741
01:23:52,293 --> 01:23:55,562
我爸爸過來告訴我
And my dad comes up to me and says,

742
01:23:56,531 --> 01:24:00,502
我努力建立自己的公司所以你也要
"I worked to build my company so you need to learn"

743
01:24:00,503 --> 01:24:02,470
有樣學樣
"How to do the same."

744
01:24:02,471 --> 01:24:07,007
之后他就給我找了個工作
So he made me get a job.

745
01:24:08,276 --> 01:24:14,915
我左看右看 上看下看 這里不就是個
And I looked and I looked and I looked and all I could find was

746
01:24:17,319 --> 01:24:19,853
愚蠢透頂的熱狗連鎖嘛
that stupid hot dog joint.

747
01:24:21,489 --> 01:24:24,059
還得帶那個帽子 你造嗎
With the hats, you know?

748
01:24:24,060 --> 01:24:28,662
那個熱狗帽真是無與倫比的蠢
Those stupid, stupid hot dog hats.

749
01:24:30,398 --> 01:24:34,935
所以那就是我工作的地方
And that's where I got a job.

750
01:24:39,574 --> 01:24:42,376
這件事我恨透了他
I was so mad at him about it.

751
01:24:43,411 --> 01:24:46,980
你知道嗎 頭戴那種香腸帽真的是浪費生命
You know, wasting my time wearing a wiener hat.

752
01:24:48,249 --> 01:24:52,786
還不如教會我如何經商
Like that was supposed to teach me to be a business man.

753
01:24:54,189 --> 01:24:56,758
而我父親反復告訴我 我所需的是
And dad's all telling me about how I need

754
01:24:56,759 --> 01:25:00,161
從底層做起 打出自己的一片天
to start from the bottom and work my way up

755
01:25:00,162 --> 01:25:04,664
細數他自己創業時的艱辛
and how tough he had it when he started his company.

756
01:25:05,567 --> 01:25:07,067
而我的所作所為就是
So what I did...

757
01:25:08,369 --> 01:25:10,598
那時有一個
There was this there was

758
01:25:10,599 --> 01:25:14,408
女孩在耳釘店工作
this girl who worked at the earring shop.

759
01:25:15,443 --> 01:25:19,546
我開始和她調情 也是件美好的事情
So I started flirting with her, this cute little thing, too.

760
01:25:22,817 --> 01:25:28,955
我讓她給我免費打了個耳洞
And I got her to give me a piercing for free.

761
01:25:29,824 --> 01:25:33,595
就是為了和他作對 你知道嗎
Just to get back at him, you know?

762
01:25:33,596 --> 01:25:36,174
所以我戴著耳釘回家
So I come home with this thing

763
01:25:36,175 --> 01:25:40,301
他就說 你到底干了些什么
in my ear and he's all, "What the hell is that?"

764
01:25:40,302 --> 01:25:42,502
然后我對他說 爸爸 我是個同志
And I go dad, I'm gay!

765
01:25:49,244 --> 01:25:51,713
天吶 你可不能錯過他當時的臉色
God, you shouldda seen him.

766
01:25:51,714 --> 01:25:54,549
我的天
God.

767
01:25:54,550 --> 01:25:58,051
他怒火中燒 憤怒無比
He was so pissed, he was so pissed.

768
01:25:59,521 --> 01:26:04,559
他沒收了我的車我的手機
He took away my car and my phone

769
01:26:04,560 --> 01:26:09,095
我的反應是 爸爸 那我現在可怎么上班
and I'm all like dad, how am I supposed to get to work now?

770
01:26:11,866 --> 01:26:13,066
天吶
God.

771
01:26:14,369 --> 01:26:18,740
偽裝成同志真是正中他的下懷 
Pretending I'm gay just to get to him, you know?

772
01:26:18,741 --> 01:26:21,208
理所當然的 我被炒了
So of course I got fired.

773
01:26:22,410 --> 01:26:25,011
我就在那里工作了一周
I only worked there a week.

774
01:26:25,647 --> 01:26:29,783
從那里后 直到大學畢業我才找到工作
And I didn't get a job until after college.

775
01:26:34,623 --> 01:26:36,658
而且如果不是他走的后門
I wouldn't even have gotten

776
01:26:36,659 --> 01:26:39,826
我也不可能找到
in if it wasn't for the strings he pulled.

777
01:26:44,566 --> 01:26:46,933
現在我在他手下工作
Now I'm workin' for him.

778
01:26:53,608 --> 01:26:55,008
天吶
Man.

779
01:27:01,316 --> 01:27:04,618
也許過去的那些并不值當
Maybe it wasn't worth it, you know?

780
01:27:07,555 --> 01:27:09,155
真的
Maybe it' wasn't.

781
01:27:19,634 --> 01:27:21,034
上帝啊
God.

782
01:27:39,787 --> 01:27:41,821
父親 求你救救我
Dad, please help me!

783
01:27:46,327 --> 01:27:47,961
求你
Please help me!

784
01:27:50,531 --> 01:27:53,099
我想回家
I want to go home.

785
01:27:56,938 --> 01:27:59,005
我想回家
I want to go home.

786
01:28:25,533 --> 01:28:27,233
我真的想回家
I wanna go home.

787
01:28:28,636 --> 01:28:30,303
真的
I want to go home.

788
01:29:40,842 --> 01:29:42,976
我還沒死 沃爾夫
I'm still alive wolf.

789
01:29:44,112 --> 01:29:45,945
我還在這
I'm still here.

790
01:29:47,915 --> 01:29:49,115
萊斯特
Les.

791
01:29:50,385 --> 01:29:53,186
她朝我肋骨上開了一槍 我告訴你
She did a number on my ribs, I'll tell you what.

792
01:29:54,823 --> 01:29:57,323
我現在呼吸困難
Breathin' gettin' hard.

793
01:29:58,793 --> 01:30:00,860
你在聽嗎
Did you hear me?

794
01:30:02,897 --> 01:30:06,634
你知道西奧多羅斯福嗎
You know about Theodore Roosevelt?

795
01:30:06,635 --> 01:30:08,334
我在聽
I'm listening.

796
01:30:09,971 --> 01:30:13,875
美國第26屆總統
26th president of these United States.

797
01:30:13,876 --> 01:30:17,011
他在巴拿馬開辟了一條隧道
He carved the canal at Panama.

798
01:30:17,012 --> 01:30:19,547
在圣胡安山
Charged San Juan hill.

799
01:30:19,548 --> 01:30:21,314
他是人中王者
He was a man's man.

800
01:30:22,717 --> 01:30:25,351
你知道他說過什么嗎 萊斯特
You know what he said, les?

801
01:30:25,620 --> 01:30:29,123
他說如果沒有在荒野生存的經歷
He said if it weren't for the time he spent in the wilderness,

802
01:30:29,124 --> 01:30:33,928
他不會擁有成為總統的勇氣
he'd never had the courage to become president.

803
01:30:33,929 --> 01:30:37,731
大自然沒有將他擊倒
And mother nature couldn't even kill him.

804
01:30:38,599 --> 01:30:42,202
就是說死亡只能讓他長眠
It was said death had to take him sleepin',

805
01:30:43,104 --> 01:30:46,106
不然他還可以奮力一搏
'cause otherwise he wouldda put up a fight.

806
01:30:52,980 --> 01:30:56,416
這又說明什么呢
And what's this supposed to teach me?

807
01:30:57,919 --> 01:31:00,186
你使我想起了他
You remind me of 'im.

808
01:31:01,022 --> 01:31:05,092
大自然同樣沒有將你打倒
It seems mother nature ain't gonna kill you, neither.

809
01:31:05,093 --> 01:31:07,894
你曾兩次從死亡邊緣爬回
You crawled back twice now.

810
01:31:08,696 --> 01:31:12,934
這是常人所無法匹敵的
That's more than most folks would ever do.

811
01:31:12,935 --> 01:31:18,371
我想是時候順路拜訪你一下了
I figure it's best time I come around, stop in for a visit.

812
01:31:21,709 --> 01:31:25,145
你這是在嚇唬我嗎 沃爾夫
Is that supposed to scare me, wolf?

813
01:31:27,014 --> 01:31:30,917
為什么你拼盡全力只為悲慘謀生
Why's you fightin' so hard for such a miserable life?

814
01:31:44,732 --> 01:31:48,034
因為我的生命才剛剛開始
Because I just started living it.

815
01:33:04,011 --> 01:33:07,347
好吧 萊斯特 你可以來找我了
Well Lester, you can ambush me.

816
01:36:04,825 --> 01:36:06,803
萊斯特 我以為
Now Lester, I thought after all

817
01:36:06,804 --> 01:36:09,930
經歷了種種 你會更有戰斗力
you'd been through, you'd put up more of a fight.

818
01:36:09,931 --> 01:36:12,265
真令人失望
What a disappointment.

819
01:36:51,540 --> 01:36:54,407
你逃到天邊也沒用的 孩子
Runnin' ain't gonna save you, boy!

