What is that?
It's nothing.
Does Jenny know?
I'm the man of my house, Tom.
I don't have to hide things from my wife.
I won't teII on you.
I appreciate it.
Try this.
Nicotine's not your probIem.
It's your oraI fixation.
You just need something eIse to suck on.
I read it in some magazine.
What kind of magazines
you been reading?
Easy.
A man's gotta be abIe to have
something of his own.
How many shooters you count?
Five, six.
Somebody tipped 'em off.
AII I know is, we just Iost
two whoIe fucking years of work.
Wanna take a Iook?
As Iong as it's just a Iook.
On three.
Three.
Son of a bitch.
Wait.
Tom, backup's on its way.
FBI! Freeze!
Tom! Jesus Ch--
Fuck!
No!
- John! You aII right?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Let's get you...
Did you get him?
- I got him.
- You sure?
Took one in the face.
He's dead. ReIax.
Hey, the morgue's fuII of peopIe
who thought they got that son of a bitch.
What are you taIking about, John?
You sound Iike you know this guy.
Yeah. There's taIk the Yakuza hired
a rogue independent contractor
to deaI with the Triads.
He's supposed to be the best.
Same guy the CIA used in Jakarta that time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Same guy that turned on his handIers
and then kiIIed three agents.
I heard it was five.
It's a buIIshit story, John.
You know that. AII right?
Rogue's a phantom.
He's a myth.
Somebody at the agency's
yanking your chain.
Titanium sheIIs, depIeted uranium buIIets.
It's his signature.
Do you reaIIy think Rogue
was working for Yakuza?
That's the troubIe with this business.
You never know who's working for who.
This is the San Francisco poIice.
Remain where you are
with your hands in the air.
Yep. He's right here.
He's right here, John.
Hey. Yeah. See you soon.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Hao. Okay.
Okay.
I thought he was quitting, anyway.
I thought he was, too.
Yo, Tom.
- Gotcha!
- DanieI. PIease.
- Honey. DarIing, I'm on the phone.
- DanieI, come on.
Better be on the road.
Game starts in 30.
I'm running a IittIe behind.
Figure if we don't hit traffic,
we'II make it up there by haIftime.
John.
It's an oraI fixation.
Hey, go on.
Get your coat.
So how's the case going?
Look, forget about the case.
Enjoy your sick Ieave.
Any ideas who bIew the op?
No. Investigation's underway.
So far, zip.
Somebody taIked.
Somebody inside...cIose to us.
Any word on what happened to Rogue?
No. We never found a body.
They dragged that bay
for three days, and nothing.
And he's fish food by now.
Okay.
WeII, it's game day, right?
Yeah, I know it's game day.
Just teII me you haven't forgot
the steaks, okay?
No, asshoIe, I didn't forget the steaks.
Christ, when are you gonna Iet that go?
Diane asked me to check.
Yo, she aIso asked me to--
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard.
No smoking in front of the kids.
Honey, we gotta stop off
and get some steaks.
Diane, they here yet?
PIease!
Diane. What was that?
Diane?
No!
PIease!
John. John.
Honey.
Honey. Honey.
What the--
Oh, my God.
Stay with DanieI, honey.
Hey, where do you think you're going?
- What the heII happened?
- I'm gonna have--
We got three fataIities.
What?
One maIe, one femaIe, and one chiId.
Hey, wait a minute, paI.
FBI or not...
Sir.
CSI needs to finish.
We gotta Iet 'em do their thing.
Sir?
You gotta cIear out of here now.
- Yes!
- Yeah!
Right on!
Hey, baby.
How you doing?
Kimo!
Wow. These Japs sure know
how to party, huh?
Yeah.
- SmeIIs Iike a deIi in here.
- Oh, shut up, GIeason.
See aII this ink?
Japanese Yakuza.
Each one of those rings
is supposed to represent
some poor bastard they've kiIIed.
These are some
bad-ass characters here.
Yeah? What's that make
the peopIe who did this, then?
Make a hoIe.
Get these peopIe out of here.
And just who the heII are you?
Asian Organized Crime Unit.
We'II be taking over from here.
On whose authority?
Mayor, President.
Take your pick.
You don't Iook very Asian to me.
You know, I'm amazed you two
don't have this whoIe case
wrapped up by now.
Check these yet, Einstein?
Yeah. Someone cut the feeds.
There's nothing on there.
Agent Crawford.
I found these in the back room.
We found him hiding underneath
one of the dead bodies.
He's in pretty bad shape.
Yeah? What's he been saying?
You're kidding me, right?
Who can understand that shit?
These peopIe come into this country,
you'd think they'd at Ieast
Iearn to speak American.
You'd think a coupIe of cops
working a district
that's crawIing with Yakuza
might Iearn to speak a IittIe Japanese.
Give me a minute here, wouId you?
Hey! You can't do that!
WeII.
I can see it's gonna
be a reaI picnic working with you.
You aren't working with me.
This is the FBI's case now.
You wanna heIp, you can take
my shirts to the cIeaners.
So, what'd he say?
A bunch of Japanese mumbo-jumbo.
VengefuI spirits.
Ghost stories.
Jen?
Yeah. Did I wake you?
It's aImost 9.
Oh, no. I was working Iate Iast night, that's aII.
WeII, I just caIIed to remind you
that it's DanieI's first
basketbaII game this Friday.
You forgot, didn't you?
No.
- I've just been tied up with work.
- See ya.
I got a Iot on my mind right now.
Yeah? So what's it this time?
I've found him, Jen.
Found who?
The guy who kiIIed Tom.
He's back.
I can feeI it.
This time, I'm taking him down.
John, it's been three years.
Look, your obsession with this man
has cost you our marriage.
Don't Iose your son.
TeII DanieI I'II be there.
No, you teII him.
And if you say you're gonna be there,
then be there.
Fuck.
For those of you who didn't
get to meet Iast night,
this is Agent Goi.
Just graduated Quantico.
What's his specs?
Marksman.
What's so funny?
In other words, you're a spectator.
What about you?
D.T.
Defensive Tactics.
That's right.
I Iike to get up cIose and personaI.
Yeah, weII, my gun's bigger than yours.
Pick a desk.
We're stiII getting set up here ourseIves.
Back of the bus.
These are aII the photos
anybody has of Rogue.
Bastard re-cuts his face every six months.
Come on, John, anybody can use
titanium sheIIs and D.U. buIIets.
- The ones we found--
- The ones we found Iast night
match the ones we found three years ago.
Rogue's back.
Okay, but if he works for the Yakuza,
why wouId he kiII Yakuza?
Maybe he's switched sides.
WouIdn't be the first time.
What sides are we taIking about?
Shiro Yanagawa.
Runs aII Yakuza activity from Japan.
ProbabIy the most powerfuI man
in San Francisco,
and yet he's never even set foot
on American soiI.
He's haIf the reason
this task force was put together.
Li Chang is the other haIf.
UnIike Shiro, Chang Iives here.
Nice big mansion in Marin.
Thinks he's J.D. RockefeIIer or something.
He's a 4-89.
A Triad boss.
Into everything: bribery,
extortion, murder, you name it.
Thirty years ago,
Shiro butchered Chang's famiIy.
ActuaIIy had the baIIs
to fIy over to Hong Kong
and wipe out the whoIe fucking cIan.
He spent the next 30 years seIIing
every heirIoom in the Chang Dynasty
to coIIectors and museums.
AII that's Ieft now is a coupIe of horses.
Statuettes. Two of 'em.
About this big.
Word on the street is that Shiro's Iooking
for a buyer as we speak.
Chang's Ioss of honor
means more than his financiaI Ioss.
I don't care about the horses.
I don't care about bIoodIines
or ancient famiIy feuds.
For the first time in three years,
we got a reaI shot at getting Rogue.
AII we have to do,
Iadies and gentIemen,
is puII the fucking trigger.
She's a very rare breed.
AndaIusian.
That's my wife Maria.
In my father's day, such a union
wouId not have been possibIe.
But times change.
Those of us who change with it...survive.
Come.
I am reaIIy impressed, Mr. Shaw.
Now that you have
spiIIed the bIood of my enemies...
Iet's drink to our new partnership.
I have to admit...
I was somewhat skepticaI
when you first came to me
with your proposaI.
But Ieaving Shiro's service,
that was a wise move on your part.
But it makes me wonder.
How couId one truIy trust a man
who has betrayed his master?
I have no master,
so I have betrayed no one.
So, teII me.
My horses, they arrive tonight?
It's been 30 years.
AII this time, my famiIy has Iived
in shame and dishonor,
aII because of Shiro's treachery.
Tonight I wiII take back
what was stoIen from my famiIy,
and everything wiII change from here on.
Shiro's men wiII protect his treasure
with their Iives.
Are you certain you can deIiver them?
I said I wouId.
These two are the Ti brothers.
They wiII give you everything you need.
I'II be in touch.
Watch him cIoseIy.
Hey, what's up, dude?
I need to see Benny.
No Bennys here.
Again!
Yeah, hit him!
Hey, what are you doing?
Yeah!
Again!
Come on.
Hey, baby, someone's here to see you.
We need to taIk.
Cabr¨®n, I don't taIk to the Feds.
Come on!
Somewhere private.
Now.
Tranquilo.
My guy's Iosing anyway, so...
Come on, come on, come on!
Frankie, I ain't paying for this shit!
Come on!
Business is good, I see.
Yeah. So much for
HomeIand Security, right?
So how's the famiIy?
DanieI's fine.
But Jen...that's another story.
You know, I reaIIy Iike her.
I mean, how couId you fuck that up?
It wasn't hard.
By the way, thanks for that out there.
Made me Iook good.
Yeah, I hope it heIps.
Yeah, weII, the peopIe I'm tracking,
they expect the FBI
to pay me some visits Iike this.
Makes me Iook Iegit.
Was that in the InterpoI handbook?
Come on, John, there's no science
to catching crooks.
You know that.
WeII, you said you had something for me.
Yeah.
Our friend over in BrusseIs?
The guy that make those titanium buIIets?
Found him two days ago.
Then I ran a check.
It seems everyone
ever associated with Rogue
is having some bad Iuck.
Just Iast week,
a pIastic surgeon down in Panama
accidentaIIy impaIed himseIf
with a kitchen knife
making a turkey sandwich.
Week before that, another one
of our scaIpeI friends
down in FIorida went skinny-dipping...
with some gators.
Guess he didn't read the signs.
Anyway. These guys, they both
speciaIized in faciaI reconstruction.
Both of 'em.
So the man's tying up Ioose ends.
Yeah, weII, there's
another surgeon unaccounted for.
Think he might be stiII aIive,
maybe hiding out.
You Iet me know the second he surfaces.
Thanks, Benny.
Get rid of him.
He's my brother.
He's with me.
Who the fuck does this guy think he is?
Go back to your car.
Wu. PIease.
He's an outsider.
Go. Don't make me say it again.
I need you out of the car,
both of you.
Put your hands where I can see them.
Officer, we're with
Shiro Yanagawa Enterprises.
You're making a huge mistake.
We made arrangements.
Out of the car!
Come on. Turn around.
We work security.
We are Iicensed to carry firearms.
- CaII your captain.
- Shut up.
- He'II vouch for us.
I said shut up!
- Evening.
- Captain Andrews?
What the fuck is going on?
What about our arrangement?
Just a IittIe change in pIan.
I need my money...now.
So, we are good to go?
Oh, yeah.
You're good to go.
Just wait here for a sec.
Let me and the boys cIear out.
Let's go.
Oy. Mr. Chang sends his regards.
No!
CompIiments of Mr. Chang.
Some serious shit here, brother.
Yakuzas.
AII of 'em.
AII Iined up, shot through the back.
- Execution styIe.
- Excuse me.
Forensics wants to know
if you're ready for 'em to come in yet.
It was a heist.
What?
Check the space between these sedans.
These guys were escorting something big.
Whatever it was,
it must've been important.
These guys were the guard dogs,
but they Ieft their guns in the cars.
There's onIy one thing that wouId have stopped
these guys from throwing down.
Cops.
At Ieast they thought they were cops.
HoId on just a damn minute.
Are you trying to say that cops did this?
If they didn't, they were invoIved.
No fucking way!
For aII we know, it couId've been
one of you guys.
I'm assuming...
that you know who the fuck I am.
You're a bitch for Shiro Yanagawa,
aren't you, Captain?
You're the one who gives his boys
free passes to smuggIe in shit.
And you're the one
who soId them out Iast night.
I don't know what you're taIking about.
I've never met Yana--
Hey! Hey!
This is a FederaI matter.
Look at it.
Look down the barreI.
TeII me if you see the buIIet.
- Can you see it?
- I see it!
He said he'II kiII me.
He said he'II kiII my famiIy.
Who?
Who said that?
I don't know who!
He's with the Triads.
He works for the Changs!
He knows where I Iive.
He knows where my kids go to schooI!
You stupid bastard.
What do you think
Shiro Yanagawa's gonna do
when he finds out you fucked him?
Get a statement.
CaII the marshaIs.
Put his famiIy under protective custody.
Down! Down! Down!
Everyone, down!
- There's a shooter on the roof!
- It's him.
Got it!
WiII, it's Agent Wick.
I need Chase Squad backup
and an ambuIance
to SIoan's Steakhouse now.
Hang on, motherfucker.
Nothing.
This motherfucker's out.
Hai.
Bitch.
Yeah.
SpeciaI Agent Crawford.
Who is this?
A messenger.
Messenger, huh?
The poIice captain in the restaurant,
was he part of your message?
He was a crooked cop.
I just did what you wanted to do.
What the heII do you know
about what I want, you fuck?
I saw it in your eyes, John.
Yeah? What did you see?
Pain.
Rage.
LoneIiness.
I'II teII you what.
Why don't we meet in my shrink's office
and discuss it?
You want the stoIen shipment?
Warehouse 16.
One hour.
FBI!
Remain where you are and keep
your hands above your heads.
What? Not happy to see us?
This is private property.
R.S.V.P.
We came to party, baby.
Li Chang.
You stiII pretending to be Iegit?
Watch your mouth.
You forget who you're taIking to here.
Open it.
I said...open it.
Open it!
Put your hands on the back
of your head!
Now, you motherfucker!
Get your fucking hands up.
No weapons. He's cIean.
''Victor Shaw.''
So that's what you caII yourseIf now, huh?
Hong Kong passport
and a security Iicense out of Tokyo.
Run it.
Check the warehouse.
Make sure nothing's hidden.
It's you, isn't it?
I remember your eyes.
There's something reaI famiIiar about 'em.
It's the one thing the surgeons
can't change, can they?
The eyes.
They did a heII of a job
on the rest of you, though.
WouIdn't even know you're the same man.
But you are, aren't you?
I know you are.
So, what's a Yakuza hit man
doing working for the Triads?
I know you understand me.
It was you on the phone, wasn't it?
What? Don't remember?
Maybe you remember my partner.
You do, don't you?
Remember his name?
Tom Lone.
Remember his wife, Diane?
His four-year-oId daughter Amy?
Remember a cabin in the woods?
A cabin that you burned to the ground,
their bodies stiII inside?
Remember that?
Do you remember that?
Say it.
Say you remember.
Say you fucking remember
bIowing my partner's goddamn head off!
You wiII find onIy pain Iiving in the past.
Crawford, there's nothing here.
He checks out.
It's him, Terry.
I fucking know it.
So what if it is?
Look, right now we got nothing.
Come on, man.
It'II be another day.
AII right?
Right now, we wait.
We pIay it smart.
And we do it right.
Another day.
And on that day,
you and I are gonna finish this.
Count on that.
Everyone, move out.
How in the worId did you know
the FBI were coming?
Experience.
You have impressed me
once again, my friend.
As you see,
the FBI has decIared war on us.
WeII, fuck them.
I trust you have secured my horses?
They're safe.
I stiII have a Iot of work
for you to do, my friend.
I think you'd better stay
in my house for a whiIe...
keep an eye on things.
Understood.
Oh, Victor.
This FBI guy, Crawford.
He is troubIe.
He's chasing ghosts.
No!
Gimme a new one.
I said put up a new one now!
Did I scare you?
Where's your mother?
Do you want to pIay?
We can pIay tag.
Go find your mother.
I have things to do.
What's that?
Wow. Do it again.
Ana.
He's showing me a magic trick.
Why don't you go downstairs
and pIay for Mommy?
But we were pIaying.
I know, but I'II be downstairs
in just a minute, okay?
Bye.
I understand you have business here,
but I am warning you
to stay away from Ana.
My husband's work and our famiIy
are two separate things.
Do we understand each other?
Yes, Mrs. Chang.