Good.
Don't think I don't know what you are doing.
Mr. Chang might think
you're his man right now.
But I am stiII the one
who Iooks after things around here.
At every moment in the worId,
things change.
''Don't make me say it again,''
he fucking teIIs me.
- Do you know how much--
- ReIax.
What the fuck?
Motherfucker!
Fucking Yakuza!
Let's go!
Buddha-heads!
Fucking Yakuza!
You fucking bastard!
I knew I shouId never have trusted you.
SubtIe, ain't it?
It's got Shiro's trademark.
So what now?
Get ready for a war.
Joey Ti, got your ass.
Park, I want you outside
Chang's pIace in Marin.
DanieIs, you get Yanagawa Motors.
KinIer, you get Warehouse 16.
Wick, take Goi. Keep an eye
on the Sayu Tea House.
I get the new guy, huh?
I think I know how to Iook
through a night scope.
Eyes open, everybody.
This shit's going to go down somewhere.
Be ready to move when you get the caII.
BinocuIars.
No night scope.
The authorities are expecting us to retaIiate.
We strike now, we risk everything.
What if it was your famiIy?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You forgot?
Once it was my famiIy!
Joey was Iike a son to me.
Revenge is a must.
But you've got to Iearn to be patient.
I wiII aIIow nothing to put our famiIy at risk.
I want you to do nothing.
Is that cIear?
Shiro knows his days are coming to an end.
One thing's for sure:
more bIood wiII be spiIIed
before this is over.
Mr. Shaw, I want your word
that my wife and daughter wiII be safe.
No harm wiII come to them.
A man shouId never give up his honor.
Or the honor of his famiIy.
Keep them.
I don't smoke.
Oh, man.
I didn't know your mom was working tonight.
Keep your eye on the mark, Goi.
Yo, heads up.
Looks Iike Takada's having
a IittIe tea party, huh?
Now, that's some spicy tuna, huh?
Shit. Get Crawford and caII for backup.
It's going down now.
Crawford.
We got troubIe.
Wu just showed up, just Iike you said.
- I'm on my way.
- Copy that.
Move! Move!
Yo, going in. Cover me.
- He's dead!
- Come on!
- On three.
- What?
- Three.
- Oh, shit.
- Freeze!
- Shit!
FBI! Drop your weapons.
Drop your weapons.
Hands on the counter where I can see them!
CIose in.
Get the fuck up.
Situation secure.
AII units stand down and cease fire.
Damn it, Goi, he said cease fucking fire!
Shit.
Look. Goi's right there.
We got a shooter, guys.
I got him!
Don't fucking move.
Get the other one.
Fuck you!
In Japan...
you'd be dead.
This isn't Japan.
I said no, no, no, no.
Yes?
Wu and his boys shot up
Takada's tea house Iast night.
What?
Wu Ti?
Are you sure?
I tried to stop them.
God damn it.
I toId him not to do anything.
He Ieaves me with no choice.
You've done weII.
My father is very pIeased.
He now asks one more thing of you.
After I kiII Chang,
his operation wiII be destroyed.
What more couId Shiro want?
The heads of the wife and chiId.
Why?
That's the order.
There is no why.
You never had a probIem
kiIIing women and chiIdren before.
WouId you dare disobey your master?
I have no master.
These are my guards.
They wiII assist you in this task
as you best decide.
If I refuse?
You dropped this.
What is happening, John?
There are men with guns
in my front yard.
Just a precaution.
A precaution?
For what?
What have you gotten us into?
Oh, my God.
It's him, isn't it?
He's coming after us.
It's not gonna happen.
Oh, I'm sorry, Jen,
not just for this, for everything.
I tried to do the right thing,
make a good Iife for you and DanieI,
to give you the things you needed.
It never had anything to do
with what we did or didn't have.
It was the job.
The job aIways came first.
Even now, even knowing you might be
putting us in the same danger
Tom and his famiIy were in.
You know, I'm not even mad
at you anymore.
Most days I just feeI sorry for you
for what you've become.
It's Benny.
Say hi to Benny for me.
What you got, Benny?
We found your pIastic surgeon.
WeIcome home, Dr. Sherman.
Hey, jefe, what's cooking?
Step in here.
Let's have a taIk. Come on.
Agent Crawford? Is that--
I don't know anything, reaIIy.
I don't know anything.
Doc, come on.
You kidding me?
Can you expIain to me
why one of the worId's
most briIIiant nip-and-tuckers
is hiding out in the sIums of Mexico?
What are you,
a fucking Nazi war criminaI?
Look, I were you,
I'd be Iapping up that pussy
on South Beach, stretching it out.
Come on now.
Look, I couId give a shit about
whatever Iaws you've broken.
That's not why we're here.
I need you to identify this man.
We know what happened
to the other two doctors.
We know you couId be next.
We can protect you.
You don't know him.
Protect me?
You can't protect me.
You can't stop him.
You found me here, he can find me here.
I can stop him.
AII I need from you is a yes or a no.
Is this Rogue?
We used to get...
commissioned...
by the U.S. government,
and we aII did a Iot of surgeries
on him when he was with the CIA.
We changed his face a Iot of times.
He came to me three years ago.
His face was aImost torn off.
I just did what I couId.
I repaired the muscIe, the nerve tissue.
I reconstructed the faciaI bones.
I never saw him again.
This is what I made him Iook Iike.
Look, Doc, we're going to take you with us.
We're going to protect you, understand?
Why don't you go get
some things together and we'II go?
- Doc.
- What? Yeah.
Is it okay if I--
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Go ahead.
You beIieve in fate, Benny?
- Fate?
- Yeah.
You know, no matter what you do,
your future's aIready decided.
I don't know about that.
I aIways thought your future depends
on what choices you make.
I have made aII
the necessary arrangements.
I wiII join you as soon
as I finish here, okay?
Don't worry.
Okay. I'II be back to waIk you out.
I Iove you.
My crew's gone.
My brother is dead.
You brought it onto yourseIf.
And how did I do that?
I gave you my trust.
I gave you my IoyaIty.
I sacrificed everything for you,
and this is how I'm treated?
You've got a Iot of nerve
to taIk to me about IoyaIty.
You're a fucking traitor!
Die!
That piece of shit.
He teIIs me that he's IoyaI,
that he's my friend.
I trusted him.
He's right.
He was IoyaI.
He was your friend.
What?
HoIy shit.
AOC base from CIark.
We've got some major action
at the Chang mansion.
Mommy Ioves you, okay?
No!
Chang is dead.
And the woman and chiId?
Take me to the bodies
so I can take their heads.
No. I kiIIed them.
I shouId have that honor.
Mommy?
Keep your eyes cIosed, okay?
Where's my husband?
- Where's CIark?
- He's on his way back.
He send the photos?
Yes, sir.
What the fuck happened out there?
Looks Iike Rogue took out Chang
and turned on Shiro's assassins.
He's using them,
pIaying both sides against each other.
Why wouId he do that?
John, you're never going to beIieve
who just fIew in.
This country Iooks very beautifuI.
Your EngIish is improving.
I have been practicing.
This is my new home, after aII.
Shiro Yanagawa.
FBI SpeciaI Agent John Crawford.
WeIcome to America.
Don't unpack.
You won't be staying Iong.
Agent Crawford, I'm a busy man.
We got a Iot of business, you and me.
I think you know that.
Three years ago, Rogue kiIIed my partner
and his famiIy.
And you know what?
Rogue was working for you.
Rogue is a myth, just a rumor.
You think so, huh?
Can't aIways trust rumors, can you?
Rogue turns around and fucking sIices up
the heavy hitters you sent with him.
Now, you got to ask yourseIf--
Now, why wouId he do
something Iike that?
I've never seen this man before in my Iife.
Look, I don't care if you
fucking sIaughter each other
tiII you're aII dead and buried.
Truth is, it makes my job a Iot easier.
If I find proof that ties
any of this shit back to you,
you ain't never going
to see Japan again.
And neither wiII that pretty
IittIe daughter of yours.
Thanks for the tip, Agent Crawford.
FinaIIy, my most IoyaI stranger,
we meet face-to-face.
Yanagawa-san,
I've waited a Iong time for this moment.
It's aII because of you
that we now have this opportunity.
Kira enjoyed working with you here.
One day she wiII make a fine Ieader
of the Yanagawa cIan.
Yeah. One day.
I am reminded of the Sengoku...
when the daimyo warriors
fought each other to unite Japan,
the one who finaIIy succeeded
was a man by the name of Oda Nobunaga.
And do you know how he did it?
He kiIIed everyone who opposed him.
Thanks to you,
aII those who oppose me here are dead.
I exist but to serve you.
In Asia, these couId never be soId.
But the fortune they wiII
bring here in the West
wiII be more than enough
to continue our American expansion.
And now it is time for your reward.
Open it.
One must remove aII future threats.
You aIIowed a threat to remain
by not kiIIing the woman and chiId.
You have disobeyed me
and broken my most sacred code.
Your code, not mine.
BetrayaI cannot be forgiven.
After aII these years,
why do you do this?
You ordered the hit.
I ordered many hits.
This one was different.
You shouId have Ieft
the wife and daughter aIone.
No!
I Ieft none to seek revenge.
You Ieft one.
Your assassin, Rogue,
never made it out aIive.
So...
you're Tom Lone.
Changing your face, your voice...
aII so you couId get to me.
Pain can be a weapon,
if you so choose.
How do you think we found out
you were FBI in the first pIace?
It was Crawford.
You kiIIed my famiIy.
He's the one who gave you up.
Crawford worked for me.
Because of him, your famiIy's dead!
Somebody taIked.
Someone inside, cIose to us.
You never know
who's working for who.
Somebody taIked.
Crawford?
Shiro's dead.
Get out of this business
whiIe you can, Goi.
Crawford.
Remember the night we met?
I remember my partner
bIowing your face off.
You Iive today onIy because
of what he did.
I Iive today onIy to kiII you,
you miserabIe prick.
Meet me there.
Goi.
Where are you?
Show yourseIf!
I got your surgeon.
He made a positive I.D.
Come on, Crawford, fIush him out.
It's over, Rogue.
You hear me?
Why did you do it?
What did Shiro promise you
that was worth my Iife
or the Iives of Diane and Amy?
No.
You're not him.
It can't be.
You don't even sound Iike him.
Look at my eyes, John.
The one thing the surgeons
can never change.
Jesus, Tom.
Is it reaIIy you?
Yeah.
Why didn't you teII me?
It was the onIy way I couId
get the man responsibIe.
But aII aIong,
I never thought it wouId bring me back
to my best friend.
I didn't know they'd send Rogue.
For Christ's sakes,
I thought he was dead.
They said they wanted
to teach you a Iesson
for shooting Rogue:
just rough you up a bit, that's aII.
Is that what they toId you?
Shiro ordered everything.
I tried to stop working for him...
to get out so many times.
I thought if I couId make that son of a bitch
pay for what he did to you,
somehow it wouId make things right again.
You think you can forgive me, Tom?
Tom Lone is dead.
My name is Rogue.
No!
Shit.