1
00:00:04,045 --> 00:00:04,739
Get out!
出去！

2
00:00:07,081 --> 00:00:09,049
Get out! Hurry!
出去…快出去！

3
00:00:18,059 --> 00:00:19,117
Inside the hut! Come on!
躲进去…快点…

4
00:00:19,227 --> 00:00:20,091
Get in! Come on!
进去…快一点…

5
00:00:22,396 --> 00:00:23,328
Out of here!
出去！

6
00:00:23,431 --> 00:00:25,956
Don't come in! Get out!
不要再进来了…出去…

7
00:00:27,668 --> 00:00:29,295
Come on! Run!
快点！快跑…

8
00:00:41,449 --> 00:00:42,279
Yes, sir
是…

9
00:00:44,118 --> 00:00:46,211
Is it Mehebu Clan?
马赫坡社吗？

10
00:00:46,320 --> 00:00:47,309
Yes, sir
是…

11
00:00:50,258 --> 00:00:53,921
Aim all cannons at the Mehebu Forest
炮口全部对准马赫坡森林…

12
00:00:55,763 --> 00:00:59,631
End this battle before the sun's out
太阳出来之前结束这场战争吧！

13
00:01:04,972 --> 00:01:06,735
Tado! Kill me!
达多…

14
00:01:06,841 --> 00:01:08,968
快把我杀了！

15
00:01:09,076 --> 00:01:10,441
Come on!
快！

16
00:01:11,646 --> 00:01:13,841
It hurts so badly!
我好痛…

17
00:01:16,984 --> 00:01:18,508
Out of the way!
让开！让开…

18
00:01:20,121 --> 00:01:22,783
Cut my head off! You hear me?
把我的头砍下来听不懂啊…

19
00:01:27,328 --> 00:01:28,522
Get off him!
手拿开…

20
00:02:28,856 --> 00:02:31,222
It's beautiful
好漂亮…

21
00:02:31,859 --> 00:02:33,884
So beautiful
好漂亮啊…

22
00:02:36,897 --> 00:02:38,865
So beautiful
好漂亮啊…

23
00:02:56,550 --> 00:02:57,949
Stop firing please
请停止射击…

24
00:02:58,052 --> 00:02:59,610
They ran away
他们逃掉了…

25
00:03:32,353 --> 00:03:39,725
Fight till you drop! Seediq Bale!
战死吧！赛德克巴莱…

26
00:04:07,521 --> 00:04:09,182
Fire the cannons! Fire!
开炮！开炮！

27
00:04:11,492 --> 00:04:12,754
We're under attack!
敌人打来了…

28
00:04:20,134 --> 00:04:23,194
You damned Japanese! Get out of our territory!
可恶的日本人…滚开我们的部落…

29
00:04:32,046 --> 00:04:33,809
You bastards! Get out!
混蛋…还不快滚…

30
00:04:49,130 --> 00:04:51,928
That's one favor I did you Mehebus today
helping you drive our the intruders
今天帮你把异族人赶出马赫坡一次…

31
00:05:03,210 --> 00:05:05,337
Out of my way! Let me kill them!
前面让开…我来打！

32
00:05:34,441 --> 00:05:35,601
Temu, give me the bullets!
泰牧…把子弹给我！

33
00:05:36,777 --> 00:05:38,210
Come on! Look out!
快点…小心前面！

34
00:05:45,953 --> 00:05:46,749
Climb up there!
爬上去！

35
00:05:55,896 --> 00:05:57,523
Sine! Sine!
西奈…西奈…

36
00:05:57,631 --> 00:05:59,155
Sine!
西奈…

37
00:05:59,266 --> 00:06:03,225
Sine! Sine!
西奈…西奈…

38
00:06:03,971 --> 00:06:04,801
Stop!
站住！

39
00:06:05,773 --> 00:06:07,297
Come back here!
给我站住！

40
00:06:07,408 --> 00:06:08,272
You take care of him!
去照顾他…

41
00:06:37,838 --> 00:06:40,170
Load the guns! Come on!
装子弹！快！

42
00:06:42,810 --> 00:06:43,834
Pawan?
巴万…

43
00:07:00,160 --> 00:07:02,287
You Japanese are finished!
日本人你们完蛋了…

44
00:07:42,169 --> 00:07:44,228
Quick! - Catch him!
-快点…
-追过去！

45
00:07:44,571 --> 00:07:46,471
Off with his head!
猎下他的头！

46
00:07:46,874 --> 00:07:48,000
Stop!
不要跑…

47
00:07:53,380 --> 00:07:54,711
Don't let him slip away!
不要放过他…

48
00:08:02,423 --> 00:08:04,186
Mouna Rudo!
莫那鲁道…

49
00:08:04,925 --> 00:08:05,892
Stop running!
大家不要逃了！

50
00:08:07,428 --> 00:08:09,225
Kill until our blood runs out!
杀到血干吧…

51
00:08:09,730 --> 00:08:12,096
Cut off their heads like true warriors!
像战士一样拿下人头…

52
00:08:13,200 --> 00:08:15,634
The heavenly home of our ancestors,
here we come!
回祖灵之家唷…

53
00:10:25,866 --> 00:10:27,857
I'm a chief, not your little brother
我是头目…不是你弟弟…

54
00:10:36,543 --> 00:10:38,670
Iyung! Iyung!
伊勇…伊勇…

55
00:10:50,524 --> 00:10:52,890
Don't touch it, lyung
手不要碰…伊勇…

56
00:10:53,927 --> 00:10:54,689
Iyung!
伊勇…

57
00:10:58,732 --> 00:11:01,030
What are you doing? Move!
干什么…走开！

58
00:11:02,769 --> 00:11:04,532
Look out! It's falling down!
倒下去了…倒下去了…

59
00:11:05,706 --> 00:11:07,105
Pawan! Get out of there!
巴万！快出来！

60
00:11:08,942 --> 00:11:11,536
Pawan, get out now!
巴万…快点出来！

61
00:11:14,047 --> 00:11:14,979
Pawan!
巴万…

62
00:11:15,516 --> 00:11:17,074
Iyung! Iyung!
伊勇…伊勇…

63
00:11:17,184 --> 00:11:18,151
Are you alright?
你怎么了？

64
00:11:18,252 --> 00:11:19,981
Pawan, I've got a good gun
巴万！拿到好枪了…

65
00:11:20,888 --> 00:11:21,616
What's wrong?
怎么了？

66
00:11:23,056 --> 00:11:24,421
Batu! -Dakis!
-巴杜…
-达基司

67
00:11:26,426 --> 00:11:27,188
Move!
走开！

68
00:11:27,895 --> 00:11:28,623
Ubus!
乌布斯…

69
00:11:51,785 --> 00:11:53,753
Come on! The Japanese are out!
快…日本人跑出来了…

70
00:12:05,132 --> 00:12:06,292
Watch out over there!
小心那边！

71
00:12:14,007 --> 00:12:15,474
There's one behind him!
后面还有一个…

72
00:12:22,583 --> 00:12:23,515
Don't go there!
不要过去！

73
00:12:36,129 --> 00:12:37,289
Stop!
不要跑！

74
00:15:33,473 --> 00:15:34,940
Bomb!
炮弹！

75
00:17:36,630 --> 00:17:39,155
So you're Mouna Rudo
原来你就是莫那鲁道…

76
00:17:42,469 --> 00:17:45,905
Now I see you clearly
我看清楚你了…

77
00:17:48,942 --> 00:17:50,375
Tado, how do we dodge those cannons?
达多…

78
00:17:50,477 --> 00:17:52,342
怎样才能躲过那些大炮？

79
00:17:58,318 --> 00:17:59,842
Chief, let this ghost lead the way
头目…

80
00:17:59,953 --> 00:18:02,581
让我这个鬼魂来带路吧！

81
00:18:13,099 --> 00:18:14,726
Fire!
开炮！

82
00:19:09,522 --> 00:19:10,819
Look!
看！

83
00:19:10,924 --> 00:19:14,155
Cherry blossoms everywhere!
樱花开满天了…

84
00:20:06,345 --> 00:20:09,715
(Those who come forward voluntarily
will be spared)

85
00:20:09,715 --> 00:20:12,735
(Come to the shelters to surrender)

86
00:20:20,860 --> 00:20:25,422
l'm crossing the rainbow bridge
我要走去彼岸的那边了…

87
00:20:25,532 --> 00:20:30,367
l am Mouna Rudo
我是莫那鲁道唷！

88
00:20:30,470 --> 00:20:35,339
Look at the road l've trodden
看我脚步所迈开的道路！

89
00:20:40,113 --> 00:20:42,547
No one's ever gonna stop us
谁也无法抵挡我们…

90
00:20:42,649 --> 00:20:44,947
The determined warriors
决死的勇士啊！

91
00:20:45,051 --> 00:20:49,954
We're home with our enemy's heads
看我们今天带着首级归来了…

92
00:20:50,056 --> 00:20:55,153
We're true warriors, like budding pine leaves
像松树嫩芽般真正的勇士啊！

93
00:21:07,640 --> 00:21:10,404
You must be starved
大家都饿了吧…

94
00:21:10,510 --> 00:21:12,535
and you must be exhausted
也都累了吧！

95
00:21:13,713 --> 00:21:16,204
It's time to decide your future
是该决定自己未来的时侯了…

96
00:21:18,384 --> 00:21:21,717
If you want to take your own life, do it
想自尽的就自尽

97
00:21:21,821 --> 00:21:24,051
If you want to turn yourself in, go ahead
想投降的就投降

98
00:21:26,059 --> 00:21:28,152
If you want to keep fighting..
想继续战斗的…

99
00:21:29,596 --> 00:21:30,392
Tado..
达多…

100
00:21:32,332 --> 00:21:33,822
My dear son..
我的儿子啊…

101
00:21:36,202 --> 00:21:38,170
The hero of Mehebu Clan
马赫坡的勇者！

102
00:21:39,139 --> 00:21:42,267
Lead them to fight
until you use up all your bullets
你带他们打完最后一颗子弹吧！

103
00:21:42,375 --> 00:21:43,205
Father! -Chief..
父亲！

104
00:21:43,309 --> 00:21:44,708
头目…

105
00:21:44,811 --> 00:21:46,073
Warriors, forgive me
战士们！

106
00:21:47,147 --> 00:21:48,546
原谅我…

107
00:21:50,517 --> 00:21:51,575
Forgive me
原谅我…

108
00:21:53,753 --> 00:21:57,587
I don't want the Japanese to insult me
in front of my people
我不愿让日本人在族人面前玩弄我

109
00:21:58,424 --> 00:21:59,686
Forgive me
原谅我…

110
00:22:02,529 --> 00:22:05,589
I'll be waiting for you on the mountain peak
我到山的极巅等你们…

111
00:22:07,333 --> 00:22:10,393
Let's cross the rainbow bridge together
to the eternal hunting ground
一起回到彩虹彼端的美丽猎场…

112
00:22:14,941 --> 00:22:16,101
Father?
父亲…

113
00:22:19,979 --> 00:22:21,606
Go..Seediq Bale!
去吧！

114
00:22:21,714 --> 00:22:23,238
赛德克巴莱！

115
00:22:59,686 --> 00:23:00,675
Chief Mouna?
莫那头目…

116
00:23:02,121 --> 00:23:03,349
Bakan,
巴冈…

117
00:23:03,456 --> 00:23:07,017
bring over everyone from the chief's family
把我们家族的人都带过来…

118
00:23:07,126 --> 00:23:08,252
Iwan, go back and tell our people in the cavern
依婉…

119
00:23:08,895 --> 00:23:11,056
回去告诉岩窟的族人

120
00:23:11,164 --> 00:23:13,564
that those who don't want to surrender
may as well kill themselves
不想投降的就自尽吧！

121
00:23:13,666 --> 00:23:15,190
I want to fight!
我要去战斗…

122
00:23:15,268 --> 00:23:15,859
Me too! -It's over!
我也要去…

123
00:23:15,969 --> 00:23:17,129
结束了…

124
00:23:17,837 --> 00:23:19,031
Mouna!
莫那！

125
00:23:19,138 --> 00:23:22,539
Mouna, where's your ancestral spirit?
莫那…你的祖灵在哪里？

126
00:23:26,980 --> 00:23:29,642
Where is it?
你的祖灵在哪里…

127
00:23:33,786 --> 00:23:39,247
There could be greater suffering if you survived
我怕你们承担不住活下来…

128
00:23:56,476 --> 00:23:59,274
Wipe your face clean
…把脸擦干净

129
00:24:30,610 --> 00:24:34,410
Thank you, women and children
谢谢你们女人孩子…

130
00:24:34,514 --> 00:24:38,883
for sacrificing yourselves
to complete the men's souls
成就了部落男人的灵魂…

131
00:26:53,453 --> 00:26:56,945
She's awake!
醒来了…

132
00:26:57,056 --> 00:26:58,956
That savage woman is awake!
那个蕃女醒来了…

133
00:26:59,058 --> 00:27:01,891
Officer Kabasoa!
桦泽警部…桦泽警部…

134
00:27:03,463 --> 00:27:04,555
What's going on?
-That savage woman is awake
-怎么了？
-那个蕃女醒来了…

135
00:27:04,664 --> 00:27:06,188
Is it Mahung? -Yes, sir
-是马红吗？
-是…

136
00:27:07,400 --> 00:27:08,367
Excuse me!
不好意思…

137
00:27:09,569 --> 00:27:10,797
Excuse me!
不好意思…

138
00:27:10,903 --> 00:27:12,234
Let me through!
…借过

139
00:27:13,706 --> 00:27:16,072
Mahung! Mahung!
马红…马红…

140
00:27:18,211 --> 00:27:19,303
Mahung..
马红…

141
00:27:19,412 --> 00:27:21,539
I'm Kabasawa. I've been to your house
我是桦泽…

142
00:27:21,647 --> 00:27:24,377
我去过你们家的…

143
00:27:24,484 --> 00:27:27,044
Do you remember me, Mahung?
记得吗？马红…

144
00:27:31,357 --> 00:27:33,848
Why did you save me?
…为什么要救我？

145
00:27:35,795 --> 00:27:42,223
My husband and children are waiting for me
我的丈夫孩子都在等我啊…

146
00:27:44,871 --> 00:27:46,065
Mahong..
马红…

147
00:27:54,747 --> 00:27:55,736
100 dollars
一百块钱！

148
00:27:56,716 --> 00:27:58,843
Son of a bitch! What are you doing?
混蛋！你们干什么？

149
00:27:58,951 --> 00:28:00,111
Don't put it on the desk!
不要放在桌子上！

150
00:28:01,454 --> 00:28:02,887
What are you looking at? Next!
看什么？下一个…

151
00:28:02,989 --> 00:28:05,116
It's only a child. You can't get 100 for it
这只是孩子，哪值一百块？

152
00:28:05,224 --> 00:28:06,122
Get it off!
拿走开！

153
00:28:06,225 --> 00:28:08,625
It's Temu Mouna from Truwan Clan
这是塔罗湾的…泰牧摩那…

154
00:28:08,728 --> 00:28:10,662
What child?
Don't you see the tattoos on his face?
什么孩子，他脸上有图腾哪！

155
00:28:10,763 --> 00:28:12,697
Put it over there! What a nuisance!
拿到那边去啦，啰嗦…

156
00:28:12,798 --> 00:28:16,290
It's Tanah Robe, the Boarung chief
这是…波阿仑头目达那哈罗拜…

157
00:28:21,574 --> 00:28:24,634
One of you from Gungu Clan killed our chief
你们荷戈社杀了我们头目…

158
00:28:47,133 --> 00:28:52,730
This one is Pawan Nawi from Mehebu Clan
这是马赫坡的巴万那威…

159
00:28:55,274 --> 00:28:57,367
Ukan! Tado!
乌干…达多…

160
00:28:57,476 --> 00:29:00,172
Where are you?
你们在哪里？

161
00:29:01,547 --> 00:29:06,644
Where is that father going?
那个父亲要去哪里哪？

162
00:29:06,752 --> 00:29:12,486
The father carrying a child on his back
那个父亲背着幼小的婴孩…

163
00:29:12,592 --> 00:29:19,657
is setting out to shoot the two suns in the sky
要去征伐天上的两颗太阳了！

164
00:29:19,765 --> 00:29:25,101
They go on and on for a long way
他们走了很远很远的路

165
00:29:25,204 --> 00:29:37,844
The child grows up
那个婴孩长大成人了…

166
00:29:37,950 --> 00:29:43,513
The father dies at an old age
那个父亲老死了…

167
00:29:43,623 --> 00:29:56,434
The child takes his father's bow and arrows
孩子背起了父亲的弓箭

168
00:29:56,535 --> 00:30:02,337
The child follows his father's footsteps
孩子继续父亲的路…

169
00:30:02,441 --> 00:30:14,911
toward the rising suns
向着日出之处前进

170
00:30:15,021 --> 00:30:20,857
He gets there at last
…终于到达了呀！

171
00:30:20,960 --> 00:30:33,464
The child gets there at last
孩子终于到达了！

172
00:30:33,572 --> 00:30:39,101
The child shoots a sun down with an arrow
孩子张弓射下了一个太阳

173
00:30:39,211 --> 00:30:51,248
The sun loses its rays
太阳的光芒消失了

174
00:30:51,357 --> 00:30:56,693
The dead sun becomes the moon
死去的太阳变成了月亮

175
00:30:56,796 --> 00:31:09,573
He's a sun-shooting hero
他是射日的英雄！

176
00:31:09,675 --> 00:31:15,204
The sun-shooting hero is returning home
射日勇士又启程归乡了！

177
00:31:15,314 --> 00:31:28,717
The sun-shooting hero has come a long,
long way
射日勇士走了很远很远的路…

178
00:31:28,828 --> 00:31:34,528
The sun-shooting hero is home at last
射日勇士终于回家了！

179
00:31:34,633 --> 00:31:47,671
But the hero is already gray-headed
勇士回家已经白发苍苍…

180
00:31:53,519 --> 00:31:56,784
l am drunk today
今天的日子我醉了

181
00:31:56,889 --> 00:31:58,948
l saw him on the way
在路上我看到他了…

182
00:31:59,058 --> 00:32:00,753
The boy from the freezing winter
那个来自酷寒严冬下的男孩

183
00:32:00,860 --> 00:32:04,455
A fair-skinned boy like a budding pine leaf
如松枝嫩芽般白白的男孩

184
00:32:04,563 --> 00:32:06,463
Let's dance together
一起来跳舞吧…

185
00:32:06,565 --> 00:32:08,157
Let's enjoy ourselves
让我们尽兴欢聚吧！

186
00:32:08,267 --> 00:32:11,703
l'm drunk today
今天的日子我醉了

187
00:32:11,804 --> 00:32:15,399
Young girls, let's dance together
年轻的女孩我们一起跳舞吧…

188
00:32:17,243 --> 00:32:18,540
Surrender? Why should we surrender?
投降？

189
00:32:19,578 --> 00:32:21,341
为什么要投降呢？

190
00:32:22,848 --> 00:32:24,645
We've had our enemy's sake wine
我们几个既然喝了敌人的酒

191
00:32:25,851 --> 00:32:28,081
Doesn't that mean conciliation?
不就算和解了吗？

192
00:32:28,187 --> 00:32:30,246
Why do we have to surrender?
为什么还需要投降呢？…

193
00:32:33,993 --> 00:32:35,460
Tado... -Say no more!
-达多…
-不要再讲了！

194
00:32:41,767 --> 00:32:43,530
Come on, drink with me
来！你也喝…

195
00:32:59,919 --> 00:33:00,817
Mahung, my little sister...
马红…

196
00:33:03,355 --> 00:33:05,983
it's much easier for me to die
哥哥要求死很容易

197
00:33:07,593 --> 00:33:09,891
than for you to go on living
你们要活下去却很难…

198
00:33:11,030 --> 00:33:13,055
But you must endure
你要多忍耐…

199
00:33:14,099 --> 00:33:16,499
and have lots of children
要多生孩子…

200
00:33:19,305 --> 00:33:22,832
Teach them everything
about the pride of our father
要教他们认识我们父亲的骄傲…

201
00:33:22,942 --> 00:33:28,244
Let your children have even more children
让你的孩子们再生孩子…

202
00:33:29,381 --> 00:33:31,008
and more and more..
再生孩子…

203
00:33:32,651 --> 00:33:33,583
Mahung, have lots of children
马红…

204
00:33:34,887 --> 00:33:36,582
再生孩子…

205
00:33:42,595 --> 00:33:45,086
Raise them up to be proud Seediqs
and to live on with pride
要每个孩子都成为骄傲的赛德克

206
00:33:46,298 --> 00:33:48,095
挺起胸膛的活着…

207
00:33:50,236 --> 00:33:51,794
Do you understand?
懂吗？

208
00:33:51,904 --> 00:33:57,342
Father, Baso and I..
…我、巴索、父亲

209
00:33:58,878 --> 00:34:02,871
along with all our fallen people
和死去的族人们…

210
00:34:05,251 --> 00:34:09,688
will be watching over you
from the rainbow bridge
都会在彩虹上看着你们…

211
00:34:15,261 --> 00:34:16,250
Look! The sun is so beautiful
…你看

212
00:34:17,463 --> 00:34:20,694
阳光好美啊！

213
00:34:36,315 --> 00:34:37,509
Oh, my wife!
妻子呀！

214
00:34:38,317 --> 00:34:42,117
ls the wine ready now?
你把酒酿好了吗？…

215
00:34:42,221 --> 00:34:45,987
Here l come, my wife and children
妻儿呀！我来了唷！

216
00:34:46,091 --> 00:34:49,720
On my way to the heavenly home
of our ancestors
在通往祖灵之家的这路上

217
00:34:49,828 --> 00:34:51,523
Wait a little longer for me please
请你们稍等一会儿

218
00:34:51,630 --> 00:34:53,495
l'll be seeing you soon
我很快就赶来和你们会面了！

219
00:34:53,599 --> 00:34:57,228
We're already on our way
我们已经上路了呀…

220
00:34:57,336 --> 00:35:00,999
Oh my wife and children, wait a little longer
妻儿呀！再等一会儿吧…

221
00:35:01,106 --> 00:35:04,507
Wait for us on the way
to the heavenly home of our ancestors
在通往祖灵之家的这路上等我们

222
00:35:04,610 --> 00:35:08,273
Oh my wife and children, wait a little longer
妻儿呀！稍等一会儿…

223
00:35:08,380 --> 00:35:11,872
We're almost there
我们已经来了…我们已经来了…

224
00:35:11,984 --> 00:35:15,420
We're about to cross the road
就快要越过道路…

225
00:35:15,521 --> 00:35:18,957
We'll be seeing you in no time
我们很快就要相会了！

226
00:35:19,058 --> 00:35:22,425
Wait for us on the way
to the heavenly home of our ancestors
在通往祖灵之家的这路上等我们

227
00:35:22,528 --> 00:35:26,020
Oh my wife and children, wait a little longer
妻儿呀！稍等一会儿…

228
00:35:26,131 --> 00:35:29,430
We're almost there
我们已经来了…我们已经来了…

229
00:35:29,535 --> 00:35:32,834
We're about to cross the road
就快要越过道路…

230
00:35:32,938 --> 00:35:36,430
We'll be seeing you in no time
我们很快就要相会了！

231
00:36:19,445 --> 00:36:23,085
(Pihu Sapu was beaten up to death)

232
00:36:23,085 --> 00:36:26,855
(in the detention house after he got caught)

233
00:36:39,705 --> 00:36:45,465
(Tado Mouna and the last surviving warriors
all committed suicide )

234
00:36:52,515 --> 00:36:56,675
(Mouna Rudo disappeared without a trace )

235
00:37:24,116 --> 00:37:31,648
300 warriors against thousands of soldiers
三百名战士抵抗数千名大军

236
00:37:31,757 --> 00:37:34,749
Those survived the battle
killed themselves eventually
不战死便自尽…

237
00:37:38,497 --> 00:37:46,233
Why did I see
in such a remote mountain area in Taiwan
为何我会在这遥远的台湾山地

238
00:37:46,338 --> 00:37:55,576
the bushido of samurais
that died over a century ago in Japan?
见到我们已经消失百年的武士精神？

239
00:37:59,351 --> 00:38:09,283
Is it because the cherry blossoms here
are far too red?
是这里的樱花开得太艳红了吗？

240
00:38:10,295 --> 00:38:11,489
No, these flowers have bloomed early this year
不！

241
00:38:12,564 --> 00:38:15,032
今年的花开早了…

242
00:38:18,370 --> 00:38:21,032
It isn't the season of cherry blossoms yet
现在不应该是樱花的季节…

243
00:38:40,685 --> 00:38:43,595
(After the incident...)

244
00:38:43,595 --> 00:38:46,365
(Kojima Genji instigated the Seediqs
from Toda)

245
00:38:46,365 --> 00:38:48,995
(to revenge the death of their chief
Temu Walis )

246
00:38:48,995 --> 00:38:51,735
(by killing all the remaining
defenseless tribesmen)

247
00:38:51,735 --> 00:38:54,365
(staying in the shelter during the night)

248
00:38:59,611 --> 00:39:00,873
Out of the way!
前面让开！

249
00:39:00,979 --> 00:39:03,607
(The few surviving tribesmen were forced)
Hurry up!
快一点！

250
00:39:03,645 --> 00:39:05,545
(to relocate to a compound along
Peikang River)

251
00:39:05,551 --> 00:39:06,144
(to relocate to a compound along
Peikang River)
Out of the way!
前面让开！

252
00:39:06,145 --> 00:39:07,015
(where the Japanese
could monitor them easily )
Out of the way!

253
00:39:07,015 --> 00:39:08,715
(where the Japanese
could monitor them easily )

254
00:39:08,715 --> 00:39:11,385
(They burned down all their remaining houses )

255
00:39:11,385 --> 00:39:13,815
(before they left)

256
00:39:35,505 --> 00:39:40,875
(Four years later...)

257
00:40:49,215 --> 00:40:53,225
(Mouna Rudo's remains were found)

258
00:40:53,225 --> 00:40:57,355
(inside a cavern,
somewhere deep in the mountains )

259
00:41:00,365 --> 00:41:02,495
(Half of his body rotted to skeleton)

260
00:41:02,495 --> 00:41:07,625
(while the other half
was weathered to a mummy )

261
00:41:09,175 --> 00:41:11,175
(In the following year...)

262
00:41:11,175 --> 00:41:13,975
(the Japanese publicly displayed
his remains and weapons )

263
00:41:13,975 --> 00:41:16,745
(in a wooden crate at the exhibition
celebrating the completion)

264
00:41:16,745 --> 00:41:18,983
(of Nenggao City Hall construction project)

265
00:41:18,984 --> 00:41:19,984
Ah, it's for real
(of Nenggao City Hall construction project)
啊~真的啊！

266
00:41:19,985 --> 00:41:22,315
Ah, it's for real

267
00:41:22,315 --> 00:41:24,789
Ah, it's for real
(After that,
his remains disappeared once again)

268
00:41:24,790 --> 00:41:29,284
l'll be arriving soon
(After that,
his remains disappeared once again)
我即将要到达…

269
00:41:29,394 --> 00:41:29,424
l'll be arriving soon
到达祖灵之家！

270
00:41:29,425 --> 00:41:34,325
at the heavenly home of our ancestors

271
00:41:34,399 --> 00:41:39,928
Yes, it's for real
真的…是真的！

272
00:41:40,872 --> 00:41:46,367
Reminisce the people from the past
怀念过去的人们啊

273
00:41:46,478 --> 00:41:47,344
Here l am
我来到这里

274
00:41:47,345 --> 00:41:49,875
Here l am
(After the second disappearance )

275
00:41:49,875 --> 00:41:51,949
Here l am
(Mouna Rudo's remains
were recovered 39 years later)

276
00:41:51,950 --> 00:41:52,314
l used to guard
these mountains and forests bravely
(Mouna Rudo's remains
were recovered 39 years later)
我曾英勇守护的山林…

277
00:41:52,315 --> 00:41:54,685
l used to guard
these mountains and forests bravely
(in the specimen room
of the College of Medicine )

278
00:41:54,685 --> 00:41:57,175
l used to guard
these mountains and forests bravely
(in National Taiwan University )

279
00:41:57,255 --> 00:42:00,724
These are our mountains
这是我们的山唷…

280
00:42:00,725 --> 00:42:02,426
Escorted by his offspring)
These are our mountains

281
00:42:02,427 --> 00:42:03,924
These are our creeks
(Escorted by his offspring)
这是我们的溪唷…

282
00:42:03,925 --> 00:42:07,565
These are our creeks
(after 43 years, he finally returned
to his hometown Wushe )

283
00:42:07,566 --> 00:42:07,824
We're the true Seediq Bale
(after 43 years, he finally returned
to his hometown Wushe )
我们是真正的赛德克巴莱唷…

284
00:42:07,825 --> 00:42:11,065
We're the true Seediq Bale
(to be buried properly )

285
00:42:11,065 --> 00:42:12,965
We're the true Seediq Bale

286
00:42:13,038 --> 00:42:18,340
We go hunting in the mountains
我们在山里追猎…

287
00:42:18,443 --> 00:42:23,574
We share food in our clan
我们在部落里分享

288
00:42:23,682 --> 00:42:29,211
We fetch water from the creeks
我们在溪流里取水…

289
00:42:29,321 --> 00:42:34,088
l'm willing to give my life for these
愿我为此献出我的生命…

290
00:42:34,192 --> 00:42:39,289
Oh, creek! Be quiet!
溪流啊！不要再吵了…

291
00:42:39,398 --> 00:42:44,426
Sisin babblers are singing
祖灵鸟在唱歌了…

292
00:42:44,536 --> 00:42:49,473
Sing us a beautiful song please
请唱首好听的歌吧！

293
00:42:49,574 --> 00:42:54,534
Sing for our people
为我们的族人唱…

294
00:42:54,646 --> 00:42:59,606
a song of our ancestral spirit
来自祖灵的歌…

295
00:42:59,718 --> 00:43:04,655
(List of Angel Fund contributors)
l'm willing to give my life too
愿我也献出我的生命…

296
00:43:04,756 --> 00:43:09,750
(List of Angel Fund contributors)
When the lightening rifts the rock
巨石雷光下

297
00:43:09,861 --> 00:43:14,764
a rainbow appears
彩虹出现了…

298
00:43:14,866 --> 00:43:19,735
and a proud man emerges
有一个人走来了…

299
00:43:19,838 --> 00:43:24,741
A proud man emerges
一个骄傲的人走来了…

300
00:43:24,843 --> 00:43:29,746
Who is this man so proud?
是谁如此骄傲啊？

301
00:43:29,848 --> 00:43:34,717
lt's your offspring
是你的子孙啊…

302
00:43:34,820 --> 00:43:44,218
A Seediq Bale
赛德克巴莱！

303
00:43:53,939 --> 00:43:55,907
Once upon a time on Mt. White Stone
there was a big tree called Pusu Qhuni
从前从前在白石山上…

304
00:43:56,007 --> 00:44:01,172
有一棵大树，名叫波索康夫尼…

305
00:44:01,279 --> 00:44:02,746
The tree trunk was half wood, half stone
他的树身…

306
00:44:02,848 --> 00:44:06,944
一半是木头，另一半是岩石…

307
00:44:07,052 --> 00:44:14,185
One day, a boy and a girl were born
from the tree trunk
有一天，他的树身生下了一男一女

308
00:44:14,292 --> 00:44:17,193
Then the couple gave birth to lots of children
后来这男女又生下了许多的孩子…

309
00:44:17,295 --> 00:44:21,664
and here we are, the Seediq Bale
就是我们…真正的赛德克人…

310
00:45:05,577 --> 00:45:18,217
Behold! The beautiful rainbow over the hilltop
你们看！美丽的彩虹，在山的那一头！

311
00:45:18,323 --> 00:45:25,058
My wife and children,
have you brewed the wine?
妻儿呀！你们把酒酿好了吗？

312
00:45:25,163 --> 00:45:37,405
Drink it!
The wine we offer to our ancestors' spirits
喝吧！献给祖灵的酒！

313
00:45:37,509 --> 00:45:50,252
Behold! What beautiful rainbow!
My ancestors are calling me
你们看！美丽的彩虹
是祖先在召唤我了！

314
00:45:50,355 --> 00:45:57,488
My wife and children! Are you on your way
to meet our ancestors spirits?
妻儿呀！你们在通往祖灵的路上了吗？

315
00:45:57,596 --> 00:46:06,265
We should get going too
我们也该上路了

316
00:46:06,371 --> 00:46:19,182
Stand still,
our people who keep the bloodline going
必须延续生命的族人呀！挺起胸膛！

317
00:46:19,284 --> 00:46:25,553
We will be proud like a true Seediq
要骄傲得像个真正的赛德克

318
00:46:25,657 --> 00:46:35,328
Our bodiless spirits will be watching over you
from the rainbow bridge
我们死去的灵魂会在彩虹桥上看着你们

319
00:46:35,433 --> 00:46:47,937
Tell every child to live on forever
告诉每个孩子，生生不息！

320
00:46:48,046 --> 00:46:54,576
To live on like a true Seediq
要活得像个真正的赛德克

321
00:46:54,686 --> 00:47:04,220
Our bodiless spirits
will keep you company in the woods
我们死去的灵魂会在山林里头陪着你们

322
00:47:13,605 --> 00:47:26,245
Behold! What beautiful rainbow!
My ancestors are calling me
你们看！美丽的彩虹
是祖先在召唤我了！

323
00:47:26,351 --> 00:47:33,519
My wife and children! Are you on your way
to meet our ancestors spirits?
妻儿呀！你们在通往祖灵的路上了吗？

324
00:47:33,625 --> 00:47:42,533
We should be on our way too
我们也该上路了

325
00:47:42,634 --> 00:47:55,013
Stand still,
our people who keep the bloodline going
必须延续生命的族人呀！挺起胸膛！

326
00:47:55,113 --> 00:48:01,814
We will be proud like a true Seediq
要骄傲得像个真正的赛德克

327
00:48:01,920 --> 00:48:10,988
Our bodiless spirits will be watching over you
from the rainbow bridge
我们死去的灵魂会在彩虹桥上看着你们

328
00:48:11,096 --> 00:48:23,873
Tell every child to live on forever
告诉每个孩子，生生不息！

329
00:48:23,975 --> 00:48:30,403
To live on like a true Seediq
活得像个真正的赛德克

330
00:48:30,515 --> 00:48:38,422
Our bodiless spirits
will keep you company in the woods
我们死去的灵魂会在山林里头陪着你们

331
00:48:44,129 --> 00:48:49,897
Look! -Drink! Drink!
-你们看～
-喝吧！喝吧！

332
00:48:50,001 --> 00:48:57,203
What a beautiful sky!
-We should be on our way
-多美丽的天空呀～
-我们该上路了！

333
00:48:57,308 --> 00:49:02,712
Look! -Drink! Drink!
-你们看～
-喝吧！喝吧！

334
00:49:02,814 --> 00:49:11,813
What a beautiful sky!
-We should be on our way
-多美丽的天空呀～
-我们该上路了！

335
00:49:46,024 --> 00:49:52,327
Children!
孩子们！

336
00:49:52,430 --> 00:49:58,767
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
看见了吧！看见彩虹了唷！

337
00:49:58,870 --> 00:50:05,173
Children!
孩子们！

338
00:50:05,276 --> 00:50:11,146
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
看见了吧！看见彩虹了唷！

339
00:50:11,249 --> 00:50:18,052
Children!
孩子们！

340
00:50:18,156 --> 00:50:24,356
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
看见了吧！看见彩虹了唷！

341
00:50:24,462 --> 00:50:30,799
Children!
孩子们！

342
00:50:30,902 --> 00:50:37,137
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
看见了吧！看见彩虹了唷！

343
00:50:37,242 --> 00:50:43,511
Children!
孩子们！

344
00:50:43,615 --> 00:50:50,020
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
看见了吧！看见彩虹了唷！

345
00:50:50,121 --> 00:50:56,321
Children!
孩子们！

346
00:50:56,427 --> 00:51:02,730
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
看见了吧！看见彩虹了唷！

347
00:51:02,834 --> 00:51:10,104
We see the rainbow
看见彩虹了唷！
