1
00:00:01,749 --> 00:00:01,942
-

2
00:00:01,942 --> 00:00:02,135
-=

3
00:00:02,135 --> 00:00:02,328
-= L

4
00:00:02,328 --> 00:00:02,521
-= LU

5
00:00:02,521 --> 00:00:02,714
-= LUO

6
00:00:02,714 --> 00:00:02,907
-= LUO M

7
00:00:02,907 --> 00:00:03,100
-= LUO MA

8
00:00:03,100 --> 00:00:03,293
-= LUO MAD

9
00:00:03,293 --> 00:00:03,486
-= LUO MADE

10
00:00:03,486 --> 00:00:03,679
-= LUO MADE D

11
00:00:03,679 --> 00:00:03,872
-= LUO MADE DV

12
00:00:03,872 --> 00:00:04,065
-= LUO MADE DVD

13
00:00:04,065 --> 00:00:04,258
-= LUO MADE DVD =

14
00:00:04,258 --> 00:00:04,451
-= LUO MADE DVD =-

15
00:00:04,451 --> 00:00:11,644
-= LUO MADE DVD =-

1
00:00:12,176 --> 00:00:32,514
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
(你们摸摸看，你们染血的双手)

2
00:00:34,258 --> 00:00:37,361
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)

3
00:00:37,361 --> 00:00:39,363
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
You've soiled me with blood
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
看你把我弄得都是血了…

4
00:00:39,363 --> 00:00:41,632
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)

5
00:00:41,632 --> 00:00:42,867
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Be still!
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
排个队动来动去

6
00:00:42,867 --> 00:00:45,269
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Get out!
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
出去！出去！

7
00:00:45,269 --> 00:00:47,271
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Who the hell let you in?
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
谁跟你说可以进来的

8
00:00:47,271 --> 00:00:49,907
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Don't you know
this is the Mehebu hunting ground?
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
你不知道这是我马赫坡的猎场吗？

9
00:00:49,907 --> 00:00:50,341
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
I don't care if it's your hunting ground or theirs
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)

10
00:00:50,341 --> 00:00:54,979
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
because everything here
belongs to us Japanese now
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
什么你的猎场，我的猎场？
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)
全部都是我们日本人的！

11
00:00:54,979 --> 00:00:57,148
I hate the Japanese no less than you do
because everything here
belongs to us Japanese now
全部都是我们日本人的！
我对日本人的仇恨

12
00:00:57,148 --> 00:00:58,516
(Touch your angry forehead)
I hate the Japanese no less than you do
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)
我对日本人的仇恨

13
00:00:58,516 --> 00:01:02,286
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)
不会少于你们…

14
00:01:02,286 --> 00:01:05,590
(Touch your angry forehead)
But do you realize that
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)
只是你们知道行动之后…

15
00:01:05,590 --> 00:01:09,026
(Touch your angry forehead)
we're going to die after all this
and all our people will be wiped out?
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)
我们一定会死…甚至灭族吗？

16
00:01:09,026 --> 00:01:10,695
(Touch your angry forehead)
Mouna, you must keep the intruders
away from our clan
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)
莫那…

17
00:01:10,695 --> 00:01:17,301
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)
千万不能让异族人进到部落…

18
00:01:17,301 --> 00:01:18,469
(Touch your angry forehead)
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)

19
00:01:18,469 --> 00:01:19,537
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)

20
00:01:19,537 --> 00:01:21,806
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
Inform the chiefs of all the 12 clans
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)
联络十二个血盟部落的头目…

21
00:01:21,806 --> 00:01:23,307
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
Tomorrow morning..
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)
明天上午…

22
00:01:23,307 --> 00:01:23,741
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
we're going to gather in Wushe
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)

23
00:01:23,741 --> 00:01:26,177
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)
一起在雾社集合

24
00:01:26,177 --> 00:01:27,245
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)

25
00:01:27,245 --> 00:01:29,547
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
and offer a blood sacrifice to our ancestors
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)
…血祭祖灵！

26
00:01:29,547 --> 00:01:34,585
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)

27
00:01:34,585 --> 00:01:36,754
My children! What are you doing?
孩子啊！你们在做什么？

28
00:01:36,754 --> 00:01:37,555
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
What on earth are you doing, my children?
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
My children! What are you doing?
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
孩子啊！你们在做什么？

29
00:01:37,555 --> 00:01:42,160
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
我的孩子啊，你们在做什么？

30
00:01:42,160 --> 00:01:56,340
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)

31
00:01:56,340 --> 00:02:01,646
(How much pain
do you swallow to sing the ancestral songs?)
(为唱出祖灵的歌需要吞下许多痛苦)

32
00:02:01,646 --> 00:02:02,480
(How much pain
do you swallow to sing the ancestral songs?)
Tanah, why are you doing this?
(为唱出祖灵的歌需要吞下许多痛苦)
达那哈…

33
00:02:02,480 --> 00:02:04,148
(为唱出祖灵的歌需要吞下许多痛苦)
你们为什么要这样哪？

34
00:02:04,148 --> 00:02:05,216
(How much shame
do you swallow to speak out your minds?)
Tanah, why are you doing this?
(为说出自己的话需要吞下许多屈辱)
你们为什么要这样哪？

35
00:02:05,216 --> 00:02:06,484
(How much shame
do you swallow to speak out your minds?)
It was Mouna Rudo's idea
(为说出自己的话需要吞下许多屈辱)
全部都算莫那鲁道的…

36
00:02:06,484 --> 00:02:10,755
(How much shame
do you swallow to speak out your minds?)
(为说出自己的话需要吞下许多屈辱)

37
00:02:10,755 --> 00:02:23,301
(How much regret
do you swallow to fulfill your dreams?)
(为实现梦想需要吞下许多遗憾)

38
00:02:23,301 --> 00:02:47,792
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(孩子啊，你们怎么了？)

39
00:02:47,792 --> 00:03:13,885
(Oh, my children!
What exactly is wrong with you?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们到底怎么了？)

40
00:03:13,885 --> 00:03:34,535
(Your dreams are vast like a blue ocean)
(你们梦广大如一片蓝色海洋)

41
00:03:36,440 --> 00:03:40,015
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(孩子啊，你们怎么了？)

42
00:03:40,016 --> 00:03:42,446
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(We, the Hanaoka brothers
are forced to leave this world)

43
00:03:42,446 --> 00:03:45,446
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(The savages are massacring the Japanese )

44
00:03:45,446 --> 00:03:48,456
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(bringing forth a situation out of control)

45
00:03:48,456 --> 00:03:51,256
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(Now we are driven to bay by the savages )

46
00:03:51,256 --> 00:03:54,596
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(and have no other choices )

47
00:03:54,596 --> 00:03:57,426
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(It is 9 o'clock on the morning
of October 27th, 1930)

48
00:03:57,426 --> 00:03:59,796
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(The savages have already
occupied most of this region)

49
00:03:59,796 --> 00:04:01,266
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(The commissioner and all his subordinates )

50
00:04:01,266 --> 00:04:03,266
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(have been killed in the school)

51
00:04:03,266 --> 00:04:05,596
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)

52
00:04:11,846 --> 00:04:24,046
Warriors of The Rainbow II : Rainbow Bridge

53
00:04:28,626 --> 00:04:29,854
Make a phone call!
打电话…

54
00:04:30,695 --> 00:04:32,253
The Wushe savages
are massacring the Japanese
雾社发生暴动了…

55
00:04:32,897 --> 00:04:33,522
Make a phone call! -What happened?
打电话…

56
00:04:33,631 --> 00:04:34,825
怎么了？

57
00:04:34,932 --> 00:04:36,331
Make a phone call!
快点打电话…

58
00:04:38,035 --> 00:04:38,831
Hurry! -How did it come to this?
快点打电话…

59
00:04:38,936 --> 00:04:40,403
怎么会搞成这样…

60
00:04:40,504 --> 00:04:42,495
Hurry up and call! -What happened?
打电话…快点打电话…

61
00:04:42,606 --> 00:04:43,766
怎么了？

62
00:04:45,142 --> 00:04:46,234
What the hell?
-The Wushe savages have revolted
怎么了…你说清楚…

63
00:04:46,344 --> 00:04:48,312
-到底是…-雾社发生暴动了…

64
00:04:48,412 --> 00:04:49,504
The Wushe savages have revolted
雾社发生暴动了…

65
00:04:49,613 --> 00:04:52,047
Hurry up and call!
快打电话…

66
00:04:52,149 --> 00:04:53,912
Phone!
电话…

67
00:04:56,787 --> 00:04:57,651
Yes?
是…

68
00:05:00,091 --> 00:05:01,058
What?
什么？

69
00:05:01,926 --> 00:05:03,826
The Wushe savages
are massacring the Japanese?
雾社蕃大出草？

70
00:05:05,363 --> 00:05:09,390
Get everybody here right now
快去把所有人都招集回来…

71
00:05:10,401 --> 00:05:13,165
Massacre...
-Gather all the policemen right away!
-大出草…
-让开！所有警察集合！

72
00:05:13,270 --> 00:05:16,330
The Wushe savages are hunting heads!
-All the policemen gather up!
-雾社蕃出草了！
-警察回去集合了！

73
00:05:16,440 --> 00:05:19,136
All the Japanese in the mountains
have been killed
山上的日本人都被杀光光了…

74
00:05:19,243 --> 00:05:20,574
And all the police stations
have been burned down
驻在所也被烧光光了…

75
00:05:20,678 --> 00:05:22,873
Only one of the Japanese survived
日本人只剩一个跑出来而已…

76
00:05:22,980 --> 00:05:25,471
Go back home! Come on! Hurry up!
你先回家去…快回去…快

77
00:05:25,583 --> 00:05:27,642
The Wushe savages are coming down
to kill more people
雾社蕃现在要下山来杀人…

78
00:05:27,752 --> 00:05:28,480
They're coming to kill us
杀我们了…

79
00:05:28,586 --> 00:05:29,644
Come on, everyone, hide!
大家赶快躲起来…

80
00:05:29,754 --> 00:05:32,052
Don't get caught -You bastard!
-不要被抓到了…
-混蛋！

81
00:05:32,156 --> 00:05:33,953
What are you talking about?
你再乱讲试看看…

82
00:05:51,976 --> 00:05:53,603
The Japanese knew already
日本人已经知道了！

83
00:06:02,119 --> 00:06:04,713
The savages are likely
to charge all the way into Puli
现在蕃人很有可能攻进埔里

84
00:06:04,822 --> 00:06:09,259
We're afraid even the plainsmen
might seize the opportunity to join in the revolt
我们担心连平地人也乘机联合造反

85
00:06:09,360 --> 00:06:10,918
This is an emergency
情况紧急…

86
00:06:11,028 --> 00:06:14,054
All county governments please send in
their armies and police forces
希望各州厅调派军警

87
00:06:14,165 --> 00:06:17,225
to lay siege to Wushe from Hualien and Tunghih
由花莲、东势一起围攻雾社…

88
00:06:17,334 --> 00:06:18,426
And I want to know if the Governor-general
can dispatch the troops
还有台北及台南方面的军队

89
00:06:18,536 --> 00:06:20,504
from Taipei and Tainan right away
请总督府马上调派支援

90
00:06:20,604 --> 00:06:22,538
The Japanese this way, to the sugar refinery
日本人往这边…往糖厂去…

91
00:06:22,640 --> 00:06:25,700
Come on! The family members
of the Japanese to the sugar refinery
快！日本人家眷快点！往糖厂…

92
00:06:25,810 --> 00:06:27,778
Come on! Hurry up! Put all the stuff away
快点！快点！把摊子收起来…

93
00:06:27,878 --> 00:06:30,642
This way! Hurry up!
往这边…你们快一点啊！

94
00:06:30,748 --> 00:06:32,773
The family members of the soldiers
to the feedstock department
军人眷属往原料厂

95
00:06:32,883 --> 00:06:34,817
The family members of the police
to the mechanical department
警察眷属往机械厂

96
00:06:34,919 --> 00:06:37,649
The family members of the officeholders
to sugar extraction department! Come on!
公务眷属往榨糖厂…快点！

97
00:06:37,755 --> 00:06:39,017
You too. Come on!
你们也是…快点！

98
00:06:39,123 --> 00:06:41,057
Come on!
-Savages will always be savages
-快点！快点！
-蕃就是蕃…

99
00:06:41,158 --> 00:06:42,523
You're nothing but beasts
跟野兽一样…

100
00:06:42,626 --> 00:06:45,789
I never know what you savages are thinking
永远不懂你们生蕃在想什么！

101
00:06:45,896 --> 00:06:48,524
It's time for me to teach you a lesson
该换我来教你知道…

102
00:06:49,834 --> 00:06:51,165
Speak Japanese!
讲国语！

103
00:06:52,002 --> 00:06:54,163
No one understands your savage language
讲一大堆蕃话谁听的懂啊？

104
00:06:56,207 --> 00:06:57,834
Your tribesmen have revolted
你们部落造反

105
00:06:58,742 --> 00:07:01,575
No more peaceful life for you
你以后也别想好过了…

106
00:07:07,351 --> 00:07:08,079
It's chilly!
很冷…

107
00:07:09,920 --> 00:07:11,751
Come on, Pihu!
快一点呀！毕夫…

108
00:07:11,856 --> 00:07:13,585
Get a larger chunk of wood
放大块的木头！

109
00:07:18,929 --> 00:07:20,157
Good morning
早安！

110
00:07:21,432 --> 00:07:22,364
Good morning
早安！

111
00:07:28,205 --> 00:07:29,297
Chief!
大头目…

112
00:07:31,408 --> 00:07:33,933
It's chilly out here
天气这么冷

113
00:07:34,044 --> 00:07:36,512
Why aren't you inside the house by the fire
instead of weaving this bag?
不进屋去烤火

114
00:07:36,614 --> 00:07:38,946
在这编什么背袋呢？

115
00:07:40,050 --> 00:07:42,211
It's the first snow of this winter
How could I miss it?
这可是今年的第一场雪哪…

116
00:07:42,319 --> 00:07:43,946
怎么可以错过！

117
00:07:49,960 --> 00:07:53,327
The snow has come early this year
今年的雪下早了！

118
00:07:59,236 --> 00:08:00,328
Takun, what are you doing?
达固…

119
00:08:00,437 --> 00:08:01,631
你在干嘛？

120
00:08:04,141 --> 00:08:04,937
Takun!
达固！

121
00:08:11,081 --> 00:08:12,207
Temu, your son will perform well
on sports day again, won't he?
铁木…

122
00:08:12,316 --> 00:08:17,515
今年运动会你儿子也会有好成绩吧！

123
00:08:17,621 --> 00:08:20,112
Takun, what's going on?
达固…怎么回事啊？

124
00:08:20,224 --> 00:08:21,657
You've got blood all over your body
怎么身上都是血啊？

125
00:08:23,961 --> 00:08:24,950
Takun!
达固…

126
00:08:30,501 --> 00:08:31,559
Takun!
达固…

127
00:08:33,037 --> 00:08:34,368
What's wrong with you?
你到底怎么了？

128
00:08:35,139 --> 00:08:36,401
Chief, today Mouna Rudo from Mehebu Clan
头目…

129
00:08:36,507 --> 00:08:39,635
今天马赫坡的莫那鲁道…

130
00:08:39,743 --> 00:08:43,839
led the Seediqs from Tgdaya
to offer a blood sacrifice to our ancestors
带领德克达亚群在雾社血祭祖灵了

131
00:08:43,948 --> 00:08:47,042
They've occupied the whole Wushe region
现在整个雾社已经被他们拿下来了

132
00:08:47,151 --> 00:08:49,244
We Seediqs from Toda should join them as well
我们道泽也一起加入吧！

133
00:08:50,955 --> 00:08:52,786
Let's kill this Japanese man!
杀了这个日本人！

134
00:08:52,890 --> 00:08:54,050
No way!
不行！

135
00:08:58,195 --> 00:08:59,594
Kojima is our friend
He's a good Japanese, not a bad one
小岛和我们是朋友！

136
00:08:59,697 --> 00:09:02,860
他是好的日本人，不是坏的日本人…

137
00:09:02,967 --> 00:09:03,865
Go away!
走开！

138
00:09:03,968 --> 00:09:04,764
Temu!
铁木！

139
00:09:05,636 --> 00:09:08,503
You're the chief of all the Seediqs from Toda
你是道泽总头目

140
00:09:08,606 --> 00:09:10,699
Why don't you drive the Japanese away
and lead your own people?
你不将日本人赶走

141
00:09:10,808 --> 00:09:13,242
让自己来治理！

142
00:09:13,344 --> 00:09:16,609
Why should you expect
the good Japanese to rule us?
却只求让好的日本人来统治！

143
00:09:16,714 --> 00:09:17,612
He's right! We don't have any Japanese friends
对！

144
00:09:17,715 --> 00:09:19,546
日本人都不是朋友！

145
00:09:19,650 --> 00:09:20,878
Don't come any closer!
不要再过来了！

146
00:09:36,734 --> 00:09:37,894
Kojima, we'll let you answer the phone
小岛…

147
00:09:38,836 --> 00:09:41,236
我们让你去接电话

148
00:09:41,338 --> 00:09:42,498
But do you have the guts to do it?
可是…

149
00:09:44,241 --> 00:09:45,868
你敢接吗？

150
00:09:49,713 --> 00:09:51,681
Have I been bad to you?
我对你们不好吗？

151
00:09:52,516 --> 00:09:54,381
Have I been bad to you?
我对你们不好吗？

152
00:09:55,586 --> 00:09:56,348
Kojima..
小岛…

153
00:09:58,122 --> 00:10:01,091
Is this how you repay me?
这就是你们报答我的动作吗？

154
00:10:01,191 --> 00:10:04,388
I can't fight back if you want me dead
你们要杀我，我无法抵抗

155
00:10:05,696 --> 00:10:06,993
But the Japanese government
will do anything to punish you
但是我们日本政府

156
00:10:07,097 --> 00:10:09,895
一定会因此对你们展开讨伐…

157
00:10:12,703 --> 00:10:15,103
We might as well die together
大家同归于尽吧！

158
00:10:17,074 --> 00:10:18,063
Kojima!
小岛…

159
00:10:22,980 --> 00:10:26,848
We have airplanes, but do you?
我们有飞机，你们有吗？

160
00:10:27,351 --> 00:10:31,447
We have machineguns and cannons,
but do you?
我们有机枪大炮，你们有吗？

161
00:10:32,923 --> 00:10:37,417
Think about
how Mouna Rudo used to insult you
想想莫那鲁道是怎么羞辱你们的…

162
00:10:37,961 --> 00:10:41,795
Last time when we're out hunting
they threatened to kill you all
上次打猎他们还扬言要杀光你们

163
00:10:41,899 --> 00:10:43,958
Don't you remember?
你们难道忘记了吗？

164
00:10:45,369 --> 00:10:47,599
Are you willing to die
with them in the battlefield?
现在还要陪他们一起战死吗？

165
00:10:48,972 --> 00:10:50,837
Temu Walis,
铁木瓦力斯？

166
00:10:50,941 --> 00:10:53,273
you won't have the chance to grow up
…我不会让你长大的！

167
00:11:02,186 --> 00:11:03,016
Hello?
喂…

168
00:11:06,523 --> 00:11:07,490
Hello?
喂…

169
00:11:07,591 --> 00:11:10,822
Take it easy! There's more!
不要抢，还有…别急…

170
00:11:11,628 --> 00:11:13,619
Hurry up!
动作快一点！

171
00:11:13,731 --> 00:11:14,993
Come on!
快一点！

172
00:11:18,035 --> 00:11:19,502
Come on!
快一点！

173
00:11:23,741 --> 00:11:25,538
Chief Mouna?
莫那头目…

174
00:11:40,357 --> 00:11:41,483
Thank you
谢谢你…

175
00:11:44,762 --> 00:11:45,626
Thank you
谢谢你！

176
00:11:46,296 --> 00:11:47,126
Thank you
谢谢你！

177
00:11:48,132 --> 00:11:50,225
Thank you
谢谢你们！

178
00:11:50,334 --> 00:11:53,201
Thank you. Thank you all
谢谢…真的谢谢你们！

179
00:11:54,238 --> 00:11:55,136
Thank you
谢谢你们！

180
00:11:55,239 --> 00:11:56,331
Thank you -Come on!
-谢谢你们！
-快一点…

181
00:11:57,541 --> 00:11:59,065
Thank you. Thank you all
谢谢！谢谢你们！

182
00:12:01,945 --> 00:12:02,468
Thank you
谢谢你们！

183
00:12:02,579 --> 00:12:03,443
Tado!
达多！

184
00:12:03,547 --> 00:12:05,242
Sapu, where's my father?
萨布，我父亲呢？

185
00:12:06,850 --> 00:12:10,217
What's going on? Why did they want us back?
到底在搞什么？叫我们回来？

186
00:12:18,228 --> 00:12:18,990
Father, why did you give up Hakaw Supeitei?
父亲…

187
00:12:19,096 --> 00:12:21,155
为什么要放弃人止关呢？

188
00:12:21,265 --> 00:12:22,857
So you're back!
回来了啊？

189
00:12:28,105 --> 00:12:30,403
Come on, let's go back to our clan
走！回部落去…

190
00:12:30,507 --> 00:12:31,804
Back to our clan? You're giving up here as well?
回部落？

191
00:12:31,909 --> 00:12:33,809
…连这里也不要了？

192
00:12:33,911 --> 00:12:35,037
Tado, you can't think like the Japanese
when fighting them
达多…

193
00:12:35,279 --> 00:12:38,806
和日本人打仗不能用日本人的想法…

194
00:12:38,916 --> 00:12:41,316
You have to think like the wind
要用风的想法…

195
00:12:41,418 --> 00:12:42,885
The wind?
风？

196
00:12:44,254 --> 00:12:46,245
The wind is invisible
风是看不见的…

197
00:12:54,898 --> 00:12:56,024
Baso, give up everything, everyone
and come back to the clan with me
巴索…

198
00:12:56,133 --> 00:12:59,034
东西都别拿了，所有人回部落！

199
00:13:00,537 --> 00:13:01,299
Japanese airplanes!
日本飞机…

200
00:13:01,405 --> 00:13:03,100
Over there! -Fire!
-在那边…
-开枪！

201
00:13:05,876 --> 00:13:07,935
Shoot it! Come on!
开枪打他！快点！

202
00:13:11,582 --> 00:13:12,549
Are you so scared?
这么害怕吗？

203
00:13:16,620 --> 00:13:19,111
Are you really so scared?
真的这么害怕吗？

204
00:13:29,233 --> 00:13:33,932
I went head hunting for the first time
when I was 15
十五岁那年，我第一次出草…

205
00:13:35,873 --> 00:13:39,570
I was so nervous
that my arms and legs were trembling
我也紧张胆怯，我的手脚发抖…

206
00:13:40,878 --> 00:13:45,281
But my eyes were sharp as arrows
但是…我的眼神如箭！

207
00:13:46,416 --> 00:13:48,577
As soon as I cut the enemy's head off
挥下敌人首级的瞬间…

208
00:13:49,920 --> 00:13:52,684
I forgot what it was like to be scared
我忘记了什么叫害怕！

209
00:13:54,191 --> 00:13:55,954
because I knew I'd go back to my clan
因为我知道…

210
00:13:57,194 --> 00:14:01,187
to feast and celebrate, being treated as a hero
我将英雄地回到部落接受酒宴欢庆

211
00:14:03,367 --> 00:14:05,699
because I knew that all my people
因为我知道…

212
00:14:05,802 --> 00:14:10,705
male and female, young and old
从今以后部落里的男女老少…

213
00:14:10,807 --> 00:14:13,537
would respect me for my bravery
都将尊敬我的勇敢！

214
00:14:13,644 --> 00:14:15,544
However, it's different this time
可是…

215
00:14:15,646 --> 00:14:17,773
这次不一样

216
00:14:23,186 --> 00:14:25,984
We successfully offered a blood sacrifice
to our ancestors today
今天我们虽然成功地血祭了祖灵

217
00:14:28,225 --> 00:14:31,353
and are now qualified
to stride over the rainbow bridge
取得了通过彩虹桥的资格

218
00:14:31,461 --> 00:14:34,225
but what awaits us now is not a festive feast
不过接下来所要面对的…

219
00:14:34,331 --> 00:14:36,424
不是欢庆的酒宴

220
00:14:36,533 --> 00:14:39,297
but to choose how we die
而是选择死亡的方式！

221
00:14:39,403 --> 00:14:41,200
Run the electricity!
送电！

222
00:14:44,408 --> 00:14:46,774
Before we initiated the revolt
早在起事之前…

223
00:14:46,877 --> 00:14:51,041
you knew it'd turn out like this, didn't you?
你们就知道这种结果了，不是吗？

224
00:14:51,248 --> 00:14:53,011
My children..
孩子们…

225
00:14:54,718 --> 00:14:56,686
...don't be scared
别急着害怕！

226
00:14:57,955 --> 00:15:01,652
You've been very brave today
你们今天表现得很勇敢

227
00:15:02,526 --> 00:15:05,017
Our ancestors' spirits have seen it all
祖灵们一定也看见了

228
00:15:05,128 --> 00:15:08,461
But the battle to come is the real one
但接下来要面对的才是真正的战斗

229
00:15:08,565 --> 00:15:12,524
It's a battle that will terrify the invaders
是要让异族人吓破胆的战斗…

230
00:15:12,903 --> 00:15:14,131
Someone's here!
有人来了…

231
00:15:14,237 --> 00:15:18,799
Sisin babblers in the forests
are driving off the scavenging crows
森林的祖灵鸟正驱赶着吃腐肉的乌鸦

232
00:15:18,909 --> 00:15:24,040
The rainbow will be more beautiful
in the sunlight after the rain
水气后的阳光只会让彩虹更艳丽…

233
00:15:26,049 --> 00:15:28,643
It's a bunch of Hans from Wushe
是从雾社下来的汉人

234
00:15:30,787 --> 00:15:32,778
Lock them all up!
把他们通通关起来…

235
00:15:41,565 --> 00:15:44,295
My children..
孩子啊…

236
00:15:44,401 --> 00:15:46,392
...don't be afraid
别害怕！

237
00:15:47,904 --> 00:15:53,274
Our ancestors' spirits know we're good warriors
guarding our hunting grounds
祖灵会肯定我们是守护猎场的好战士

238
00:15:54,711 --> 00:15:57,805
The blood stains on your hands can prove it
你们手上的血痕就是印记

239
00:15:57,914 --> 00:16:00,940
Every one of you is a Seediq Bale
你们已经是个赛德克巴莱

240
00:16:02,219 --> 00:16:04,949
Remember, you have to be proud
记住…

241
00:16:05,055 --> 00:16:07,990
要骄傲！

242
00:16:08,091 --> 00:16:11,288
Let's cross the rainbow bridge together
彩虹桥上我们一起过！

243
00:16:58,108 --> 00:17:00,338
Nobody's guarding here
没人防守啊…

244
00:17:00,444 --> 00:17:03,345
Not a single soul on this path
整条路上上下下全是空的！

245
00:17:06,383 --> 00:17:08,146
How could it be?
怎么可能？

246
00:17:14,357 --> 00:17:15,847
Advance!
前进…

247
00:17:15,959 --> 00:17:17,017
Wait!
等一下！

248
00:17:17,127 --> 00:17:19,357
Stop! Halt!
停！停下来！

249
00:17:20,130 --> 00:17:21,722
Don't rush uphill
I know these savages all too well
先别上去…

250
00:17:21,832 --> 00:17:24,528
我太了解这些生蕃了…

251
00:17:35,145 --> 00:17:37,170
What a chilly night!
怎么这么冷啊…

252
00:17:39,649 --> 00:17:41,981
It's warm here
这个好暖和…

253
00:18:04,307 --> 00:18:06,138
Savages!
有生蕃！

254
00:18:13,416 --> 00:18:14,883
Hold the fire!
停火！

255
00:18:17,320 --> 00:18:26,058
l'm trekking over the high mountains
我走在高山峻岭上

256
00:18:26,163 --> 00:18:35,333
The creek water is so thick and muddy
溪水是那么地混浊

257
00:18:35,438 --> 00:18:44,710
l can't help but shed my tears
我忍不住掉下眼泪

258
00:18:44,815 --> 00:18:54,122
l'm walking along a wide road
我沿着宽敞的大路走

259
00:19:00,564 --> 00:19:02,156
He's asleep
他睡着了…

260
00:19:10,240 --> 00:19:12,105
Ichiro?
一郎…

261
00:19:12,209 --> 00:19:16,043
Today is our wedding anniversary
今天是我们的结婚纪念日

262
00:19:16,146 --> 00:19:18,239
You remember, don't you?
…你记得吗？

263
00:19:23,186 --> 00:19:32,458
We're walking on
with perseverance and determination
我们要坦荡坚忍地走下去…

264
00:19:32,562 --> 00:19:41,436
We can't fall asleep anymore
已经无法入睡了…

265
00:19:41,538 --> 00:19:50,640
Let's go back to the heavenly home
of our ancestors
快点回祖灵之家呀…

266
00:19:52,849 --> 00:19:53,645
Kojima!
小岛！

267
00:19:54,284 --> 00:19:55,717
Long time no see
好久不见了…

268
00:19:56,152 --> 00:19:57,050
Captain!
队长！

269
00:19:58,521 --> 00:19:59,920
Let me introduce you, Captain
我来向你介绍

270
00:20:00,557 --> 00:20:03,253
This is the chief of Tnbarah Clan, Temu Walis
这位是屯巴拉社头目铁木瓦力斯…

271
00:20:05,729 --> 00:20:07,287
Got a good head on his shoulders
聪明的家伙！

272
00:20:09,499 --> 00:20:10,466
Kojima?
小岛…

273
00:20:15,338 --> 00:20:19,274
I heard all your family were killed in the venue?
听说你的家人都在会场上被杀了？

274
00:20:19,376 --> 00:20:21,344
We will seek revenge
…我们会报复的！

275
00:20:54,244 --> 00:20:56,371
Attack!
突击！

276
00:21:16,866 --> 00:21:19,562
Officer, nothing here
警部，什么都没有啊…

277
00:21:22,205 --> 00:21:23,638
Officer Goto!
后藤警部！

278
00:21:33,883 --> 00:21:37,375
What the hell are these savages up to?
…这些蕃人到底想干嘛？

279
00:21:48,631 --> 00:21:51,429
The Japanese are coming!
日本人来了…

280
00:22:31,941 --> 00:22:33,932
Look behind you -Yeah
-小心后面…-是！

281
00:22:35,812 --> 00:22:38,542
This clan is over here
这个部落是那边…

282
00:22:38,648 --> 00:22:41,481
This clan is over there
然后这个部落在那边…

283
00:22:41,584 --> 00:22:44,576
Behind them is a creek
后面有一条溪流…

284
00:22:47,090 --> 00:22:48,421
Where do the Hans live? -The Hans..
那平常汉人都住在哪里？

285
00:22:48,525 --> 00:22:50,584
汉人是…

286
00:22:52,295 --> 00:22:54,320
We're under attack! Duck!
有攻击…趴下！

287
00:22:54,431 --> 00:22:55,796
Hide!
快躲起来！

288
00:23:11,247 --> 00:23:13,147
Awata! Awata!
粟田…粟田…

289
00:23:13,249 --> 00:23:14,807
Contact the Oizumi Squad
and find out where they are now
问一下大泉中队

290
00:23:14,918 --> 00:23:17,011
看他们到哪里了…

291
00:23:29,632 --> 00:23:32,294
This is Wushe Substation
这是雾社分室！这是雾社分室！

292
00:23:32,402 --> 00:23:34,927
This is Oizumi Squad
这是大泉中队！这是大泉中队！

293
00:23:35,505 --> 00:23:37,473
We're now by Suku Creek
我们现在在斯库溪…斯库溪…

294
00:23:37,574 --> 00:23:40,372
We're ambushed by the savages.
We need back up
正遭到蕃人的伏击…请求支援…

295
00:23:40,477 --> 00:23:42,240
We're stuck in the creek water
现在被困在水中…

296
00:23:47,383 --> 00:23:51,217
Oizumi Squad..
大泉中队！大泉中队…

297
00:23:53,356 --> 00:23:54,118
Captain?
大尉…

298
00:23:54,224 --> 00:23:57,785
Assemble a banzai squad for a suicide charge
组织敢死队，冲上去…

299
00:24:01,598 --> 00:24:03,429
Where is Yamada Police Squad?
山田警察队呢？

300
00:24:39,702 --> 00:24:40,828
Charge!
冲啊！

301
00:24:44,807 --> 00:24:45,899
Pihu, let's go!
比荷！走了！

302
00:24:58,621 --> 00:25:00,350
Watch out! Dodge!
危险！闪开！

303
00:25:00,456 --> 00:25:02,947
Duck! Seek cover!
闪开！闪开！

304
00:25:21,778 --> 00:25:24,576
The women and children
from Boarung Clan are all here
波阿仑的妇孺都来了…

305
00:25:25,748 --> 00:25:27,010
Come on, let's go!
我们快点了！

306
00:25:33,356 --> 00:25:36,553
Have you packed up enough clothes, Mahung?
马红，衣服有多带吗？

307
00:25:36,659 --> 00:25:38,024
Yes, I have
有…

308
00:25:38,795 --> 00:25:39,659
Pawan, you kids know how to get there
巴万

309
00:25:39,762 --> 00:25:41,957
你们几个孩子知道路

310
00:25:42,065 --> 00:25:44,533
Take the Boarung women and children along
with those of us that are ready
带外面那些波阿仑的女人孩子

311
00:25:44,634 --> 00:25:48,297
和这边已经整理好的人先过去…

312
00:25:48,504 --> 00:25:50,597
Baso, I'm no longer a child
巴索，我已经不是孩子了！

313
00:25:52,609 --> 00:25:55,601
Don't let the dogs follow us
We don't have enough food
别让狗跟着，我们食物不够…

314
00:26:02,151 --> 00:26:03,175
Mahung, are you ready? Is it heavy?
马红…

315
00:26:03,286 --> 00:26:05,914
该带的都带了吧？很重吗？

316
00:26:09,425 --> 00:26:10,187
Mahung, you go ahead with Pawan and others
马红

317
00:26:10,293 --> 00:26:12,955
你先和巴万他们一起过去吧！

318
00:26:13,062 --> 00:26:14,996
I'll wait for Sapu
我等萨布…

319
00:26:15,098 --> 00:26:16,998
Why is everyone in here?
干嘛都挤在这里呢？

320
00:26:19,002 --> 00:26:20,867
Mother, don't touch that!
母亲，那个不要动…

321
00:26:27,343 --> 00:26:31,109
You're out of your minds!
The men in this house have all gone mad
疯了！我们家的男人全疯了…

322
00:26:36,452 --> 00:26:37,612
Go ahead to Paran Clan, Obing
欧嫔…你跟他们去巴兰社吧！

323
00:26:37,720 --> 00:26:39,244
No!
不要！不要！

324
00:26:39,355 --> 00:26:41,585
Jiro, let me stay with you
二郎…让我留下来…

325
00:26:41,691 --> 00:26:43,921
Jiro!
二郎…二郎…

326
00:26:44,027 --> 00:26:46,587
Let go of me!
-All pregnant women go to Paran Clan
-不要拉我…
-有身孕的都去巴兰社吧！

327
00:26:46,696 --> 00:26:49,722
Auntie, I'm the wife of a policeman
姑妈…我是警察的妻子…

328
00:26:49,832 --> 00:26:52,926
but I'm the daughter of the Gungu Chief as well
可是我也是荷戈社头目的女儿呀…

329
00:26:53,036 --> 00:26:54,503
Auntie, let go of me!
姑妈…

330
00:26:54,604 --> 00:26:56,037
不要拉我…

331
00:26:56,139 --> 00:26:57,003
Give birth to your child in Paran Clan
-不要拉…
-去巴兰社把孩子生下来…

332
00:26:57,106 --> 00:27:00,337
Jiro! I want to stay with you!
二郎…我要留下来…

333
00:27:00,443 --> 00:27:03,378
I don't want to go there, Auntie!
我不要走…姑妈…

334
00:27:03,479 --> 00:27:06,971
Give birth to your child in Paran Clan
我不要走…我要留下来…

335
00:27:09,719 --> 00:27:12,449
They're all pregnant
她们有身孕

336
00:27:12,555 --> 00:27:14,921
The Japanese won't harm them
日本人不会对她们怎样的…

337
00:28:48,184 --> 00:28:49,173
Pawan!
巴万…

338
00:28:50,586 --> 00:28:52,053
Pawan!
巴万！

339
00:28:54,390 --> 00:28:55,482
What is it?
怎么啦？

340
00:28:57,560 --> 00:28:59,619
The cavern is right up ahead
You can carry these over by yourselves
岩窟就在前面了

341
00:28:59,729 --> 00:29:02,789
这些东西你们可以搬得过去的…

342
00:29:03,966 --> 00:29:06,400
We have to go now
我们要先走了！

343
00:29:08,271 --> 00:29:09,863
But where to?
…走去哪里啊？

344
00:29:15,511 --> 00:29:20,813
No, Mother! -Grandmother!
-不要啊…母亲…
-祖母…

345
00:29:20,917 --> 00:29:24,648
Mother! -Grandmother!
-母亲…
-祖母…

346
00:29:24,754 --> 00:29:26,984
No, Mother! -Grandmother!
-不要啊…母亲…
-祖母…

347
00:29:27,089 --> 00:29:29,649
What are you doing?
你在干什么？你们在干什么啦…

348
00:29:29,759 --> 00:29:31,124
Mother, don't!
母亲…不要…

349
00:29:31,227 --> 00:29:33,957
Grandmother! -What are you doing?
-祖母…祖母！
-你们干什么啦…

350
00:29:34,063 --> 00:29:37,464
Chief Mouna and others will be here soon
莫那头目他们等一下就来了…

351
00:29:37,567 --> 00:29:41,970
Grandmother! -Mother!
-祖母…
-母亲…

352
00:29:42,071 --> 00:29:46,633
You'll have to fight the Japanese for a long time
你们得跟日本人长期战斗…

353
00:29:46,742 --> 00:29:49,677
There's not enough food for all of us
这些存粮不够那么多人吃的！

354
00:29:49,779 --> 00:29:51,007
What are you talking about?
你乱讲…

355
00:29:51,113 --> 00:29:54,014
Chief Mouna told us we're going to
fight our decisive battle soon
莫那头目说很快就会决战的…

356
00:29:54,116 --> 00:29:56,607
Grandmother!
祖母…

357
00:29:56,719 --> 00:29:57,879
Pawan!
巴万…

358
00:29:59,222 --> 00:30:04,455
I'm so glad that you're a warrior now
guarding our hunting grounds
母亲很高兴你已是守护猎场的战士

359
00:30:04,560 --> 00:30:07,529
We'll be waiting for you
at the other end of the rainbow bridge
我们先去彩虹的另一端等着你们！

360
00:30:07,630 --> 00:30:11,430
You'll be meeting us
after you finish your glorious battles
等着你们决战之后，风光的回家…

361
00:30:11,534 --> 00:30:13,229
Stop following us!
不要跟来…

362
00:30:13,336 --> 00:30:15,861
Fight for your hunting grounds -Mother!
-为你的猎场战斗…
-母亲…

363
00:30:15,972 --> 00:30:17,132
Grandmother, don't you want me anymore?
祖母…

364
00:30:17,240 --> 00:30:20,801
你怎么不要我了…

365
00:30:20,910 --> 00:30:23,845
Mother!
母亲…

366
00:30:23,946 --> 00:30:25,971
Mother!
母亲…母亲…

367
00:30:26,082 --> 00:30:28,812
Pawan, please tell my husband Watan
巴万，请告诉我的丈夫瓦旦

368
00:30:28,918 --> 00:30:32,547
that I'll have the wine ready for him
at the other end of the rainbow bridge
我在彩虹那端把酒酿好等他过来…

369
00:30:32,655 --> 00:30:34,885
Watan is building up huts in the cavern
You can go tell him yourself
瓦旦就在岩窟搭草寮

370
00:30:34,991 --> 00:30:37,152
你自己去跟他讲…

371
00:30:38,160 --> 00:30:40,219
Lubi! Lubi!
露比…露比…

372
00:30:40,329 --> 00:30:42,559
Stop following us! -Mother!
-不要跟来…
-母亲…

373
00:30:42,665 --> 00:30:45,031
Don't follow us! -Mother, don't!
-不要跟来…
-母亲不要…

374
00:30:45,134 --> 00:30:48,069
Please... -Mother!
-妈妈求你了…
-母亲…

375
00:30:48,170 --> 00:30:50,502
Don't cry -Grandmother!
-不要哭…不要哭…
-祖母…

376
00:30:50,606 --> 00:30:52,699
Listen to me..
听我说…

377
00:30:52,808 --> 00:30:55,333
you're a grownup man now
你现在已经是男人了…

378
00:30:55,444 --> 00:30:56,274
Go on!
去吧…

379
00:30:56,379 --> 00:30:58,677
Grandmother! -To the battlefield!
-祖母…
-去战斗吧！

380
00:30:58,781 --> 00:31:01,113
Fight for your hunting grounds!
-Grandmother!
-为你的猎场…用力战斗！
-祖母…

381
00:31:01,217 --> 00:31:02,514
To the battlefield!
去战斗…

382
00:31:05,354 --> 00:31:08,812
Grandmother!
祖母…

383
00:31:08,925 --> 00:31:10,984
Mother! -Grandmother!
-母亲…
-祖母…

384
00:31:12,828 --> 00:31:14,887
Mother!
母亲…

385
00:31:14,997 --> 00:31:16,828
Mother!
母亲…

386
00:31:16,933 --> 00:31:22,371
Don't go, Mother! -Grandmother!
-不要走呀…母亲…
-祖母…

387
00:31:25,608 --> 00:31:27,371
Mother..
母亲…

388
00:31:29,845 --> 00:31:38,719
With tears in my eyes
我眼中含泪

389
00:31:38,821 --> 00:31:47,160
l'm walking along a wide road
沿着宽广的路前进

390
00:31:47,263 --> 00:31:56,137
l beseech you
我恳求你们

391
00:31:56,238 --> 00:32:05,169
Tell me if your hearts are at peace
你们甘心吗？

392
00:32:05,281 --> 00:32:14,246
Oh, poor innocent children
孩子们是多么的可怜啊…

393
00:32:14,357 --> 00:32:23,231
What's the matter with you?
你们是怎么了呢？

394
00:32:23,332 --> 00:32:31,865
We're really exhausted
我们真的非常地疲累…

395
00:33:35,371 --> 00:33:36,633
Hanako?
花子…

396
00:33:41,143 --> 00:33:46,740
You look just as pretty
as you were on our wedding day
你还是跟我们结婚时一样漂亮…

397
00:34:16,011 --> 00:34:24,146
Good boy! Close your eyes!
乖…眼睛闭起来…

398
00:34:58,454 --> 00:35:03,391
My child, let's go together
孩子…我们一起走吧…

399
00:36:11,293 --> 00:36:12,453
Jiro?
二郎…

400
00:36:13,963 --> 00:36:16,932
Are we the subjects of Japan's Mikado?
我们到底该是日本天皇的子民？

401
00:36:18,534 --> 00:36:20,968
Or the descendants of the Seediq ancestors?
还是赛德克祖灵的子孙？

402
00:36:24,840 --> 00:36:27,070
Do it
…切开吧！

403
00:36:27,176 --> 00:36:30,077
Cut it up and end your conflicts
right here and now
一刀切开你矛盾的肝肠吧…

404
00:36:30,179 --> 00:36:32,943
We don't have to go anywhere once we're dead
哪儿也别去了…

405
00:36:33,048 --> 00:36:35,448
Let's both be free wandering spirits
当个自在的游魂吧！

406
00:36:50,866 --> 00:36:52,458
Thank you
谢谢…

407
00:38:01,937 --> 00:38:04,064
This way please, General
司令，这边请…

408
00:38:15,050 --> 00:38:17,518
This is Officer Kabasoa, sir
司令，这位是桦泽警部

409
00:38:17,619 --> 00:38:19,314
He's a local policeman
and he knows the Wushe savages very well
是此地的警察

410
00:38:19,421 --> 00:38:21,252
对雾社地区的蕃情相当熟悉…

411
00:38:21,357 --> 00:38:23,757
Then why are you still alive?
那你为什么还活着？

412
00:38:26,161 --> 00:38:30,063
He was not there when the incident happened
…他当时不在公学校

413
00:38:40,576 --> 00:38:41,474
General, according to our investigation
司令

414
00:38:41,577 --> 00:38:42,737
根据我们的察访

415
00:38:42,845 --> 00:38:44,540
there are six clans involved in the revolt
over 300 warriors in all
参与反抗的部落有六个

416
00:38:44,646 --> 00:38:46,443
共有三百多名战士…

417
00:38:47,616 --> 00:38:48,548
Warriors?
战士？

418
00:38:50,619 --> 00:38:52,746
You call them 'warriors'
你称他们为战士…

419
00:38:54,289 --> 00:38:57,816
Each of these clans took actions separately
他们在凌晨时，各部落单独行动

420
00:38:57,926 --> 00:38:59,450
at dawn and annihilated
the local police stations
歼灭当地驻在所之后

421
00:38:59,561 --> 00:39:02,291
Then they got together to besiege Wushe
再一起集合围攻雾社

422
00:39:02,398 --> 00:39:05,492
That's why we don't think it incidental
所以我们判断这绝不是突发事件

423
00:39:05,601 --> 00:39:08,866
They had been planning it carefully
from the beginning
而是一开始就经过详细的计划！

424
00:39:10,773 --> 00:39:14,072
Planning it carefully?
详细计划？

425
00:39:14,176 --> 00:39:16,303
Mr. Kabasoa?
桦泽先生…

426
00:39:16,412 --> 00:39:19,404
Don't you think
you're overestimating these savages?
你会不会太高估了这些野蛮人？

427
00:39:19,515 --> 00:39:23,884
General, all our reinforcements
were under fatal attacks yesterday
司令…昨天我们各个支援的部队

428
00:39:23,986 --> 00:39:26,284
都遭到了严重的突击…

429
00:39:27,156 --> 00:39:28,953
...including here
包括这里…

430
00:39:38,901 --> 00:39:43,065
This is nothing but animal-like savagery
这只是动物性的野蛮行为…

431
00:39:45,974 --> 00:39:49,910
Once the rain stops,
we'll besiege them immediately
等雨一停，立刻围攻部落！

432
00:39:50,012 --> 00:39:50,706
Yes, sir!
是！

433
00:39:53,716 --> 00:39:59,716
(Headquarters of Kamada Detachment)

434
00:40:48,103 --> 00:40:49,331
Chief,
头目…

435
00:40:49,438 --> 00:40:52,430
are we going for the decisive battle tomorrow?
明天要决战了吗？

436
00:41:10,425 --> 00:41:11,790
Ah, it hurts!
啊…痛啊…

437
00:41:11,894 --> 00:41:15,830
Chief, the wounds are still fresh
头目…伤口还没好哪…

438
00:41:24,406 --> 00:41:25,270
Pawan, you're not a child anymore
巴万

439
00:41:26,275 --> 00:41:28,140
你已经不是个孩子了！

440
00:41:33,148 --> 00:41:34,240
Chief, can we fight the decisive battle now?
…头目

441
00:41:35,551 --> 00:41:38,543
我们快点决战好不好？

442
00:42:07,783 --> 00:42:08,511
What's happening?
发生什么事…

443
00:42:09,785 --> 00:42:10,774
Give me the gun!
枪给我…

444
00:42:11,954 --> 00:42:13,444
Hurry up!
快…快点…

445
00:42:19,828 --> 00:42:21,853
Let's go!
走！

446
00:42:33,041 --> 00:42:34,133
Hurry up!
快点！

447
00:42:35,410 --> 00:42:36,308
Be careful!
小心！

448
00:42:37,613 --> 00:42:38,875
Go over there! Be careful!
你们过去那边！

449
00:42:38,981 --> 00:42:40,608
小心一点！

450
00:42:50,826 --> 00:42:51,793
Stop! The savages!
停下来！

451
00:42:51,893 --> 00:42:53,622
有凶蕃！

452
00:43:00,202 --> 00:43:01,499
Stop running!
不要跑！

453
00:43:09,845 --> 00:43:11,005
Over there!
在那边…

454
00:43:17,052 --> 00:43:18,451
What the hell?
在搞什么东西啊？

455
00:43:23,759 --> 00:43:24,726
Fire!
开枪！

456
00:43:29,698 --> 00:43:30,858
Retreat! All retreat!
撤退…

457
00:43:30,966 --> 00:43:34,959
全部撤退…

458
00:43:39,241 --> 00:43:40,708
Hurry up and run!
快点…大家快跑…

459
00:43:59,995 --> 00:44:03,226
Seek covers! -Down there!
往下面去…找掩护…

460
00:44:05,000 --> 00:44:06,490
Signalman, call for reinforcements
通讯兵，快通报支援…

461
00:44:07,803 --> 00:44:09,031
Retreat downhill! Hide!
往下撤退…

462
00:44:09,137 --> 00:44:10,570
躲起来…

463
00:44:11,239 --> 00:44:13,002
Out of the way!
让开！让开！

464
00:44:43,271 --> 00:44:44,738
Watch out!
后面小心…

465
00:44:45,507 --> 00:44:47,600
Quite slippery here
这边很滑…

466
00:44:52,414 --> 00:44:53,745
Are you alright?
还好吗？

467
00:44:53,849 --> 00:44:56,784
Halt, everyone!
前面队伍停下来…

468
00:45:09,364 --> 00:45:11,628
Jump!
跳下去！

469
00:45:47,569 --> 00:45:48,900
Machine gun!
机关枪…机关枪…

470
00:45:49,004 --> 00:45:49,902
Step back! -Take aim!
-向后退！
-打那边一点…

471
00:45:50,005 --> 00:45:51,199
You're aiming too high! Hold on to your guns!
你打太高了！枪拿稳…

472
00:45:52,240 --> 00:45:54,470
Come on, fire it,
Sapu! What are you waiting for?
快打呀萨布！等什么？

473
00:45:54,576 --> 00:45:56,407
I can't fire it
打不出去呀…

474
00:46:00,115 --> 00:46:01,241
Move over! I'll do it!
让开我来！

475
00:46:03,018 --> 00:46:05,009
Come on! Hurry up!
快跑…快一点…

476
00:46:05,754 --> 00:46:07,745
What the hell? Fell asleep or something?
搞什么？睡着了啊？

477
00:46:09,057 --> 00:46:10,285
Over there! Come on!
那边…快点…

478
00:46:10,392 --> 00:46:11,620
He's gone!
跑掉了…

479
00:46:12,394 --> 00:46:15,022
If I aim at the rock deliberately
如果我故意打在石头上

480
00:46:15,130 --> 00:46:17,860
will the bullet bounce off
and hit the officer over there?
子弹会反弹到后面那个军官吗？

481
00:46:18,767 --> 00:46:19,927
Why don't you give it a try?
你试试看…

482
00:46:24,005 --> 00:46:26,633
No, it won't
不行啦…没有用…

483
00:46:26,741 --> 00:46:29,972
Have you two got too many bullets?
你们两个子弹太多是不是？

484
00:46:30,078 --> 00:46:31,010
No, but that is a military officer
with a katana sword
不是呀…

485
00:46:31,112 --> 00:46:33,876
那是个军官哪…带刀的！

486
00:46:43,024 --> 00:46:43,854
Chief, Tado robbed a couple of machineguns
头目…

487
00:46:43,959 --> 00:46:46,621
达多抢到了两挺机枪

488
00:46:46,728 --> 00:46:49,788
Chief Mouna asked us to bring you one and..
莫那头目叫我们送一挺来给你们…

489
00:46:49,898 --> 00:46:51,331
还有…

490
00:46:51,433 --> 00:46:53,924
here's the ammunition and..
这是弹药…还有…

491
00:46:54,035 --> 00:46:55,900
and this bag of sweet potatoes
还有这些地瓜…

492
00:46:57,539 --> 00:47:00,372
Kids nowadays are so weak
现在的孩子怎么这么没用啊？

493
00:47:00,475 --> 00:47:03,672
Look how they pant with so little running
才跑没多远就喘成这样！

494
00:47:05,347 --> 00:47:07,247
Do you know how to use it?
这东西你会弄吗？

495
00:47:09,251 --> 00:47:12,618
I don't think this machinegun works
这机枪好像打不出去…

496
00:47:15,957 --> 00:47:18,619
Why did you give me one that doesn't work?
拿个打不出去的机枪给我干嘛？

497
00:47:22,797 --> 00:47:24,924
That damned Mouna!
莫那这家伙…

498
00:47:28,136 --> 00:47:29,296
Chief Dahdo..
塔道头目

499
00:47:30,605 --> 00:47:32,971
My Paran relatives told me..
我听到我巴兰社的亲戚说…

500
00:47:35,377 --> 00:47:38,835
that your entire family committed suicide
…你整个头目家族全都自尽了…

501
00:47:46,621 --> 00:47:47,485
Chief Dahdo, a bigger and more powerful army
is coming our way
塔道头目…

502
00:47:47,589 --> 00:47:50,922
更大更多的军队往这里围过来了…

503
00:47:51,026 --> 00:47:52,960
They have lots of cannons
还有好多的大炮！

504
00:48:06,741 --> 00:48:07,605
Pawan, when I was young
巴万…

505
00:48:08,677 --> 00:48:10,076
我年轻时的威风…

506
00:48:10,178 --> 00:48:13,306
I was no less strong or brave
than your Mehebu Chief Mouna Rudo
可不输给你们马赫坡的莫那鲁道

507
00:48:13,415 --> 00:48:14,746
you understand?
你懂吗？

508
00:48:18,620 --> 00:48:19,552
Awi, lead the group and retreat to Rkudaya
阿威…

509
00:48:20,755 --> 00:48:23,553
等一下带大家退到鲁库达亚…

510
00:48:28,563 --> 00:48:29,427
Chief!
头目…

511
00:48:29,531 --> 00:48:31,522
Chief!
头目…

512
00:48:38,039 --> 00:48:39,768
Chief! Chief!
头目…头目…

513
00:48:42,711 --> 00:48:44,770
Retreat! To Rkudaya!
退！退到鲁库达亚…

514
00:48:44,879 --> 00:48:46,107
Give it to me! Let's go!
拿过来…快走…

515
00:48:46,214 --> 00:48:48,580
Retreat to Rkudaya! Our chief's dead!
快退到鲁库达亚…头目死了…

516
00:48:48,683 --> 00:48:51,277
Come on!
…快点！

517
00:48:53,655 --> 00:48:55,680
Pihu, come on!
比荷…快点！

518
00:49:04,933 --> 00:49:06,992
Retreat to Rkudaya!
退到鲁库达亚…

519
00:49:07,102 --> 00:49:09,366
Come on! To Rkudaya!
快点！往鲁库达亚！

520
00:49:09,471 --> 00:49:11,666
Come on! Let's go!
快点！快点！

521
00:49:12,607 --> 00:49:13,801
Fire!
发射！

522
00:49:18,046 --> 00:49:19,741
Chase them!
追击！

523
00:49:21,916 --> 00:49:22,746
Come on!
快！

524
00:49:23,885 --> 00:49:24,874
Come on!
快一点！

525
00:50:11,633 --> 00:50:14,329
Run in separate ways!
Let's meet up in Rkudaya!
分开跑…往鲁库达亚集合…

526
00:50:15,437 --> 00:50:17,962
Hurry up! Come on!
快点…快点…

527
00:50:35,790 --> 00:50:37,018
Awi, come on!
阿威，快！

528
00:50:37,125 --> 00:50:38,183
Here comes the airplane again!
飞机又来了…

529
00:50:46,835 --> 00:50:48,166
Why is Pihu still there?
比荷怎么还在那边？

530
00:50:50,772 --> 00:50:51,534
Come on!
快过去…

531
00:51:01,783 --> 00:51:03,546
Hurry up, Pihu!
比荷，快点！

532
00:51:03,651 --> 00:51:05,585
The bridge is collapsing!
桥要断了…

533
00:51:13,495 --> 00:51:15,360
Come on, the bridge is collapsing!
快一点…桥要倒下来了…

534
00:51:27,008 --> 00:51:28,942
Medic! Medic!
卫生兵！卫生兵！

535
00:51:29,043 --> 00:51:31,136
Hurry up!
走快一点…

536
00:51:38,953 --> 00:51:40,420
Hurry up!
走快一点…

537
00:51:42,223 --> 00:51:46,091
No matter which route we took
we were ambushed by them
不管哪个路线都会掉进他们的埋伏

538
00:51:46,194 --> 00:51:49,493
好像他们早就猜到我们的行动一样

539
00:51:49,597 --> 00:51:51,724
These savages are too good at this
这些凶蕃太厉害了

540
00:51:51,833 --> 00:51:53,994
We should ask for more reinforcements,
otherwise..
我们应该再增兵支援

541
00:51:54,102 --> 00:51:54,830
否则…

542
00:51:57,205 --> 00:52:00,697
With thousands of soldiers
and all kinds of powerful weapons
几千名火力强大的武装部队

543
00:52:01,743 --> 00:52:06,544
and you ended up being toyed with
by 300 savages?
竟被三百个生蕃给耍得团团转？

544
00:52:07,749 --> 00:52:12,812
Our airplanes have been patrolling
and bombing all this time
我们飞机在天空飞半天、轰半天…

545
00:52:12,921 --> 00:52:15,651
without killing any savage
为何就是打不到人…

546
00:52:16,758 --> 00:52:20,956
And you call yourselves military officers?
你们这些军官到底是干什么吃的？

547
00:52:33,141 --> 00:52:37,202
Those savages played hit and run
这些凶蕃打了就跑…

548
00:52:37,312 --> 00:52:39,906
They're like ghosts
像鬼一样…

549
00:52:40,648 --> 00:52:42,639
They ran easily
over the ragged mountain paths
在连站都站不稳的山路上…

550
00:52:42,750 --> 00:52:44,479
that we barely walked properly on
跑起来像飞的一样

551
00:52:44,586 --> 00:52:47,646
We never knew where they came from
or where they disappeared to
不知道从哪里来也不知道往哪里去

552
00:52:47,755 --> 00:52:50,019
They were so unpredictable
完全无法预料呀…

553
00:52:51,426 --> 00:52:53,394
For example, a kid named Pawan Nawi..
像一个叫巴万那威的孩子

554
00:52:54,462 --> 00:52:57,022
We saw him here the day before yesterday
but we found him here yesterday
前天在这个地方看到

555
00:52:57,131 --> 00:52:59,292
昨天又在这里被发现

556
00:52:59,400 --> 00:53:02,096
Then he was here today
今天又变到这个地方来了

557
00:53:03,338 --> 00:53:06,432
These are three different places
far away from one another
这些地方距离都那么远

558
00:53:06,541 --> 00:53:08,941
No one knows how he managed to do so
这孩子是怎么跑到的？

559
00:53:10,278 --> 00:53:12,007
…真的搞不懂！

560
00:53:21,155 --> 00:53:22,986
Pawan, have you fought any battle?
巴万，你们打仗了吗？

561
00:53:23,958 --> 00:53:25,186
Pawan! -Chief Mouna!
-巴万…
-莫那头目…

562
00:53:29,697 --> 00:53:34,464
Chief Dahdo Nokan from Gungu Clan
was killed in a battle
荷戈社的塔道诺干头目…

563
00:53:35,570 --> 00:53:37,697
战死了！

564
00:53:51,586 --> 00:53:53,850
Has anyone seen Mouna Rudo yet?
莫那鲁道出现了吗？

565
00:53:59,460 --> 00:54:00,484
Answer me! -No, sir
回答！

566
00:54:00,595 --> 00:54:01,459
没有…

567
00:54:02,730 --> 00:54:05,221
That old bastard!
这死老乌龟…

568
00:54:05,767 --> 00:54:07,894
He had the guts to revolt
but he dares not confront me personally
有种造反…

569
00:54:08,002 --> 00:54:11,665
却没种出来和我决一死战

570
00:54:11,773 --> 00:54:14,606
What kind of warrior is he?
What kind of chief is he?
算什么战士！算什么头目！

571
00:54:17,345 --> 00:54:18,710
Be quiet!
安静！

572
00:54:30,992 --> 00:54:33,290
They've got lines and lines of defense
and endless reinforcement
一道又一道的防线

573
00:54:33,394 --> 00:54:37,990
怎么切都切不断的支援线路…

574
00:54:39,701 --> 00:54:42,135
I can't believe those savages
would have battle plans so well-knit
这样粗鲁的野蛮人

575
00:54:43,104 --> 00:54:47,131
竟然有如此绵密的作战计划…

576
00:54:56,451 --> 00:54:59,511
Ask the high command to provide us
with gas bombs
向军司令部申请糜烂性炮弹！

577
00:54:59,620 --> 00:55:02,418
Gas bombs?
糜烂性炮弹？

578
00:55:06,361 --> 00:55:09,626
I wanted you to be civilized
叫你们文明…

579
00:55:09,731 --> 00:55:12,757
but you forced me to be savage
你们却逼我野蛮！

580
00:55:19,240 --> 00:55:22,073
You're Mouna Rudo
你是莫那鲁道…

581
00:55:25,079 --> 00:55:27,479
but I'm Kamada Yahiko
我可是鎌田弥彦！

582
00:55:28,850 --> 00:55:31,819
From now on..
从现在开始

583
00:55:31,919 --> 00:55:40,554
you're part of the Japanese
military and police forces
你们就属于大日本帝国军警队的一员

584
00:55:40,661 --> 00:55:44,563
You'll have to follow our wartime decrees
今后对军警的战地勒令要绝对服从

585
00:55:44,665 --> 00:55:47,156
Those of you who fight bravely
will be rewarded accordingly
对于勇武善战者…

586
00:55:47,268 --> 00:55:49,429
我们会给予奖赏

587
00:55:50,304 --> 00:55:52,204
But those of you
但是…

588
00:55:52,306 --> 00:55:58,836
who fail to take orders from
the Japanese police or run away
如果不遵从日本警察的命令…

589
00:55:58,946 --> 00:56:03,144
will be punished harshly by law
临阵脱逃者，绝对依法严办！

590
00:56:03,985 --> 00:56:05,350
Do you understand?
明白了没？

591
00:56:07,121 --> 00:56:11,080
Now I'm announcing
the bounties of head-hunting
我现在宣布猎首奖金…

592
00:56:15,797 --> 00:56:18,732
We'll give every one of you a gun
我们会发给每个人一把枪！

593
00:56:24,605 --> 00:56:28,701
Come and sign for it after this
等一下每个人都过来登记！

594
00:56:36,484 --> 00:56:37,610
A chief.. 150 to 200 dollars
头目…

595
00:56:38,619 --> 00:56:43,181
一百五十元到两百元不等…

596
00:56:43,324 --> 00:56:46,691
An able-bodied man, 100
壮丁…一百元！

597
00:56:49,163 --> 00:56:52,792
A woman, 30
妇女…三十元！

598
00:56:52,900 --> 00:56:55,835
A child, 20
小孩…二十元！

599
00:56:57,572 --> 00:56:59,267
And a special bounty for the head of..
…特别奖

600
00:57:09,217 --> 00:57:10,650
...Mouna Rudo!
莫那鲁道

601
00:57:27,368 --> 00:57:28,562
Gas bombs?
糜烂性炮弹？

602
00:57:34,909 --> 00:57:36,399
But sir,
报告…

603
00:57:37,411 --> 00:57:40,676
Gas bombs are still being experimented on
这种炸弹还在实验阶段…

604
00:57:40,781 --> 00:57:42,749
We don't know the effects yet
效果如何也还不知道…

605
00:57:43,417 --> 00:57:44,509
Yes, sir
是…

606
00:57:45,720 --> 00:57:47,244
Yes, sir
是…

607
00:57:47,788 --> 00:57:50,621
But currently it's not ready for use
…可是目前真的不适合…

608
00:57:50,725 --> 00:57:52,659
Yes, sir
是…

609
00:57:52,760 --> 00:57:53,419
Yes, sir
是…

610
00:58:52,653 --> 00:58:54,280
Come on!
快一点…

611
00:58:56,490 --> 00:58:57,889
Watan, you go that way!
瓦旦，你们往那边…

612
00:59:11,205 --> 00:59:11,967
Sapu!
萨布！

613
00:59:13,374 --> 00:59:15,274
I'm alright. They hit my sweet potatoes
我没事！地瓜挡着哪…

614
00:59:24,919 --> 00:59:26,978
Don't stop! Run!
不要停下来，快跑…

615
00:59:31,492 --> 00:59:33,756
Shoot! Shoot him!
快开枪…射他！

616
00:59:33,861 --> 00:59:35,192
Come on!
快！

617
00:59:42,837 --> 00:59:44,202
Out of the way!
不要挡路！

618
01:00:15,236 --> 01:00:16,669
Over there!
那边！在那边！

619
01:00:39,393 --> 01:00:41,122
A Seediq from Tgdaya! -Where?
-德克达亚人！
-在哪里？

620
01:00:41,228 --> 01:00:42,286
He's over there!
跑到那边了…

621
01:00:42,930 --> 01:00:43,919
Kill him!
杀了他！

622
01:01:47,161 --> 01:01:48,856
Burn it down!
烧掉…

623
01:02:43,818 --> 01:02:44,842
Temu!
泰目…

624
01:03:15,082 --> 01:03:16,640
Come on! Run!
快跑…快跑…

625
01:05:53,874 --> 01:05:55,102
Chief Mouna! It's me, Pawan
莫那头目

626
01:05:55,209 --> 01:05:56,437
我是巴万啊…

627
01:05:59,546 --> 01:06:00,911
Chief Mouna! It's me, Pawan Nawi
莫那头目…

628
01:06:01,015 --> 01:06:02,812
是我，巴万那威啊…

629
01:06:21,735 --> 01:06:23,066
Chief Mouna, we heard what Baso told you
莫那头目…

630
01:06:23,137 --> 01:06:25,799
我们有听到巴索和你说的话…

631
01:06:25,906 --> 01:06:30,138
We know that a large number of
Japanese soldiers have gathered in Suku Clan
大批日军已经由斯库社集结…

632
01:06:30,244 --> 01:06:32,940
Time for the decisive battle, isn't it?
是决战的时侯了吧！

633
01:06:39,753 --> 01:06:40,981
Chief Mouna, we have no family now
Why don't you let us fight?
莫那头目

634
01:06:41,088 --> 01:06:42,817
我们都已经没有家人了

635
01:06:42,923 --> 01:06:45,050
为什么你就不让我们去打仗呢？

636
01:06:45,159 --> 01:06:46,751
Like everyone else, none of us can sleep or eat
我们和大家一样…

637
01:06:46,860 --> 01:06:50,318
每天吃不饱、睡不饱

638
01:06:50,431 --> 01:06:54,424
and we don't want to be killed by gas bombs
可是我们真的不想被毒炸弹炸死…

639
01:07:00,774 --> 01:07:02,139
Chief Mouna, look at the tattoos on our faces
We're not children anymore
莫那头目

640
01:07:02,242 --> 01:07:03,709
你看我们脸上的图腾

641
01:07:03,811 --> 01:07:05,745
我们已经不是孩子了…

642
01:07:05,846 --> 01:07:07,507
Please let us fight the Japanese
like everybody else
你就让我们和大家一样

643
01:07:07,614 --> 01:07:09,775
用力和日本人打一仗吧！

644
01:07:13,153 --> 01:07:15,519
Then I can have a good, long rest
我想好好睡个觉…

645
01:07:16,690 --> 01:07:20,148
We're so tired
我们好累…

646
01:07:20,260 --> 01:07:23,195
We're really exhausted
我们真的好累…

647
01:07:44,351 --> 01:07:45,340
My children, do you remember
where our ancestors came from?
孩子们…

648
01:07:46,220 --> 01:07:48,245
还记得我们的祖先从哪来的吗？

649
01:07:48,355 --> 01:07:49,185
Mt. White Stone.. -I know. Once upon a time...
-Let me tell the story!
白石山…

650
01:07:49,289 --> 01:07:50,017
-我知道…从前…
-我来讲…

651
01:07:50,124 --> 01:07:51,352
Quiet!
安静！

652
01:07:53,026 --> 01:07:54,391
Can't you wait?
急什么？

653
01:07:56,363 --> 01:08:00,163
A good hunter should learn how to lie in wait!
好猎人要学会安静等待！

654
01:08:02,302 --> 01:08:03,826
Pawan, you tell the story
巴万你讲…

655
01:08:12,246 --> 01:08:14,271
Once upon a time on Mt. White Stone
there was a big tree called Pusu Qhuni
从前从前在白石山上…

656
01:08:14,381 --> 01:08:19,512
有一棵大树，名叫波索康夫尼…

657
01:08:19,620 --> 01:08:21,281
The tree trunk was half wood, half stone
他的树身…

658
01:08:21,388 --> 01:08:25,324
一半是木头，另一半是岩石…

659
01:08:25,425 --> 01:08:32,627
One day, a boy and a girl were born
from the tree trunk
有一天，他的树身生下了一男一女

660
01:08:32,733 --> 01:08:35,634
Then the couple gave birth to lots of children
后来这男女又生下了许多的孩子…

661
01:08:35,736 --> 01:08:39,729
and here we are, the Seediq Bale
就是我们…真正的赛德克人…

662
01:09:07,634 --> 01:09:10,102
Let me help you, Awi
阿威，我帮你吧！

663
01:09:13,640 --> 01:09:15,904
It's ready, my brother
兄弟，准备好了…

664
01:09:40,400 --> 01:09:41,458
I'm ready
可以了…

665
01:09:47,241 --> 01:09:50,176
Let go, my brother
放手吧！兄弟…

666
01:09:50,277 --> 01:09:51,972
Pihu Walis..
比荷瓦力斯…

667
01:09:52,913 --> 01:09:54,244
Don't go! -Let go!
-你不要走…
-放手吧！

668
01:09:54,915 --> 01:09:56,849
I'm in great pain
我真的好痛苦…

669
01:09:56,950 --> 01:09:58,611
Don't go
不要走…

670
01:10:27,547 --> 01:10:29,071
I'm not fighting anymore! No more!
我不要打了…

671
01:10:29,182 --> 01:10:30,706
不打了！

672
01:10:30,817 --> 01:10:32,250
No more!
不打了…

673
01:10:32,352 --> 01:10:33,341
You son of a bitch!
混蛋！

674
01:10:34,688 --> 01:10:36,622
What do you mean by not fighting?
-Kojima!
你说不打了是什么意思？

675
01:10:36,723 --> 01:10:37,382
小岛…

676
01:10:37,491 --> 01:10:39,652
What do you mean by that? -Kojima!
-不打了是什么意思？
-小岛…

677
01:10:39,760 --> 01:10:40,727
Pick it up! Pick up your gun!
捡起来…

678
01:10:40,827 --> 01:10:41,885
把枪给我捡起来！

679
01:10:41,995 --> 01:10:43,519
Out of my way! -Temu!
-走开…
-铁木…

680
01:10:44,064 --> 01:10:44,962
Temu!
铁木…

681
01:10:48,869 --> 01:10:52,862
We fight to offer blood sacrifice to our ancestors
我们战斗…是为了血祭祖灵

682
01:10:53,607 --> 01:10:57,008
not to revenge the death of your family
不是替你死去的家人报复！

683
01:11:15,729 --> 01:11:17,253
Temu, I know what you saw
铁木…

684
01:11:17,364 --> 01:11:20,162
我知道你看见了什么…

685
01:11:20,267 --> 01:11:24,499
but Mouna Rudo has spread the word
asking for your head
但莫那鲁道已经放话要拿你人头了…

686
01:11:24,604 --> 01:11:27,630
This is not the time to make trouble
现在不是惹麻烦的时侯…

687
01:11:46,293 --> 01:11:47,954
Father, you told me only the bravest warriors
父亲…

688
01:11:48,061 --> 01:11:51,497
你说过，最美丽的猎场…

689
01:11:51,598 --> 01:11:55,932
are qualified to guard
the most beautiful hunting ground
只有最勇敢的战士才够资格去守护

690
01:11:56,036 --> 01:11:57,936
So that's why Mouna Rudo's people and we
have to fight one another constantly
那我们和莫那鲁道他们…

691
01:11:58,038 --> 01:12:00,700
是不是要不断地互相战斗…

692
01:12:00,807 --> 01:12:06,439
to prove to our ancestors
that we're the bravest warriors?
才能向祖灵证明自己是最勇武的战士？

693
01:12:12,452 --> 01:12:14,977
So in the eternal hunting ground
at the other end of the rainbow
那在彩虹顶端的美丽猎场里…

694
01:12:15,088 --> 01:12:18,524
we'll become allies forever
and there would be no more hatred?
大家是不是就成为永远的战友…

695
01:12:18,625 --> 01:12:21,150
不会再有仇恨了？

696
01:12:23,463 --> 01:12:24,760
Yeah, I guess so
…应该是吧！

697
01:12:25,699 --> 01:12:28,896
I want to fight them if possible
to prove my bravery
如果可以的话我也想和他们打一仗

698
01:12:29,002 --> 01:12:31,562
来证明我的武勇…

699
01:12:33,573 --> 01:12:34,835
Sleep, my boy
快睡吧！

700
01:14:02,963 --> 01:14:04,726
Is that our man?
那是我们的人吗？

701
01:14:08,301 --> 01:14:15,366
Get him! He's a savage! Come on!
快点拦下那个蕃人…快点…

702
01:14:16,309 --> 01:14:17,901
Stop!
不要跑！

703
01:14:19,379 --> 01:14:20,505
Stop!
不要跑！

704
01:14:21,114 --> 01:14:21,978
What's wrong?
怎么了？

705
01:14:22,082 --> 01:14:24,448
A savage ran over the suspension bridge
into the woods
有个蕃人从吊桥跑进树林里了！

706
01:14:27,687 --> 01:14:29,382
From there? -Yes, from there
-从那边吗？
-对，那边！

707
01:14:31,391 --> 01:14:32,449
Gather up!
集合！

708
01:14:32,559 --> 01:14:34,151
Gather up, First Team!
第一部队集合…

709
01:14:34,261 --> 01:14:35,489
Gather up!
集合…

710
01:14:35,595 --> 01:14:36,926
First Team!
第一部队！

711
01:14:41,801 --> 01:14:43,098
Stop!
不要跑！

712
01:14:50,577 --> 01:14:52,169
Good
很好…

713
01:14:52,279 --> 01:14:54,042
Come closer..
再过来…再过来一点…

714
01:14:54,147 --> 01:14:55,842
Good
很好…

715
01:14:55,949 --> 01:14:57,814
Stop, you little bastard
停下来…你这个家伙…

716
01:15:15,602 --> 01:15:17,194
Aoki!
青木…

717
01:15:17,304 --> 01:15:19,033
Okubo! -Aoki!
-大久保…
-青木…

718
01:15:19,139 --> 01:15:21,266
Where are you? -Aoki!
-你们在哪里？
-青木…

719
01:15:21,374 --> 01:15:23,934
Okubo! -Aoki!
-大久保…
-青木…

720
01:15:24,044 --> 01:15:29,243
Aoki! Okubo!
青木…大久保…

721
01:15:30,984 --> 01:15:32,747
Let's split up and search!
大家散开来找…

722
01:15:35,689 --> 01:15:37,122
Aoki!
青木…

723
01:15:37,824 --> 01:15:40,850
Okubo! Aoki!
大久保…青木…

724
01:15:40,961 --> 01:15:42,258
Stop!
停…

725
01:15:42,629 --> 01:15:43,755
Everybody, stop!
所有人停下来！

726
01:16:22,035 --> 01:16:25,368
These Seediqs from Tgdaya
are driven crazy by hunger
这些德克达亚真的是饿疯了…

727
01:16:28,708 --> 01:16:30,073
Okubo!
大久保…

728
01:16:31,711 --> 01:16:32,700
Where are you?
你们在哪里？

729
01:16:36,249 --> 01:16:37,944
Aoki!
青木…

730
01:16:40,520 --> 01:16:42,147
Where are you?
你在哪里？

731
01:16:42,255 --> 01:16:43,381
Okubo!
大久保…

732
01:16:45,959 --> 01:16:47,256
Okubo!
大久保…

733
01:16:48,328 --> 01:16:49,158
Someone's there!
那边有人！

734
01:16:49,262 --> 01:16:51,059
Where? -In that tree!
-在哪里？
-在那棵树上！

735
01:16:51,731 --> 01:16:52,527
Get down!
趴下…

736
01:16:54,401 --> 01:16:57,564
Get down! -Hide!
-趴下…
-躲起来！

737
01:17:07,881 --> 01:17:09,143
Machineguns?
机枪？

738
01:17:09,249 --> 01:17:11,183
Get the mortars!
迫击炮过来！

739
01:17:11,284 --> 01:17:13,752
Signalman! Signalman!
通讯兵…通讯兵…

740
01:17:38,745 --> 01:17:41,145
Here come the savages!
凶蕃打来了…

741
01:17:41,247 --> 01:17:44,273
Here come the savages!
凶蕃打来了…

742
01:17:46,653 --> 01:17:48,086
Here come the savages!
凶蕃打来了…

743
01:19:03,596 --> 01:19:04,688
It's you then
就是你了！

744
01:19:07,400 --> 01:19:09,698
Chief, Baso is hit!
头目，巴索被打中了！

745
01:19:09,836 --> 01:19:12,168
Baso! Baso!
巴索…巴索…

746
01:19:12,272 --> 01:19:14,240
Baso!
巴索…

747
01:19:21,481 --> 01:19:24,279
We're in the Mehebu Forest
这里是马赫坡森林…

748
01:19:26,052 --> 01:19:27,781
Baso! Baso!
巴索…巴索…

749
01:19:27,887 --> 01:19:30,822
Baso, are you alright?
巴索…你怎么了…

750
01:19:30,924 --> 01:19:32,391
Baso, be still!
巴索…你不要动…

751
01:19:32,492 --> 01:19:33,481
Retreat!
撤退！

752
01:19:34,727 --> 01:19:36,251
Come on, retreat!
快点撤退…
