Get out!
Get out! Hurry!
Inside the hut! Come on!
Get in! Come on!
Out of here!
Don't come in! Get out!
Come on! Run!
Yes, sir
Is it Mehebu Clan?
Aim all cannons at the Mehebu Forest
End this battle before the sun's out
Tado! Kill me!
Come on!
It hurts so badly!
Out of the way!
Cut my head off! You hear me?
Get off him!
It's beautiful
So beautiful
Stop firing please
They ran away
Fight till you drop! Seediq Bale!
Fire the cannons! Fire!
We're under attack!
You damned Japanese! Get out of our territory!
You bastards! Get out!
That's one favor I did you Mehebus today
helping you drive our the intruders
Out of my way! Let me kill them!
Temu, give me the bullets!
Come on! Look out!
Climb up there!
Sine! Sine!
Sine!
Stop!
Come back here!
You take care of him!
Load the guns! Come on!
Pawan?
You Japanese are finished!
Quick! - Catch him!
Off with his head!
Stop!
Don't let him slip away!
Mouna Rudo!
Stop running!
Kill until our blood runs out!
Cut off their heads like true warriors!
The heavenly home of our ancestors,
here we come!
I'm a chief, not your little brother
Iyung! Iyung!
Don't touch it, lyung
Iyung!
What are you doing? Move!
Look out! It's falling down!
Pawan! Get out of there!
Pawan, get out now!
Pawan!
Iyung! Iyung!
Are you alright?
Pawan, I've got a good gun
What's wrong?
Batu! -Dakis!
Move!
Ubus!
Come on! The Japanese are out!
Watch out over there!
There's one behind him!
Don't go there!
Stop!
Bomb!
So you're Mouna Rudo
Now I see you clearly
Tado, how do we dodge those cannons?
Chief, let this ghost lead the way
Fire!
Look!
Cherry blossoms everywhere!
(Those who come forward voluntarily
will be spared)
(Come to the shelters to surrender)
l'm crossing the rainbow bridge
l am Mouna Rudo
Look at the road l've trodden
No one's ever gonna stop us
The determined warriors
We're home with our enemy's heads
We're true warriors, like budding pine leaves
You must be starved
and you must be exhausted
It's time to decide your future
If you want to take your own life, do it
If you want to turn yourself in, go ahead
If you want to keep fighting..
Tado..
My dear son..
The hero of Mehebu Clan
Lead them to fight
until you use up all your bullets
Father! -Chief..
Warriors, forgive me
Forgive me
I don't want the Japanese to insult me
in front of my people
Forgive me
I'll be waiting for you on the mountain peak
Let's cross the rainbow bridge together
to the eternal hunting ground
Father?
Go..Seediq Bale!
Chief Mouna?
Bakan,
bring over everyone from the chief's family
Iwan, go back and tell our people in the cavern
that those who don't want to surrender
may as well kill themselves
I want to fight!
Me too! -It's over!
Mouna!
Mouna, where's your ancestral spirit?
Where is it?
There could be greater suffering if you survived
Wipe your face clean
Thank you, women and children
for sacrificing yourselves
to complete the men's souls
She's awake!
That savage woman is awake!
Officer Kabasoa!
What's going on?
-That savage woman is awake
Is it Mahung? -Yes, sir
Excuse me!
Let me through!
Mahung! Mahung!
Mahung..
I'm Kabasawa. I've been to your house
Do you remember me, Mahung?
Why did you save me?
My husband and children are waiting for me
Mahong..
100 dollars
Son of a bitch! What are you doing?
Don't put it on the desk!
What are you looking at? Next!
It's only a child. You can't get 100 for it
Get it off!
It's Temu Mouna from Truwan Clan
What child?
Don't you see the tattoos on his face?
Put it over there! What a nuisance!
It's Tanah Robe, the Boarung chief
One of you from Gungu Clan killed our chief
This one is Pawan Nawi from Mehebu Clan
Ukan! Tado!
Where are you?
Where is that father going?
The father carrying a child on his back
is setting out to shoot the two suns in the sky
They go on and on for a long way
The child grows up
The father dies at an old age
The child takes his father's bow and arrows
The child follows his father's footsteps
toward the rising suns
He gets there at last
The child gets there at last
The child shoots a sun down with an arrow
The sun loses its rays
The dead sun becomes the moon
He's a sun-shooting hero
The sun-shooting hero is returning home
The sun-shooting hero has come a long,
long way
The sun-shooting hero is home at last
But the hero is already gray-headed
l am drunk today
l saw him on the way
The boy from the freezing winter
A fair-skinned boy like a budding pine leaf
Let's dance together
Let's enjoy ourselves
l'm drunk today
Young girls, let's dance together
Surrender? Why should we surrender?
We've had our enemy's sake wine
Doesn't that mean conciliation?
Why do we have to surrender?
Tado... -Say no more!
Come on, drink with me
Mahung, my little sister...
it's much easier for me to die
than for you to go on living
But you must endure
and have lots of children
Teach them everything
about the pride of our father
Let your children have even more children
and more and more..
Mahung, have lots of children
Raise them up to be proud Seediqs
and to live on with pride
Do you understand?
Father, Baso and I..
along with all our fallen people
will be watching over you
from the rainbow bridge
Look! The sun is so beautiful
Oh, my wife!
ls the wine ready now?
Here l come, my wife and children
On my way to the heavenly home
of our ancestors
Wait a little longer for me please
l'll be seeing you soon
We're already on our way
Oh my wife and children, wait a little longer
Wait for us on the way
to the heavenly home of our ancestors
Oh my wife and children, wait a little longer
We're almost there
We're about to cross the road
We'll be seeing you in no time
Wait for us on the way
to the heavenly home of our ancestors
Oh my wife and children, wait a little longer
We're almost there
We're about to cross the road
We'll be seeing you in no time
(Pihu Sapu was beaten up to death)
(in the detention house after he got caught)
(Tado Mouna and the last surviving warriors
all committed suicide )
(Mouna Rudo disappeared without a trace )
300 warriors against thousands of soldiers
Those survived the battle
killed themselves eventually
Why did I see
in such a remote mountain area in Taiwan
the bushido of samurais
that died over a century ago in Japan?
Is it because the cherry blossoms here
are far too red?
No, these flowers have bloomed early this year
It isn't the season of cherry blossoms yet
(After the incident...)
(Kojima Genji instigated the Seediqs
from Toda)
(to revenge the death of their chief
Temu Walis )
(by killing all the remaining
defenseless tribesmen)
(staying in the shelter during the night)
Out of the way!
(The few surviving tribesmen were forced)
Hurry up!
(to relocate to a compound along
Peikang River)
Out of the way!
(where the Japanese
could monitor them easily )
Out of the way!
(where the Japanese
could monitor them easily )
(They burned down all their remaining houses )
(before they left)
(Four years later...)
(Mouna Rudo's remains were found)
(inside a cavern,
somewhere deep in the mountains )
(Half of his body rotted to skeleton)
(while the other half
was weathered to a mummy )
(In the following year...)
(the Japanese publicly displayed
his remains and weapons )
(in a wooden crate at the exhibition
celebrating the completion)
(of Nenggao City Hall construction project)
Ah, it's for real
(After that,
his remains disappeared once again)
l'll be arriving soon
(After that,
his remains disappeared once again)
l'll be arriving soon
at the heavenly home of our ancestors
Yes, it's for real
Reminisce the people from the past
Here l am
(After the second disappearance )
(Mouna Rudo's remains
were recovered 39 years later)
l used to guard
these mountains and forests bravely
(Mouna Rudo's remains
were recovered 39 years later)
l used to guard
these mountains and forests bravely
(in the specimen room
of the College of Medicine )
l used to guard
these mountains and forests bravely
(in National Taiwan University )
These are our mountains
Escorted by his offspring)
These are our creeks
(Escorted by his offspring)
(after 43 years, he finally returned
to his hometown Wushe )
We're the true Seediq Bale
(after 43 years, he finally returned
to his hometown Wushe )
We're the true Seediq Bale
(to be buried properly )
We go hunting in the mountains
We share food in our clan
We fetch water from the creeks
l'm willing to give my life for these
Oh, creek! Be quiet!
Sisin babblers are singing
Sing us a beautiful song please
Sing for our people
a song of our ancestral spirit
(List of Angel Fund contributors)
l'm willing to give my life too
When the lightening rifts the rock
a rainbow appears
and a proud man emerges
A proud man emerges
Who is this man so proud?
lt's your offspring
A Seediq Bale
Once upon a time on Mt. White Stone
there was a big tree called Pusu Qhuni
The tree trunk was half wood, half stone
One day, a boy and a girl were born
from the tree trunk
Then the couple gave birth to lots of children
and here we are, the Seediq Bale
Behold! The beautiful rainbow over the hilltop
My wife and children,
have you brewed the wine?
Drink it!
The wine we offer to our ancestors' spirits
Behold! What beautiful rainbow!
My ancestors are calling me
My wife and children! Are you on your way
to meet our ancestors spirits?
We should get going too
Stand still,
our people who keep the bloodline going
We will be proud like a true Seediq
Our bodiless spirits will be watching over you
from the rainbow bridge
Tell every child to live on forever
To live on like a true Seediq
Our bodiless spirits
will keep you company in the woods
Behold! What beautiful rainbow!
My ancestors are calling me
My wife and children! Are you on your way
to meet our ancestors spirits?
We should be on our way too
Stand still,
our people who keep the bloodline going
We will be proud like a true Seediq
Our bodiless spirits will be watching over you
from the rainbow bridge
Tell every child to live on forever
To live on like a true Seediq
Our bodiless spirits
will keep you company in the woods
Look! -Drink! Drink!
What a beautiful sky!
-We should be on our way
Look! -Drink! Drink!
What a beautiful sky!
-We should be on our way
Children!
Did you see that? We see the rainbow
We see the rainbow