-
-=
-= L
-= LU
-= LUO
-= LUO M
-= LUO MA
-= LUO MAD
-= LUO MADE
-= LUO MADE D
-= LUO MADE DV
-= LUO MADE DVD
-= LUO MADE DVD =
-= LUO MADE DVD =-
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
You've soiled me with blood
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Be still!
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Get out!
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Who the hell let you in?
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
Don't you know
this is the Mehebu hunting ground?
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
I don't care if it's your hunting ground or theirs
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
because everything here
belongs to us Japanese now
I hate the Japanese no less than you do
(Touch your angry forehead)
But do you realize that
we're going to die after all this
and all our people will be wiped out?
(Touch your angry forehead)
Mouna, you must keep the intruders
away from our clan
(Touch your angry forehead)
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
Inform the chiefs of all the 12 clans
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
Tomorrow morning..
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
we're going to gather in Wushe
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
and offer a blood sacrifice to our ancestors
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
My children! What are you doing?
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
What on earth are you doing, my children?
(How much pain
do you swallow to sing the ancestral songs?)
Tanah, why are you doing this?
(How much shame
do you swallow to speak out your minds?)
Tanah, why are you doing this?
(How much shame
do you swallow to speak out your minds?)
It was Mouna Rudo's idea
(How much shame
do you swallow to speak out your minds?)
(How much regret
do you swallow to fulfill your dreams?)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(Oh, my children!
What exactly is wrong with you?)
(Your dreams are vast like a blue ocean)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(We, the Hanaoka brothers
are forced to leave this world)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(The savages are massacring the Japanese )
(bringing forth a situation out of control)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(Now we are driven to bay by the savages )
(and have no other choices )
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(It is 9 o'clock on the morning
of October 27th, 1930)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(The savages have already
occupied most of this region)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(The commissioner and all his subordinates )
(have been killed in the school)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
Warriors of The Rainbow II : Rainbow Bridge
Make a phone call!
The Wushe savages
are massacring the Japanese
Make a phone call! -What happened?
Make a phone call!
Hurry! -How did it come to this?
Hurry up and call! -What happened?
What the hell?
-The Wushe savages have revolted
The Wushe savages have revolted
Hurry up and call!
Phone!
Yes?
What?
The Wushe savages
are massacring the Japanese?
Get everybody here right now
Massacre...
-Gather all the policemen right away!
The Wushe savages are hunting heads!
-All the policemen gather up!
All the Japanese in the mountains
have been killed
And all the police stations
have been burned down
Only one of the Japanese survived
Go back home! Come on! Hurry up!
The Wushe savages are coming down
to kill more people
They're coming to kill us
Come on, everyone, hide!
Don't get caught -You bastard!
What are you talking about?
The Japanese knew already
The savages are likely
to charge all the way into Puli
We're afraid even the plainsmen
might seize the opportunity to join in the revolt
This is an emergency
All county governments please send in
their armies and police forces
to lay siege to Wushe from Hualien and Tunghih
And I want to know if the Governor-general
can dispatch the troops
from Taipei and Tainan right away
The Japanese this way, to the sugar refinery
Come on! The family members
of the Japanese to the sugar refinery
Come on! Hurry up! Put all the stuff away
This way! Hurry up!
The family members of the soldiers
to the feedstock department
The family members of the police
to the mechanical department
The family members of the officeholders
to sugar extraction department! Come on!
You too. Come on!
Come on!
-Savages will always be savages
You're nothing but beasts
I never know what you savages are thinking
It's time for me to teach you a lesson
Speak Japanese!
No one understands your savage language
Your tribesmen have revolted
No more peaceful life for you
It's chilly!
Come on, Pihu!
Get a larger chunk of wood
Good morning
Chief!
It's chilly out here
Why aren't you inside the house by the fire
instead of weaving this bag?
It's the first snow of this winter
How could I miss it?
The snow has come early this year
Takun, what are you doing?
Takun!
Temu, your son will perform well
on sports day again, won't he?
Takun, what's going on?
You've got blood all over your body
Takun!
What's wrong with you?
Chief, today Mouna Rudo from Mehebu Clan
led the Seediqs from Tgdaya
to offer a blood sacrifice to our ancestors
They've occupied the whole Wushe region
We Seediqs from Toda should join them as well
Let's kill this Japanese man!
No way!
Kojima is our friend
He's a good Japanese, not a bad one
Go away!
Temu!
You're the chief of all the Seediqs from Toda
Why don't you drive the Japanese away
and lead your own people?
Why should you expect
the good Japanese to rule us?
He's right! We don't have any Japanese friends
Don't come any closer!
Kojima, we'll let you answer the phone
But do you have the guts to do it?
Have I been bad to you?
Kojima..
Is this how you repay me?
I can't fight back if you want me dead
But the Japanese government
will do anything to punish you
We might as well die together
Kojima!
We have airplanes, but do you?
We have machineguns and cannons,
but do you?
Think about
how Mouna Rudo used to insult you
Last time when we're out hunting
they threatened to kill you all
Don't you remember?
Are you willing to die
with them in the battlefield?
Temu Walis,
you won't have the chance to grow up
Hello?
Take it easy! There's more!
Hurry up!
Come on!
Chief Mouna?
Thank you
Thank you. Thank you all
Thank you -Come on!
Thank you
Tado!
Sapu, where's my father?
What's going on? Why did they want us back?
Father, why did you give up Hakaw Supeitei?
So you're back!
Come on, let's go back to our clan
Back to our clan? You're giving up here as well?
Tado, you can't think like the Japanese
when fighting them
You have to think like the wind
The wind?
The wind is invisible
Baso, give up everything, everyone
and come back to the clan with me
Japanese airplanes!
Over there! -Fire!
Shoot it! Come on!
Are you so scared?
Are you really so scared?
I went head hunting for the first time
when I was 15
I was so nervous
that my arms and legs were trembling
But my eyes were sharp as arrows
As soon as I cut the enemy's head off
I forgot what it was like to be scared
because I knew I'd go back to my clan
to feast and celebrate, being treated as a hero
because I knew that all my people
male and female, young and old
would respect me for my bravery
However, it's different this time
We successfully offered a blood sacrifice
to our ancestors today
and are now qualified
to stride over the rainbow bridge
but what awaits us now is not a festive feast
but to choose how we die
Run the electricity!
Before we initiated the revolt
you knew it'd turn out like this, didn't you?
My children..
...don't be scared
You've been very brave today
Our ancestors' spirits have seen it all
But the battle to come is the real one
It's a battle that will terrify the invaders
Someone's here!
Sisin babblers in the forests
are driving off the scavenging crows
The rainbow will be more beautiful
in the sunlight after the rain
It's a bunch of Hans from Wushe
Lock them all up!
My children..
...don't be afraid
Our ancestors' spirits know we're good warriors
guarding our hunting grounds
The blood stains on your hands can prove it
Every one of you is a Seediq Bale
Remember, you have to be proud
Let's cross the rainbow bridge together
Nobody's guarding here
Not a single soul on this path
How could it be?
Advance!
Wait!
Stop! Halt!
Don't rush uphill
I know these savages all too well
What a chilly night!
It's warm here
Savages!
Hold the fire!
l'm trekking over the high mountains
The creek water is so thick and muddy
l can't help but shed my tears
l'm walking along a wide road
He's asleep
Ichiro?
Today is our wedding anniversary
You remember, don't you?
We're walking on
with perseverance and determination
We can't fall asleep anymore
Let's go back to the heavenly home
of our ancestors
Kojima!
Long time no see
Captain!
Let me introduce you, Captain
This is the chief of Tnbarah Clan, Temu Walis
Got a good head on his shoulders
Kojima?
I heard all your family were killed in the venue?
We will seek revenge
Attack!
Officer, nothing here
Officer Goto!
What the hell are these savages up to?
The Japanese are coming!
Look behind you -Yeah
This clan is over here
This clan is over there
Behind them is a creek
Where do the Hans live? -The Hans..
We're under attack! Duck!
Hide!
Awata! Awata!
Contact the Oizumi Squad
and find out where they are now
This is Wushe Substation
This is Oizumi Squad
We're now by Suku Creek
We're ambushed by the savages.
We need back up
We're stuck in the creek water
Oizumi Squad..
Captain?
Assemble a banzai squad for a suicide charge
Where is Yamada Police Squad?
Charge!
Pihu, let's go!
Watch out! Dodge!
Duck! Seek cover!
The women and children
from Boarung Clan are all here
Come on, let's go!
Have you packed up enough clothes, Mahung?
Yes, I have
Pawan, you kids know how to get there
Take the Boarung women and children along
with those of us that are ready
Baso, I'm no longer a child
Don't let the dogs follow us
We don't have enough food
Mahung, are you ready? Is it heavy?
Mahung, you go ahead with Pawan and others
I'll wait for Sapu
Why is everyone in here?
Mother, don't touch that!
You're out of your minds!
The men in this house have all gone mad
Go ahead to Paran Clan, Obing
No!
Jiro, let me stay with you
Jiro!
Let go of me!
-All pregnant women go to Paran Clan
Auntie, I'm the wife of a policeman
but I'm the daughter of the Gungu Chief as well
Auntie, let go of me!
Give birth to your child in Paran Clan
Jiro! I want to stay with you!
I don't want to go there, Auntie!
Give birth to your child in Paran Clan
They're all pregnant
The Japanese won't harm them
Pawan!
What is it?
The cavern is right up ahead
You can carry these over by yourselves
We have to go now
But where to?
No, Mother! -Grandmother!
Mother! -Grandmother!
What are you doing?
Mother, don't!
Grandmother! -What are you doing?
Chief Mouna and others will be here soon
Grandmother! -Mother!
You'll have to fight the Japanese for a long time
There's not enough food for all of us
What are you talking about?
Chief Mouna told us we're going to
fight our decisive battle soon
Grandmother!
Pawan!
I'm so glad that you're a warrior now
guarding our hunting grounds
We'll be waiting for you
at the other end of the rainbow bridge
You'll be meeting us
after you finish your glorious battles
Stop following us!
Fight for your hunting grounds -Mother!
Grandmother, don't you want me anymore?
Mother!
Pawan, please tell my husband Watan
that I'll have the wine ready for him
at the other end of the rainbow bridge
Watan is building up huts in the cavern
You can go tell him yourself
Lubi! Lubi!
Stop following us! -Mother!
Don't follow us! -Mother, don't!
Please... -Mother!
Don't cry -Grandmother!
Listen to me..
you're a grownup man now
Go on!
Grandmother! -To the battlefield!
Fight for your hunting grounds!
-Grandmother!
To the battlefield!
Grandmother!
Mother! -Grandmother!
Mother!
Don't go, Mother! -Grandmother!
Mother..
With tears in my eyes
l'm walking along a wide road
l beseech you
Tell me if your hearts are at peace
Oh, poor innocent children
What's the matter with you?
We're really exhausted
Hanako?
You look just as pretty
as you were on our wedding day
Good boy! Close your eyes!
My child, let's go together
Jiro?
Are we the subjects of Japan's Mikado?
Or the descendants of the Seediq ancestors?
Do it
Cut it up and end your conflicts
right here and now
We don't have to go anywhere once we're dead
Let's both be free wandering spirits
Thank you
This way please, General
This is Officer Kabasoa, sir
He's a local policeman
and he knows the Wushe savages very well
Then why are you still alive?
He was not there when the incident happened
General, according to our investigation
there are six clans involved in the revolt
over 300 warriors in all
Warriors?
You call them 'warriors'
Each of these clans took actions separately
at dawn and annihilated
the local police stations
Then they got together to besiege Wushe
That's why we don't think it incidental
They had been planning it carefully
from the beginning
Planning it carefully?
Mr. Kabasoa?
Don't you think
you're overestimating these savages?
General, all our reinforcements
were under fatal attacks yesterday
...including here
This is nothing but animal-like savagery
Once the rain stops,
we'll besiege them immediately
Yes, sir!
(Headquarters of Kamada Detachment)
Chief,
are we going for the decisive battle tomorrow?
Ah, it hurts!
Chief, the wounds are still fresh
Pawan, you're not a child anymore
Chief, can we fight the decisive battle now?
What's happening?
Give me the gun!
Hurry up!
Let's go!
Be careful!
Go over there! Be careful!
Stop! The savages!
Stop running!
Over there!
What the hell?
Fire!
Retreat! All retreat!
Hurry up and run!
Seek covers! -Down there!
Signalman, call for reinforcements
Retreat downhill! Hide!
Out of the way!
Watch out!
Quite slippery here
Are you alright?
Halt, everyone!
Jump!
Machine gun!
Step back! -Take aim!
You're aiming too high! Hold on to your guns!
Come on, fire it,
Sapu! What are you waiting for?
I can't fire it
Move over! I'll do it!
Come on! Hurry up!
What the hell? Fell asleep or something?
Over there! Come on!
He's gone!
If I aim at the rock deliberately
will the bullet bounce off
and hit the officer over there?
Why don't you give it a try?
No, it won't
Have you two got too many bullets?
No, but that is a military officer
with a katana sword
Chief, Tado robbed a couple of machineguns
Chief Mouna asked us to bring you one and..
here's the ammunition and..
and this bag of sweet potatoes
Kids nowadays are so weak
Look how they pant with so little running
Do you know how to use it?
I don't think this machinegun works
Why did you give me one that doesn't work?
That damned Mouna!
Chief Dahdo..
My Paran relatives told me..
that your entire family committed suicide
Chief Dahdo, a bigger and more powerful army
is coming our way
They have lots of cannons
Pawan, when I was young
I was no less strong or brave
than your Mehebu Chief Mouna Rudo
you understand?
Awi, lead the group and retreat to Rkudaya
Chief!
Chief! Chief!
Retreat! To Rkudaya!
Give it to me! Let's go!
Retreat to Rkudaya! Our chief's dead!
Come on!
Pihu, come on!
Retreat to Rkudaya!
Come on! To Rkudaya!
Come on! Let's go!
Fire!
Chase them!
Come on!
Run in separate ways!
Let's meet up in Rkudaya!
Hurry up! Come on!
Awi, come on!
Here comes the airplane again!
Why is Pihu still there?
Come on!
Hurry up, Pihu!
The bridge is collapsing!
Come on, the bridge is collapsing!
Medic! Medic!
Hurry up!
No matter which route we took
we were ambushed by them
These savages are too good at this
We should ask for more reinforcements,
otherwise..
With thousands of soldiers
and all kinds of powerful weapons
and you ended up being toyed with
by 300 savages?
Our airplanes have been patrolling
and bombing all this time
without killing any savage
And you call yourselves military officers?
Those savages played hit and run
They're like ghosts
They ran easily
over the ragged mountain paths
that we barely walked properly on
We never knew where they came from
or where they disappeared to
They were so unpredictable
For example, a kid named Pawan Nawi..
We saw him here the day before yesterday
but we found him here yesterday
Then he was here today
These are three different places
far away from one another
No one knows how he managed to do so
Pawan, have you fought any battle?
Pawan! -Chief Mouna!
Chief Dahdo Nokan from Gungu Clan
was killed in a battle
Has anyone seen Mouna Rudo yet?
Answer me! -No, sir
That old bastard!
He had the guts to revolt
but he dares not confront me personally
What kind of warrior is he?
What kind of chief is he?
Be quiet!
They've got lines and lines of defense
and endless reinforcement
I can't believe those savages
would have battle plans so well-knit
Ask the high command to provide us
with gas bombs
Gas bombs?
I wanted you to be civilized
but you forced me to be savage
You're Mouna Rudo
but I'm Kamada Yahiko
From now on..
you're part of the Japanese
military and police forces
You'll have to follow our wartime decrees
Those of you who fight bravely
will be rewarded accordingly
But those of you
who fail to take orders from
the Japanese police or run away
will be punished harshly by law
Do you understand?
Now I'm announcing
the bounties of head-hunting
We'll give every one of you a gun
Come and sign for it after this
A chief.. 150 to 200 dollars
An able-bodied man, 100
A woman, 30
A child, 20
And a special bounty for the head of..
...Mouna Rudo!
Gas bombs?
But sir,
Gas bombs are still being experimented on
We don't know the effects yet
Yes, sir
But currently it's not ready for use
Come on!
Watan, you go that way!
Sapu!
I'm alright. They hit my sweet potatoes
Don't stop! Run!
Shoot! Shoot him!
Come on!
Out of the way!
Over there!
A Seediq from Tgdaya! -Where?
He's over there!
Kill him!
Burn it down!
Temu!
Come on! Run!
Chief Mouna! It's me, Pawan
Chief Mouna! It's me, Pawan Nawi
Chief Mouna, we heard what Baso told you
We know that a large number of
Japanese soldiers have gathered in Suku Clan
Time for the decisive battle, isn't it?
Chief Mouna, we have no family now
Why don't you let us fight?
Like everyone else, none of us can sleep or eat
and we don't want to be killed by gas bombs
Chief Mouna, look at the tattoos on our faces
We're not children anymore
Please let us fight the Japanese
like everybody else
Then I can have a good, long rest
We're so tired
We're really exhausted
My children, do you remember
where our ancestors came from?
Mt. White Stone.. -I know. Once upon a time...
-Let me tell the story!
Quiet!
Can't you wait?
A good hunter should learn how to lie in wait!
Pawan, you tell the story
Once upon a time on Mt. White Stone
there was a big tree called Pusu Qhuni
The tree trunk was half wood, half stone
One day, a boy and a girl were born
from the tree trunk
Then the couple gave birth to lots of children
and here we are, the Seediq Bale
Let me help you, Awi
It's ready, my brother
I'm ready
Let go, my brother
Pihu Walis..
Don't go! -Let go!
I'm in great pain
Don't go
I'm not fighting anymore! No more!
No more!
You son of a bitch!
What do you mean by not fighting?
-Kojima!
What do you mean by that? -Kojima!
Pick it up! Pick up your gun!
Out of my way! -Temu!
Temu!
We fight to offer blood sacrifice to our ancestors
not to revenge the death of your family
Temu, I know what you saw
but Mouna Rudo has spread the word
asking for your head
This is not the time to make trouble
Father, you told me only the bravest warriors
are qualified to guard
the most beautiful hunting ground
So that's why Mouna Rudo's people and we
have to fight one another constantly
to prove to our ancestors
that we're the bravest warriors?
So in the eternal hunting ground
at the other end of the rainbow
we'll become allies forever
and there would be no more hatred?
Yeah, I guess so
I want to fight them if possible
to prove my bravery
Sleep, my boy
Is that our man?
Get him! He's a savage! Come on!
Stop!
What's wrong?
A savage ran over the suspension bridge
into the woods
From there? -Yes, from there
Gather up!
Gather up, First Team!
First Team!
Stop!
Good
Come closer..
Stop, you little bastard
Aoki!
Okubo! -Aoki!
Where are you? -Aoki!
Aoki! Okubo!
Let's split up and search!
Aoki!
Okubo! Aoki!
Stop!
Everybody, stop!
These Seediqs from Tgdaya
are driven crazy by hunger
Okubo!
Where are you?
Aoki!
Okubo!
Someone's there!
Where? -In that tree!
Get down!
Get down! -Hide!
Machineguns?
Get the mortars!
Signalman! Signalman!
Here come the savages!
It's you then
Chief, Baso is hit!
Baso! Baso!
Baso!
We're in the Mehebu Forest
Baso! Baso!
Baso, are you alright?
Baso, be still!
Retreat!
Come on, retreat!