1
00:00:40,738 --> 00:00:42,033
What's your name?

2
00:00:42,772 --> 00:00:43,965
Mosquito

3
00:00:45,405 --> 00:00:47,894
Why did those mad dogs pick on you?

4
00:00:49,838 --> 00:00:51,202
For a chicken leg

5
00:00:51,372 --> 00:00:52,462
Huh?

6
00:01:02,773 --> 00:01:04,432
Want me to go with you?

7
00:01:05,305 --> 00:01:06,396
No

8
00:01:08,406 --> 00:01:09,770
Not the first time anyway

9
00:01:09,938 --> 00:01:11,097
l can go by myself

10
00:01:46,174 --> 00:01:46,935
Sorry

11
00:02:01,341 --> 00:02:03,432
Three schools in two years, huh?

12
00:02:03,608 --> 00:02:06,540
Missed classes for half semester when you were in Grove Town

13
00:02:06,708 --> 00:02:09,901
You been busy, huh? Lots of business going on?

14
00:02:10,307 --> 00:02:11,068
Nah

15
00:02:11,241 --> 00:02:12,571
No?

16
00:02:12,741 --> 00:02:13,638
l'm telling you,

17
00:02:13,808 --> 00:02:15,172
you better behave,well

18
00:02:15,341 --> 00:02:17,001
and finish school here

19
00:02:17,174 --> 00:02:18,504
Don't mess around

20
00:02:19,575 --> 00:02:20,540
Huh?

21
00:02:20,709 --> 00:02:21,572
Uh-huh

22
00:02:21,741 --> 00:02:22,832
Uh-huh, what you mean by uh-huh?

23
00:02:23,008 --> 00:02:24,474
Taking shit uh-huh, huh?

24
00:02:29,475 --> 00:02:30,498
Gambling, eh?

25
00:02:30,675 --> 00:02:33,072
You've got some guts, huh?

26
00:02:33,242 --> 00:02:36,731
Hands forward, forward

27
00:03:18,910 --> 00:03:19,341
(The new guy)

28
00:03:19,444 --> 00:03:20,432
(On the dike, tomorrow after school )

29
00:03:20,476 --> 00:03:21,840
(Bring NT$3000 to pay your respect)

30
00:03:21,943 --> 00:03:22,909
(Or else...)

31
00:03:33,377 --> 00:03:34,104
What the fuck

32
00:03:36,778 --> 00:03:37,903
Loser

33
00:03:38,944 --> 00:03:40,171
You need some beating

34
00:03:48,978 --> 00:03:50,069
Boss Dog Boy

35
00:03:50,244 --> 00:03:51,608
You eat my lunch everyday

36
00:03:51,778 --> 00:03:53,244
My nanny says l've become too skinny

37
00:03:53,411 --> 00:03:54,173
Too skinny?

38
00:03:54,878 --> 00:03:57,037
Your nanny's blind or somethin'

39
00:03:57,111 --> 00:03:58,509
Talkin'shit

40
00:04:07,578 --> 00:04:09,100
What you eating that fast for?

41
00:04:20,178 --> 00:04:21,804
Hey, Grove guy

42
00:04:23,212 --> 00:04:25,007
Haven't paid your bill this month?

43
00:04:25,178 --> 00:04:28,338
lt's OK, you can pay with a chicken leg

44
00:04:28,513 --> 00:04:29,808
Collected by me, Mr. Dog Boy

45
00:04:32,412 --> 00:04:33,106
Welcome, you're now listening to

46
00:04:33,279 --> 00:04:36,143
Mr. Lee's ''Hour of Sensibility''

47
00:04:36,312 --> 00:04:41,768
This is a barbequed chicken leg from the Grove guy

48
00:05:04,679 --> 00:05:08,544
'' What the fuck is meaning? All l know is brotherhood.''

49
00:05:26,714 --> 00:05:27,645
Don't run!

50
00:05:45,782 --> 00:05:47,213
Dice go!

51
00:05:47,381 --> 00:05:48,847
You need only five

52
00:05:49,015 --> 00:05:49,572
C'mon

53
00:05:49,748 --> 00:05:51,509
Again, again

54
00:05:52,381 --> 00:05:53,472
Hit it

55
00:05:57,548 --> 00:05:59,639
So many of them picking on one?

56
00:06:06,049 --> 00:06:07,981
Where the hell is this fag from?

57
00:06:08,149 --> 00:06:09,580
Just got transferred

58
00:06:10,616 --> 00:06:12,445
See how far you can go

59
00:06:51,383 --> 00:06:52,441
Get him up

60
00:07:00,384 --> 00:07:01,349
Go ahead and run

61
00:07:01,518 --> 00:07:03,347
You fucker keep running!

62
00:07:03,518 --> 00:07:05,279
You run fast

63
00:07:06,718 --> 00:07:08,479
Playing dumb in front of your daddy?

64
00:07:15,051 --> 00:07:16,244
Shit

65
00:07:23,785 --> 00:07:24,808
What're you doing?

66
00:07:39,285 --> 00:07:40,512
What about that?

67
00:07:41,185 --> 00:07:42,174
Not bad

68
00:08:14,386 --> 00:08:15,851
Where's your manners?

69
00:08:28,487 --> 00:08:29,747
Scar, cigarettes

70
00:08:30,887 --> 00:08:32,944
This is a beauty salon, not a barber shop

71
00:08:33,120 --> 00:08:34,779
What's wrong with him?

72
00:08:37,521 --> 00:08:39,043
l'll tend to your wound in a minute

73
00:08:51,454 --> 00:08:52,284
Scar

74
00:08:55,954 --> 00:08:56,612
Sister Ling

75
00:08:56,788 --> 00:08:58,879
What's this for, no

76
00:08:59,055 --> 00:09:01,680
You have already sent so many flower banquets

77
00:09:02,455 --> 00:09:04,546
You also spent quite a lot when you took over the business

78
00:09:04,721 --> 00:09:06,278
How could you say no to my cash gift ?

79
00:09:11,622 --> 00:09:12,780
Bye, Sister Ling

80
00:09:42,822 --> 00:09:44,311
Pay 50 bucks to get through

81
00:09:57,989 --> 00:09:59,683
Want to be friends?

82
00:10:00,790 --> 00:10:02,086
Fuck off

83
00:10:04,724 --> 00:10:06,280
Did you get that chick yesterday?

84
00:10:06,457 --> 00:10:07,150
She ran away

85
00:10:07,323 --> 00:10:08,879
Loser

86
00:10:22,424 --> 00:10:24,083
What?

87
00:10:24,258 --> 00:10:24,882
l beat up the newbie

88
00:10:25,058 --> 00:10:26,717
what's that to do with you Temple Front?

89
00:10:26,891 --> 00:10:29,153
Excuse me, Mr. Boss Dog Boy

90
00:10:29,323 --> 00:10:31,290
Just a notice

91
00:10:31,458 --> 00:10:34,617
From now on, his business is my business

92
00:10:34,791 --> 00:10:37,280
His enemy, is my enemy

93
00:10:37,457 --> 00:10:39,480
Whatever people owes him

94
00:10:39,658 --> 00:10:41,749
l'll get it back for him

95
00:10:41,924 --> 00:10:44,186
Whatever he doesn't want from people

96
00:10:44,358 --> 00:10:46,324
l will give it back for him

97
00:10:47,491 --> 00:10:49,457
Would you please tell me

98
00:10:49,625 --> 00:10:52,386
Did you pick on him yesterday?

99
00:10:53,791 --> 00:10:55,655
Dragon Lee

100
00:10:55,824 --> 00:10:56,916
Don't pick on me

101
00:10:57,092 --> 00:10:59,023
when my cousin is in jail

102
00:11:00,858 --> 00:11:02,347
Pick on you

103
00:11:03,225 --> 00:11:06,089
Just like you called up those body builders to pick on him yesterday?

104
00:11:09,325 --> 00:11:10,518
Making him pay respect, huh?

105
00:11:11,892 --> 00:11:13,881
This is your turf, huh?

106
00:11:19,559 --> 00:11:21,990
Now, nobody is picking on anybody

107
00:11:22,159 --> 00:11:25,455
Now l am asking you, fair and square

108
00:11:25,893 --> 00:11:27,950
Did you pick on him yesterday?

109
00:11:29,292 --> 00:11:31,986
How nice, everyone's here

110
00:11:32,159 --> 00:11:37,821
l, Dragon Lee, is here, no one dares to hit back, so be my guest

111
00:12:23,828 --> 00:12:26,657
Do me a favor, the new guy

112
00:12:26,828 --> 00:12:29,317
Can you make it quick, 10 minutes have passed

113
00:12:29,494 --> 00:12:32,290
You don't really need that much thinking

114
00:12:46,796 --> 00:12:48,727
lf you don't fuck'em up today

115
00:12:50,062 --> 00:12:52,187
One day they'll fuck you up

116
00:14:05,598 --> 00:14:08,961
My name is Chou Yi-Mong, friends call me Mosquito

117
00:14:09,131 --> 00:14:11,892
l moved to Monga when l was 1 7

118
00:14:12,065 --> 00:14:15,656
l became a gangster, because of a chicken leg

119
00:14:23,632 --> 00:14:24,927
All this fighting, is there a meaning to it?

120
00:14:25,099 --> 00:14:26,587
What the fuck is meaning?

121
00:14:29,465 --> 00:14:32,091
Your daddy only know brotherhood, never heard of meaning

122
00:15:48,700 --> 00:15:51,565
Since l was little, l had no father, no friends

123
00:15:51,734 --> 00:15:54,598
l was bullied by all the neighbors and kids

124
00:16:00,902 --> 00:16:02,992
Until l met my brothers

125
00:16:03,169 --> 00:16:05,361
My life seemed to have some meaning

126
00:16:05,535 --> 00:16:06,626
No

127
00:16:06,802 --> 00:16:08,199
What the fuck is meaning?

128
00:16:08,369 --> 00:16:09,891
All l know, is brotherhood

129
00:16:11,635 --> 00:16:12,931
Dragon Lee

130
00:16:13,102 --> 00:16:16,625
The only son of Geta, the boss of Monga Temple Front

131
00:16:16,803 --> 00:16:20,166
A street prince born with a silver spoon

132
00:16:20,335 --> 00:16:21,891
As the son of a gangster boss

133
00:16:22,069 --> 00:16:22,557
Naturally

134
00:16:22,735 --> 00:16:25,133
all the kids respect him as the big brother

135
00:16:25,302 --> 00:16:26,529
Since he's little

136
00:16:26,702 --> 00:16:29,429
he's been the gangster force on campus, maintaining the orders

137
00:16:29,602 --> 00:16:31,500
So much so, that the word Brotherhood, in his definition

138
00:16:31,669 --> 00:16:34,464
Has everything to do with Power

139
00:16:34,636 --> 00:16:36,261
( Protection fee, 500 )

140
00:16:36,436 --> 00:16:39,062
However, the one who really has what it takes to be a boss, is him

141
00:16:39,236 --> 00:16:42,202
Monk, real name Ho Tien-Yo

142
00:16:42,369 --> 00:16:44,131
His family owns a Buddhist Accessory Shop

143
00:16:44,302 --> 00:16:45,700
When he's 5, a fortune-teller

144
00:16:45,869 --> 00:16:47,165
determined that this kid was to become a gangster

145
00:16:47,336 --> 00:16:49,995
( Your boy is destined to be a gangster )

146
00:16:50,170 --> 00:16:53,693
His dad therefore asked his best friend Geta to look after him

147
00:16:53,869 --> 00:16:55,267
Monk is extremely intelligent

148
00:16:55,436 --> 00:16:58,562
Showed amazing talent as early as in elementary school

149
00:16:58,737 --> 00:17:01,635
He can finish test papers for 4 people at once

150
00:17:09,804 --> 00:17:11,360
Each year, he won six championships at school:

151
00:17:11,537 --> 00:17:14,731
writing, speech, reading, spelling

152
00:17:14,904 --> 00:17:17,267
calligraphy and art

153
00:17:17,437 --> 00:17:19,063
( Boss, the high mountain tea you ordered is here )

154
00:17:19,237 --> 00:17:22,202
Because he has high lQ, and he's resourceful and well-mannered

155
00:17:22,371 --> 00:17:23,234
Comparing to any of us

156
00:17:23,404 --> 00:17:26,336
Monk does everything with more ease and professionalism

157
00:17:26,504 --> 00:17:28,732
Growing up with Dragon

158
00:17:28,904 --> 00:17:30,870
Monk only cares for Dragon

159
00:17:31,038 --> 00:17:32,163
The way l see it

160
00:17:32,337 --> 00:17:34,895
His definition of brotherhood is

161
00:17:35,371 --> 00:17:37,395
lncomprehensible to others

162
00:17:39,704 --> 00:17:42,102
A-Po, Huang Wan-Po

163
00:17:42,271 --> 00:17:44,067
An underdog who knows best about survival

164
00:17:44,237 --> 00:17:46,101
( l've been a butcher all my life )

165
00:17:46,271 --> 00:17:47,828
( How come my son is such a coward? )

166
00:17:47,938 --> 00:17:51,597
He claims that he's killed 233 pigs

167
00:17:51,971 --> 00:17:54,698
Done 107 women

168
00:17:55,338 --> 00:17:56,861
Kicked 375 people's asses

169
00:17:57,038 --> 00:17:58,526
( 376,379... )

170
00:17:58,705 --> 00:18:02,603
Brotherhood for him, is a means to hustle around

171
00:18:02,772 --> 00:18:05,169
A truth only idiots would buy into

172
00:18:05,972 --> 00:18:07,665
The idiot A-Po refers to

173
00:18:07,838 --> 00:18:09,634
Would be Monkey

174
00:18:11,173 --> 00:18:14,195
Monkey, real name Hou Chun-Sheng

175
00:18:14,373 --> 00:18:16,669
His dad died soon after he was born

176
00:18:16,839 --> 00:18:19,305
His mom ran away with some man ( On my white horse )

177
00:18:19,472 --> 00:18:20,994
His grandpa raised him

178
00:18:21,173 --> 00:18:23,366
( Through three territories )

179
00:18:23,539 --> 00:18:27,938
( This is my line, who the heck are you? )

180
00:18:28,106 --> 00:18:29,037
( l am Chun-Sheng )

181
00:18:29,206 --> 00:18:29,933
Just like me

182
00:18:30,106 --> 00:18:32,299
Monkey was often bullied as a kid

183
00:18:32,473 --> 00:18:33,564
What's different is

184
00:18:33,739 --> 00:18:34,535
When he turned 10

185
00:18:34,706 --> 00:18:37,501
He Suddenly realized that he was good at fighting

186
00:18:37,673 --> 00:18:39,298
Since then, he's the one beating people up

187
00:18:39,473 --> 00:18:41,200
No one can hit him

188
00:18:42,274 --> 00:18:43,433
lt was in the same year

189
00:18:43,606 --> 00:18:46,800
That Dragon recruited him, and he became a gangster kid

190
00:18:57,240 --> 00:18:58,227
l took on three all by myself

191
00:18:58,407 --> 00:19:00,168
You're talking shit

192
00:20:46,343 --> 00:20:48,332
The highest record we ever made

193
00:20:48,511 --> 00:20:52,203
was to pick up a mass fight among all gangs in Monga

194
00:20:53,178 --> 00:20:54,302
lt was that night

195
00:20:54,477 --> 00:20:55,966
that five of us became sworn brothers

196
00:20:56,144 --> 00:20:57,632
and formed the Prince Gang

197
00:20:57,811 --> 00:20:59,834
Were not born on the same day

198
00:21:00,011 --> 00:21:02,773
But are willing to die on the same day

199
00:21:02,944 --> 00:21:06,468
Shall anyone think twice, will be punished by the Master God of Monga

200
00:21:06,645 --> 00:21:09,509
To have the limbs broken and die an ugly death

201
00:21:33,278 --> 00:21:39,178
Hey. What do you want to do the most in life?

202
00:21:40,512 --> 00:21:42,671
Join the gang, be the boss

203
00:21:44,045 --> 00:21:45,909
You wanna replace me?

204
00:21:48,746 --> 00:21:51,871
lf l become the boss, then you'll be the boss's boss

205
00:21:53,846 --> 00:21:56,778
Sweet talker

206
00:21:58,245 --> 00:21:59,871
What if you ain't in the gang?

207
00:22:00,046 --> 00:22:01,569
lf Monk wasn't a gangster

208
00:22:01,746 --> 00:22:04,042
he could get a PhD and win Nobel prize

209
00:22:04,213 --> 00:22:06,406
Anyway he's gotta be someone big lah

210
00:22:06,913 --> 00:22:10,141
lf l ain't in the gang, what would l be?

211
00:22:10,313 --> 00:22:14,110
Eighteen Copper Men conquer the world with Shaolin Kung-Fu

212
00:22:15,447 --> 00:22:17,572
Famous traditional kung-fu medicine

213
00:22:17,747 --> 00:22:19,111
Go back to sleep

214
00:22:23,447 --> 00:22:27,005
What about you, what you wanna do the most?

215
00:22:28,347 --> 00:22:33,871
Me, l wanna go to Japan

216
00:22:35,648 --> 00:22:36,807
And do what?

217
00:22:41,115 --> 00:22:42,444
Go see the cherry blossoms

218
00:22:42,814 --> 00:22:44,440
So ''romantico''

219
00:22:47,281 --> 00:22:51,112
My dad sent home a postcard from Japan before he died

220
00:22:51,282 --> 00:22:54,009
On it, there's cherry blossoms all over the sky

221
00:22:58,615 --> 00:23:01,547
He got passed on some kind of disease two months after he got there

222
00:23:03,382 --> 00:23:04,678
He probably died not even

223
00:23:04,848 --> 00:23:06,439
knowing l was born

224
00:23:15,048 --> 00:23:16,639
Have you ever seen cherry blossoms?

225
00:23:44,917 --> 00:23:48,178
Look, cherry blossom

226
00:23:53,583 --> 00:23:55,776
Here, to your dad

227
00:24:14,250 --> 00:24:16,113
Fuck! What you splashed on me with?

228
00:24:16,284 --> 00:24:17,341
Pee, of course

229
00:24:17,517 --> 00:24:19,506
Bitch, asshole

230
00:24:19,683 --> 00:24:21,775
You can't get me, won't get me

231
00:24:24,385 --> 00:24:25,112
Don't go.

232
00:25:02,252 --> 00:25:02,979
Thanks

233
00:25:05,585 --> 00:25:06,381
Hey

234
00:25:09,319 --> 00:25:10,784
What you had was broken

235
00:25:10,953 --> 00:25:12,248
Got you a new one

236
00:25:13,718 --> 00:25:14,707
Takin' off

237
00:25:36,653 --> 00:25:37,846
Not sleeping yet?

238
00:25:44,754 --> 00:25:46,185
What's going on?

239
00:25:47,687 --> 00:25:49,516
How's school?

240
00:25:50,687 --> 00:25:54,175
Ok, nothing special

241
00:25:55,087 --> 00:25:56,485
Just the way it is

242
00:26:05,720 --> 00:26:06,708
(Notification for Absence without Leave)

243
00:26:06,887 --> 00:26:09,513
l've never asked you to get good grades

244
00:26:09,688 --> 00:26:11,176
All l want is that you graduate

245
00:26:11,354 --> 00:26:13,286
Graduate from high school, that's it

246
00:26:13,454 --> 00:26:15,284
ls that too much to ask?

247
00:26:17,054 --> 00:26:19,486
with the Temple Front hooligans all the time?

248
00:26:21,854 --> 00:26:23,684
Will there be a future for you sticking with them?

249
00:26:25,488 --> 00:26:27,647
There's no such thing as future for someone like me

250
00:26:27,822 --> 00:26:29,049
Say that again

251
00:26:31,721 --> 00:26:32,415
l wouldn't have survived school

252
00:26:32,588 --> 00:26:34,214
if they didn't watch my back

253
00:26:34,388 --> 00:26:35,582
You don't steal, rob, or do anything unspeakable,

254
00:26:35,755 --> 00:26:38,017
why do you need them to protect you?

255
00:26:38,188 --> 00:26:40,677
What about you? Aren't you doing the same thing?

256
00:26:40,856 --> 00:26:43,219
We just moved here, and you already hooked up with the Mainlanders

257
00:26:43,388 --> 00:26:44,685
What kind of mindset's that?

258
00:26:44,855 --> 00:26:47,378
Don't you also need someone to watch your back?

259
00:26:54,923 --> 00:26:56,479
We're sworn brothers now

260
00:26:59,622 --> 00:27:01,918
l never had any friends since l was little

261
00:27:02,889 --> 00:27:04,378
This is the first time

262
00:27:24,356 --> 00:27:25,413
Happy birthday

263
00:27:28,356 --> 00:27:29,912
How do you know it's my birthday?

264
00:27:30,091 --> 00:27:31,852
l have my way to find out

265
00:27:32,024 --> 00:27:33,513
Let's go celebrate

266
00:27:34,757 --> 00:27:35,780
Move it

267
00:27:59,524 --> 00:28:00,421
How's it?

268
00:28:00,591 --> 00:28:01,648
Take a look

269
00:28:08,692 --> 00:28:11,987
Not bad huh, do you like it?

270
00:28:12,925 --> 00:28:14,016
Thanks

271
00:28:30,493 --> 00:28:31,652
Dragon, big bro

272
00:28:31,826 --> 00:28:34,758
Come, come. Come on in

273
00:28:52,426 --> 00:28:54,914
Woo-hoo! Love birds

274
00:28:55,093 --> 00:28:56,649
Get lost

275
00:28:57,260 --> 00:28:58,384
lgnore them

276
00:29:20,294 --> 00:29:22,816
Mosquito, Mosquito

277
00:29:23,693 --> 00:29:24,784
Drink up

278
00:29:25,561 --> 00:29:26,993
l'll puke if l drink more

279
00:29:27,160 --> 00:29:28,592
Are we brothers or not?

280
00:30:03,495 --> 00:30:06,620
Monk, Mosquito, come on, dance

281
00:30:06,795 --> 00:30:07,886
Hurry up

282
00:30:08,062 --> 00:30:09,460
Get movin'

283
00:30:10,629 --> 00:30:11,526
Let's go

284
00:30:34,896 --> 00:30:36,088
Monkey

285
00:30:44,830 --> 00:30:46,126
Dance with them

286
00:30:47,363 --> 00:30:48,294
No, l can't dance

287
00:30:48,464 --> 00:30:53,658
Hate, love, commotion in my heart

288
00:30:53,830 --> 00:30:59,559
This trap, trap, trap, why me?

289
00:31:01,996 --> 00:31:04,485
Hey, isn't it time to give our b-day boy the present?

290
00:31:12,797 --> 00:31:13,763
Mosquito

291
00:31:15,264 --> 00:31:16,559
Aren't we going to get some squid soup?

292
00:31:16,730 --> 00:31:19,060
Let's have it to go, you go get it

293
00:31:19,231 --> 00:31:20,026
Oh

294
00:31:22,498 --> 00:31:23,986
Remember to tell the owner it's for the Temple Front

295
00:31:24,164 --> 00:31:25,687
This way he'll add extra squid, hear me?

296
00:31:25,864 --> 00:31:26,693
OK

297
00:31:39,398 --> 00:31:43,023
Hi, 5 squid soups to go, it's for the Temple Front

298
00:31:44,198 --> 00:31:46,790
Five to go, for the Temple Front

299
00:32:08,999 --> 00:32:09,862
Temple Front

300
00:32:15,499 --> 00:32:18,193
Damn Temple Front, don't run! Knock him dead!

301
00:32:20,066 --> 00:32:21,123
Don't run!

302
00:32:26,767 --> 00:32:28,425
Temple Front! Get him!

303
00:32:29,500 --> 00:32:30,261
Don't go

304
00:32:30,433 --> 00:32:31,625
Kill him!

305
00:32:58,768 --> 00:32:59,631
Wow, they're coming, coming, coming

306
00:32:59,734 --> 00:33:02,598
Wow, super fast, 9 minutes 35 seconds

307
00:33:14,868 --> 00:33:15,596
Mosquito

308
00:33:23,634 --> 00:33:30,329
(The priest undertaking fear expel ceremony for Mosquito)

309
00:33:41,002 --> 00:33:43,025
Hey, sorry about the squid soups

310
00:33:43,202 --> 00:33:44,929
Should l go get them again?

311
00:33:45,103 --> 00:33:46,194
Get them again?

312
00:33:53,736 --> 00:33:54,895
What you laughing about?

313
00:33:55,069 --> 00:33:57,092
Jeez, you're unbelievable

314
00:33:57,269 --> 00:33:58,030
You almost got killed

315
00:33:58,203 --> 00:33:59,601
and you're going back there again?

316
00:33:59,769 --> 00:34:02,428
Hey Monk, enlighten him

317
00:34:04,236 --> 00:34:07,725
This is the Temple Front, our turf

318
00:34:09,170 --> 00:34:10,862
Monga, Since the Ching Dynasty to the Japanese Era

319
00:34:11,036 --> 00:34:14,128
has always been the busiest commercial center of Taipei

320
00:34:14,303 --> 00:34:16,030
lt's like a gold mountain

321
00:34:16,204 --> 00:34:18,193
full of opportunities and dreams

322
00:34:18,369 --> 00:34:20,631
ln places like this, all kinds of people mixing together

323
00:34:20,803 --> 00:34:22,769
Someone needs to maintain

324
00:34:22,937 --> 00:34:24,597
the order and allocate the interests

325
00:34:24,770 --> 00:34:27,464
That's where a ''Block Boss'' steps in

326
00:34:27,636 --> 00:34:29,966
The streets and lanes are their borders

327
00:34:30,137 --> 00:34:32,659
Each takes care of things big and small on his own turf

328
00:34:32,837 --> 00:34:35,531
Each protects the civilians on his turf

329
00:34:36,037 --> 00:34:37,832
Some say there are

330
00:34:38,004 --> 00:34:39,095
over 70 block bosses in Monga

331
00:34:39,270 --> 00:34:41,031
And some say over 30

332
00:34:41,205 --> 00:34:42,261
But no one knows

333
00:34:42,437 --> 00:34:44,027
for sure the actual number

334
00:34:44,204 --> 00:34:44,897
Haven't you been asking

335
00:34:45,071 --> 00:34:46,559
why we fight all the time?

336
00:34:46,737 --> 00:34:47,430
You get it now?

337
00:34:47,604 --> 00:34:48,967
Boss Dragon

338
00:34:49,138 --> 00:34:50,103
Anywhere in Monga

339
00:34:50,271 --> 00:34:51,736
mention Dragon's dad's name

340
00:34:51,904 --> 00:34:53,131
No one dares to touch you

341
00:34:53,304 --> 00:34:55,396
Because we, the Temple Front, are Monga's most powerful

342
00:34:55,571 --> 00:34:57,003
lf you run into those from the Back Alley,

343
00:34:57,171 --> 00:34:59,501
No need to say anything, just hit 'em

344
00:34:59,671 --> 00:35:01,160
Didn't we kick their ass the other day?

345
00:35:01,338 --> 00:35:03,065
And also those at the night market tonight

346
00:35:03,239 --> 00:35:05,204
Dragon Bro

347
00:35:05,371 --> 00:35:06,200
Have a cigarette

348
00:35:06,371 --> 00:35:09,030
No l'm good

349
00:35:09,205 --> 00:35:11,228
Give it to others

350
00:35:11,406 --> 00:35:14,200
Hey Dragon, what's your dad's name?

351
00:35:14,371 --> 00:35:16,929
Didn't l just tell you, Geta (Wooden clogs)

352
00:35:17,105 --> 00:35:20,197
The one that shielded off the sword with two clogs

353
00:35:20,371 --> 00:35:22,803
Hey Dragon, your dad is really cool

354
00:35:23,572 --> 00:35:25,333
Hi, good day, good day

355
00:35:27,005 --> 00:35:28,130
Boss Geta

356
00:35:28,306 --> 00:35:31,396
Come here, eat

357
00:35:31,872 --> 00:35:33,338
Time to eat lah

358
00:35:43,439 --> 00:35:45,667
Lazy dude shits and pees a lot

359
00:35:45,840 --> 00:35:47,204
You use the toilet whenever it's time to eat

360
00:35:47,372 --> 00:35:49,202
My belly hurts, what can l do?

361
00:35:49,372 --> 00:35:50,396
Hey your kid is big

362
00:35:50,573 --> 00:35:52,039
you should go and register

363
00:35:52,207 --> 00:35:54,196
She wouldn't marry me

364
00:35:57,073 --> 00:36:00,437
Come on, meal time

365
00:36:00,607 --> 00:36:01,902
The kitchen ceiling is still leaking

366
00:36:02,073 --> 00:36:03,403
what did you do to fix it?

367
00:36:03,574 --> 00:36:04,198
Look

368
00:36:04,373 --> 00:36:04,997
Tomorrow,

369
00:36:05,107 --> 00:36:07,335
if l still have to wear this shower cap when l cook

370
00:36:07,474 --> 00:36:09,372
You'll be the one that's leaking

371
00:36:11,607 --> 00:36:12,834
Ok, ok, take a break

372
00:36:13,006 --> 00:36:14,495
clean up and eat

373
00:36:18,308 --> 00:36:19,501
Wow, braised pork

374
00:36:19,674 --> 00:36:23,072
Oi, watch out for the hygiene, not with your hands

375
00:36:23,807 --> 00:36:25,670
Come and eat

376
00:36:25,841 --> 00:36:26,636
Come on, eat lah

377
00:36:26,807 --> 00:36:28,034
Come and eat

378
00:36:28,941 --> 00:36:31,634
ls this the way of the gangster? Not exactly what l imagined

379
00:36:31,807 --> 00:36:33,705
This, is the real Taiwanese gangster

380
00:36:33,874 --> 00:36:35,067
Vulgar and powerful

381
00:36:41,174 --> 00:36:41,970
Ma'am

382
00:36:44,408 --> 00:36:45,067
Mom

383
00:36:45,241 --> 00:36:46,605
No, l'm good, you go ahead

384
00:36:46,774 --> 00:36:47,434
Get you some rice?

385
00:36:47,608 --> 00:36:49,335
No, l am fed up

386
00:36:49,508 --> 00:36:50,871
l just lost 16,000

387
00:36:51,042 --> 00:36:52,940
to that Mei-ji bitch

388
00:36:53,109 --> 00:36:54,631
lf l don't get it back next time along with the interest

389
00:36:54,808 --> 00:36:56,535
l'll write my name backwards

390
00:36:56,709 --> 00:36:59,503
Mom, this is my sworn brother, Mosquito

391
00:37:00,209 --> 00:37:01,197
Hi there

392
00:37:01,608 --> 00:37:03,074
Alright, you guys carry on

393
00:37:12,309 --> 00:37:13,969
Boss, it's taken care of

394
00:37:14,142 --> 00:37:15,301
How'd it go?

395
00:37:15,709 --> 00:37:16,834
Kept wailing

396
00:37:17,008 --> 00:37:19,202
Ok lah, go sit down and eat

397
00:37:19,976 --> 00:37:20,873
Have a seat

398
00:37:25,210 --> 00:37:27,540
Riot at the Rocky Bay Prison

399
00:37:32,943 --> 00:37:34,499
They even sent in the SWAT team

400
00:37:35,410 --> 00:37:36,933
lt's turned into such a big deal

401
00:37:50,176 --> 00:37:51,143
Take some of this

402
00:37:54,910 --> 00:37:59,309
This reduces your internal heat, have some

403
00:38:03,644 --> 00:38:05,234
Get some more

404
00:38:13,678 --> 00:38:14,769
Dad you're home

405
00:38:19,778 --> 00:38:21,266
You were saying

406
00:38:21,444 --> 00:38:23,001
Wim-Kian's uncle

407
00:38:23,178 --> 00:38:24,700
Uh-huh

408
00:38:25,945 --> 00:38:27,275
Which uncle is it?

409
00:38:29,212 --> 00:38:30,678
Well it's Dog Boy's dad

410
00:38:31,211 --> 00:38:33,973
Oh, Doggy

411
00:38:47,645 --> 00:38:51,771
Wim-Kian is raised by Doggy

412
00:38:52,412 --> 00:38:56,072
He'll get even for sure

413
00:38:57,545 --> 00:38:59,102
You better watch out

414
00:39:03,079 --> 00:39:04,272
Boss

415
00:39:04,446 --> 00:39:07,207
Uncle lost 200 grand at the Temple Front bookie

416
00:39:07,379 --> 00:39:09,073
He told them

417
00:39:09,246 --> 00:39:12,042
to collect from you when you come out

418
00:39:12,880 --> 00:39:15,072
But they insisted on chopping down one of his fingers

419
00:39:21,146 --> 00:39:21,976
Fuck

420
00:39:23,147 --> 00:39:24,306
What you doing?

421
00:39:32,713 --> 00:39:34,838
Hey where the hell are we going?

422
00:39:35,013 --> 00:39:37,501
Just chill, you'll know in a minute

423
00:39:37,681 --> 00:39:38,611
Where's Monk?

424
00:39:39,347 --> 00:39:40,005
Boss Dragon

425
00:39:40,180 --> 00:39:41,043
There's no way he'd come for this

426
00:39:41,214 --> 00:39:42,840
He's not interested in women

427
00:39:43,680 --> 00:39:45,840
Try saying that to him next time if you got the balls

428
00:39:46,014 --> 00:39:46,569
lt is true

429
00:39:46,747 --> 00:39:47,508
He is Monk

430
00:39:47,681 --> 00:39:50,579
a monk should be vegetarian and celibate

431
00:39:50,747 --> 00:39:53,339
Exquisite Tower

432
00:39:53,514 --> 00:39:56,208
Tower is exquisite, there are 13 stories in the Tower

433
00:39:56,380 --> 00:39:59,404
A temple in front of the Tower, an old monk in the temple

434
00:39:59,581 --> 00:40:02,945
The old monk is the Master of six pupils

435
00:40:06,881 --> 00:40:08,245
See?

436
00:40:08,782 --> 00:40:09,974
Auntie has prepared

437
00:40:10,148 --> 00:40:13,512
swallow nests and shark fins for you

438
00:40:13,682 --> 00:40:16,477
Pick one you like and enjoy the tonic

439
00:40:16,648 --> 00:40:19,546
Feed yourself well, so you'll be strong

440
00:40:19,714 --> 00:40:22,409
Auntie, my dad doesn't let me come to Treasure Borough,

441
00:40:22,548 --> 00:40:23,206
you know that right?

442
00:40:23,381 --> 00:40:24,278
l know lah

443
00:40:24,449 --> 00:40:25,005
Cow Dung

444
00:40:25,148 --> 00:40:25,614
Yes ma'am

445
00:40:25,715 --> 00:40:26,578
No one knows

446
00:40:26,682 --> 00:40:27,807
Boss Dragon was here, got it?

447
00:40:27,982 --> 00:40:28,413
l know lah

448
00:40:29,515 --> 00:40:31,709
Next!

449
00:40:32,415 --> 00:40:34,540
Auntie, get him a good one

450
00:40:34,715 --> 00:40:35,703
my treat

451
00:40:35,882 --> 00:40:38,609
Sure, leave it to me

452
00:40:39,649 --> 00:40:42,547
Little handsome, come, your turn

453
00:40:42,715 --> 00:40:45,773
Wait, l'll wait, they go first

454
00:40:47,915 --> 00:40:49,609
First timer, huh?

455
00:40:50,983 --> 00:40:53,245
Auntie will get you a pretty one in a minute

456
00:40:53,416 --> 00:40:55,110
Make you lose your virginity tonight

457
00:40:55,283 --> 00:40:57,544
Then take a red envelope for good luck

458
00:40:57,716 --> 00:40:59,272
Auntie come in for a second

459
00:41:01,316 --> 00:41:04,248
Take your pick

460
00:41:04,417 --> 00:41:05,848
Don't be scared

461
00:41:28,917 --> 00:41:30,382
You scared the shit out of me

462
00:41:30,550 --> 00:41:33,345
Auntie, how can you sell this kind of product?

463
00:41:35,784 --> 00:41:36,511
What you lookin' at?

464
00:41:36,684 --> 00:41:38,344
l'll dig your eyes out

465
00:41:41,984 --> 00:41:43,109
Her, l can do with her

466
00:42:02,418 --> 00:42:04,248
Did you go to Show Shang Elementary School?

467
00:42:06,985 --> 00:42:08,178
Didn't you always carry your lunchbox

468
00:42:08,352 --> 00:42:10,840
in a washing powder bag?

469
00:42:17,352 --> 00:42:18,579
You're confusing me with someone else

470
00:42:31,385 --> 00:42:32,510
You

471
00:42:34,919 --> 00:42:36,748
Why do you want to be a hooker?

472
00:42:42,920 --> 00:42:43,976
What about you?

473
00:42:45,186 --> 00:42:46,651
Why do you want to be a gangster?

474
00:43:03,121 --> 00:43:04,916
Can we talk first?

475
00:43:16,287 --> 00:43:17,912
What's your name?

476
00:43:18,087 --> 00:43:19,110
Whatever

477
00:43:23,688 --> 00:43:24,881
l'm Mosquito

478
00:43:47,589 --> 00:43:48,953
Music?

479
00:43:51,956 --> 00:43:53,013
Whatever

480
00:45:02,958 --> 00:45:04,150
Thanks, come again

481
00:45:11,190 --> 00:45:11,952
Hey

482
00:45:14,024 --> 00:45:15,047
My name is Ning

483
00:45:16,724 --> 00:45:17,815
Oh

484
00:45:58,526 --> 00:45:59,548
Stop pouting

485
00:45:59,726 --> 00:46:00,282
l'm not pouting

486
00:46:00,459 --> 00:46:01,288
lf you wanna see ''Fatal Attraction''

487
00:46:01,459 --> 00:46:02,981
we can do it next time

488
00:46:03,160 --> 00:46:04,182
How was it?

489
00:46:04,659 --> 00:46:05,818
How was what?

490
00:46:05,993 --> 00:46:07,322
Was it good?

491
00:46:07,493 --> 00:46:09,152
With that birthmark girl yesterday

492
00:46:09,326 --> 00:46:09,917
No

493
00:46:10,093 --> 00:46:10,650
None of your business

494
00:46:10,826 --> 00:46:14,314
l don't want next time. l wanna see it today

495
00:46:14,494 --> 00:46:16,789
Hey what's the fuss about?

496
00:46:16,893 --> 00:46:17,984
Everybody wants to see this one

497
00:46:18,127 --> 00:46:19,285
Everybody, everybody. lt's everybody again.

498
00:46:19,360 --> 00:46:20,053
No idea

499
00:46:23,060 --> 00:46:25,458
Fuck, mad woman

500
00:46:25,627 --> 00:46:28,752
What do you want? Picking on me or what?

501
00:46:28,926 --> 00:46:30,949
l am not picking on you

502
00:46:31,127 --> 00:46:32,753
lf only you did what you promised

503
00:46:38,261 --> 00:46:40,056
The ''Project A'' sequel is what l wanna see

504
00:46:40,227 --> 00:46:42,216
lf you don't like it, then leave

505
00:47:11,761 --> 00:47:13,250
Excuse me, l am Dragon's friend

506
00:47:13,428 --> 00:47:14,656
You guys had a fight?

507
00:47:15,828 --> 00:47:17,317
He asked me to come look for you

508
00:47:17,495 --> 00:47:18,723
He wants to apologize

509
00:47:18,895 --> 00:47:20,088
He didn't earlier

510
00:47:20,262 --> 00:47:21,727
because the other guys were there

511
00:47:21,896 --> 00:47:22,986
You understand, right?

512
00:47:23,162 --> 00:47:25,458
Men don't like to look bad in front of friends

513
00:47:25,628 --> 00:47:26,753
He asked me to come get you

514
00:47:26,929 --> 00:47:27,916
He's waiting for you in the back

515
00:47:28,095 --> 00:47:30,926
Come this way, in the back

516
00:47:31,095 --> 00:47:32,459
This way

517
00:47:34,729 --> 00:47:35,660
ln the back

518
00:47:41,262 --> 00:47:43,785
l just wanted to enjoy a movie with him

519
00:47:43,962 --> 00:47:45,088
And he invited those guys again

520
00:47:45,263 --> 00:47:47,024
l don't understand

521
00:47:49,063 --> 00:47:50,757
Why does he have to be like this all the time?

522
00:47:50,929 --> 00:47:52,122
He's in the back

523
00:47:52,829 --> 00:47:53,852
Come, come here

524
00:47:59,797 --> 00:48:00,989
You know why?

525
00:48:02,396 --> 00:48:05,793
Because Dragon Lee is a freakin' fag

526
00:48:05,964 --> 00:48:08,486
Without those guys around all the time

527
00:48:09,263 --> 00:48:11,093
He'd be scared shitless

528
00:48:12,064 --> 00:48:13,290
You got me?

529
00:48:14,064 --> 00:48:15,189
Shush

530
00:48:41,231 --> 00:48:41,925
Hey

531
00:48:43,631 --> 00:48:44,619
Gotta go

532
00:48:44,799 --> 00:48:45,764
See you tomorrow

533
00:48:50,297 --> 00:48:51,321
Have you seen Hui?

534
00:49:02,232 --> 00:49:03,959
Fuck, you're shitting me

535
00:49:04,132 --> 00:49:04,825
Boss, l am not lying

536
00:49:04,999 --> 00:49:05,896
that chick is real hot

537
00:49:06,066 --> 00:49:06,929
Show me tomorrow then

538
00:49:07,098 --> 00:49:08,893
Sure, l'll take you tomorrow

539
00:49:32,266 --> 00:49:34,391
l have no idea what you're saying

540
00:49:35,733 --> 00:49:37,358
l didn't do anything

541
00:49:37,533 --> 00:49:38,931
Didn't do anything?

542
00:49:39,099 --> 00:49:41,224
Then why did you run?

543
00:49:42,134 --> 00:49:44,725
Gimme a break, you guys got weapons

544
00:49:44,900 --> 00:49:46,264
Who wouldn't run when they see you?

545
00:49:46,433 --> 00:49:47,592
Who knows, maybe the Prince Gang is just

546
00:49:47,766 --> 00:49:49,288
itching to beat someone up

547
00:49:49,467 --> 00:49:51,329
Fuck, you're full of shit

548
00:49:51,501 --> 00:49:53,262
A man is responsible for his actions

549
00:49:53,433 --> 00:49:55,559
How come there's such garbage like you?

550
00:49:55,733 --> 00:49:57,063
l didn't do nothing

551
00:49:57,233 --> 00:49:58,427
l'm being framed

552
00:49:58,600 --> 00:50:01,067
Some fucking bitch set me up

553
00:50:01,234 --> 00:50:02,665
Shut his mouth

554
00:50:11,534 --> 00:50:14,261
Hey you can't be serious

555
00:50:17,034 --> 00:50:19,125
To be a man is to be serious

556
00:50:20,734 --> 00:50:23,166
First, l will seal your mouth

557
00:50:25,168 --> 00:50:26,292
And then left eye

558
00:50:27,268 --> 00:50:28,495
Then right eye

559
00:50:29,368 --> 00:50:30,493
Left ear

560
00:50:31,401 --> 00:50:32,594
Right ear

561
00:50:33,201 --> 00:50:34,531
Left nostril

562
00:50:35,401 --> 00:50:37,492
Then drive you into the mountains

563
00:50:37,667 --> 00:50:39,827
Dig a hole, throw you in there

564
00:50:40,001 --> 00:50:42,366
Pour in vitriol, and then fill up the hole

565
00:50:42,535 --> 00:50:44,661
Monk, you can't do this

566
00:50:44,835 --> 00:50:47,597
What you gonna say to my cousin?

567
00:50:49,169 --> 00:50:51,293
Why do l have to explain to Wim-Kian?

568
00:50:51,469 --> 00:50:53,264
l don't belong to the Back Alley, l am from the Temple Front

569
00:50:53,436 --> 00:50:55,128
Are you fucked up in the head?

570
00:50:55,802 --> 00:50:57,734
Besides, having done something like that

571
00:50:57,902 --> 00:50:58,698
You are the one

572
00:50:58,869 --> 00:51:00,892
who should figure out what to say to Wim-Kian

573
00:51:01,569 --> 00:51:03,125
Stay away from me

574
00:51:03,302 --> 00:51:04,768
Don't you come closer

575
00:51:04,935 --> 00:51:06,231
What the fuck, what the fuck are you doing?

576
00:51:06,402 --> 00:51:07,265
Fuck, what you doing

577
00:51:07,436 --> 00:51:08,902
Seal it

578
00:51:09,069 --> 00:51:10,194
Seal his mouth

579
00:51:10,369 --> 00:51:12,631
Fuck, don't fuck with me

580
00:51:14,337 --> 00:51:17,427
What the fuck

581
00:51:26,736 --> 00:51:27,725
Seal the eyes

582
00:51:29,936 --> 00:51:30,902
This is enough

583
00:51:37,704 --> 00:51:39,033
Dragon, Dragon

584
00:51:39,203 --> 00:51:40,601
Fuck, let go of me

585
00:51:40,769 --> 00:51:41,497
Let go of me

586
00:51:41,669 --> 00:51:43,432
He fucked my woman, don't you know that?

587
00:51:43,604 --> 00:51:44,535
He fucked my Hui

588
00:51:44,704 --> 00:51:46,499
Yeah, l know

589
00:52:00,770 --> 00:52:01,759
l'll do it

590
00:52:42,806 --> 00:52:43,328
Hey

591
00:52:44,939 --> 00:52:45,904
No need to worry

592
00:52:46,639 --> 00:52:49,265
l'll take him to the doc l know he'll fix it

593
00:52:50,038 --> 00:52:50,901
lt'll be alright

594
00:53:23,241 --> 00:53:25,571
Thank you, see you again

595
00:53:25,740 --> 00:53:26,707
Thanks

596
00:53:26,874 --> 00:53:29,238
Auntie, l want Ning

597
00:53:29,407 --> 00:53:31,168
Ning is with a customer at the moment

598
00:53:31,340 --> 00:53:32,931
l'll get you a prettier one

599
00:53:33,107 --> 00:53:35,073
Hey A-mei

600
00:53:36,608 --> 00:53:37,664
lt's ok, l'll wait

601
00:53:38,141 --> 00:53:39,266
So faithful

602
00:53:39,441 --> 00:53:43,464
Handsome, come in, don't go away

603
00:53:58,275 --> 00:53:59,332
Come again soon

604
00:54:23,575 --> 00:54:24,633
Who did this?

605
00:54:25,108 --> 00:54:26,335
lf l collect less than 30 cards

606
00:54:26,509 --> 00:54:28,237
One whip for one card short

607
00:54:46,409 --> 00:54:47,466
Sorry

608
00:54:50,076 --> 00:54:51,201
What you sorry for

609
00:54:52,376 --> 00:54:54,399
You didn't turn me into this

610
00:55:01,910 --> 00:55:03,466
What's up with you?

611
00:55:16,811 --> 00:55:18,299
Can l spend the night here?

612
00:55:22,644 --> 00:55:24,735
How many more do you need? l'll buy them all

613
00:56:18,546 --> 00:56:19,341
l bought a lot

614
00:56:19,745 --> 00:56:21,143
Even one for Dog Boy

615
00:56:24,946 --> 00:56:26,571
Sorry, l forgot that he can't eat

616
00:56:27,213 --> 00:56:29,111
How could this happen?

617
00:56:30,179 --> 00:56:32,146
Didn't you say it's no problem?

618
00:56:36,346 --> 00:56:37,903
Could be too much in the nose

619
00:57:34,748 --> 00:57:35,577
Oi

620
00:57:36,915 --> 00:57:38,074
Where is it?

621
00:57:39,048 --> 00:57:40,105
What?

622
00:57:40,282 --> 00:57:41,508
The yo-yo

623
00:58:19,817 --> 00:58:23,806
The five of you, try to fly

624
00:58:23,983 --> 00:58:25,972
when you still don't know how to walk?

625
00:58:26,151 --> 00:58:28,480
Blackie and l only went to the South for a couple of days

626
00:58:28,650 --> 00:58:31,673
You already made such a big mess

627
00:58:31,850 --> 00:58:34,078
When the day comes that l'm gone

628
00:58:34,251 --> 00:58:36,648
Would that mean the end of Temple Front?

629
00:58:37,550 --> 00:58:39,607
The Prince Gang my ass

630
00:58:39,784 --> 00:58:42,944
Lost your mind for a Mainlander chick

631
00:58:43,117 --> 00:58:46,515
Dragon Lee, you really think you're a prince?

632
00:58:46,683 --> 00:58:49,479
man's life is worth nothing for you?

633
00:58:55,551 --> 00:58:58,346
You can kill when you can't even kneel properly?

634
00:58:58,518 --> 00:59:00,882
Look, if you fall again

635
00:59:01,051 --> 00:59:02,277
l'll beat you to death

636
00:59:02,452 --> 00:59:05,008
l'll be your page boy if l don't

637
00:59:06,584 --> 00:59:10,017
Boss, l made this mess

638
00:59:10,185 --> 00:59:11,980
lt's got nothing to do with them

639
00:59:12,152 --> 00:59:13,516
lt's all my fault

640
00:59:16,685 --> 00:59:17,878
Fine, get up

641
00:59:18,385 --> 00:59:19,577
All of you, get up

642
00:59:21,785 --> 00:59:22,876
All get up!

643
00:59:36,919 --> 00:59:38,714
You are good

644
00:59:38,886 --> 00:59:40,715
l wouldn't know if you didn't tell me

645
00:59:40,886 --> 00:59:42,977
lt's your fault

646
00:59:43,152 --> 00:59:45,641
lt has nothing to do with them

647
00:59:45,820 --> 00:59:47,012
You are good

648
00:59:47,186 --> 00:59:48,378
You are good

649
00:59:48,553 --> 00:59:49,484
How come you're so good?

650
00:59:49,653 --> 00:59:50,243
So good

651
00:59:50,418 --> 00:59:51,407
You are really good

652
00:59:51,585 --> 00:59:53,313
Really good

653
01:00:12,653 --> 01:00:13,449
Dad

654
01:00:17,953 --> 01:00:18,715
You

655
01:02:07,757 --> 01:02:08,654
Heading back?

656
01:02:08,824 --> 01:02:09,687
Uh-huh

657
01:02:10,224 --> 01:02:11,121
Boss Masa

658
01:02:11,291 --> 01:02:12,723
Boss Masa

659
01:02:22,524 --> 01:02:24,082
He almost wasted him. God forbid

660
01:02:24,258 --> 01:02:27,418
He meant to kill him or what?

661
01:02:27,591 --> 01:02:31,046
When kids make a mistake, they should be disciplined

662
01:02:31,224 --> 01:02:34,088
You haven't changed a bit, so naive

663
01:02:34,259 --> 01:02:36,486
Don't you know what kind of person he is?

664
01:02:37,825 --> 01:02:38,950
Sigh...

665
01:02:40,458 --> 01:02:43,016
We're brothers for so many years

666
01:02:43,191 --> 01:02:44,817
We're like family

667
01:02:44,992 --> 01:02:49,186
Family? lf only he felt the same way, too

668
01:02:49,359 --> 01:02:50,984
Secretly hired someone

669
01:02:51,159 --> 01:02:53,954
to chop off your hand, and took your place

670
01:02:54,125 --> 01:02:57,387
And now, he fucked up your son when he got the chance

671
01:02:59,559 --> 01:03:01,149
Don't talk about this in front of the kid

672
01:03:01,325 --> 01:03:03,315
Come, come outside

673
01:03:21,759 --> 01:03:24,157
Hey, why aren't you sleeping? What's going on?

674
01:03:26,859 --> 01:03:28,485
What he just said, is it true?

675
01:03:41,360 --> 01:03:42,223
Chou Ling-Wan, your registered mail

676
01:03:42,394 --> 01:03:43,086
Oh

677
01:03:43,660 --> 01:03:44,921
Be right back

678
01:04:05,095 --> 01:04:06,220
l'm takin' off

679
01:04:07,594 --> 01:04:08,719
Got enough money with you?

680
01:04:08,895 --> 01:04:09,690
Yeah

681
01:04:10,127 --> 01:04:10,991
Careful

682
01:04:11,162 --> 01:04:12,149
l will

683
01:04:16,195 --> 01:04:17,024
Sorry about that

684
01:04:17,194 --> 01:04:17,751
No worries

685
01:04:17,928 --> 01:04:20,486
Your son is very good-looking, going out?

686
01:04:20,661 --> 01:04:21,957
Yeah

687
01:04:22,128 --> 01:04:23,458
Pre-graduation trip

688
01:04:23,629 --> 01:04:25,117
He's graduating?

689
01:04:25,295 --> 01:04:26,760
You are really lucky

690
01:04:26,928 --> 01:04:27,825
You're too kind

691
01:04:28,595 --> 01:04:30,083
''1987''

692
01:04:30,228 --> 01:04:35,422
''Together, We Stepped into the World of Grown-ups And There Was No Turning Back''

693
01:04:59,329 --> 01:05:00,386
Sweeping Blade

694
01:05:00,563 --> 01:05:01,756
Stabbing tube

695
01:05:01,929 --> 01:05:02,759
Samurai 8-feet

696
01:05:02,930 --> 01:05:03,657
Samurai 2-feet

697
01:05:03,830 --> 01:05:04,523
Edged stiletto

698
01:05:05,729 --> 01:05:07,060
Whenever you have time,

699
01:05:07,229 --> 01:05:09,127
take them out, feel them and clean them

700
01:05:09,297 --> 01:05:11,285
Befriend them

701
01:05:11,463 --> 01:05:12,985
When you are in trouble

702
01:05:13,164 --> 01:05:14,595
Your friends will support you

703
01:05:14,763 --> 01:05:15,922
Get it?

704
01:05:25,263 --> 01:05:26,457
Hurry up, you're falling behind

705
01:05:38,131 --> 01:05:39,721
Son of a bitch, fuck

706
01:06:33,499 --> 01:06:36,828
One, two, three

707
01:06:43,300 --> 01:06:44,287
That's how it's done

708
01:06:47,133 --> 01:06:49,690
Hey, l just took a piss

709
01:09:43,639 --> 01:09:45,162
What age is it ?

710
01:09:45,338 --> 01:09:47,065
They all use guns now

711
01:09:47,238 --> 01:09:49,830
What's the point of practicing these?

712
01:09:50,005 --> 01:09:50,903
Come on, when the guns are loaded

713
01:09:51,071 --> 01:09:53,936
Do we have the time to turn around and get our 2-feet, 8-feet?

714
01:09:54,106 --> 01:09:56,163
Our asses are already getting shot at

715
01:09:56,338 --> 01:09:57,804
What the fuck did you say?

716
01:09:57,972 --> 01:09:58,768
Boss Geta

717
01:09:58,939 --> 01:09:59,870
Dad

718
01:10:00,039 --> 01:10:02,562
Boss

719
01:10:02,739 --> 01:10:05,570
Guns are evil things imported from the West

720
01:10:05,740 --> 01:10:07,603
They are for those who don't have balls

721
01:10:07,773 --> 01:10:11,001
Weapon for the lowly

722
01:10:11,173 --> 01:10:13,435
To establish oneself in the underground society

723
01:10:13,606 --> 01:10:16,595
One depends on his fists and knives

724
01:10:17,140 --> 01:10:19,731
l won't let the five of you lay your hands on guns

725
01:10:19,906 --> 01:10:21,168
You hear me?

726
01:10:22,740 --> 01:10:23,762
Hear me?

727
01:10:23,940 --> 01:10:24,905
Yes

728
01:10:27,706 --> 01:10:28,603
Let's go

729
01:10:31,073 --> 01:10:33,062
Take your shit and let's go

730
01:10:33,240 --> 01:10:35,797
Yay! The training camp is over!

731
01:10:35,973 --> 01:10:38,667
Black Dog Bro on the mountain top

732
01:10:38,840 --> 01:10:42,500
He is the young master of the ranch

733
01:10:42,673 --> 01:10:45,798
Hard working night and day

734
01:10:45,974 --> 01:10:49,804
His huge ranch takes up the whole mountain

735
01:10:49,974 --> 01:10:52,940
His singing is loud and cheerful

736
01:10:53,107 --> 01:10:57,063
He sings non-stop all day long

737
01:10:57,241 --> 01:11:00,230
His songs are so beautiful

738
01:11:00,407 --> 01:11:03,771
His nice singing voice got him famous

739
01:11:03,941 --> 01:11:07,499
l hear his voice but can't see him, yo le yi li

740
01:11:07,674 --> 01:11:11,107
Throughout the whole mountain there is his voice, yo le yi li

741
01:11:11,275 --> 01:11:14,672
The voice is pure and lovely, yo le yi li

742
01:11:14,841 --> 01:11:18,672
Yo le yi, yo le yi li

743
01:11:20,509 --> 01:11:21,565
Thank you

744
01:11:21,742 --> 01:11:23,503
Applause please

745
01:11:27,108 --> 01:11:29,700
Boss, what an incredible night

746
01:11:29,875 --> 01:11:32,273
Both bosses of Monga Temple Front

747
01:11:32,442 --> 01:11:34,407
and Back Alley are here

748
01:11:34,576 --> 01:11:35,268
Masa is here?

749
01:11:35,442 --> 01:11:36,634
Yeah

750
01:11:36,809 --> 01:11:38,467
Good, l'll go have a drink with him later

751
01:11:38,643 --> 01:11:39,835
Sure, sure

752
01:11:40,010 --> 01:11:40,736
Hey

753
01:11:40,910 --> 01:11:42,705
aren't the Back Alley guys our enemies?

754
01:11:42,875 --> 01:11:43,842
Of course

755
01:11:44,009 --> 01:11:47,305
Then why Boss Geta said he'd go drink with the boss of Back Alley?

756
01:11:47,476 --> 01:11:49,135
Oh, they are buddies

757
01:11:49,310 --> 01:11:50,138
They are buddies?

758
01:11:50,309 --> 01:11:51,570
Uh-huh

759
01:11:51,743 --> 01:11:53,766
They were sworn brothers

760
01:11:53,942 --> 01:11:55,340
Like the five of us

761
01:11:55,509 --> 01:11:58,101
One day you'll get your own block, l'll have mine

762
01:11:58,276 --> 01:11:59,833
Our subordinates fight when they see each other

763
01:12:00,009 --> 01:12:02,601
But for us on the top, when we meet

764
01:12:02,776 --> 01:12:04,332
having a drink is a must

765
01:12:06,343 --> 01:12:07,434
You'd better watch out

766
01:12:07,609 --> 01:12:08,973
l'm not scared of you

767
01:12:11,210 --> 01:12:17,143
lf you don't tell what's on your mind

768
01:12:17,310 --> 01:12:22,038
Who will ever know?

769
01:12:23,577 --> 01:12:29,567
Sometimes l really want to

770
01:12:29,745 --> 01:12:35,699
Just let out all of my sorrow

771
01:12:35,878 --> 01:12:41,742
Stepped into the underground

772
01:12:41,911 --> 01:12:47,867
l shouldn't have

773
01:12:48,044 --> 01:12:54,035
Now that l want to undo my mistakes

774
01:12:54,212 --> 01:13:00,201
Who would understand?

775
01:13:00,379 --> 01:13:06,278
My love if you know my heart...

776
01:13:16,646 --> 01:13:19,908
Hey, homeboy, what a coincidence

777
01:13:20,079 --> 01:13:22,374
l was about to go have a drink with you

778
01:13:22,546 --> 01:13:23,773
Who you with?

779
01:13:23,946 --> 01:13:27,071
Wim-Kian, he just got out

780
01:13:27,245 --> 01:13:29,302
Came to welcome him back

781
01:13:29,479 --> 01:13:30,877
How long was he in there?

782
01:13:31,045 --> 01:13:32,307
House Cleaning Operation, it's been three years

783
01:13:32,479 --> 01:13:34,741
Three years already

784
01:13:34,913 --> 01:13:36,879
He brought a Mainlander with him

785
01:13:37,046 --> 01:13:39,477
Said the Mainlander took care of him in there

786
01:13:39,647 --> 01:13:41,306
Brought him to introduce to us

787
01:13:42,280 --> 01:13:43,802
Lately l heard those Mainlanders

788
01:13:43,980 --> 01:13:47,468
want a piece of Monga

789
01:13:47,646 --> 01:13:52,944
Oh, gimme a break, don't think too much

790
01:13:53,113 --> 01:13:56,102
l can't even speak ''Mandorin''

791
01:13:56,280 --> 01:13:59,440
With them, there is nothing we can talk about

792
01:14:01,147 --> 01:14:05,602
Hey homeboy, l'm thinking, seriously

793
01:14:05,780 --> 01:14:08,440
Couple of events happened to Wim-Kian's household

794
01:14:08,613 --> 01:14:11,977
lf you can, would you come and say hello?

795
01:14:12,147 --> 01:14:15,409
His uncle cheated in games, l handled it by the book

796
01:14:15,580 --> 01:14:18,172
His cousin raped a woman

797
01:14:18,347 --> 01:14:19,937
l sorted it out for him, too

798
01:14:20,114 --> 01:14:22,774
The street, and business, the rules, l did everything right

799
01:14:22,948 --> 01:14:24,038
Why should l apologize

800
01:14:24,214 --> 01:14:26,442
to a youngster for things like these?

801
01:14:26,614 --> 01:14:28,512
Nah, you know it

802
01:14:28,681 --> 01:14:31,704
Wim-Kian is like a mad dog

803
01:14:31,880 --> 01:14:32,972
l don't care what kind of dog he is

804
01:14:33,148 --> 01:14:35,444
lt's your dog, train it yourself

805
01:14:48,781 --> 01:14:51,475
Geta, nowadays the Grey Wolf's gang

806
01:14:51,648 --> 01:14:53,978
is doing very well

807
01:14:54,148 --> 01:14:57,080
Boss Masa, please stop teasing me

808
01:14:57,182 --> 01:14:59,478
Did l say it wrong?

809
01:14:59,982 --> 01:15:02,573
Dragon, make a toast

810
01:15:05,515 --> 01:15:06,742
Boss Geta's son

811
01:15:06,916 --> 01:15:07,813
My son

812
01:15:07,981 --> 01:15:09,811
Dragon, handsome fellow

813
01:15:09,982 --> 01:15:11,073
Bro. Grey Wolf

814
01:15:14,916 --> 01:15:18,041
Grey Wolf, he's the most promising among

815
01:15:18,216 --> 01:15:19,773
the younger generation in Monga

816
01:15:20,416 --> 01:15:21,313
We should watch our back

817
01:15:21,483 --> 01:15:23,005
or soon we'll be history

818
01:15:24,616 --> 01:15:26,548
Boss Geta, look

819
01:15:28,117 --> 01:15:29,446
For the past 3 years when l was in there

820
01:15:29,616 --> 01:15:31,276
thanks for taking care of our boss

821
01:15:31,449 --> 01:15:33,348
And people in my household

822
01:15:33,516 --> 01:15:34,777
One day l, Wim-Kian

823
01:15:34,950 --> 01:15:36,506
will do my best to repay you

824
01:15:37,217 --> 01:15:40,650
Now that you're out, you should be happy

825
01:15:40,816 --> 01:15:43,783
Saying all this nonsense is useless

826
01:15:43,950 --> 01:15:45,916
Alright, come on, drink up

827
01:15:46,083 --> 01:15:47,276
Here, everyone, cheers

828
01:15:47,450 --> 01:15:48,915
Cheers, everyone, drink up

829
01:15:49,083 --> 01:15:49,515
Cheers

830
01:15:49,684 --> 01:15:51,047
Wim-Kian

831
01:16:00,417 --> 01:16:03,781
How's your boss doing overseas?

832
01:16:04,317 --> 01:16:07,908
He's in good shape physically, but he's kind of depressed

833
01:16:08,084 --> 01:16:10,073
lt's hard not to get depressed

834
01:16:13,450 --> 01:16:15,542
Mainlanders are indeed different

835
01:16:15,717 --> 01:16:17,774
That Grey Wolf, he moves a finger and the cigarette comes

836
01:16:17,951 --> 01:16:19,712
The glass gets refilled as soon as it got empty

837
01:16:19,885 --> 01:16:21,577
lt's like they were telepathic

838
01:16:21,752 --> 01:16:23,445
And the whole group

839
01:16:23,617 --> 01:16:25,243
stood still in the back all night long

840
01:16:25,418 --> 01:16:26,611
Tall and straight like the Military Police

841
01:16:26,784 --> 01:16:28,512
My legs got sore by just looking at them

842
01:16:28,685 --> 01:16:30,742
Sigh, Monga is hopeless

843
01:16:30,919 --> 01:16:31,646
So maybe you should

844
01:16:31,818 --> 01:16:33,250
join them if you like them so much

845
01:16:33,418 --> 01:16:34,315
You shitting me?

846
01:16:34,485 --> 01:16:36,110
They just look more impressive

847
01:16:36,285 --> 01:16:38,843
Wouldn't we look cool if we act like them?

848
01:16:39,018 --> 01:16:40,746
l think they look phony

849
01:16:40,919 --> 01:16:43,646
Yeah, bunch of fakes

850
01:16:44,085 --> 01:16:46,017
You know that Grey Wolf?.

851
01:16:46,186 --> 01:16:48,344
You know him personally?

852
01:16:48,519 --> 01:16:52,212
No, my mom does

853
01:16:53,619 --> 01:16:55,244
Your mom's sleeping with him?

854
01:16:55,653 --> 01:16:56,880
Fuck, shut your face

855
01:16:57,052 --> 01:16:58,882
Ah-ha, something fishy here

856
01:17:00,986 --> 01:17:02,474
lf your mom doesn't want him

857
01:17:02,653 --> 01:17:04,415
give him to my mom. He is her type.

858
01:17:04,586 --> 01:17:05,677
Shut up

859
01:17:11,687 --> 01:17:12,550
ls it good?

860
01:17:12,719 --> 01:17:14,548
Hmm, it's good

861
01:17:16,853 --> 01:17:18,649
Then l'll bring some more next time

862
01:17:18,819 --> 01:17:19,750
OK

863
01:17:27,153 --> 01:17:28,813
Did you have a tough time in the mountains?

864
01:17:34,787 --> 01:17:35,684
What's up with you?

865
01:17:36,887 --> 01:17:38,614
You look not yourself today

866
01:17:44,254 --> 01:17:45,913
l ran into someone l don't like

867
01:17:46,621 --> 01:17:47,984
Who was it?

868
01:17:51,087 --> 01:17:53,212
My mom's ex, before she married my dad

869
01:17:56,021 --> 01:17:58,078
My mom said she'd been with him since she was 16

870
01:17:58,754 --> 01:18:00,721
But one day

871
01:18:00,888 --> 01:18:03,615
He left without a word

872
01:18:04,755 --> 01:18:07,186
And disappeared until a few years ago

873
01:18:12,655 --> 01:18:16,212
Are you gonna disappear like him someday?

874
01:18:22,621 --> 01:18:23,883
You're scared that l'll disappear?

875
01:18:28,655 --> 01:18:29,917
Silly

876
01:18:31,389 --> 01:18:32,650
Why call me silly

877
01:18:32,822 --> 01:18:33,719
l won't

878
01:18:36,489 --> 01:18:37,682
What did you say?

879
01:18:37,856 --> 01:18:39,685
Something nice that l'm not gonna say again

880
01:19:24,790 --> 01:19:25,915
Hey boss, a barbequed chicken leg

881
01:19:26,090 --> 01:19:28,114
OK, OK, right away

882
01:19:35,057 --> 01:19:35,886
l'll get one more then

883
01:19:36,058 --> 01:19:36,921
OK OK

884
01:19:52,825 --> 01:19:54,551
Boss, have a chicken leg

885
01:19:54,724 --> 01:19:55,417
Oh

886
01:19:56,524 --> 01:19:57,683
Come, sit here

887
01:20:06,559 --> 01:20:08,025
You grew up without a father?

888
01:20:11,625 --> 01:20:12,682
That obvious?

889
01:20:18,792 --> 01:20:21,350
Leave us; kids shouldn't listen to adults' discussion

890
01:20:21,525 --> 01:20:22,082
OK

891
01:20:25,358 --> 01:20:26,450
Boss Masa

892
01:20:28,992 --> 01:20:31,390
l heard you've been working

893
01:20:31,560 --> 01:20:33,525
with the Mainlanders, why didn't you tell me?

894
01:20:35,359 --> 01:20:38,450
Who is talking such nonsense?

895
01:20:40,626 --> 01:20:42,320
Words spread fast

896
01:20:43,494 --> 01:20:44,982
Gimme a break

897
01:20:45,159 --> 01:20:46,523
l can't even speak Mandarin

898
01:20:46,693 --> 01:20:48,989
how do l work with the Mainlanders?

899
01:20:49,160 --> 01:20:51,990
You really buy that shit?

900
01:20:54,426 --> 01:20:55,756
Seriously, no?

901
01:20:59,594 --> 01:21:02,060
They did talk to me about it

902
01:21:02,227 --> 01:21:05,625
But l haven't agreed

903
01:21:05,793 --> 01:21:09,090
That means yes then, and you're still playin' dumb with me?

904
01:21:10,360 --> 01:21:13,191
l've told Wim-Kian about this

905
01:21:13,360 --> 01:21:15,588
lf Boss Geta doesn't agree

906
01:21:15,761 --> 01:21:17,750
then l won't do it

907
01:21:21,094 --> 01:21:23,117
Our Monga is an old town

908
01:21:23,994 --> 01:21:27,518
We have our own way and traditions in managing this place

909
01:21:27,695 --> 01:21:29,887
We don't want to work with outsiders

910
01:21:30,161 --> 01:21:33,491
Masa and l are no exception

911
01:21:42,695 --> 01:21:43,718
l understand

912
01:21:46,029 --> 01:21:47,517
How about this?

913
01:21:49,196 --> 01:21:51,094
ln the beginning l won't show up

914
01:21:51,262 --> 01:21:54,228
And you two bosses still handle everything

915
01:21:54,395 --> 01:21:56,521
We can observe each other for a while

916
01:21:56,695 --> 01:21:58,752
Until we've reached certain level of understanding and trust

917
01:21:58,929 --> 01:22:00,361
Then we'll go from there

918
01:22:00,529 --> 01:22:02,290
Moreover

919
01:22:02,462 --> 01:22:04,394
The business l run outside of Monga

920
01:22:04,562 --> 01:22:07,051
lf you are interested, please let me know

921
01:22:07,230 --> 01:22:08,922
l would love to have you join me

922
01:22:10,062 --> 01:22:11,460
Thanks a lot

923
01:22:12,095 --> 01:22:13,493
l think we better stay in Monga

924
01:22:13,663 --> 01:22:16,220
with our small business

925
01:22:16,396 --> 01:22:19,089
We don't know much about the outside world

926
01:22:19,263 --> 01:22:21,320
We are not interested in running around

927
01:22:31,764 --> 01:22:34,195
What about Boss Masa, what do you think?

928
01:22:35,164 --> 01:22:37,458
My position is very simple

929
01:22:37,630 --> 01:22:39,357
Whatever Boss Geta says

930
01:22:39,530 --> 01:22:41,758
l do my best to follow suit

931
01:22:46,830 --> 01:22:50,354
Yeah, you are the shit now

932
01:22:50,530 --> 01:22:54,122
Dozens of block bosses, with losts of grease to go around

933
01:22:54,297 --> 01:22:55,923
And then

934
01:22:56,097 --> 01:22:58,086
Fucking old asses getting in your way

935
01:22:58,264 --> 01:22:58,661
Look at your bosses:

936
01:22:58,830 --> 01:23:01,092
drink all day, the women, a great life

937
01:23:01,264 --> 01:23:04,059
Eventually, they will suck Monga dry

938
01:23:04,231 --> 01:23:06,322
lt's such a wonderful land, what a waste

939
01:23:13,164 --> 01:23:15,063
Look at our Big Boss

940
01:23:15,231 --> 01:23:16,958
He's got brains

941
01:23:17,132 --> 01:23:20,427
He doesn't sleep, he spends his days thinking

942
01:23:20,598 --> 01:23:22,962
Thinking about how to develop the organization

943
01:23:23,131 --> 01:23:25,996
Now, as soon as he gives an order, it'll be like cell division

944
01:23:26,731 --> 01:23:29,754
We'll no longer be just a gang of hundreds

945
01:23:29,932 --> 01:23:32,194
But tens of thousands, l am telling you

946
01:23:32,365 --> 01:23:34,388
Guns will be brought in by sea in boxes

947
01:23:34,566 --> 01:23:36,623
Halls will be established one after another

948
01:23:36,798 --> 01:23:37,822
And you

949
01:23:38,998 --> 01:23:40,294
Hanging out on your block

950
01:23:40,465 --> 01:23:43,488
Selling toilet paper and selected tea, collecting fees

951
01:23:43,666 --> 01:23:45,723
Getting turned in every now and then

952
01:23:46,399 --> 01:23:48,592
Times are changing, bro

953
01:23:49,265 --> 01:23:50,993
Do it right

954
01:23:52,199 --> 01:23:54,665
We set up a hall in Monga, and you'll be the Boss

955
01:23:56,699 --> 01:23:58,495
Each of us needs our own stage

956
01:23:58,866 --> 01:24:01,457
The world is going to be ours

957
01:24:12,599 --> 01:24:15,088
lt's gonna be diffiicult if there's only one hall for the entire Monga

958
01:24:16,600 --> 01:24:18,361
The two major powers in Monga

959
01:24:18,533 --> 01:24:20,590
Are our Back Alley and the Temple Front

960
01:24:20,767 --> 01:24:23,097
We've got our own blocks on each side

961
01:24:23,633 --> 01:24:25,826
You won't have any problem with me

962
01:24:26,000 --> 01:24:27,397
But if you wanna make this work

963
01:24:27,567 --> 01:24:30,328
You'll have to include the Temple Front

964
01:24:30,501 --> 01:24:32,763
Otherwise you'll have to deal with all the blocks behind them

965
01:24:32,867 --> 01:24:34,060
lt won't be easy

966
01:24:35,134 --> 01:24:36,600
lt's gonna be a tough fight

967
01:24:41,568 --> 01:24:43,692
You got someone from the Temple Front?

968
01:25:03,135 --> 01:25:05,863
l still remember four years ago, right here

969
01:25:07,036 --> 01:25:09,160
You were against over a dozen from Da Dao Cheng

970
01:25:09,635 --> 01:25:11,567
l saw them beating the life out of you

971
01:25:12,036 --> 01:25:13,626
Still you wouldn't give in

972
01:25:14,769 --> 01:25:17,599
l owe you for that

973
01:25:17,768 --> 01:25:19,359
No need to thank me

974
01:25:19,536 --> 01:25:21,297
lt was because you've got balls

975
01:25:23,835 --> 01:25:25,358
lf you weren't tough enough

976
01:25:25,535 --> 01:25:28,331
Even if you got beaten to death in front of me 100 times

977
01:25:28,502 --> 01:25:30,366
l wouldn't give a shit

978
01:25:34,335 --> 01:25:35,859
Really, l owe you a lot

979
01:25:38,736 --> 01:25:40,497
And that thing about the Dog Boy

980
01:25:43,803 --> 01:25:45,325
l am fully aware

981
01:25:47,069 --> 01:25:49,502
Dragon messed with somebody's girlfriend four years ago

982
01:25:51,136 --> 01:25:52,796
But you took on the heat

983
01:25:57,236 --> 01:25:58,862
Can we spare Dragon?

984
01:26:04,137 --> 01:26:07,661
What? You want to protect your brother?

985
01:26:09,904 --> 01:26:11,199
Look

986
01:26:11,337 --> 01:26:12,826
l am afraid that we are losing the entire Monga

987
01:26:12,970 --> 01:26:13,833
you know that?

988
01:26:15,304 --> 01:26:17,532
lt's like the last years of Ching Dynasty

989
01:26:17,704 --> 01:26:19,227
All the foreign powers have surrounded China with

990
01:26:19,404 --> 01:26:21,496
their firearms, canons and ships

991
01:26:22,371 --> 01:26:25,803
That old empress Tz'u-Hsi still thought she could bring them all down

992
01:26:27,537 --> 01:26:30,026
That's exactly what's happening in Monga

993
01:26:33,772 --> 01:26:34,737
Our Boss Masa

994
01:26:34,905 --> 01:26:37,768
puts on fancy clothes and fools around everyday

995
01:26:38,505 --> 01:26:41,800
And your Boss Geta is a stubbern old fool

996
01:26:42,338 --> 01:26:45,463
The future is knocking on the door, and Monga is still asleep

997
01:26:50,972 --> 01:26:52,494
They all call me mad dog

998
01:26:53,104 --> 01:26:54,128
They are right

999
01:26:55,872 --> 01:26:59,497
But l had been thinking a lot during the 3 years in prison

1000
01:27:01,805 --> 01:27:05,294
My boss turned me in during the Big Crackdown

1001
01:27:06,306 --> 01:27:08,737
That Dragon, you took on the beating

1002
01:27:08,906 --> 01:27:10,394
every time he screwed up

1003
01:27:13,505 --> 01:27:15,404
That's the kind of fate for people like us

1004
01:27:20,706 --> 01:27:23,137
Now the Mainlanders are asking nicely to do business with us

1005
01:27:23,906 --> 01:27:26,838
The proud old folks refused right on the spot

1006
01:27:29,140 --> 01:27:30,833
When the time comes, who's put on the frontline?

1007
01:27:31,839 --> 01:27:33,304
No one else but you and me

1008
01:27:36,006 --> 01:27:37,369
lt's guns in their hands

1009
01:27:38,473 --> 01:27:40,666
You really think you can fight them with a stabbing tube?

1010
01:27:41,373 --> 01:27:43,930
Don't feel ashamed to work with the outsiders

1011
01:27:44,373 --> 01:27:45,339
You really think l'll let

1012
01:27:45,507 --> 01:27:47,632
the Mainlanders take over Monga?

1013
01:27:49,107 --> 01:27:51,072
Look who's thinking for Monga

1014
01:27:52,674 --> 01:27:54,606
Shoot, talking is useless

1015
01:27:59,373 --> 01:28:03,204
Holy crap, all that wind, and now the rain

1016
01:28:04,074 --> 01:28:05,869
ls the typhoon really coming?

1017
01:28:12,741 --> 01:28:15,366
Boss Masa have a good night, come again

1018
01:28:15,541 --> 01:28:19,439
And you, don't run around, be good

1019
01:28:33,208 --> 01:28:35,834
Ah, you came for Auntie Ai as well?

1020
01:28:41,042 --> 01:28:41,871
Boss

1021
01:28:42,676 --> 01:28:43,936
Boss Geta is here with all of his Temple Front

1022
01:28:44,108 --> 01:28:45,870
brothers, to pay their respect

1023
01:28:46,042 --> 01:28:48,974
Please bless them, so that they are safe, healthy and prosperous

1024
01:28:57,776 --> 01:29:00,765
Homeboy, rest in peace

1025
01:29:02,210 --> 01:29:04,267
l swear right here, on my name

1026
01:29:04,842 --> 01:29:06,671
That l will find the murderer

1027
01:29:06,842 --> 01:29:08,308
To do your vengeance

1028
01:29:14,610 --> 01:29:17,075
My condolence, take care

1029
01:29:29,076 --> 01:29:29,973
Boss Geta

1030
01:29:30,810 --> 01:29:33,173
l have mobilized everyone in the Back Alley

1031
01:29:33,343 --> 01:29:36,332
l've also notified Taoyuan, Chungli and the South

1032
01:29:36,511 --> 01:29:37,737
Boss, if you can help us find him

1033
01:29:37,910 --> 01:29:39,604
l'd very much appreciate

1034
01:29:39,777 --> 01:29:41,505
We have to get A-Chung

1035
01:29:41,678 --> 01:29:45,201
l want him kneel in front of our boss, and pay back with his life

1036
01:29:46,444 --> 01:29:48,171
l'll help you find A-Chung

1037
01:29:49,212 --> 01:29:52,178
But we don't need to kill him

1038
01:29:52,344 --> 01:29:56,106
l'll find out if he's the murderer

1039
01:29:56,277 --> 01:29:58,573
Who knows? Maybe it's your own man

1040
01:29:58,744 --> 01:30:00,972
who did this, then frame him

1041
01:30:02,011 --> 01:30:04,875
Boss, how can you say this?

1042
01:30:05,045 --> 01:30:05,738
Are you saying that

1043
01:30:05,911 --> 01:30:08,139
our men killed our own boss?

1044
01:30:08,311 --> 01:30:11,210
Fuck, l'd say someone from you Temple Front killed him

1045
01:30:15,078 --> 01:30:16,237
Don't move!

1046
01:30:18,512 --> 01:30:22,035
God is watching, we all know what we did

1047
01:30:43,146 --> 01:30:45,873
Boss, got news from the Back Alley

1048
01:30:46,046 --> 01:30:47,569
They said A-Chung is spotted nearby the Watergate

1049
01:30:47,746 --> 01:30:50,405
Now they and the Da Dao Cheng people are all out to get him

1050
01:30:51,979 --> 01:30:52,968
Boss

1051
01:30:54,479 --> 01:30:55,672
l heard A-Chung is around Watergate

1052
01:30:55,779 --> 01:30:56,609
Everyone, go get him now

1053
01:30:56,713 --> 01:30:57,803
OK let's go

1054
01:31:08,479 --> 01:31:09,467
You go with them

1055
01:31:09,646 --> 01:31:10,408
Boss, what about you?

1056
01:31:10,580 --> 01:31:12,773
There's nothing to worry about, l'm on my own turf

1057
01:31:12,947 --> 01:31:14,277
Go, hurry

1058
01:31:21,747 --> 01:31:23,678
Boss, you're closing

1059
01:31:23,847 --> 01:31:25,073
Yeah

1060
01:31:25,248 --> 01:31:29,804
Everybody's out to get A-Chung, not much business around here

1061
01:31:30,414 --> 01:31:33,812
All of the Temple Front went?

1062
01:31:33,981 --> 01:31:36,412
Your Boss Geta, l think he stayed

1063
01:31:41,515 --> 01:31:43,503
Then please make two for me

1064
01:31:43,681 --> 01:31:45,147
Please

1065
01:31:45,315 --> 01:31:46,281
OK

1066
01:31:59,515 --> 01:32:02,072
Sorry, come early tomorrow

1067
01:32:02,249 --> 01:32:05,339
We came all the way from the South, can we just do a brief prayer?

1068
01:32:05,515 --> 01:32:06,503
Oh

1069
01:33:53,952 --> 01:34:01,317
Boss, boss

1070
01:34:01,485 --> 01:34:02,575
Anybody?

1071
01:34:03,253 --> 01:34:04,650
Anybody here?

1072
01:34:04,819 --> 01:34:06,580
Call the ambulance

1073
01:34:06,752 --> 01:34:08,684
Hurry call the ambulance

1074
01:34:17,019 --> 01:34:18,212
Boss

1075
01:34:23,853 --> 01:34:26,546
Somebody?

1076
01:34:27,852 --> 01:34:30,819
Call the ambulance

1077
01:34:41,420 --> 01:34:43,649
Anybody here?

1078
01:35:00,920 --> 01:35:02,546
Boss Dragon is gone

1079
01:35:08,020 --> 01:35:09,919
l told Dragon not to come today

1080
01:35:10,087 --> 01:35:12,815
lf Dragon shows up today, he will die

1081
01:35:12,987 --> 01:35:15,648
Those bastards want our Dragon dead

1082
01:35:15,821 --> 01:35:16,650
They want us dead

1083
01:35:16,821 --> 01:35:18,650
they want us at the Temple Front all dead

1084
01:35:18,822 --> 01:35:20,753
Can't you see what's happening?

1085
01:35:22,055 --> 01:35:23,282
l'll go find him

1086
01:35:24,056 --> 01:35:24,680
You stay right here

1087
01:35:24,854 --> 01:35:25,821
l don't want him back, l don't want him here

1088
01:35:25,988 --> 01:35:27,648
Don't you go get him

1089
01:35:27,821 --> 01:35:29,310
our Geta will understand

1090
01:35:29,488 --> 01:35:31,716
Madam, madam, calm down, have a seat

1091
01:35:31,888 --> 01:35:35,844
l don't want him back

1092
01:35:36,022 --> 01:35:38,318
don't bring him back

1093
01:37:05,458 --> 01:37:05,821
Who is it?

1094
01:37:05,992 --> 01:37:07,854
lt's me, me

1095
01:37:09,792 --> 01:37:11,087
lt's OK now

1096
01:37:28,558 --> 01:37:29,456
lt's me

1097
01:37:41,359 --> 01:37:43,621
lt's time, can't wait anymore

1098
01:37:45,092 --> 01:37:46,820
Who will hold the memorial tablet then?

1099
01:37:50,427 --> 01:37:51,393
l'll do it

1100
01:38:27,494 --> 01:38:29,460
Geta or Masa, take your pick

1101
01:38:34,827 --> 01:38:35,690
Geta

1102
01:38:39,595 --> 01:38:41,424
Goddamn sons of bitches

1103
01:38:41,595 --> 01:38:44,390
How dare you, getting all despicable in front of Master God

1104
01:38:45,628 --> 01:38:47,389
You two go from the back door

1105
01:38:49,127 --> 01:38:50,389
Go now

1106
01:41:00,233 --> 01:41:01,994
lf you don't kill them today

1107
01:41:02,166 --> 01:41:04,291
One day they'll kill you

1108
01:41:08,465 --> 01:41:10,364
l want them to pay with their blood

1109
01:41:13,800 --> 01:41:15,390
Why are you pushing me?

1110
01:41:18,633 --> 01:41:20,156
Motherfucker

1111
01:41:23,700 --> 01:41:25,256
You think we're their match?

1112
01:41:25,633 --> 01:41:26,929
How on Earth do you think we can do anything about it?

1113
01:41:27,099 --> 01:41:29,293
Boss Geta is dead, Boss Masa is dead too

1114
01:41:29,767 --> 01:41:30,391
Aren't you humans?

1115
01:41:30,533 --> 01:41:31,897
Don't you have any feelings?

1116
01:41:32,066 --> 01:41:33,999
Do you even have feelings?

1117
01:41:34,167 --> 01:41:35,463
Don't you be stirring things up

1118
01:41:35,567 --> 01:41:37,157
How do we revenge without knowing who did it?

1119
01:41:37,299 --> 01:41:39,561
lt's Wim-Kian, must be him

1120
01:41:39,701 --> 01:41:42,223
Everybody knows it, but no one dares to touch him

1121
01:41:42,400 --> 01:41:43,525
Motherfucker

1122
01:41:43,700 --> 01:41:45,462
No! Stop it!

1123
01:41:45,867 --> 01:41:46,696
Monk

1124
01:41:48,534 --> 01:41:51,159
Stop it, Monk

1125
01:41:51,833 --> 01:41:53,265
Stop it

1126
01:42:04,601 --> 01:42:06,794
At this point, revenge is suicide

1127
01:42:13,601 --> 01:42:15,897
Besides, Dragon can't stay in Monga

1128
01:42:22,501 --> 01:42:23,432
You three

1129
01:42:24,068 --> 01:42:26,262
take Dragon to the Philippines, lay low for a while

1130
01:42:27,034 --> 01:42:28,466
l'll stay and investigate

1131
01:42:29,635 --> 01:42:31,431
We need evidence

1132
01:42:34,402 --> 01:42:35,628
l'll stay too

1133
01:42:52,769 --> 01:42:55,462
Do you remember, the night Boss Geta died

1134
01:42:56,069 --> 01:42:58,558
You were all sent to find that A-Chung

1135
01:43:00,636 --> 01:43:01,965
Have you ever thought

1136
01:43:02,136 --> 01:43:04,034
it could just be a smoke bomb?

1137
01:43:28,437 --> 01:43:28,960
A-Shing

1138
01:43:29,804 --> 01:43:31,292
The thing, l want it done tomorrow

1139
01:43:31,470 --> 01:43:33,663
OK, no problem, leave it to me

1140
01:43:33,837 --> 01:43:36,167
Get some rest Boss, l'm heading off

1141
01:44:01,172 --> 01:44:02,933
Monkey is involved in an armed assault

1142
01:44:03,105 --> 01:44:04,230
Now the police suspects that

1143
01:44:04,404 --> 01:44:05,200
the gun in his possesion

1144
01:44:05,371 --> 01:44:07,497
is the same one that killed

1145
01:44:07,671 --> 01:44:08,899
the Back Alley boss

1146
01:44:09,072 --> 01:44:10,732
You pathetic liars

1147
01:44:10,905 --> 01:44:13,996
My Monkey is still at school

1148
01:44:14,172 --> 01:44:15,967
What did you take me here for?

1149
01:44:16,138 --> 01:44:17,331
l gotta hurry home

1150
01:44:17,505 --> 01:44:19,198
and cook for him

1151
01:45:02,640 --> 01:45:03,765
Fuck your sorry ass

1152
01:45:03,940 --> 01:45:06,236
Dragon, don't do that

1153
01:45:06,907 --> 01:45:07,669
Let's go

1154
01:45:10,307 --> 01:45:11,238
lgnore 'em

1155
01:45:15,473 --> 01:45:17,133
Why are they like this?

1156
01:45:19,274 --> 01:45:21,467
Because Monkey killed Boss Masa

1157
01:45:22,407 --> 01:45:23,703
Apparently Boss Geta ordered Monkey to do it

1158
01:45:23,808 --> 01:45:26,399
so he could take over the Back Alley

1159
01:45:26,574 --> 01:45:28,733
Then they in turn killed Boss Geta and Blackie

1160
01:45:29,208 --> 01:45:31,105
Temple Front did something like this

1161
01:45:31,275 --> 01:45:33,366
The gang has lost people's respect

1162
01:45:33,542 --> 01:45:35,030
What are you talking about?

1163
01:45:36,341 --> 01:45:38,170
Monkey didn't kill Boss Masa

1164
01:45:43,575 --> 01:45:45,165
Then you go explain to everybody

1165
01:45:45,842 --> 01:45:47,239
What is the reason that made

1166
01:45:47,408 --> 01:45:49,340
Monkey become the scapegoat?

1167
01:46:10,042 --> 01:46:11,030
Something to drink?

1168
01:46:11,209 --> 01:46:12,869
l am just here to ask you a question

1169
01:46:13,042 --> 01:46:14,303
Then l'm out of here

1170
01:46:16,542 --> 01:46:17,600
Have a seat

1171
01:46:24,709 --> 01:46:28,836
Hey you guys take a break, Grey Wolf Bro. has a meeting

1172
01:46:42,409 --> 01:46:44,466
Why did you leave my mom in the first place?

1173
01:46:46,776 --> 01:46:47,935
Something went wrong

1174
01:46:48,477 --> 01:46:49,568
Had to get away

1175
01:46:50,644 --> 01:46:52,405
Then why didn't you explain to her?

1176
01:46:56,310 --> 01:46:57,832
Because then she would have waited for me

1177
01:46:58,711 --> 01:47:00,768
Didn't want her to waste her youth waiting

1178
01:47:04,777 --> 01:47:06,709
Then, if you were given a second chance

1179
01:47:07,911 --> 01:47:09,638
Would you stay with her?

1180
01:47:12,278 --> 01:47:13,834
We only live once

1181
01:47:16,178 --> 01:47:17,144
l've run out of my chances

1182
01:47:17,311 --> 01:47:18,299
Yes

1183
01:47:20,311 --> 01:47:21,901
You still have a chance

1184
01:47:23,511 --> 01:47:25,999
lf something happens to me, please take good care of her

1185
01:47:27,245 --> 01:47:28,575
What are you talking about?

1186
01:47:30,178 --> 01:47:31,905
l'm warning you

1187
01:47:32,079 --> 01:47:34,738
Your mom went through hell to raise you

1188
01:47:34,912 --> 01:47:36,275
You owe her your life

1189
01:47:36,312 --> 01:47:37,300
You get me?

1190
01:47:37,479 --> 01:47:40,740
But Boss Geta died in my arms

1191
01:47:41,346 --> 01:47:44,971
l can never forget how he died in my arms

1192
01:47:57,979 --> 01:47:58,877
You know what?

1193
01:48:00,579 --> 01:48:02,636
Whichever way the wind blows

1194
01:48:04,346 --> 01:48:06,175
The grass bends along

1195
01:48:10,613 --> 01:48:13,307
When l was young l thought l was the wind

1196
01:48:18,380 --> 01:48:20,403
But eventually it cost me dearly

1197
01:48:22,614 --> 01:48:24,705
Then l realized we're all just grass

1198
01:48:40,147 --> 01:48:42,238
You are still young, you've got options

1199
01:48:45,014 --> 01:48:46,946
Go to the Philippines and lay low for a while

1200
01:48:48,880 --> 01:48:51,312
What's gonna happen in Monga nobody knows

1201
01:49:25,315 --> 01:49:26,178
l need to speak to Monk

1202
01:49:27,515 --> 01:49:30,777
l've made up my mind, l'll go to the Philippines too

1203
01:49:41,682 --> 01:49:43,807
l'll be in the Philippines for a couple months

1204
01:49:47,482 --> 01:49:49,948
You haven't served in the military, how do you get out of the country?

1205
01:49:55,250 --> 01:49:56,216
Unregistered boat

1206
01:50:05,284 --> 01:50:06,749
l will be back soon

1207
01:50:16,084 --> 01:50:18,380
l've asked Auntie how much you owe her

1208
01:50:22,451 --> 01:50:24,474
l'll figure out a way to get that money

1209
01:50:26,750 --> 01:50:28,080
When l come back

1210
01:50:29,883 --> 01:50:32,112
l'll get you out of here

1211
01:50:40,718 --> 01:50:43,116
l'll take you to the movies some time

1212
01:50:45,551 --> 01:50:47,040
How's that possible

1213
01:50:47,218 --> 01:50:50,308
lf l get caught, they'll break my legs

1214
01:50:51,352 --> 01:50:53,249
Auntie promised me, personally

1215
01:50:54,651 --> 01:50:57,050
She'll tell them that you're going for abortion

1216
01:52:57,989 --> 01:52:58,421
Here

1217
01:52:58,588 --> 01:52:59,384
Cheers

1218
01:53:02,356 --> 01:53:03,720
Grey Wolf, that's it then, we're heading off

1219
01:53:03,889 --> 01:53:05,013
Sure

1220
01:53:09,889 --> 01:53:10,854
Scar, see them to the door

1221
01:53:11,023 --> 01:53:11,613
Yes, sir

1222
01:53:11,789 --> 01:53:13,016
That's it

1223
01:53:13,656 --> 01:53:14,986
There's no problem right?

1224
01:53:15,155 --> 01:53:16,052
Don't worry

1225
01:53:31,323 --> 01:53:32,948
You need to do it nice and clean

1226
01:53:33,724 --> 01:53:36,121
Don't leave behind anything that'd make us lose sleep

1227
01:53:37,490 --> 01:53:39,921
He already agreed to get on the boat with them

1228
01:53:40,090 --> 01:53:42,886
And then, what are we gonna do when he's back?

1229
01:54:39,359 --> 01:54:42,655
Mom, l left some savings in your closet

1230
01:54:43,159 --> 01:54:44,284
Why in my closet?

1231
01:54:44,459 --> 01:54:47,857
Deposit it in the bank, and you can earn interest

1232
01:54:51,326 --> 01:54:52,518
Then you do it for me

1233
01:55:26,027 --> 01:55:30,255
Boss Geta, excuse me, please lend me your 2-feet

1234
01:55:30,760 --> 01:55:34,023
Bless me, and help me to find the truth

1235
01:55:57,794 --> 01:55:59,760
Boy, go get the car

1236
01:56:45,363 --> 01:56:46,488
l'm leaving everything to you

1237
01:56:48,429 --> 01:56:50,259
OK, take care

1238
01:56:57,162 --> 01:56:58,094
Let's go yeah?

1239
01:56:58,664 --> 01:56:59,561
Wait

1240
01:57:02,030 --> 01:57:03,690
Let's go pray to the Master God for a sec

1241
01:57:07,363 --> 01:57:08,989
What you talking this shit to me for?

1242
01:57:11,130 --> 01:57:13,426
l'm afraid you won't be able to explain to Sister Ling

1243
01:57:15,265 --> 01:57:16,424
Explain to whom?

1244
01:57:17,731 --> 01:57:20,094
l'm a goddamn gangster, who am l answering to?

1245
01:57:21,164 --> 01:57:22,925
He's not my son for God's sake

1246
01:57:33,497 --> 01:57:35,759
Get the car; we're going to Monga

1247
01:57:41,598 --> 01:57:42,495
He's not here

1248
01:57:43,665 --> 01:57:46,131
Oh, earlier he told me to deposit money for him

1249
01:57:57,832 --> 01:58:01,060
What's up with all this money?

1250
01:58:06,632 --> 01:58:09,155
All his regular clothes are gone

1251
01:58:21,666 --> 01:58:22,722
Why is the postcard l sent you

1252
01:58:22,899 --> 01:58:24,455
in Yi Mong's closet?

1253
01:58:39,833 --> 01:58:41,924
How could you keep me in the dark for so many years?

1254
01:59:29,435 --> 01:59:32,162
Shut the door, go shut the door

1255
01:59:34,968 --> 01:59:36,025
What are you doing?

1256
01:59:36,202 --> 01:59:37,031
Yeah, Mosquito, what you doing?

1257
01:59:37,102 --> 01:59:38,432
Stay where you are

1258
01:59:40,535 --> 01:59:42,296
l want to know something

1259
01:59:43,135 --> 01:59:44,464
Tell us

1260
01:59:44,636 --> 01:59:45,795
Are you sending us to the boat

1261
01:59:45,969 --> 01:59:47,491
or to Hell?

1262
01:59:48,502 --> 01:59:49,161
What the fuck?

1263
01:59:49,335 --> 01:59:50,562
There is no boat, right?

1264
01:59:50,736 --> 01:59:51,827
Mosquito, can you put down the knife first?

1265
01:59:52,002 --> 01:59:53,866
lf there's a misunderstanding, we can sort it out

1266
01:59:54,035 --> 01:59:55,501
There's no misunderstanding

1267
01:59:56,535 --> 01:59:58,161
Listen

1268
01:59:58,335 --> 02:00:00,529
Tonight, there is no boat but trap

1269
02:00:01,602 --> 02:00:03,965
Thre's no way we're getting to the Philippines

1270
02:00:05,102 --> 02:00:06,000
Monk

1271
02:00:06,169 --> 02:00:07,634
Explain, what's going on?

1272
02:00:07,803 --> 02:00:09,029
What's the deal?

1273
02:00:09,202 --> 02:00:10,533
Why did Mosquito say something like that?

1274
02:00:10,703 --> 02:00:11,690
What's the situation?

1275
02:00:11,870 --> 02:00:12,994
Mosquito, have you lost your mind?

1276
02:00:13,169 --> 02:00:14,634
Say it!

1277
02:00:22,037 --> 02:00:24,195
We swore to be brothers, at the very same place

1278
02:00:25,803 --> 02:00:27,701
And now one of you's putting a knife against my neck

1279
02:00:27,870 --> 02:00:29,927
Another one is starting to doubt me

1280
02:00:31,170 --> 02:00:32,033
What the fuck is this?

1281
02:00:32,204 --> 02:00:35,170
lf you've go the fucking guts, tell the truth in front of the Master God

1282
02:00:36,203 --> 02:00:36,999
lf l misunderstood you

1283
02:00:37,170 --> 02:00:38,726
feel free to give me a stab

1284
02:00:39,970 --> 02:00:41,765
But if you are the traitor who sold out the Temple Front

1285
02:00:41,937 --> 02:00:43,493
l want you to pay with your life

1286
02:00:43,671 --> 02:00:44,762
Sell out?

1287
02:00:45,704 --> 02:00:47,670
How could that be Monk?

1288
02:00:47,837 --> 02:00:48,928
Can you please stop this shit? OK?

1289
02:00:49,105 --> 02:00:50,832
Stop acting like this

1290
02:00:51,437 --> 02:00:52,266
l saw him with Wim-Kian

1291
02:00:52,437 --> 02:00:54,336
and Grey Wolf, with my own eyes

1292
02:01:05,504 --> 02:01:06,197
Your mama

1293
02:01:09,238 --> 02:01:10,703
Not my day

1294
02:01:21,106 --> 02:01:22,401
Times are changing

1295
02:01:23,971 --> 02:01:25,870
The outside world is changing

1296
02:01:27,105 --> 02:01:29,038
lf we are as stubborn as the old bosses

1297
02:01:29,205 --> 02:01:30,967
we'll be dead sooner or later

1298
02:01:31,138 --> 02:01:33,367
The entire Monga will fall into their hands

1299
02:01:34,572 --> 02:01:36,936
l met with Grey Wolf and Wim-Kian, was to save Monga

1300
02:01:37,106 --> 02:01:38,037
To save

1301
02:01:40,339 --> 02:01:41,361
The Temple Front

1302
02:01:43,972 --> 02:01:45,632
So, did you kill my dad?

1303
02:01:47,840 --> 02:01:49,862
You're the one who killed my dad?

1304
02:01:58,373 --> 02:01:59,271
Kill them

1305
02:02:01,506 --> 02:02:03,097
Motherfuckers

1306
02:06:55,315 --> 02:06:56,543
Everything l do

1307
02:06:59,783 --> 02:07:01,214
is for you

1308
02:07:37,384 --> 02:07:38,408
Have you seen Mosquito?

1309
02:08:22,718 --> 02:08:23,548
Go get everybody

1310
02:08:23,718 --> 02:08:25,241
Should we go take a look?

1311
02:09:08,819 --> 02:09:10,752
lf you got on the boat, then we wouldn't end up like this

1312
02:09:12,353 --> 02:09:13,876
Why didn't you just get on the boat?

1313
02:09:14,654 --> 02:09:16,347
Why are you making me do this?

1314
02:09:58,155 --> 02:09:59,348
Go ahead and kill me

1315
02:10:00,855 --> 02:10:02,515
lf you don't kill me today

1316
02:10:03,855 --> 02:10:05,878
l will kill you tomorrow

1317
02:10:08,223 --> 02:10:09,051
l never understood

1318
02:10:09,222 --> 02:10:11,780
what's the point in all this fighting

1319
02:10:13,622 --> 02:10:16,053
Now l am even more confused

1320
02:10:16,222 --> 02:10:17,449
You're my brother

1321
02:10:17,622 --> 02:10:19,747
but l have to kill you

1322
02:10:22,622 --> 02:10:24,248
Because this is the street

1323
02:10:25,789 --> 02:10:27,982
Because we're gangsters

1324
02:10:29,790 --> 02:10:31,482
Whoever gets in the way dies

1325
02:10:32,789 --> 02:10:35,051
There's no other choice

1326
02:10:37,023 --> 02:10:38,546
lf this were the way of the street

1327
02:10:42,390 --> 02:10:44,515
Then l am not a gangster

1328
02:10:46,090 --> 02:10:48,055
l am in this for friendship

1329
02:10:49,822 --> 02:10:52,118
l am in this for brotherhood

1330
02:11:06,357 --> 02:11:11,449
Guns are weapons for the lowly

1331
02:11:29,025 --> 02:11:30,048
Monk

1332
02:11:32,125 --> 02:11:34,250
You thought l was going to embrace you

1333
02:11:35,091 --> 02:11:37,114
So you opened your arms

1334
02:11:38,425 --> 02:11:39,914
At that moment

1335
02:11:40,225 --> 02:11:43,157
You chose to believe in me, didn't you?

1336
02:11:44,592 --> 02:11:47,114
You thought you were in this as a gangster

1337
02:11:48,059 --> 02:11:52,889
But like me, you're here for friendship and brotherhood, too

1338
02:12:01,859 --> 02:12:05,121
You thought Geta was a decent man?

1339
02:12:06,960 --> 02:12:08,948
He wanted to become the Boss

1340
02:12:10,127 --> 02:12:11,888
So he chopped off my dad's arm

1341
02:12:14,159 --> 02:12:17,422
Did you know how he treated his brothers?

1342
02:12:50,694 --> 02:12:52,717
What's good in the cinema lately?

1343
02:12:54,161 --> 02:12:55,387
Dumb Recruit is pretty funny

1344
02:12:56,294 --> 02:12:57,283
Really

1345
02:14:13,696 --> 02:14:15,663
Mosquito, are you OK?

1346
02:14:20,664 --> 02:14:23,221
Dragon, Dragon

1347
02:14:23,630 --> 02:14:25,653
Hurry, let's go

1348
02:14:28,164 --> 02:14:29,459
Dragon

1349
02:14:55,798 --> 02:14:57,162
Look, something happened

1350
02:14:57,331 --> 02:14:59,854
Go look for some guy called Mosquito

1351
02:15:26,866 --> 02:15:27,991
Where's my ear?

1352
02:15:47,333 --> 02:15:48,230
Some say

1353
02:15:48,799 --> 02:15:52,392
Joining the gang is like getting a bad lot

1354
02:15:52,866 --> 02:15:54,492
You end up either living in exile

1355
02:15:54,667 --> 02:15:56,530
Or getting brutally murdered on the streets

1356
02:15:57,600 --> 02:16:01,192
But that year, me and my brothers

1357
02:16:01,767 --> 02:16:03,529
we all believed joining the gang

1358
02:16:03,700 --> 02:16:05,030
using violence to gain control

1359
02:16:05,200 --> 02:16:06,666
was the way to rule

1360
02:16:07,633 --> 02:16:11,361
The only way for survival

1361
02:16:19,034 --> 02:16:21,159
Why do the four of you want to recruit me?

1362
02:16:24,634 --> 02:16:26,395
Because it takes five fingers

1363
02:16:26,567 --> 02:16:28,123
to form a fist

