We've started our descent.
Please put your seat back up.
Let me help you.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
Sir, please put your seat back up.
-Is your boyfriend meeting you?
-The old one or the young one?
You?
The married one
or the single one?
Hello!
Are you coming to pick me up?
Xiang, I'm with a patient.
I've heard that one before,
Brian!
-Are you with your wife?
-I really am with a patient.
Okay, don't come, then.
You don't ever have to pick me
up again.
Let me call you back.
-Sandy?
-Yeah?
Sandy, my precious?
Was your birthday trip fun?
It was okay.
Dad, our daughter's
going away.
Say a few words.
You're glued to that game,
Sandy.
You'll go blind!
Yeah, sure.
-Look at this, Dad.
-Here's the luggage now.
Let me know when you have time.
Right, of course I will.
No problem.
Hi, is Shi Ge there?
This is Xiao Jie.
I'm here in Taipei.
Are you coming to pick me up?
Hoping East Road.
But I've never been here before.
What if I can't find it?
Hello?
Still mad at me, Xiang?
I was mixing for Gigi that day.
I couldn't get away.
I don't care if it was Gigi
or Madonna.
I never want to see you again.
Why?
We're just not right
for each other.
Why?
Why what? Why always ''why''?
-I'm boarding now.
-Didn't you just land?
I know you did. I checked.
You just got back, didn't you?
We need you here, Qi.
Okay.
Good morning, Mr. Jack!
You're not up yet?
But it's already 7 a.m.
in New York!
I just came back from Malaysia.
Wait a minute.
Give it to me straight.
Are you sleeping alone?
We're not seeing each other.
You can tell me the truth.
Me? I sleep alone sometimes.
Sometimes with someone.
Sometimes with lots of people.
I have to when I'm
on the plane!
I called because I was bored!
How can I find a decent man
with all the flying?
What else can I do?
I'm not going to follow my mother
and teach piano!
It hasn't gotten that bad yet.
Never forget,
it was my mother who broke us up.
Fortunately,
I didn't marry you then.
It'd be tragic to be married
to a playboy like you.
Would you really take care of me
in my old age?
It's good to be home. I'm beat.
Aren't you going to work?
What's wrong with these lights?
All alone with no one
to fix the lights for me.
Help.
The Meteorology Center
reports that the earthquake...
...was 5.0 on the Richter scale.
Fires were reported in the Shilin
and Nangang Districts in Taipei.
Minor injuries have been reported
and treated at the hospital.
Districts in Taipei have reported
minor damages to buildings.
Evaluations are being done to
determine the extent of damages.
The weather bureau has issued
an aftershock warning...
...for the next few days. How's
everyone feeling after the quake?
Let's go to some live interviews.
Why are you still on the street?
-I came out with my girlfriend.
-What about aftershocks?
Xiang, are you okay?
Please open the door!
Xiang!
Are you there?
Let me in!
Is someone with you?
Open up!
Xiang!
Open the door!
-Hello?
-Miss Ku...
...your windshield's been smashed.
Shall I call the police?
No, ignore him.
Hello?
-I can come over pretty soon.
-No, don't.
-Brian.
-Meet me at Pixel.
-No.
-Brian.
-I'll wait for you.
-My fish are everywhere.
Thank God none died.
Xiang!
Xiang! What are you doing?
-Why do you treat me like this?
-Let go of me!
-Why didn't you open the door?
-I have a date.
Don't be like this.
Let's talk, okay?
Let go of me first.
I left work early
just to pick you up.
-Why didn't you wait for me?
-Why did you smash my car?
Who are you to tell me
what to do?
You can't treat people like this.
You come and go as you like.
That's me! That's my life.
-Don't be like this. Forgive me.
-Let go of me.
You're so immature.
You wouldn't love me
if I were mature.
Don't take me for a fool.
Don't leave me.
What's wrong?
Xiang, what's wrong?
Marry me?
Okay?
Why do you always avoid
the subject?
Look me in the eyes.
Look at me!
Marry me, will you?
Give me a straight answer.
Or you won't see me again.
Are you threatening me?
-I don't like being threatened.
-Yes! I'm threatening you.
Don't ask me to pick you up.
Don't call me when you're lonely.
I mean it.
You're being childish again.
Don't say that.
Will you marry me?
Okay?
-No.
-Marry me!
-No!
Yes. No.
Thank you.
Brian Sun! If you have the balls,
come face me!
Here she is! I hear the sound
of money at my door!
-You'll call us twins? No way!
-You'll be twins if I say so.
This place was hard to find.
Yes, it's a little out of the way.
-This is Jie from Singapore.
-Malaysia.
Right, Malaysia.
This is Tong from Hong Kong.
Hi.
What's with the handshake?
Rude!
Sit!
Let me see you together.
Very little resemblance indeed.
No matter. I'll still present you
as twin sisters.
Audiences want
satisfaction nowadays.
lmagine a pair
of singing and dancing twins...
...who can maybe do
some magic tricks.
People will just fall over
themselves.
I'm telling you!
This is a world
without boundaries.
You're from
two different places.
Your union will be a symbol...
...of the global village.
Who's hot now?
-F4
-Yes.
And there is Yang Yang.
They all have a common appeal.
They make people smile.
They have that
feel-good quality.
Whether you're from Hong Kong,
Taiwan or anywhere else...
...everyone just needs
some simple fun.
Where are you staying?
If their idols
make them feel good....
She doesn't even
have a place to stay!
It doesn't matter,
they can't sing or dance.
Sorry about that.
-That's okay, I got it.
-Here, let me help.
-I got it.
-Let me help you.
-It's heavy.
-It's okay.
You've got it?
-Where's the hotel?
-Not far. Let's take the bus.
Sit anywhere.
Can I use your closet?
-Sure, why not?
-Thanks.
I've never been to Malaysia.
I'm from Alor Setar.
It's small but beautiful.
How come you speak Cantonese?
I learned it by watching movies.
We have lots of Cantonese movies
and a lot of Canto-pop music.
What time
are our lessons tomorrow?
Don't we have to learn
lots of things?
-Singing. Dancing.
-Yeah.
I'm really nervous.
Forget about it. It'll dry.
Let me clean it up anyway.
-What's happening?
-What?
-What's going on?
-Earthquake.
Earthquake! Are you scared?
Thank you for the interview.
Excuse me. This lady.
May I ask...?
Excuse me, madam.
Madam, may l...?
I'm sorry. I know nothing.
Another earthquake!
What do you feel?
Can I ask a question? It'll
just take a couple of minutes.
Please. It's just an interview.
Jie! We're on TV!
What?
I want to record it for my mother.
I have a digital video camera.
No earthquakes in Hong Kong,
right?
No, but we have typhoons.
-Yes, typhoons.
-So this is your first earthquake?
Yes, it was pretty scary.
We don't have earthquakes
in Malaysia.
At first I was scared,
but I'm okay now.
Mom, I was on TV.
-I taped it for you.
-Are you okay?
-Everything is fine. How are you?
-I'm worried about you over there.
-I'm living with a girl.
-Take care of yourself.
We're worried sick
about you being away.
Dad is really upset.
I'm putting in a good word for you.
I know.
Please come home soon....
This call is expensive.
I must go.
-Keep in touch!
-Okay.
The flowers. Oh, my God!
Nothing seems to be broken.
Hey! I was terrified last night.
I was on the subway,
and it felt like a roller coaster.
Okay, let's get on and clean up.
-At least nothing's broken.
-Yeah, clean them up.
Yes.
Mrs. Zhao, I need the day off.
My father had a heart attack.
I need to go to the hospital.
-Add some more of these.
-Okay.
Our glass door was shattered.
We were pretty lucky here.
-Just a few broken pots.
-I'll say.
-Hello. Love Home Florist.
-With some more white daisies.
What's the matter?
My mother fell from a window.
-What? Which floor was she on?
-The second.
-I'm going to the hospital.
-The second isn't too bad.
Don't worry. Will you be back?
She won't call.
Hello! Love Home Hospital.
Love Home Florist.
The flowers will be delivered
on time.
What are you doing?
This street's one-way!
Sorry, sorry.
Patience, patience.
-Yes?
-For Mr. and Mrs. Zhao.
-Yes.
-Anniversary.
Okay, thank you.
-Where shall I put these?
-Over there.
-Twelve, 1 1 , 1 0, 9...
-...8, 7, 6, go!
-Hey!
-What?
-That's my idol!
-Who?
-Qi Yu.
-Who's Qi Yu?
She sings ''Olive Tree''
and ''Walk in the Rain.''
I know her!
Let's get an autograph.
-Where's my notebook?
-Got any paper?
Got it. Here, here.
Qi Yu. Miss Qi Yu.
-Hi!
-Could I get your autograph?
-I love your music.
-Me too!
The first album I bought
was yours.
-Really?
-Yes. Thank you.
-He looks cheesy.
-I think he's good-looking.
-That's my type.
-A real hunk.
It's not how they look.
Take Shi Ge.
It's what's inside that counts.
So you know what's inside
Shi Ge?
-Real talent.
-Crazy girls.
The guys I like don't like me.
Those I don't like
always go for me.
When I'm famous,
I'll marry Tony Leung.
He'll leave his girlfriend?
-I am younger than her.
-He'll be old by then.
Doesn't matter,
I still love him.
Do you have a girlfriend,
Shi Ge?
What's it to you? Of course.
Is she from Hong Kong?
Is she a pop star?
-She's an ordinary person.
-Do we know her?
No, she's not famous.
-Then how do you know her?
-How?
She has a beautiful voice.
She's pretty, with long hair.
I wrote songs for her,
but it's no good.
She's married,
so, what's the point?
Wow, he's in love!
You guys are crazy.
Get out. You're distracting me.
-When do we start working?
-We can't start without a song.
I'm writing one.
Get out and practice.
-Practice, practice, practice.
-Go away.
We're off to practice.
I have five brothers and sisters.
I'm the oldest.
My father works
on a rubber plantation.
My mother stays home
and cares for us.
My dad and I support
the family...
...so this is my last chance.
If this doesn't work, I'll have
to go back to a boring job.
A clerk, maybe, or a salesgirl.
Do you really love
to sing and dance?
I love singing the most.
At least it's something
you want to do.
What about you?
Isn't there something
you want to do?
Me?
I didn't want to tell you...
...but suddenly
I feel like saying it.
Are you listening?
My mother is having an affair.
I need to know what he's like
and how he could...
...turn my mother away from my dad.
-Have you ever been in love?
-Me?
I had a boyfriend once.
I don't think it was love.
Isn't it the same thing?
How is it different? If you
want to be with him, it's love.
Why would you dump someone
you like?
Why didn't you come out
that day?
You didn't even answer my call.
I waited for you downstairs.
I know you were home.
Are you mad at me?
Is your wife away on business?
She's in Beijing.
I thought we agreed
not to complain.
Sorry.
I'm flying to Europe this time.
Let's think about this thing
between us.
We need to make up our minds.
You said there'd be
no strings attached.
I am not attaching strings.
I'm just not sure
I love you anymore.
I have to go.
We're all old friends.
I really don't know
how to do this.
I hope you can cool down
for a while and reconsider.
Thank you for the advice.
Lily, I didn't want a divorce.
Your keys!
Mommy, why do you
want a divorce?
You'll understand
when you get older.
Men can't be relied upon.
We can get by just fine
without them.
Do you have any savings?
Don't forget about alimony.
It's hard to find someone
at 40-something.
When you do, you don't want them.
Why not?
If he's good, then why not?
Bottoms up, down in one!
Peter. Peter! One, 2, 3!
Time to eat!
Time to eat.
Are you feeling better today?
Linda, Grandma's winning!
You bet.
You can talk to her.
She likes being talked to.
She can hear you.
Try reading the newspaper
to her.
She likes that.
She looks just fine.
''A minor flat to E major.
It tries to express the idea
that we exist in our memories.
From a baby staring at a mirror...
...to when we start to observe
ourselves in mirrors.''
Are you listening?
My name is Lily.
I have a daughter.
I'm recently divorced.
Have you been married?
Do you have family?
Do they come to visit you?
Can you hear me?
What? Just a second.
Jack? What did you say?
Married? But you told me....
We agreed
we'd never marry anyone.
Do you realize what you've done?
It's pouring, and I can't find a cab.
I can't get home.
I'm cold.
Don't call me again.
Who will I call
when I need someone?
I knew this would happen.
Hello? Xiang?
Are you there?
Hello?
Xiang.
Mom, why do I have to
study piano?
A girl needs a backup.
If your husband
ever leaves you...
...you can teach piano
to support yourself.
-But why would he leave me?
-Who knows?
At least you'll be prepared.
Carry on!
I'm dying.
I am dying.
No one will care if I'm dead.
I am going to die.
I am dead.
I'll marry the next guy
who knocks.
Lots of people
are interested in your piano.
-Are you really going to sell it?
-I want to sell everything.
I want to sell myself too.
This guy is looking for a piano
as a gift for his daughter.
Whatever. If my mother found out,
she'd turn over in her grave.
-Show me that one.
-Okay.
-That one.
-This one?
They're all black.
Going to a funeral?
This one?
No, that one.
Which one?
Are you going to Ying's wedding?
It's not me getting married.
Why bother?
So expensive.
I can't wear them all.
Hi.
I'm packing.
I'm about to leave.
Okay, get on with your surgery.
Bye.
Hey, Qi, I'm packing.
I'm about to leave.
Get on with your
recording session. Bye.
Hello, Jack. I'm packing.
I'm about to leave.
Shit!
Why did you buy a tape recorder?
I want to record my own stuff.
Maybe a new song, a phrase...
...the sounds of Taipei
and your voice babbling.
This is my 20th day in Taipei.
Taipei's a big city.
-What are you saying?
-Quiet! Don't talk behind my back.
I have a fat, ugly friend,
and she babbles on every day.
How dare you say I'm ugly!
I'm babbling, not ugly.
She does love to talk.
I'm really happy.
So no problem.
I'll just wait.
We haven't started training,
let alone performing.
-What are you saying?
-I'm badmouthing you!
Have you ever kissed a girl?
Have you?
-I haven't!
-Me neither.
In my school,
lots of girls like girls.
Same here.
Do all Malaysian girls
sleep in their bras?
You! So, what do you call this?
Why are you so scared when l...?
How do you know those old songs?
I learned them from my mother.
She knows a lot of old songs.
She has a great voice.
You don't know these songs?
Why am I here?
What am I looking for?
Oh, my God!
So the long weekend's coming.
Any plans?
Maybe the hot springs
with my man.
-Great!
-We're going to the lake.
-Really? Look, how's this?
-Not bad at all.
-Okay, that's decided, then.
-Thanks.
Guess what! I'm going to the
East Coast with my boyfriend.
-I'm really looking forward to it!
-Bring me back a souvenir.
-Me too.
-Do these go together?
Sure! Let's see
how to arrange them.
Where are you
and your husband going?
James? This is Lily.
You're still here! I figured
you'd be gone for the weekend.
What? You're in Bangkok! Sorry!
Hello. Is Mr. Wu there?
This is....
Who's this?
Oh! Mrs. Wu.
Please tell him...
...Ms. Shi called
from Citibank.
Hi, Fred. This is Lily.
Hello. Lu Yi-zheng.
We were in elementary school
together.
Lily Shi.
Are you free this weekend?
Hello. Mr. Wang.
Mr. Wang,
can you show me some apartments?
You've changed jobs?
May I ask what you're doing now?
You're teaching tennis?
You're teaching tennis.
Tennis. Well, that's fine too.
Let's start. Watch the ball.
It's all right. Again.
This is tennis, not dodge ball.
Hit the ball,
don't hide from it.
Hold the racket a little lower.
Turn the handle back a little.
Hold tight.
You'll gain more strength.
Swing like this.
Swing through your shoulder.
Same with your backhand.
Follow through smoothly.
What's with the backhand?
Grip tight with both hands. Stare
in the direction of the ball.
Swing back through
your shoulder.
Loosen up the shoulder a bit.
-Look at the ball. Try this.
-Okay.
Good.
-Right?
-Look at the ball, not at me.
Good, good!
Hey, you don't look your age.
Go, go, go.
Move both your hands. Backhand.
Forehand. To the front.
Lily, come on.
Are you doing okay?
Lily, get up. Exercise time.
Hurry! Wake up. Wake up.
Get up and exercise.
Come on!
Off the bed. Come on!
Move, move. Come on!
Come on! Come on!
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
Up, up! You're fine!
Come on. Almost there.
Lily, my dear.
No more, no more. I beg you.
The more you resist
the more excited I get.
Please, I really can't.
-Lily! Come on.
-I'm begging you.
Really, no more.
No more.
Lily.
-Lily, come on. Don't run!
-I really can't!
You won't find twin girls
in Taiwan...
-...half as talented as mine.
-No kidding?
The big labels approached me,
but I'm holding back.
The majors, you name it.
I'm not doing business with them.
Why's that?
Why, you ask?
Hello? Hi, sweetheart.
What's the time there?
You're still up?
You should be in bed by now.
Mommy's having lunch
with friends.
It's noisy.
No, you don't know them.
They're all new friends.
You don't know them.
I've been busy playing tennis,
and dancing and hiking too.
Skiing? Sure you can go skiing.
So you won't be back
for Christmas?
No problem, you go skiing.
There will be lots
of parties here.
Maybe I'll go away
with friends.
Sandy, you have to call Daddy.
Mommy misses you.
Okay. Take care. Bye!
Bye!
I want them to be this generation's
new pop idols.
Good for you!
Hello?
I'm in a meeting.
Get on with your practicing, then.
Bye!
See how dedicated they are?
Do you want to book them
for a concert?
''The law is inadequate
in protecting the elderly at home.
Although....''
This is all about...
...the aged.
There is nothing else in here!
Let's not read anymore, okay?
No more news.
How about I trim your nails?
They're really long!
I've got clippers here.
Let me trim your nails.
I used to cut
my daughter's nails.
But one year,
when she turned 1 2...
...she started to do it herself.
She hasn't needed me much
since then.
Children grow up and leave.
Parents age and go away.
Men go away too.
Good thing they do.
Otherwise, I wouldn't
have met you.
Right?
Let's hear it
for the Sunday Sisters.
Next up are Cindy and Candy.
Hey, who are you?
Who invited you?
Why did you sing so many songs?
Who the hell are you?
What's your problem!
You know who I am?
-Who cares? You're an asshole.
-Are you crazy?
Crazy? I'm defending you here.
Why are you so mad?
What's with you?
I defend you, and you yell at me?
You're crazy!
I'm crazy? You never think
of people's feelings.
-I have feelings too!
-Have you finished?
-Stay out of this.
-What is it?
-Stop it!
-Who are you?
-I'm their manager. Talk to me.
-Manager? From where?
We're just starting out.
-That figures.
-Shut up. What's it to you?
-Pipe down.
-Stop it. Quiet, please.
Did I give permission
to go on-stage?
-You're crazy.
-You're nuts.
-Excuse me, what did you say?
-Why didn't you get my permission?
-Why do I need your permission?
-Don't you know who I am?
No!
His dad is the principal.
Get out, you guys. Get out.
-Get out.
-Wait outside.
-Nut case.
-I'm sorry.
-They're an ignorant bunch!
-They're new.
-They were very rude.
-You're right. Damn ignorant.
-And rude.
-Forgive them. I apologize!
Sorry!
We must have been terrible
up there.
No way.
We Sunday Sisters top everyone.
What is the bravest thing
you've done?
-Me? Milking a cow.
-Milking a cow? I'm serious!
That cow kicked someone to death.
No one dared milk her.
So do you dare make love to me?
There's no one here.
It's dirty.
Very dirty.
This one is nicer.
Maybe every stall is different.
What? Why are you laughing?
Why are you laughing?
What's so funny?
What? What?!
Check her out.
It's the girl we met
this morning.
-Hey.
-What do you want?
-Where's your friend?
-Mind your own business!
-Let's call it a truce.
-No.
-Come on.
You have a pen? A pen.
-What do you want?
-Can I give you my number?
Call me and we'll go out sometime.
Okay?
It's all right. Just a kid.
Don't worry.
May I sit with you?
Put this up for me.
Yes, right up there.
-This side. Put it here.
-Do it yourself!
You're taller. Help me!
Higher up. Thank you.
Xiang!
Listen to me.
Xiang.
Don't act like this.
-Leave me alone!
-No. Xiang!
Be careful!
What's going on?
Come help rescue my fish.
Can you see that one?
You're standing on it!
There's one over there.
Be careful. Don't squash it.
There's another one!
-Give it to me. Qi, give me.
-Be careful.
What are you two doing?
Catch it!
-Hello.
-Who's this guy?
-This is ridiculous.
-How should I know who he is?
Who are you?
-What's it to you?
-What kind of game is this?
-This is too much.
-You have no right to question me.
Nor do you. You think I don't know
what you and May were doing?
-It's all crap.
-May asked for my help.
-I did nothing!
-Of course she asked.
And you do whatever she wants?
Right?
-You have no right to lecture me.
-Don't act like this.
Don't touch me.
I need to get a new fishbowl.
Close the door when you leave.
Who are you?
I'm Situ.
I've come for the piano.
-Sorry, today isn't a good day.
-I can see that. Another time?
I have to stop flying...
...change my numbers...
...and disappear
from this world.
Look over there.
Check out the one in gray.
He's looking over here.
Behave yourself, girl!
I looked at the same man for 30 years.
Now there are new ones.
-Why shouldn't I stare?
-Don't just look, do something.
Go for it, Lily!
-All talk, no action?
-Calm down.
Oh, my God, she's going for it!
She's fearless!
She won't give up!
Yes, here's the sauna.
-Hi.
-Hello.
Excuse me,
I just told my friends...
...we went to primary school together.
They won't believe me!
You probably don't remember
that we were classmates.
You probably don't recall
my name--
Lily Shi.
-What?
-It wasn't primary school.
We were in middle school together.
I was in Ms. Chen's class.
You were in Ms. Liu's class.
No kidding?
Here's my card.
-''Zhang Shi-Jie''?
-Call me Jerry.
Let's meet up sometime.
Miss, can I get a pen?
''Zhang Shi-Jie.''
Zhang Shi-Jie.
Hello. All alone?
You don't have a lunch date?
Take your time.
I meant with your girlfriends.
I was just passing by.
I thought I'd see how you were doing.
The flowers are beautiful as usual.
Maybe I'll buy some.
But there's no one
to give them to.
I came to talk to you
about Sandy.
She still won't talk to me.
Can you put in a word for me?
Please?
This is grown-up business.
Why drag her into this?
I've discussed it with Amy--
Hello? Hold on a second.
Listen to me.
Amy wouldn't ask Sandy
to call her ''Mom.''
So it's okay, right?
Please talk to her.
Hey! Would you--?
Would you please talk to her
about it?
Let's talk some other time.
-Love Home Florist.
-This is Jerry. Is this Lily?
Yes. This is she.
Jerry. Sorry about just now.
I'd like to order some flowers.
Were we really in school together?
Why can't I remember?
I was sort of a nerd back then.
Not the kind people remember.
Me too.
Why do you remember me?
You'd like to order flowers?
What kind?
Can you help me decide?
Who are they for?
Is it a special occasion?
They're for a girl.
The message is, ''Dear Emmy.... ''
E-M-M-Y.
''Welcome back. Love, Jerry. ''
How much do you want to spend?
Your call.
They need to be beautiful and big.
I trust your judgment.
Lily, what exactly
should the card say?
It says here ''Dear Emily''
and ''Go to hell.''
This is....
Should it be ''Dear Emily,
welcome back. Love, Jerry''?
-Okay. Yes.
-Is it ''Emily''?
-Flowers to deliver, Xiang!
-Okay.
-Welcome!
-Lily, l....
Wait a moment.
-I'll add some of this.
-Okay.
-How much?
-1 000 NT. Qin, take the money.
Okay!
Thank you.
Please deliver the flowers
on Friday.
-We will.
-Thanks again.
Take care!
Do you want more flowers?
We've got some good ones today.
Did you like the flowers?
I can do a new arrangement.
-You misspelled the name.
-Misspelled? Misspelled what?
''Emmy.'' You wrote ''Emily.''
Oh, no! Qin, you misspelled it.
-Can't be!
-Check it!
-I'm so sorry.
-Jerry, I really am sorry!
My God, how could this happen?
She must have been upset.
Nothing jewelry can't fix.
Wow. That's nice!
-Women are--
-Easy to please!
One little stone and we're all set.
Men are more difficult.
-Correct it.
-All right.
-Change it to Emily. No, I mean--
-Emmy!
-Emmy.
-E-M-M-Y.
Jerry, I'm sorry.
Let me pay you back.
Really, I must.
-Don't worry.
-Please! Are you free now?
It will be really quick.
Let's just have a quick lunch.
Wait for me. Wait.
I won't take no for an answer.
It'll make me feel better.
I'm so embarrassed!
I haven't had a quiet meal for ages.
Jerry Zhang, 47,
divorced for eight years.
Son's in college. Lives alone.
Girlfriend is young,
a flight attendant.
He's in the toy business
and travels to China a lot.
He might move there,
but she doesn't want to go.
They fight about this a lot.
Jerry, do you play tennis?
Do you like hiking?
I like to stay home.
I like the comfort of home.
-Hello.
-Mrs. Zhao!
It's Miss Shi now.
You forgot again.
-Sorry, Miss Shi.
-Yes.
-Reservation for Friday?
-Friday? Okay.
-7:30.
-7:30. How many of you? Two.
Two. Usual table?
It's not for me.
It's for Mr. Zhang. Jerry Zhang.
Jerry Zhang. Okay. Good.
Should I have a bottle
of wine ready?
Wine?
-Put some champagne on ice.
-Okay.
Welcome!
Do you have a reservation?
-Jerry. Jerry Zhang.
-Yes. This way, please.
Mr. Zhang,
we have champagne for you.
Thanks.
Your guests are here, Miss Shi.
You must be Emmy.
These are for you from Mr. Zhang.
I'm the florist.
I am here to apologize
for misspelling your name.
-No problem. Thank you.
-You two enjoy. Bye!
This way. Into the alley.
Keep going!
Love Home Florist. This is Lily.
Lily.
-Thanks.
-How was the food?
Where do we put the fridge?
-In the kitchen, thanks.
-Okay.
Move up a little. Okay.
This way. This way.
-Miss Ku.
-The washing machine?
-Miss Ku?
-Go through the kitchen...
...onto the balcony.
That's not right, mister.
The drawer is on the right side.
Please nail it in. You have
to take the box off first.
-Where should we put this?
-Move back first.
Don't leave yet.
I need help.
Guys, take the case off outside.
So how about this?
Take the speakers and put it....
-Where should I put this?
-Over here, okay? Right here.
-How's that? Yeah.
-The cabinet? Put it here.
-That room?
-Yes, thanks.
-Sir, please take these boxes out.
-The mirror's in the way here.
-Is it okay if I move it?
-Okay. Thanks.
-Please put it in that room.
-Okay.
-Please take that case outside.
Here's another one.
Take it down.
Don't leave it by the elevator.
The dryer is done.
Want to test it?
Okay.
I heard you used to go to that
restaurant with your husband.
I rarely hear you mention him.
I'm not interested in the past.
Is he a bastard?
It's no one's fault.
We weren't good for each other.
No one's at fault.
Did your girlfriend leave?
She's flying to America this time.
Do you miss her?
I don't know if I miss her
or if I'm just lonely.
People are selfish.
We find a partner to keep us...
...from loneliness in old age.
Where do I put the mirror?
-Here. In the corner.
-There.
Just put it here. Careful.
All right. One, two, three.
That's good. Yeah, over.
There you go.
-Here?
-Okay.
You don't remember me, do you?
My mother gave me this
when I was 8.
I'm a bit reluctant
to give it up.
But keeping it....
You're giving it to your daughter?
And she's also 8?
Why do you want her
to study piano?
Yaqi?
My daughter-- Her mother
passed away two years ago.
I think all little girls like to play piano.
At any rate, I think it's nice
for girls to learn piano.
Have you asked her?
I want to surprise her.
I don't have much money,
and your price fits my budget.
So here I am.
Where's the metronome?
Do you mind its age?
Whose age?
You'll need a new one of these.
I mean the age of the piano.
It's old,
but the sound is excellent.
I haven't been taking care of it.
It needs tuning,
but it's still a good piano.
Sounds like I'm talking
about myself.
Promise me
you'll take care of it.
I've had it for 20 years.
I'm very attached to it.
-These are great dumplings.
-Really good!
Eat one garlic clove
and a dumpling.
One clove for each dumpling!
You sure?
Why not?
I'm sleeping alone tonight.
-What about you?
-Same here.
-Eat up, then.
-Okay.
Good!
Why didn't you order food?
-I've finished.
-Finished?
-Why didn't you wait for us?
-Forget it. I'll order.
You're half an hour late!
I didn't know the movie
was so long.
Jie, 1 0 dumplings for me.
Okay, 1 0 dumplings.
And five more for me.
-Beer.
-She's mad at us.
-Who?
-Her.
Why? Don't be.
Excuse me.
Can I have the chili sauce?
Don't be mad. Here's to you.
-From Jie to Jie.
-Right! You're both Jie.
Yeah. You have a connection
with both of us.
Let's drink.
Just one drink.
I'm leaving.
What happened?
Walking in the Rain
Does the song make you sad?
I don't have time for sadness.
I just try to enjoy it.
Xiang? Where are you?
Don't ever call me again!
-Morning.
What are you doing here?
-This is my block too.
-Oh.
Coming! Coming! Hello?
I got it, Qin.
-Hello?
-Bad day, Lily.
One of my shipments was rejected.
I have to go to China to fix it.
Emmy is having a party,
and I can't go. She's very upset.
This time, don't buy more jewelry.
If a man calls you
once or twice a day...
...what does it mean?
I'm sure he's not interested in me.
But he even calls me
when he's abroad.
Emmy! Going on vacation?
I'm going to Japan.
-How nice!
-To try to work things out.
Don't be temperamental.
He said he was pretty upset.
I asked if he'd quarreled
with Emmy.
He didn't want to discuss it.
He only says
that he's irritated...
...and must make
an important decision.
What do you think it is?
Wow, gorgeous!
I'm so sorry.
Hang on.
You still have
your wedding ring on.
But I've never seen
your family here.
Hey! You're so cute.
Come here!
It's your roommate's birthday today.
Her whole family's here.
I celebrated with my family last year.
But we mustn't be jealous of others.
Hurry, blow out the candles!
What are you doing?
-They want us to pay every week.
-Every week.
-Can I put it on my credit card?
-Yes.
How could my credit card
get denied?
I'll check it out.
Lend me your phone card.
No.
Operator.
I'm calling collect to Hong Kong.
You can keep your card.
I'm broke too.
I'll have my mom
send money here.
What do you mean,
no collect calls?
You call and ask
for Li Mei-ling.
Tell her
that her daughter's calling.
I'm not paying the charges.
Collect call, get it?
You don't know
what a collect call is?
We'd better find Shi Ge.
For what? He lies
and screws people's wives.
That's all he's good for.
Then why did you come here?
Shi Ge.
We have no money
to pay the rent.
You want some?
You really like singing?
I never meant to lie to you.
I wrote a lot of songs.
I worked really hard.
But they don't want them.
They said the songs were crap.
I took them to dinner.
-This studio's finished.
-Why?
I don't have money for the rent.
We can record a demo.
I can sing--
No way!
Crap! They're all crap!
Sorry.
Take the money and go home.
Good girl.
Just go home.
Don't sing.
Don't cry. Don't sing.
I never even got to record anything...
...and you want me to go home.
Go in.
Go in and sing.
Good girl.
Go inside and sing.
Go on.
I was thinking
about a blue story.
It gave me a wonderful feeling.
When I tell my friends the story,
they always ask, ''And then what?''
I say, ''There is no 'and then. '
The story is over. ''
I'm really homesick.
I'm finally feeling the pain.
Until there's a cure...
...perhaps soap operas
and ice cream...
...will do the trick.
Mom, I want to settle down,
but how?
It's easy to find someone
who loves me.
But where is the right man?
You always said,
''Men always leave. ''
So whenever I'm in love,
I'm always suspicious of the man.
Will I ever be lucky enough
to find true love?
Is love ever that simple?
When the right man shows up,
how will I know he's the one?
Mom...
...can you at least give me a sign?
Maybe with the sound of a bell...
...or angels singing...
...or even a gust of wind.
Yaqi, see that lady there?
She's the piano lady
I told you about.
Mother will be relieved
when I'm home.
My dad will stop nagging me.
Maybe I'll go back to Hong Kong
and become a flight attendant.
I'll fly everywhere...
...meet different people.
You can do it too!
Maybe we could meet
in France one day.
Does Malaysian Air fly to France?
I want to go to Greece and Egypt.
-I want to go to Italy.
-Italian men are gorgeous.
Yes, they are!
Spanish men are hotter!
Let's go there too.
I wonder how Shi Ge is.
Don't worry about him.
He'll always find a way.
Besides, he has love.
At least...
...he really loves my mom.
That's right.
He's my mother's lover.
I think my mother loves him
because...
...he cares about her
more than my father does.
Does Shi Ge know about you?
No.
I came all the way here...
...just to see if the guy...
...is a good guy.
This is the tape
from the earthquake.
You're on it.
Am I really?
Of course! I'm on there too!
Why else would I give it to you?
Bye!
Good.
Again. Go back to ''do.''
-Did you enjoy that?
-Very much.
-Why do you want to learn piano?
-I like it.
Yes. Liking it is important.
When you grow up, you can
play it for your loved ones.
Dad, I'll play for you.
I am an abandoned woman.
I am an abandoned woman!
So I am an abandoned woman.
Yeah. I am an abandoned woman.
Happy birthday.
-Morning!
Morning!
Good morning!
Have a nice day!