Tropical Fish
Nature works in mysterious ways.
A young man named Liu
wrote to us from Taipei.
He said he found a hearing aid
when he was little.
He tried it on
and heard a mysterious voice.
Since then,
he hears less of everyday sounds.
But the mysterious voice
keeps telling him
he is gaining a super power
with which he will save the world.
Very interesting!
Do go on sending us your letters.
Tell us your exotic experiences.
Share your sensations with us.
OK, before we hear more of
the legend of King Saloman,
the Super Fish-Man,
Iet's listen to a song first...
Liu Chih-chiang!
Just 31 days to the Joint Entrance Exam!
I can't go on punishing you.
But if you fail the Exam,
you'll suffer all your life.
Those who lack confidence...
Raise your hands!
Okay, hands down.
You've given up?
Throwing in the towel?
Cowards!
I had one student who never scored...
... higher than 400 in any test.
But he passed the Exam! You know why?
Because he never gave up.
He slept just 4 hours a day
in the final month.
He never let up.
And he made it!
You could do the same.
31 days is plenty.
Work hard and don't lose heart.
Who dares say you won't succeed?
Now I'll ask you again...
Those who lack confidence...
Raise your hands!
Are you giving up?
No!
Are you confident?
Yes!
Louder!
Did I ask you to play with me?
Are you any good?
Idiot!
Idiot! Let's go.
I'm ashamed to have a friend like you.
Have a cigarette.
Juvenile Division?
Where is the boy?
Did you see that thing in the paper?
About girls being slashed in the backside
when they're out walking at night?
Well, meet the wolf himself!
Bullshit!
You don't believe me?
I'll show you next time.
OK!
What do you want most after the Exam?
A tank of tropical fish.
Don't you have a small one already?
No fish yet?
My dad won't let me.
I put the tank away.
He never stops bugging you, huh?
You know what I want most?
What?
Get laid.
Hello, how are you?
You don't know me yet,
but I believe in fate.
Amid the sea of people,
we ride the same bus.
That's fate. It means
we could do other things together.
Let's go further
than the bus can take us.
I invite you on a submarine trip.
We'll soon bid farewell to Junior High.
At that historic moment, I'll show you
tropical fish on Green lsland.
Tsai Chia-chi, 8 out of 1 00!
Hsu Wei-li, 23!
Liu Chih-chiang, 41!
Hands out!
Have a puff.
Wasn't that a shitty subject
for an essay?
"My dream"? What the hell...
You know what I was gonna write?
What?
I was gonna write about my wet dream.
And?
I changed my mind.
Why?
Because I was afraid
teacher might've had the same dream.
Asshole!
So what did you write?
I wrote...
about a deep ocean fish...
which feeds on the dreams of kids.
When it's eaten 9,999 of them...
it will fly out of the sea.
And then?
If you glimpse it at daybreak...
you turn into a Super Fish-Man.
Man, aren't you going to Senior High?
What's all this crap
about fish and Fish-Men?
What goes on in your head?
How much are Green lsland submarine tours?
Are you serious about this?
Smoking?
Which school?
Lost your tongues?
Cheng Tao Junior High School.
Class?
Well?
Class 4, ninth grade.
Names?
Liu Chih-chiang.
You?
Hsu Wei-li.
Same class?
What's his name?
Liu Chih-chiang.
Phone number?
His is 767-8804.
Smart-ass!
And yours?
760-6451.
Don't lie to me!
Follow me.
Move it.
What happened?
The fucker touched me up.
He's coming...
Chih-chiang? This is Wei-li.
Has that guy called your dad?
No! Yours?
Not yet!
Fuck, I'm staying home tomorrow.
What about you?
I have to go to school.
Okay, tell teacher
I'm ill if she asks.
And if that guy calls...
... say that we were framed.
Got it?
Okay, got it.
Bye.
Yam fries, please.
Spicy?
Sure.
No, not on mine.
Okay.
How much is that?
$1 20.
Any money left?
I'll get it.
Thanks.
Got enough?
Then let's move! Bring your books.
$1 00.
He did better in History.
But not in Geography. See only 56!
He only had to memorize it.
It shows he didn't try hard enough!
And English, Math...
Ah, Liu, here you are!
Liu Chih-chiang's father?
Yes.
This is his last test result.
427.
Mr. Liu, don't be embarrassed about it.
These other parents
are in the same boat.
What I'm saying is...
all your children who are
sitting the Exam next month...
... will fail!
Chih-chiang!
These rooster testicles will do you good.
Good for what? It's hopeless.
You got a mark of only 400.
Do you want to study or not?
If not, what do you want?
You think you could be
a laborer or apprentice?
No one will want you.
Don't nag him over dinner!
You were the one who spoiled him!
It beats me.
Aren't you worried that he's backward?
What kind of mother are you?
You go to the next PTA meeting.
See if you don't feel ashamed.
Students!
This will be your last test here.
Do your best.
Now put away your books.
You knew all the answers
or just sat there?
What took you so long?
I didn't have a clue.
I'll never score higher than 400.
They say the last test seals your fate.
I'm doomed. Hey.
C'mon, it's over,
Iet's have fun.
How?
With this...
Hey, Chih-chiang.
Where's Dad?
He went to your school.
What for?
I don't know.
A case of kidnapping in Taipei.
7-year-old Wang Tao-nan
Ieft home yesterday,
and has not been seen since.
His family didn't notice his absence
until they received a ransom call
at noon today.
Head of the family...
Hey, Mom, Mom!
I know who kidnapped that kid!
Hey, Dad, look!
I know who kidnapped him!
Look at you rest result!
396!
Wei-li.
Wei-li, I'm going home.
Wei-li!
What the fuck?
Chih-chiang, run!
Stop!
Stop, you little asshole!
Now here's a letter from
Hsieh Fu-lai in Taichung.
He says a beautiful three-eyed girl
... appeared in his mirror...
... smiling at him...
... when he peeled an apple at midnight.
That's truly fascinating.
Back to the legends of King Saloman.
Saloman was bitten by the old shark
when he tried to rescue the princess.
Will he manage to escape?
We'll be back after this song.
On your feet!
You're asking for it.
Telephone number?
Don't fuck with me! The number!
767-8804.
Get that down.
767...
8804!
Hello, Dad? I've been kidnapped.
How do you know?
Wei-li? No, this is for real.
There's...
Got it straight? I have your son.
If you want him back, get 5 million ready.
That's your problem! Listen carefully.
Put it in the trash can
outside Zhongxiao Theater.
5 million, at 1 pm tomorrow.
I warn you!
If the money isn't there,
or the cops show up,
get ready for your boy's funeral.
So, it's your show now.
Let's wait and see.
Are you worth 5 million to your dad?
What about the little one?
Shall we let him go?
You must be fucking crazy!
Free him to turn us in?
I'm not that bored with my life.
So what do we do?
His old man doesn't care.
He was adopted.
Never mind,
now this one's father is worried.
Stop gawking!
You too!
If your dad doesn't show up
with the cash,
it'll be curtains for you.
Help me with my glasses.
Stop kissing me!
Long time no see!
What's your line of work now?
What are you doing here?
Me? -What are you doing here?
I'm on duty.
No kidding!
Me? This is a stake out for a kidnap.
A kidnap? -Right!
A kidnap! Why are you here?
I'm on duty. How come you...
Hey, isn't that Tsai?
Sure it is!
And Chen's over there, the whole team.
It's chaos.
You've got a small army here.
Right!
Who are you out to nail?
Whoever picks up the ransom.
Nobody's showed up yet. -Not yet.
You're in construction?
You've made a fortune!
No, no. Who told you that?
Don't forget your old pals,
now you're rich.
I'll look you up when I retire.
See if you can give me a job.
Hell yes.
Make sure you do that.
So why are you here?
Who, me?
You! -You?
Yeah, what are you up to?
I'm meeting someone here.
So where's your friend?
What time is it?
He hasn't shown up? It's odd...
Can't talk now because I'm on duty.
I'll buy you a drink sometime
when I'm on leave.
Great!
Need any help now?
No, you've left this stuff behind.
We've enough support.
Well, I'll be off then.
OK!
Sorry about the rush, maybe we...
Say hello to Tsai for me.
Sure! I'll do.
Sorry. Hey, sorry.
Thank you.
Thank you. Bye.
I want to watch cartoons.
There's none on.
No cable TV here?
No. Eat this...
A man was knocked off
his motorcycle...
... and run over by a truck
alongside works...
... for the Mass Transit Railway
on Roosevelt Road.
The unfortunate victim died
immediately.
Deceased was Lai Mao-chun, aged 46...
An ex-policeman
now working in construction.
His next-of-kin have been informed.
Careful!
Come on, move it!
Takes two guys to carry one painting?
Hey, this is valuable old stuff.
Can you manage that alone?
Be careful...
A-ching, where have you been hiding?
Deep fuckin' asleep!
Yeah, too much sex!
Are you hungry?
What?
I'm so hungry.
Me too.
Where? Here?
Sorry, I'll rub it for you.
Hey, don't run away!
Bro, wait for me!
Where are you going?
Wait for me!
You'll get us into trouble...
Hurry up!
A-hsien!
Are you studying?
You gonna sit the test again?
No, wanna get a job.
Doing what?
Black Bull says I can collect debts for him.
Fuck that for a game of cobblers.
A-chun, long time no see.
Join us, it's been too long.
You haven't come for ages.
Come on, sit here.
A-chun, why isn't A-tsai with you?
He's working in Taipei?
That's good.
My A-ching works in Taipei, too.
Please ask A-tsai to take care of Ching
when you see him.
Do you know that man outside?
You don't!
Join us... sit here.
Let us feed ourselves.
We won't run away.
Alright, here.
How come they caught you too?
I was gonna rescue you.
Rescue me? You're that strong?
Heard of King Saloman?
I'm King Saloman, Super Fish-Man.
You're kidding.
If you're as good as you say...
... why didn't you get the bad guys?
I was on half-power.
Look, my power-unit is dead.
Wow! But what can we do now?
So we're gonna die for sure then?
Shall we try to get help?
Okay... Help! Help!
Okay, place your bets!
Hey, Hsiung!
A-ching! How are you doing?
Where's Auntie?
What is it?
Gonna talk to her.
Okay, hang on.
Be right there.
Lost again?
Fraid so! New game!
Lay your bets!
I'll give you two for 500,
it's good stuff.
Hey, look who's back!
A-ching, when did you get back?
This afternoon.
Doing well in Taipei?
Not too great.
Looking for your aunt? -Yeah.
She's inside.
Mom's inside
It's a swindle.
In that costume at your age...
Shut the fuck up.
You chose to buy the ticket.
Did anyone drag you in here?
Go look at your own mother.
You curse my mother?
Yes, so what?
Time's up, out you go.
Crazy! -It's a con!
Nobody forced you in.
I'm going to the police.
Go ahead, asshole! Whatever you want.
Nobody's stopping you!
I'm earning an honest penny here!
Auntie, I need to talk to you.
A-ching? Wait outside.
I'll just get changed.
Okay.
A-ching, choose one for yourself.
What's the problem?
I'll tell you...
Yes?
Quality clothing, Miss.
Two for 500, or 290 for one. Alright?
Department store quality.
Pack up, Ming-chu, we're going home.
What's up, Mom?
Tell you later, where's A-hsiung?
A-hsiung, we're leaving!
Still gambling?
You play while we do all the work.
You'll die gambling.
I didn't bet much.
Empty pockets, that's why.
I've told you...
We're going broke
because you never work hard.
Nobody buys this con-trick any more.
Says who?
Just as well we don't rely on you.
Or we'd have starved to death.
But this whole thing was your idea.
What's eating you?
Told you not to wear sunglasses!
You're clueless!
This way, nobody will recognize me.
Fool!
Let me look!
Looks so stupid,
no wonder he got kidnapped.
I've never seen a kidnap victim before.
Auntie, what shall we do now?
Bring them home.
Bring them home?
Too dangerous out here.
Help me, A-hsiung,
we'll take them home.
Okay.
What the hell are you doing?
Get the light off my face!
Delicious!
Really good!
Not bad!
I want a hamburger.
Keep your voice down, damn you.
Isn't this good enough for you?
Shut up! Another word from you
and I'll make hamburger
from your willie.
Eat up!
A-chuan, come and join us.
You're such a good cook.
Don't stay in the kitchen.
My dear in-law, do join us!
Congratulations!
Grandma, it's these two.
These two are your sons?
Such dear boys.
She's lost it again.
Over here, Grandma.
What?
Whose slipper is this?
Looks like mine.
Are you eating with your feet?
A-ching,
when will the water go down?
Dunno! Sometimes it takes a day.
But sometimes it might take days.
What caused this anyhow?
Maybe the dam?
I really don't know.
Yeah, it's because the dam broke.
It's our irrigation system.
Water can't flow out.
Listen to Mr. Scholar!
Why isn't it fixed?
Why don't you complain about it?
No point, no-one's smart around here.
At least you got that right.
That's why I asked to study.
But you quit school!
A-chang,
Iet's see the TV news.
Okay.
Singer Lu Fei was mobbed
by fans at his concert.
One woman fainted in the crush.
But happily
she regained consciousness
after being rushed to hospital.
Lu Fei! Lu Fei!
Events really have a way of telling us
what a kaleidoscopic modern world
we live in.
What's up?
Relax,
we won't hurt you.
We'll free you
when your dad coughs up.
Why the tears?
Didn't you hear me?
Auntie,
he's a bit hard of hearing.
One dumb
and the other deaf.
If I were your dad,
I wouldn't pay.
It's now three days
since Liu Chih-chiang was kidnapped.
But there are no new leads.
The police suspect a link
between this case,
and the kidnap of another school boy
Wang Tao-nan.
The kidnapper telephoned only once
on the day that Liu was taken.
The police have issued
this picture of Liu Chih-chiang.
Any citizen who sights Liu Chih-chiang
is requested to contact...
Not a bad picture of you.
He looks better in the flesh.
Not much difference.
Why are you crying?
You sound like a
professional funeral wailer.
That's enough.
Let's clear up, it's bedtime.
I wanna pee.
Pee anywhere you want!
We're underwater anyway.
Are you stronger than
the four invincible kings?
God damn it, go to sleep!
Auntie, where do we go from here?
How do we get him back to Taipei?
Hell, we can't let him go now.
Didn't you promise
to take the family to Taipei and
support your brother's schooling?
And what about your Grandma...
I'm totally lost.
The kidnapping was my boss's idea.
Now he's dead.
This wasn't my plan in the first place.
Don't worry.
I'll help you out.
These kids will bring us a fortune,
won't they?
Nah, the little one is worth nothing.
How come?
His dad doesn't want him.
What kind of father is he?
I learned it later.
He's not his real dad.
His mother had him
by an earlier boyfriend.
Then that guy took off.
His mother married this other guy.
She killed herself few years back.
Killed herself? Why?
Because he treated her badly.
And he took a mistress.
So he's really not his dad.
The kid is an orphan now.
poor little thing.
This father has no heart at all.
Right!
He had dealings with my boss.
He cheated my boss.
That's why he took the kid.
The man doesn't want the kid back.
He's happy that we took him!
Such misfortune.
And he's so cute.
The ninth grade student
Liu Chih-chiang is absent
because he has been kidnapped.
So that he could not be with us today.
I'm sure we all share the same sorrow.
We condemn the wrong-doers.
And sincerely trust that
all of you here today
will never stray from
the path of righteousness.
Shall we observe one minute's silence
for Liu Chih-chiang.
We pray for his safe return.
Ming-chu!
Stop!
You want to shake your baby out?
Go get some rest!
See that?
She could go into labor any minute.
And she's jumping around like a child.
That little one might try to escape.
He wouldn't dare.
Don't be so sure.
Maybe the other one is an orphan too?
No, he isn't.
I know he has a father.
Certain?
Yeah!
Look, another update on TV.
Our Chih-chiang has always been
a weak child.
Please be kind to him.
He loves sausages
and preserved eggs.
Have a heart, feed him well, please.
Chih-chiang,
who were all those letters to?
I beg his captors to set my boy free!
I'll do whatever you tell me to!
I promise I will do. No matter what.
Please give him back to me.
The Joint Entrance Exam
is only ten days away.
If he isn't back, he'll miss it!
I beg of you!
Who are you criminals working for?
Explain to me what you want!
You can't just abduct kids like this!
Talk to me city councilors candidate
Hsu Huo-tu.
My doors are open to you.
Liu Chih-chiang is a fine student.
He is well behaved.
He doesn't talk much,
and gets good grades.
He has a bright future.
The police call for the immediate release
of the captives.
According to the police...
Auntie.
Let's have a word inside.
What is it?
Come inside!
I'm sorry.
I'd have let you go
if I'd known about the Exam.
But now you're here!
Can't just let you go!
But never mind.
You can study here.
I'll take you home
when we get the cash.
Work at it, Chih-chiang!
Don't end up useless, like me.
You can start right away!
Oh...
Right!
See here, Chih-chiang!
Maybe you can use
these books of A-chuan's.
Geography, History, you name it.
If there's not enough,
I can buy more in Chiayi City.
See all those A-chuan underlined?
She used to study hard.
Eight!
Your turn.
A-hsien, who are those kids?
Can't tell you now.
But we're gonna get rich.
We'll move to Taipei...
No more floods!
It doesn't flood in Taipei?
Dope! You think
the President's Palace floods?
Eighteen!
Show your cards.
You didn't see them.
Why'd you have to show her?
What's going on here?
What are you looking at?
Who can play with her?
Are these the right books?
I got them in Chiayi City.
It's Math?
How's it going?
If you don't get it, write it down.
I can ask someone in the village.
Mr. Lin is very good
in Chinese studies.
And I think he knows Math too.
I can ask him anything you don't get.
Mrs. Lin, is Mr. Lin home?
I got the answer, Chih-chiang.
I'll explain...
Mr. Lin says... this is...
In the triangle ABC...
Because... well...
The angle ACB equals...
Is greater than...
Therefore angle E...
Hang on, I'll ask him again.
How old are these?
Eat quietly.
You sound like a pig in a trough.
You like my idea?
No, too dangerous!
Dongshi Township is too small
for us to keep it secret.
No it ain't.
What danger?
Old Hui shot it!
Never seen such a big fish!
Grandma,
we're talking about the ransom.
We're not shooting fish.
Dangerous or not.
You know,
Old Hui died in an accident.
Grandma, you live in a different world!
Where the hell have we got to?
A-ching, I've been thinking...
We can't risk getting this wrong.
They'll shoot us if we screw up.
You don't know?
It's death penalty!
Let's think about this.
The Exam is few days away...
I don't think Chih-chiang
is gonna make it in the Exam.
Why not?
If he studies hard when he's home...
That's right.
He can study hard here, can't he?
And it's quieter here.
What I mean is...
There's still several days to go.
All we must do is clinch the deal
before the big day.
Right?
Okay.
Okay, my ass!
You're so useless.
What's the big deal here?
Who cares if he passes or fails?
If I were you...
Well? What?
He brought them here,
nothing to do with you.
Shut up!
We'd be right to take heed.
That's what we should do.
We shouldn't rush.
We should take heed.
Old Hui failed to take heed.
That's why he was struck by that car.
She's off again.
Ma, who is this Old Hui?
How should I know?
She's bad enough
and you're dancing to her tune?
Talk about Old Hui...
Let's postpone
the rest of this discussion.
Sure, why not?
Get some beer, A-chang.
C'mon, let's play again.
Are you serious?
It'll cure your headache!
Play again?
Sure. -Think you can win some back?
No way,
just don't lose your ass!
Who's losing what?
Let's play then!
No problem!
Make some space here.
Ming-chu,
clear this mess away.
Sit on those papers.
Put it away!
It's so bitter!
You like this bitter taste?
Come on.
Deal me in.
You want her in, too?
As I bought this book...
The bookseller found his bird dead.
Yesterday it sang, today it's gone forever.
Life just slips away.
Just as my youth will slip away.
Are you through in there, Sis?
What the hell's taking so long?
"A-chuan,
why don't you speak to me? "
"l am the summer slipping into autumn"
"You can revive me from hibernation"
"l am the dust you stir up"
"A-chuan..."
I knew you had the hots for her.
You fancy getting clobbered?
Piss off!
Only ten days to go to the Exam.
I'm sure that all students
are striving their utmost.
All of them know that the Exam...
... is crucial for their futures.
But for Liu who has been missing
for more than ten days,
will he have a future?
This must be a concern for all of us.
This morning his father and
Councilor Yang delivered a petition
to the Education Dept..
asking for the boy to be exempted the Exam.
I entrusted my boy to the school.
Now my boy's been kidnapped.
I wonder...
...doesn't the school have a duty?
The Exam is approaching
but my boy has been denied
access to his books.
Who will compensate him?
What if he's not back for the Exam?
Wouldn't that be unjust?
Tired? Let's hit the beach.
That tickles!
How was the beach?
Great!
Beautiful tropical fish in the sea!
What bullshit are you talking now?
We don't have tropical fish here.
The sea's full of them!
You're a bigger liar than I am.
Ain't no tropical fish on this coast.
They're all in the South.
You have to go to Kending.
Don't even know that!
Dunno what they teach you in school.
You're pig ignorant.
Okay, enough, eat your meal.
When can you recharge your power-unit?
I need sea-water.
It contains idiotic potassium.
I need that for my recharge.
To regain my super-powers.
The ocean is so mysterious.
There are things we can't see
or even imagine.
Bro, will you tell me a story?
Okay.
In the deepest part of the sea...
... there's a weird-looking fish.
It feeds on children's dreams.
When it has eaten 9,999 of them,
it will fly out of the sea on wings.
If you happen to be out at sea...
... as the sun comes up...
... shout out "I'm a fish!"
Then that winged fish will fly up...
... and take you on a trip
through the sea...
...right to the ends of that world.
And in the Dragon King's palace...
... it will feed you a red pearl.
And once you've eaten it...
... you'll become King Saloman.
Then you'll be so bright.
You'll be top of your class.
Hey, A-ching!
You're back?
Didn't look me up?
A-fu, long time no see!
No kidding.
Have a smoke.
Putting on weight!
And very tanned!
Really?
Fishing?
Who are those two kids?
Those two kids...
They're...
...my friend's sons.
Their parents went abroad
so I took them back.
How are you doing in Taipei?
I hear you're getting rich.
Nah, can't earn much as a laborer.
You do better than me on your salary.
Then come back and work the boats!
Fishing's hard work,
but the hours are flexible.
Everyone's leaving,
I get so bored here.
How long before you go back to Taipei?
Are you going back?
I'll leave in a couple of days.
Really?
Look me up before you go.
We'll catch up properly.
I will do.
Gotta start my shift now.
Okay...
Bye! -Bye!
Don't forget!
Sure... see ya!
A-chuan!
Bro,
when will you be recharged?
It takes time.
There are only five days to the Exam.
The police believe that
Liu Chih-chiang is still alive.
This station has received
countless calls...
... expressing concern for his fate.
Our callers are all praying...
... for his safe return
in time for the Exam.
One, two, three.
Ming-chu,
take some rest.
The doctor told me to exercise.
A-hsiung!
The Exam's only five days away!
Are you blind?
You just sat on my foot!
I'm sorry.
There's only five days left.
We gotta think what to do.
We're running out of time.
I've been trying to think!
You think I like this waiting around?
You have to think of something
The main thing is...
... to fix the time
and place for the handover.
Then we can call his father.
How mush should we demand?
One million?
Just one million?
Are we running a charity here?
At least two million,
Ieave room to bargain.
Bargaining over two million?
Why not demand five and then bargain?
Idiot!
Okay, let's go for five million.
Where will we make the switch?
Betel nuts!
Old Hui liked betel nuts!
Having mentioned betel nuts...
I know a guy who sells betel nuts.
I have an idea.
Hsiung. -What?
When did you last see him?
I wonder if he's still in business.
The stall looks deserted.
We did military service together.
Haven't seen him since we got out.
You mean 20 or 30 years ago?
What? Don't exaggerate!
We spoke to each other two years ago!
Did you get the address right?
We've been waiting for an hour.
This is it!
Zhongzheng Rd. Betel Nuts!
There's no mistake!
Many Zhongzheng Rd. in Taiwan.
None of your business, kid.
It sure is his business!
A-hsiung, it's too hot in here.
Enough of this waiting.
Let's go home.
All right.
I'll call A-ching.
A-ching! We're giving up!
Damn!
Are you through?
I'm trying to do business here.
Sorry, just a bit longer.
Mr. Liu, I'm afraid we must give up.
I've checked.
I think this is the wrong place.
There are many betel nut stalls
on this road.
We have many men on the case.
You go home first.
Maybe the kidnappers will call again.
Don't you worry, go on home.
I'll take care of things here.
I'll go check. You go home.
It's okay.
Call it off.
Thank you.
One pack of betel nuts!
Call it off.
Fuck, if I get through
I'll add a million
and curse the shit out of them!
Right!
Hey, aren't they cops?
Uh-oh...
A new development in the Liu kidnapping.
The abductor called
his parents yesterday
and demand five million in cash
at a betel nut stall
on Zhongzheng Road.
The kidnappers are now
known to be a gang.
Yesterday's caller
was not the man who called before.
Here is the recording of the call.
Hello, Mr. Liu?
Fuck, lousy pictures!
You want money or your son?
But I feel...
You son's life is worth more...
So I feel...
You son's life is worth more, right?
Cut the crap!
Get to the point!
Mr. Liu, let me tell you.
We have your son here.
Get five million ready in cash.
Or we won't be responsible
for his safety.
Let me hear!
Don't snatch the phone!
Old Hui,
why not come over for a drink?
Hell!
A-ching, take her home!
Hello Mr. Liu?
Did you hear me?
Yes, yes!
So it's a deal.
Have five million ready tomorrow.
Be at the betel nut stand
on Zhongzheng Road.
We'll meet you there.
At what time?
Four... four o'clock.
Ming-chu, will four be too late?
No.
Okay, four it is.
A-chang, anything else to say?
Quick, we're almost out of change.
Ma, you can't mention Chang's name!
You've given us away!
Damn!
Hello Mr. Li,
you got all the details?
Tomorrow, four o'clock! Bye!
Ming-chu sounded the worst.
You think you sounded better?
To think we all got on TV!
Although it sounded like a prank call,
the police have gleaned some clues.
The police believe the mastermind
to be a man named Old Hui.
The call was traced to
the village of Dongshi.
The police are now combing the area.
They expect to find the boy
before the Exam date.
How'd they manage that?
What shall we do?
Bro, the place is crawling with cops.
They're questioning A-fu.
We're done for!
A-fu has seen the two kids!
Auntie, what shall we do?
It's not safe here!
Think of something!
Where can we hide them?
Grandma, what do you think?
What do you think she knows about it?
Let's send them out to sea on a boat.
Out to sea?
That's not a bad idea!
Right, we know the sea
Yeah! -Right, out to sea!
Shut up, you kids.
What about a boat? -Boat...
Where are my schoolbooks?
What have you done with my books?
Chih-chiang has them.
He's taking the Exam.
What the hell?
A-chuan's acting strangely.
He's had her books for days already!
Now you're looking for your books?
By what right did you take my books?
A-chuan!
By what right?
Stop it! Stop it!
You hit me?
You dare hit me?
I ended up like this
because you forced me to quit school.
People look down on me.
Do I deserve this?
A-chuan, don't!
Ming-chu, look after her.
Who are those two?
Why are they fighting?
Black Carp,
do you read me? Over.
Red Dragon,
this is Black Carp. Over.
Had breakfast yet?
Not yet.
A-chang is so dumb.
Sending you off with books
but no food.
Is Chih-chiang studying?
Yes, studying English now.
Good.
But what are you going to eat?
A-hsiung has a fishing rod.
Says he'll catch something.
No problem!
So we'll be having sashimi soon.
Auntie, the food doesn't matter.
The main thing is...
Have you called the parents?
We'll dock when you hear from them.
All right.
Don't worry.
A-hsien has gone to call them.
We'll know soon.
Tell Chih-chiang to study hard.
Read you! Bye! Over
Bye!
This walkie-talkie is quite useful.
Did you get through?
The line's always busy.
Go and try again.
I've tried many times.
Just do it.
Go on!
What a weird family...
Talking on the phone for so long.
Get in!
Old Hui has gone South!
We're ordered to trace him,
got it?
Get in!
Shit, we two always get left behind.
What?
You'd rather be in the firing line?
Get a move on!
Where to?
"Snow White's Sex-Crazed Sister"
Fuck, what is it?
Snow White's sister?
Lucky I found this...
... or I'd die of hunger.
Thought you were an expert?
What have you caught?
How can Chih-chiang study
when he's hungry?
I'm doing my best.
Fuck! The fish just aren't biting.
Anyway, show some respect!
I'm trying to feed us all.
Chih-chiang!
Coming.
Uncle Hsiung, what's that?
Shit!
Why?
Because I'm full of it.
Only when King Saloman was taken
did he realize the Mermaid Princess
was the shark's sister.
The Sea Monster snatched the princess.
So Saloman and the shark teamed up
in a bid to rescue her
from the sea monster.
What will happen next?
But first,
Iet's pause for a letter.
Chen Hsiao-tung from Hualien
writes to say
there's a little green man
in his uncle's guitar.
And whenever his uncle plays it,
the little green man sings along.
But it's been a while
since he heard him.
His uncle married and stopped playing.
Come on, whip it out! -Excuse me?
Haven't got one? -Here!
A club! I knew yours was small!
See, I got a big spade!
Enough!
How can you play
at a time like this?
You're driving me crazy! Stop it.
Pay attention!
Okay, okay.
A-hsien, did you try to call?
Sure.
There's only one day left!
You didn't play the fruit machine?
No, I've still got your coin.
See, it's the same coin, made in 1 981!
Maybe you're dialing the wrong number?
No way. I wrote it on my hand!
767-8804...
Right!
Strange, huh?
It's the right number.
Why can't you get through?
How should I know?
This is killing me.
Shit, only these two tiddlers all day!
Shame on you.
Not exactly a sashimi dinner.
Is there any mustard?
Nope.
You're lucky we found this soy sauce!
This is not a Japanese restaurant!
Chih-chiang, have some.
Aren't you hungry?
Hsiung! -What?
Get A-chang to bring some food out.
No, what if the cops see him?
So we starve to death.
No we won't.
I'll try the walkie-talkie.
Yeah, give it a try.
Red Dragon,
this is Black Carp calling.
Do you read me? Over.
Well?
Red Dragon, do you read me?
Shit, may be the battery.
Oh no!
Red Dragon...
this is Black Carp calling...
Hey,
Let's get up for tomorrow's sunrise
Why?
Because that's
when the winged fish flies up!
Oh, right!
Uncle Ching!
Can you wake us
before dawn tomorrow?
Why?
I want to watch the sun rise.
Watch the sun rise?
You can watch that from heaven!
Okay, I'll wake you.
Get up!
Get up, dawn's coming!
Bro, get up!
It's nearly dawn!
How long to go?
Not long, see that light coming?
Will the winged fish show up?
Sure, if you're sincere.
And if fate allows.
Okay.
Here it comes!
I'm a fish!
What's all this?
What's that sound?
The winged fish is coming.
Fly to me!
This way!
This is the last day before the Exam.
There are less than 20 hours to go.
Keep watching for regular updates.
Now we cross to
an interview with the police.
This is Chen Shih-chieh reporting
from Dongshi Township.
Coming to you live.
I expected to find a large force here
But a search has uncovered
only these two officers.
Gentlemen, can you tell us...
...why you are the only ones here?
Well, it was because
... yesterday our Chief had a special...
Sorry, it's classified
for student Liu's safety.
Again, gentleman...
...have you found any clues here?
Not just yet.
But I'm sure that
LlU is here in Dongshi Township.
I may be fresh out of Police Academy,
but I've always had good hunches.
And my senior here is a sure shot.
I'm sure we'll nail the villains.
We'll risk our lives for Liu
if necessary.
Turning to Mr. Sure Shot...
Do you have an opinion about this?
We just follow orders.
Thanks for sharing that with us.
Hello?
A-ching, what the hell?
How come nobody answers?
The Exam is just hours away...
This is just...
Here, not over there!
Enough over there!
Stop shouting at me!
A-hsien, try once more.
We must get through.
Again!
Yes!
You're useless!
Get a move on!
You walk like you're at sea.
Well?
Only a few hours left.
The walkie-talkie is dead.
Wonder if they've made contact
with his family?
What shall we do?
It's three now,
Iet's wait till four.
If we still haven't heard...
We'll take him to the Exam,
and forget about the money.
And forget about the money?
Then what about your family?
Have you thought about them?
Forget about the money!
Forget about the money?!
Then what the hell am I doing here?
Ma, it's almost four. Let's give up.
Ma, we can't play with his future!
A-hsiung!
I'm trying to take a leak!
What time is it?
It's too late, let's go back.
You really want to give up?
Can't start this thing.
Great piece of junk you borrowed!
Now what?
How do we get back?
Let me think.
Sure, take your time.
What now?
What?
Get over here!
What's up?
Cops!
Chih-chiang, Tao-nan...
Put on these life-vests.
What now?
It'll be quicker to swim.
Swim?
Ma!
Ma, let's give up!
Okay...
... go fetch them.
Okay, hurry up.
It's almost four. Quick.
Fair? I ranked first in High School.
but I didn't pass my first Entrance Exam.
What's fair about it?
You call it fair?
You should have studied more!
What the hell do you know?
What was your mark?
From which school?
Okay. Okay.
Let's not get over-excited now.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be right back to discuss
"Kidnap and the Entrance Exam"
Juan, we're going to fetch Chih-chiang.
We're sending him back to Taipei.
Hurry, they may be ashore by now.
How in heaven will we find them?
Maybe A-ching is bringing them back.
Let's wait for them.
How could he be?
He might be.
Hey, cops!
A-ching, no need to hurry.
I don't want to sit the Exam.
Say no more.
No matter what, you gotta do it!
Shit, how did I get into this?
The Board should award
Liu a special bonus mark.
Eighteen!
Ten!
I'll give you another chance.
Stop thumping me, will ya?
Again!
Where the hell are they?
A-ching, I have to take a rest.
Keep going, we're almost there.
But I've got cramp!
Hang in there, Liu Chih-chiang!
A-ching, go on without me!
What are you saying?
Come on, I'll push you.
Look, a boat! Help!
God save you, Liu Chih-chiang!
Eighteen!
Two hundred sausages!
Junior, tell you what?
I have a hunch...
... we're about to nab Old Hui.
I feel a vacation coming on.
Hey boss, do me a favor.
Heat 40 of them for me.
40! -Okay...
Junior, take 40.
Give them to everyone in sight.
My treat!
Okay.
Shouldn't we see the boat by now?
Maybe something's happened?
Cut the crap!
Hello, everyone.
My senior won 200 sausages.
Help yourselves, on us!
Come on, everyone.
Thank you.
Thanks a lot.
Waiting for someone?
Yes, for my husband!
"A sailor boy for me"?
I've heard that one.
Help yourselves, there's plenty.
Okay...
Asshole!
Look, there's a boat!
Looks like Hsiung.
A-hsiung!
Ten!
I quit!
400 sausages!
You owe me 400 sausages, buddy.
Senior, look, a boat!
Shall we treat them too?
Sure, it's all on me.
All on me.
Come on, quick.
Coming up!
A-hsiung, what's wrong with you?
I'm dying.
A-hsiung, don't die on me!
He just has cramp, Auntie!
He won't die.
Thank you, we owe you for this.
Quick, there's a cop coming.
Here, sausages for everyone!
One for you, kid.
Don't move!
Sir! Sir!
What?
Liu Chih-chiang!
Uh?
On your knees, all of you.
Call the Chief, right now!
Quick!
You two, stand up!
Liu Chih-chiang?
Wang Tao-nan?
Did these two kidnap you?
No! They rescued us.
So where are the kidnappers?
They stole a boat from these guys...
... threw us in the water and got away.
These men kept us afloat
until we were picked up by this boat.
Is any of you Old Hui?
No! No!
I'm A-ching.
I'm A-hsiung.
He's my husband.
Sir! Sir!
Chief says to send them back to Taipei.
So he can sit the Exam.
They're sending back-up now.
Good.
These aren't the villains.
Help them up.
Sorry about that.
Please get up.
You helped us crack the case.
Our back-up is on the way.
Please wait for them.
Liu Chih-chiang, come with us.
You wait a while, please.
I have 400-odd sausages there...
Help yourselves!
Chih-chiang!
Go!
Do it! Pass the Exam!
You can do it!
Bye bye!
Do well! We're with you!
Do well!
Bye!
Still busy!
Weird...
Let me try for you. What's the number?
767-8804.
In Taipei?
02-767...
What's that "02"?
Area code.
Oh, right!
Thank you!
They've found him!
Get his things ready for the Exam.
No time to lose.
What else? Quick!
Here, I'll help you.
What's this?
For Liu Chih-chiang, from A-chuan.
What's it?
I don't know.
Okay, anything else?
Move out of my way!
Liu Chih-chiang, this is from A-chuan.
A-chuan!
Chih-chiang, you said
you saw tropical fish in the sea.
I used to be a bit like you.
Thinking there were tropical fish here.
Later I found out...
... there aren't any in the sea here.
But last time we got flooded...
... I found this tropical fish...
... Ieft behind in a ditch.
I've no idea how it got here.
I want you to have it.
I hope you like it.
Although we never
talked to each other...
... I know you're a dreamer.
I envy you.
You can study.
Even sit the Exam.
But I can't.
A year ago,
my brother took me out of school
and sent me to work in Kaohsiung.
I fell in love with a guy there.
To my horror...
... he and his friend raped me.
I used to be a dreamer too.
But now...
I have no dreams left.
We have to walk through life,
not dream it.
Make the best of what you have.
Stick to the road you choose!
Good luck with the Exam!
We're at the Taichung exit
from the highway.
Liu Chih-chiang's police escort
is due any moment.
Huge crowds are here
to catch a glimpse of him.
Liu Chih-chiang! Go!
This is a touching scene.
Now we hand you back to
Chen Shih-chieh in Taipei.
Since the two brave policemen
rescued him...
... kind people have rushed
to help Liu Chih-chiang.
Offering books and test papers...
... to welcome him back
Liu Chih-chiang! Go for it!
The Exam results are out, and so...
... we'll end our story
of King Saloman today.
Now here's a letter
from Wang Tao-nan
of Puguang Orphanage in Taipei.
He's written it phonetically.
He's probably very young.
He says, there's a kind of fish...
... Iiving at the bottom of the sea...
... which feeds on children's dreams.
When it's eaten 9,999 dreams...
... it will fly
out from the sea on wings.
Wang Tao-nan says
he saw it a month ago.
A gigantic fish flying up
from the bottom of the sea.