1
00:00:02,324 --> 00:00:04,189
Mouna! Mouna!
莫那…莫那…

2
00:00:06,395 --> 00:00:09,523
Bakan,
why does Mouna need so many matches?
巴冈，莫那干嘛一直在买火柴？

3
00:00:10,433 --> 00:00:11,491
Who knows?
谁知道…

4
00:00:13,669 --> 00:00:15,068
Had any meat, my boy?
有没有吃肉呀？

5
00:00:15,938 --> 00:00:17,803
Have a drink!
喝杯酒吧！

6
00:00:23,412 --> 00:00:26,347
Father! Father!
父亲…父亲！

7
00:00:27,716 --> 00:00:31,854
Father, can we slaughter a cow?
父亲…再杀头牛吧！

8
00:00:31,854 --> 00:00:33,823
Not enough to eat?
不够吃吗？

9
00:00:33,823 --> 00:00:37,384
It's enough, but we haven't had beef
for such a long time
够！可是大家好久没吃牛肉了…

10
00:00:40,029 --> 00:00:41,724
Do it then
…那就杀吧！

11
00:00:43,399 --> 00:00:46,334
Let's slaughter a cow!
再杀一头牛啊！

12
00:00:48,904 --> 00:00:52,101
Hooray! Let's slaughter a cow!
好啊！头目…再杀一头牛唷！

13
00:01:21,170 --> 00:01:22,404
Baso, grab it!
巴索…抓好…

14
00:01:22,404 --> 00:01:24,773
Grab its legs!
扳它的脚…

15
00:01:24,773 --> 00:01:25,899
Come on!
快点！

16
00:01:29,411 --> 00:01:31,436
I've cut off the head
of the Japanese Governor-general
日本总督的头被我拿下来了…

17
00:01:35,351 --> 00:01:37,911
Wow! What a party!
哇！这么热闹啊…

18
00:01:41,390 --> 00:01:43,392
Sir Yoshimura
吉村大人…

19
00:01:43,392 --> 00:01:44,950
Whose wedding day is it?
今天又是谁结婚啊？

20
00:01:45,995 --> 00:01:47,796
It's Watan and Lubi's
是瓦旦和露比结婚…

21
00:01:47,796 --> 00:01:49,732
Come! Have a drink with us, sir
来！大人，你也来杯小米酒吧！

22
00:01:49,732 --> 00:01:50,824
No
不要！

23
00:01:52,167 --> 00:01:54,937
No -Come on, have a drink
-不要！
-来啦，一起喝嘛！

24
00:01:54,937 --> 00:01:56,472
No way
不要啦…

25
00:01:56,472 --> 00:01:58,807
I don't drink the wine with your nasty saliva in it
我才不喝这种用口水做的脏酒！

26
00:01:58,807 --> 00:02:00,276
Come on, have a drink
-I told you that I don't want to
-来啦，喝嘛！
-跟你讲不要…

27
00:02:00,276 --> 00:02:02,141
Your hand is all dirty with blood
小心你手上的血…

28
00:02:05,581 --> 00:02:08,717
I invited you with good will
-You son-of-a-bitch!
-我这么好意请你…
-你这家伙…

29
00:02:08,717 --> 00:02:10,810
You've soiled me with blood!
看你把我弄得都是血了…

30
00:02:11,620 --> 00:02:14,023
I offered you a drink and you hit me?
请你喝酒，你怎么打人呢？

31
00:02:14,023 --> 00:02:15,824
I'll beat you into senses!
不明白我打到你明白！

32
00:02:15,824 --> 00:02:18,952
Stop!
-I don't need to reason with a savage
-不要打了…
-我还听生蕃讲理？

33
00:02:21,330 --> 00:02:23,161
What is it? Let's go look!
怎么了？…过去看看！

34
00:02:23,999 --> 00:02:26,235
Hurry up!
快点…

35
00:02:26,235 --> 00:02:28,703
I know what you said just now
with a boar's head in your hand
你提猪头喊什么蕃话我听不懂吗？

36
00:02:30,205 --> 00:02:33,442
Out of my way!
Say it again in Japanese if you dare
让开…有本事你用日语讲一遍啊…

37
00:02:33,442 --> 00:02:35,808
Say it again!
你再讲一遍啊！

38
00:02:36,512 --> 00:02:42,144
Get out of my way! -I dare you!
-让开…
-你敢不敢讲啊？

39
00:02:43,185 --> 00:02:44,453
Come on, guys!
大家过去！

40
00:02:44,453 --> 00:02:45,750
Faster!
跑快一点！

41
00:02:51,060 --> 00:02:52,084
Tado!
达多…

42
00:02:58,367 --> 00:02:59,835
Baso, kill him!
巴索…打死他…

43
00:02:59,835 --> 00:03:02,531
I'm holding down his feet! Beat him up!
我抓住他的脚了，你们用力打！

44
00:03:04,873 --> 00:03:06,773
I'm holding down his feet again!
我又抓住他的脚了…

45
00:03:07,810 --> 00:03:10,301
Stop! All of you!
住手！…通通住手！

46
00:03:11,780 --> 00:03:14,984
What is it? What the hell?
怎么会这样？搞什么东西呀？

47
00:03:14,984 --> 00:03:16,975
Let me cut off this pig head of yours!
看我砍下你这颗猪头…

48
00:03:39,375 --> 00:03:42,867
Stop! Stop! Yoshi..
不要打了…不要打了…吉…

49
00:03:43,512 --> 00:03:44,274
Yoshimura
吉村…

50
00:03:51,587 --> 00:03:52,747
Yoshimura
吉村…

51
00:04:02,731 --> 00:04:04,756
You're in big trouble
你们完蛋了…

52
00:04:06,635 --> 00:04:09,805
You have the nerve to beat me up
-Let's kill him!
竟然敢打我！
杀了他！

53
00:04:09,805 --> 00:04:11,272
Shut your mouth!
你闭嘴！

54
00:04:28,857 --> 00:04:30,586
Excuse us! Let us through!
借过…借过…

55
00:04:39,101 --> 00:04:43,265
I'll kill all you Mehebu clansmen
…我一定要杀光你们马赫坡！

56
00:04:43,972 --> 00:04:47,032
I'll kill you all
…我一定会杀光你们马赫坡！

57
00:04:48,177 --> 00:04:51,447
Let's do it, Father,
before the Japanese kill us all
父亲，先动手吧！
他们不会放过我们的！

58
00:04:51,447 --> 00:04:54,942
Why the hell did you provoke him
when you knew he'd kill us all?
你明知道他们不会放过我们
你还要去惹他？

59
00:04:57,152 --> 00:04:59,154
You're nothing but a bunch of hounds
你们这群只懂追猎…

60
00:04:59,154 --> 00:05:00,951
that can only chase and hunt
and know nothing of self-restraint
不懂控制的猎犬！

61
00:05:01,690 --> 00:05:03,783
How much longer do I have to put up with you?
我要忍耐你们到什么时侯？

62
00:05:07,863 --> 00:05:10,229
Out of my way!
让开…让开…

63
00:05:26,648 --> 00:05:28,616
Now you're here to bribe me with wine?
现在才想到拿酒来求我？

64
00:05:30,319 --> 00:05:31,616
It's too late
来不及了！

65
00:05:32,921 --> 00:05:35,389
I've filed the report on the case
of you beating up a police officer
殴打巡查的案子我已经呈报上去了

66
00:05:37,526 --> 00:05:38,959
Tell you something..
告诉你…

67
00:05:40,863 --> 00:05:45,163
This time I'll destroy your clan
我一定要毁了你们整个部落！

68
00:05:47,569 --> 00:05:48,763
Yoshimura..
吉村…

69
00:05:49,705 --> 00:05:53,475
I, Mouna Rudo, come here to
apologize to you personally
我莫那鲁道亲自来跟你道歉

70
00:05:53,475 --> 00:05:56,035
Stop being so arrogant
你别太不给脸…

71
00:05:57,679 --> 00:05:59,613
Who do you think you are?
莫那鲁道又怎样！

72
00:06:04,720 --> 00:06:08,554
You think you're still a chief?
你还像个头目吗？

73
00:06:10,526 --> 00:06:13,595
You can't even control your own sons
连自己的儿子都管不好

74
00:06:13,595 --> 00:06:16,587
I don't think you're qualified
to be a chief anymore
还有资格当头目？

75
00:06:23,172 --> 00:06:25,874
Get out!
出去！出去！

76
00:06:25,874 --> 00:06:27,743
Who the hell let you in?
谁跟你说可以进来的

77
00:06:27,743 --> 00:06:29,511
Get the hell out!
都给我滚出去！

78
00:06:29,511 --> 00:06:31,213
I don't want to see your faces again
我不要再看到你们…

79
00:06:31,213 --> 00:06:32,407
Go home and rot!
回家等死吧！

80
00:06:34,583 --> 00:06:36,581
Hey! Why did you do that to him?
-Shut up!
喂！你们干嘛打他呢？
闭嘴！

81
00:06:50,432 --> 00:06:54,303
I couldn't sleep last night because of a mosquito
被一只蚊子搞到整晚睡不着！

82
00:06:54,303 --> 00:06:56,828
Really? I'll see to it
是喔，那我再去了解一下…

83
00:07:03,478 --> 00:07:04,740
Mr. Hanaoka!
花冈先生

84
00:07:08,116 --> 00:07:08,810
Yes?
是！

85
00:07:09,484 --> 00:07:12,419
May I know which clan you grew up in?
请问你是哪一个蕃社长大的？

86
00:07:13,722 --> 00:07:14,882
Gungu Clan
荷戈社！

87
00:07:15,624 --> 00:07:16,613
And your original name?
本名呢？

88
00:07:19,928 --> 00:07:21,597
Dakis Nawi
…达奇斯那威

89
00:07:21,597 --> 00:07:23,462
Dakis Nawi
达奇斯那威…

90
00:07:24,600 --> 00:07:29,238
We have another savage policeman
named Hanoka Ichiro
我们还有个叫花冈一郎的蕃人警察

91
00:07:29,238 --> 00:07:33,436
He is the highest educated policemen here
是所有山地警察中学历最高的

92
00:07:35,577 --> 00:07:38,239
What are you doing this afternoon?
…你下午有事要忙吗？

93
00:07:40,249 --> 00:07:43,218
I'm going home for some private matter
…我等一下有事情需要回家一趟

94
00:07:43,218 --> 00:07:46,755
I was to ask you
to patrol all the savage clans with us
原本想请你陪我到各蕃社去视察

95
00:07:46,755 --> 00:07:50,953
and tell me the relationships among them all
顺便帮我介绍各蕃社的关系…

96
00:07:51,793 --> 00:07:54,193
Come with us! -No, it's alright
-你先陪我们去嘛！
-没关系…！

97
00:07:55,364 --> 00:07:56,965
It's alright
没关系的！

98
00:07:56,965 --> 00:07:59,627
Do whatever you need to do
你先去办你的事吧！

99
00:08:02,204 --> 00:08:03,472
It's alright
没关系！

100
00:08:03,472 --> 00:08:05,340
Kabasawa will go with us -Yes
-桦泽会和我们去！
-是的！

101
00:08:05,340 --> 00:08:06,830
He knows the savages well too
他也是个蕃通！

102
00:08:26,128 --> 00:08:28,562
Yoshimura has reported
Tado's case to the substation
吉村已经把达多的案子…

103
00:08:29,698 --> 00:08:31,791
上报到分室来了！

104
00:09:01,430 --> 00:09:04,166
I can't believe this Yoshimura
这个吉村也真是的…

105
00:09:04,166 --> 00:09:06,902
Chief Mouna apologized to him personally
莫那头目都亲自去道歉了

106
00:09:06,902 --> 00:09:09,427
Why did he insist on filing the case?
怎么还硬要把案子往上送！

107
00:09:10,906 --> 00:09:15,010
Yoshimura and Sugiura are not the same
as Kojima after all
吉村和衫浦，毕竟不是小岛

108
00:09:15,010 --> 00:09:17,913
They will never try to understand our people
是不会花心思去了解族人

109
00:09:17,913 --> 00:09:23,412
If Kojima were living in Mehebu
there wouldn't be so much trouble
如果小岛在马赫坡的话…
这事就算发生，也不会这么严重

110
00:09:26,088 --> 00:09:28,556
Since I was very little
从小到大…

111
00:09:30,025 --> 00:09:32,585
I've always been scared of Chief Mouna
我一看到莫那头目都会害怕

112
00:09:35,597 --> 00:09:40,435
It looks as if underneath his mantle
he's always gripping his machete
总觉得他藏在披风里的手

113
00:09:40,435 --> 00:09:43,734
ready to draw it to kill anytime
是随时握着刀准备猎杀的！

114
00:09:44,639 --> 00:09:47,709
He's no ordinary man
不能小看他…

115
00:09:47,709 --> 00:09:50,644
He's impossible to be tamed
他是不可能被驯服的！

116
00:09:51,580 --> 00:09:56,651
It must be difficult for him to torn between
the expectations of his fellow tribesmen
夹在族人期望和日本人威胁之间

117
00:09:56,651 --> 00:09:59,921
and the intimidation of the Japanese
生活是很痛苦的！

118
00:09:59,921 --> 00:10:02,549
Aren't we living like that as well?
我们两个不也是这样子吗？

119
00:10:04,059 --> 00:10:06,895
We don't want to be savages
…不想当野蛮人

120
00:10:06,895 --> 00:10:09,659
but however hard
we try to dress up like the Japanese
但不管怎么努力装扮

121
00:10:10,599 --> 00:10:14,535
we'll always be seen as uncivilized people
也改变不了这张不被文明认同的脸

122
00:10:16,772 --> 00:10:19,908
We've lived like this for 20 years
已经忍了二十年了

123
00:10:19,908 --> 00:10:22,638
Another 20 years won't be impossible
就再忍个二十年吧！

124
00:10:25,080 --> 00:10:26,915
By the time our children grow up
等我们的孩子长大…

125
00:10:26,915 --> 00:10:30,407
maybe we will have changed forever
the savage image of ours
或许就能彻底改变我们的野蛮形象

126
00:10:32,387 --> 00:10:34,321
Do we still have the chance?
忍得了吗？

127
00:10:35,223 --> 00:10:39,057
Mehebu Clan may be wiped out soon
马赫坡就要被赶尽杀绝了…

128
00:11:06,154 --> 00:11:08,486
Father, let's fight the Japanese
父亲…和日本人拚了吧！

129
00:11:11,960 --> 00:11:14,656
Ouch! It hurts! -You dumb ass!
-烫…好烫啊…
-混帐东西！

130
00:11:17,566 --> 00:11:19,363
Father, don't be mad!
父亲…不要生气…

131
00:11:19,668 --> 00:11:23,038
Father! -You never learn!
-父亲…父亲…
-讲不听！

132
00:11:23,038 --> 00:11:27,998
Enough! -You moron!
-好了…够了啦…
-混帐东西！

133
00:11:58,406 --> 00:12:00,340
Oh no! How come..
糟糕…怎么…

134
00:12:00,542 --> 00:12:03,979
It's the temporary bamboo bridge
that the savages used in the past
那是蕃人以前使用的竹便桥

135
00:12:03,979 --> 00:12:06,114
It's ugly and insecure,
又丑又不坚固

136
00:12:06,114 --> 00:12:08,783
but they keep walking over it
可是他们还老是要走那边…

137
00:12:08,783 --> 00:12:11,219
I'll tear it down sooner or later
哪天我直接把它给拆了！

138
00:12:11,219 --> 00:12:14,756
But it saves them lots of time
if they walk over it to fetch water or to the field
其实他们提水或是到田里…
都还是走那边比较方便呀！

139
00:12:14,756 --> 00:12:18,590
Look! This wire bridge is strong and firm
你看这铁线桥做得这么坚固！

140
00:12:22,731 --> 00:12:23,891
Tado?
达多…

141
00:12:31,640 --> 00:12:32,834
Tado?
达多…

142
00:12:36,278 --> 00:12:39,581
This young man is Tado Mouna
这个年轻人叫达多莫那

143
00:12:39,581 --> 00:12:41,742
the eldest son of the Mehebu chief Mouna Rudo
是马赫坡社头目莫那鲁道的长子

144
00:12:43,652 --> 00:12:48,523
But he saw us without saying anything
Is there anything wrong with him?
他见到我们怎么没有任何表示？
是不是有什么问题？

145
00:12:48,523 --> 00:12:53,321
No, it's a habit of the savages
-It's not a very good habit
没事！这是蕃人的习惯！
这不是很好的习惯！

146
00:12:54,829 --> 00:12:56,765
Oh well, they're savages after all
…因为他们是生蕃嘛！

147
00:12:56,765 --> 00:12:59,000
Can you stop talking about them like that?
你可以不要一直用这种口气吗？

148
00:12:59,000 --> 00:13:03,305
Sugiura! -Welcome, sirs
-衫浦…
-主任、课长，欢迎！

149
00:13:03,305 --> 00:13:05,140
This is Officer Sugiura
这位是衫浦巡查…

150
00:13:05,140 --> 00:13:06,975
This way please
请往这边走！

151
00:13:06,975 --> 00:13:09,244
You should've informed me
before you came here, sir
课长要来怎么不先通知呢？

152
00:13:09,244 --> 00:13:13,815
I could've asked those savages
to welcome you with dances
我可以叫这些蕃人来跳舞欢迎啊！

153
00:13:13,815 --> 00:13:15,383
No need for that
不用麻烦了…

154
00:13:15,383 --> 00:13:18,318
We're only showing our hospitality
哎呀！课长怎么这样客气呀！

155
00:13:24,192 --> 00:13:25,489
Chief Mouna!
莫那头目…

156
00:13:28,530 --> 00:13:30,293
Chief Mouna!
莫那头目…

157
00:13:35,837 --> 00:13:36,963
What?
干嘛？

158
00:13:43,311 --> 00:13:44,980
Chief Mouna,
莫那头目…

159
00:13:44,980 --> 00:13:47,682
can you tell me something about Japan?
跟我说说日本内地的事吧！

160
00:13:47,682 --> 00:13:49,775
I know you've been there before
我知道你去过日本！

161
00:13:55,957 --> 00:13:59,661
They have armies, cannons, machineguns
…日本有军队、大炮和机关枪…

162
00:13:59,661 --> 00:14:01,896
airplanes and large steamers in Japan
飞机和大轮船…

163
00:14:01,896 --> 00:14:05,700
There are more Japanese people
than the tree leaves in the forest
日本人比森林的树叶还要繁密

164
00:14:05,700 --> 00:14:08,168
than the pebbles in Jhuoshuei River
比浊水溪的石头还多！

165
00:14:09,537 --> 00:14:11,473
I know why you're asking me this
我也知道你问这些…

166
00:14:11,473 --> 00:14:13,608
You don't really want to know Japan
并不是真的想知道那里的事

167
00:14:13,608 --> 00:14:16,543
All you want is to remind me
how powerful the Japanese are
你只是要提醒我日本有多厉害而已

168
00:14:19,848 --> 00:14:23,113
Don't worry. I'll never forget
你放心吧！我不会忘记的！

169
00:14:26,354 --> 00:14:31,393
Humph! You Japanese policemen
took us on the ship for days to Japan
哼！你们这些日本警察…
带我们坐好几天的船去日本

170
00:14:31,393 --> 00:14:35,697
but all they showed us
were airplanes and cannons
却只让我们看飞机、大炮…

171
00:14:35,697 --> 00:14:37,098
However, the policemen in Japan
不过…

172
00:14:37,098 --> 00:14:39,801
were much nicer and kinder
than those of you here
那边的警察比你们山地警察好多了

173
00:14:39,801 --> 00:14:43,038
They feared we'd revolt against them
so they tried their best to befriend us
他们担心反抗，想尽办法对我们好

174
00:14:43,038 --> 00:14:45,940
But those of you here in the mountains
但是你们这些山地日本警察

175
00:14:45,940 --> 00:14:49,171
always provoke us so much
that I want to hunt your heads
却总是坏得让我想出草！

176
00:14:52,213 --> 00:14:55,917
Chief Mouna, I'm still a Seediq
莫那头目，我还是一个赛德克啊！

177
00:14:55,917 --> 00:14:58,486
Although I'm now a Japanese policeman
虽然我是日本警察

178
00:14:58,486 --> 00:15:00,750
I never forget
that the same blood runs in our veins
但我没忘记我和你们流着一样的血…

179
00:15:04,059 --> 00:15:09,631
Dakis, when you die
are you entering a Japanese shrine?
达奇斯…
你将来要进日本人的神社？

180
00:15:09,631 --> 00:15:11,963
Or the heavenly home of our ancestors?
还是我们祖灵的家？

181
00:15:20,542 --> 00:15:23,378
I heard that..
…我听说了

182
00:15:23,378 --> 00:15:28,380
in the school for savage children
you beat up our kids like the Japanese do
你在蕃童教育所里…
像日本人一样地打着我们的孩子！

183
00:15:31,720 --> 00:15:41,029
I beat them up because I don't want
the Japanese to look down on them
我打他们是希望…
…希望他们不要被日本人瞧不起！

184
00:15:41,029 --> 00:15:43,231
You graduated from Normal School
你师范学校毕业

185
00:15:43,231 --> 00:15:48,269
You're more highly-educated
than any other Japanese policemen
学历比其他的日本警察还高

186
00:15:48,269 --> 00:15:51,261
But how come you get the lowest salary?
为什么你领的薪水是最低的？

187
00:15:52,674 --> 00:15:55,310
Don't the Japanese look down on you already?
日本人瞧得起你吗？

188
00:15:55,310 --> 00:15:57,835
Beating up your own people makes them
look down on you even more
…自己打自己才会让人瞧不起！

189
00:16:05,787 --> 00:16:09,424
During our stay in Japan
以前去日本观光的时侯

190
00:16:09,424 --> 00:16:13,695
the Japanese knew all of us chiefs
from different clans hated one another
日本人明知道我们族群间有仇恨…

191
00:16:13,695 --> 00:16:17,132
but they made us sit together
at the dining table deliberately
还故意安排我们坐在一起吃饭

192
00:16:17,132 --> 00:16:20,869
We were glaring at one another
all the time while we were eating
让我们每个人边吃饭边瞪着对方

193
00:16:20,869 --> 00:16:23,770
intending to draw our machetes and kill
恨不得马上拔刀杀了对方！

194
00:16:26,608 --> 00:16:29,736
Humph! The Japanese are good at these things
哼，这些日本人就是懂这个…

195
00:16:32,981 --> 00:16:36,109
Chief, is it so bad to be ruled by the Japanese?
头目，被日本统治不好吗？

196
00:16:38,186 --> 00:16:40,455
At least we're leading a civilized life
我们现在文明的过生活

197
00:16:40,455 --> 00:16:43,792
We have schools and post offices
有教育所，有邮局

198
00:16:43,792 --> 00:16:48,828
and we don't have to survive
by hunting savagely anymore
不必再像从前一样…
得靠野蛮的猎杀才能生存

199
00:16:50,165 --> 00:16:52,200
Is it so bad to be ruled by the Japanese?
…被日本人统治不好吗？

200
00:16:52,200 --> 00:16:54,327
Is it so good to be ruled by them?
被日本人统治好吗？

201
00:16:55,703 --> 00:16:58,640
Our men are forced to bend over
to carry logs on our backs
男人被迫弯腰搬木头

202
00:16:58,640 --> 00:17:02,701
and our women have to kneel down
to serve and pour wine
女人被迫跪着帮佣陪酒

203
00:17:03,011 --> 00:17:06,981
And all the money ends up
in the pockets of the Japanese policemen
该领的钱全进了日本警察的口袋

204
00:17:06,981 --> 00:17:09,484
I'm a chief
我这个当头目的…

205
00:17:09,484 --> 00:17:12,053
but all I can do is get drunk
and pretend I see nothing and hear nothing
除了每天醉酒假装看不见、听不见

206
00:17:12,053 --> 00:17:14,088
What else can I do?
还能怎么样？

207
00:17:14,088 --> 00:17:17,959
Post offices? Stores? Schools?
邮局？商店？学校？

208
00:17:17,959 --> 00:17:21,463
Do any of those things
make our lives easier and better?
什么时侯让族人的生活过得更好？

209
00:17:21,463 --> 00:17:26,264
Instead,
we're made to see how impoverished we are
反倒让他们看见自己有多贫穷了！

210
00:17:36,211 --> 00:17:39,080
Chief, can't we bear it for another 20 years?
头目…
我们再忍个二十年好吗？

211
00:17:39,080 --> 00:17:43,718
In 20 years, there will be no Seediq
and there will be no hunting ground
再二十年就不是赛德克！
就没有猎场！

212
00:17:43,718 --> 00:17:45,515
All our children will have turned Japanese
孩子全都是日本人了！

213
00:18:06,708 --> 00:18:08,710
Chief Mouna,
…莫那头目…

214
00:18:08,710 --> 00:18:10,610
have you made up your mind to do it?
你真的要干了吗？

215
00:18:17,085 --> 00:18:18,143
Chief Mouna?
莫那头目…

216
00:18:19,354 --> 00:18:22,448
About Yoshimura... -I'm old
-殴打吉村的事…
-我已经老了…

217
00:18:22,690 --> 00:18:24,626
Don't worry
放心吧！

218
00:18:24,626 --> 00:18:27,795
The Japanese are far too powerful
日本人这么厉害

219
00:18:27,795 --> 00:18:29,922
I won't go against them
我不敢怎样的…

220
00:18:31,466 --> 00:18:34,168
Go home
你回去吧！

221
00:18:34,168 --> 00:18:38,973
This is the hunting ground
that belongs to me only
这里是我一个人的猎场…

222
00:18:38,973 --> 00:18:40,372
Get lost
你走开！

223
00:18:42,443 --> 00:18:44,240
Chief... -Get lost!
-头目…
-走开！

224
00:18:57,191 --> 00:19:00,854
Dakis, have a drink
达奇斯…喝酒吧！

225
00:19:01,563 --> 00:19:04,123
Go home and get yourself dead-drunk
回家以后喝它个大醉吧！

226
00:19:06,334 --> 00:19:08,029
We can't drink anymore
不能再喝了…

227
00:19:08,970 --> 00:19:10,838
We already... -Drink!
-我们已经…
-喝吧！

228
00:19:10,838 --> 00:19:12,806
The millet wine that we make
我们酿的酒…

229
00:19:14,309 --> 00:19:17,412
can set our people free
可以让人无拘无束

230
00:19:17,412 --> 00:19:20,404
making them sing and dance,
cry and laugh freely
让人唱歌跳舞、哭笑随性！

231
00:19:21,416 --> 00:19:25,443
You'll see once you're drunk
大醉一场之后你就会懂了！

232
00:19:26,020 --> 00:19:27,146
Go home now
回去吧！

233
00:19:58,720 --> 00:20:00,017
Mouna!
莫那…

234
00:20:45,400 --> 00:20:46,458
Father?
…父亲…

235
00:20:49,937 --> 00:20:55,043
Mouna, the tattoos on your face
are still so dark and clear
莫那！
你脸上的刺纹还是这么的深黑…

236
00:20:55,043 --> 00:20:58,646
You're indeed a Seediq Bale
你果然是一个赛德克巴莱！

237
00:20:58,646 --> 00:21:02,707
You're a true hero
一个真正的英雄哪！

238
00:21:09,223 --> 00:21:10,520
Mouna? Look at the lines on that rock
…莫那！

239
00:21:11,926 --> 00:21:16,630
It split into half
when struck by the lightening, didn't it?
你看那巨石的线条…
是被雷光削开的吧！

240
00:21:19,834 --> 00:21:25,306
In the dim light at dusk
the lightening splits a rock into half
昏黑的天色下…雷光削巨石…

241
00:21:25,306 --> 00:21:28,798
What a beautiful sight!
多美丽的画面啊！

242
00:21:30,178 --> 00:21:31,475
Father?
父亲…

243
00:21:32,280 --> 00:21:35,306
I can't keep the intruders away
我阻止不了异族人…

244
00:21:37,351 --> 00:21:43,357
(Ah, it's for real)
啊~真的啊！

245
00:21:43,357 --> 00:21:49,564
(Here l am)
我来到这里

246
00:21:49,564 --> 00:21:56,237
(l used to guard these mountains
and forests bravely)
我曾英勇守护的山林…

247
00:21:56,237 --> 00:22:00,908
(Oh yes, it's for real)
真的呀…是真的！

248
00:22:00,908 --> 00:22:03,811
Mouna, let's sing
莫那…
来唱歌吧！

249
00:22:03,811 --> 00:22:06,279
We haven't sung together for long
好久没一起唱歌了！

250
00:22:14,155 --> 00:22:19,894
(Reminisce the people from the past)
怀念过去的人们啊…

251
00:22:19,894 --> 00:22:25,566
(Here l am)
我来到这里

252
00:22:25,566 --> 00:22:31,239
(l used to guard these mountains
and forests bravely)
我曾英勇守护的山林…

253
00:22:31,239 --> 00:22:37,245
(These are our mountains)
这是我们的山唷…

254
00:22:37,245 --> 00:22:42,283
(These are our creeks)
这是我们的溪唷…

255
00:22:42,283 --> 00:22:48,089
(We're the true Seediq Bale)
我们是真正的赛德克巴莱唷…

256
00:22:48,089 --> 00:22:53,895
(We go hunting in the mountains)
我们在山里追猎…

257
00:22:53,895 --> 00:22:59,634
(We share food in our clan)
我们在部落里分享

258
00:22:59,634 --> 00:23:05,139
(We fetch water from the creeks)
我们在溪流里取水…

259
00:23:05,139 --> 00:23:10,545
(l'm willing to give my life for these)
愿我为此献出生命…

260
00:23:10,545 --> 00:23:16,217
(Oh, creek! Be quiet)
溪流啊！不要再吵了…

261
00:23:16,217 --> 00:23:22,123
(Sisin babblers are singing)
祖灵鸟在唱歌了…

262
00:23:22,123 --> 00:23:27,829
(Sing us a beautiful song please)
请唱首好听的歌吧！

263
00:23:27,829 --> 00:23:33,367
(Sing for our people)
为我们的族人唱…

264
00:23:33,367 --> 00:23:38,906
(a song of our ancestral spirit)
来自祖灵的歌…

265
00:23:38,906 --> 00:23:44,345
(l'm willing to give my life too)
愿我也献出生命！

266
00:23:44,345 --> 00:23:50,785
(When the lightening rifts the rock)
巨石雷光下

267
00:23:50,785 --> 00:23:57,024
(a rainbow appears)
彩虹出现了…

268
00:23:57,024 --> 00:24:02,430
(and a proud man emerges)
一个骄傲的人走来了…

269
00:24:02,430 --> 00:24:07,935
(Who is this man so proud?)
是谁如此骄傲啊？

270
00:24:07,935 --> 00:24:13,374
(lt's your offspring)
是你的子孙啊…

271
00:24:13,374 --> 00:24:21,247
(A Seediq Bale)
赛德克巴莱！

272
00:24:28,055 --> 00:24:29,590
What?
什么！

273
00:24:29,590 --> 00:24:36,631
Tado Mouna became a hero before I did
达多怎么比我先当上英雄了！

274
00:24:36,631 --> 00:24:40,201
Those Japanese are outrageous
这些日本人实在太可恶了！

275
00:24:40,201 --> 00:24:45,539
I can't believe they beat up someone
who offers them a drink
连请他喝酒都要被打…

276
00:24:45,539 --> 00:24:46,874
A while ago..
上一次…

277
00:24:46,874 --> 00:24:51,846
three girls from Boarung Clan
were asked to serve them drinks
波阿仑社有三个女孩被叫去陪酒

278
00:24:51,846 --> 00:24:53,939
and they were raped
还被强暴！

279
00:24:55,116 --> 00:24:57,285
Why couldn't Tado be a real hero
…达多既然想当英雄

280
00:24:57,285 --> 00:25:01,517
and kill Yoshimura right on the spot?
怎么不直接把吉村给杀了！

281
00:25:03,090 --> 00:25:05,059
Kill him?
杀了他？

282
00:25:05,059 --> 00:25:10,224
Don't you remember how my family died?
…我的家人怎么死的？
难道你们忘了吗？

283
00:25:11,332 --> 00:25:14,168
My father killed only one Japanese man
我父亲只杀了一个日本人

284
00:25:14,168 --> 00:25:18,537
and they burned my whole family alive
我们全家人就被大火给活活烧死…

285
00:25:23,110 --> 00:25:27,548
I was hiding in the woods watching
那时我躲在树林里…

286
00:25:27,548 --> 00:25:29,846
without even blinking my eyes
可是连眼睛都没眨一下…

287
00:25:33,587 --> 00:25:35,990
So..
所以…

288
00:25:35,990 --> 00:25:38,726
that's why we can't kill only one Japanese man
绝对不能只杀掉一个日本人…

289
00:25:38,726 --> 00:25:41,762
We have to kill all of them to make a difference
一定要杀光所有的日本人才行！

290
00:25:41,762 --> 00:25:43,559
Are you kidding me?
你在开玩笑吗？

291
00:25:44,465 --> 00:25:51,694
We wouldn't still be sitting here
if we could kill them all
如果杀得完的话
我们为什么还要忍到现在？

292
00:25:52,907 --> 00:25:54,342
Now the Mehebu chief Mouna Rudo
is driven to bay
因为今天马赫坡的莫那鲁道…

293
00:25:54,342 --> 00:25:56,833
by that policeman from the lumberyard
被制材所的小警察逼上了绝路！

294
00:25:57,878 --> 00:26:02,338
and the day after tomorrow on October 27th
is the big sports day
后天十月二十七日雾社举行运动会…

295
00:26:09,457 --> 00:26:18,054
By then, all the Japanese in Wushe
are going to gather in one place
到时雾社所有的日本人…
都会集合在一起…

296
00:26:36,350 --> 00:26:38,580
Is it time already?
时侯真的到了吗？

297
00:26:39,787 --> 00:26:42,289
Father, there won't be a better chance
父亲！等不到更好的机会了！

298
00:26:42,289 --> 00:26:43,791
And we have no other choice
这是最后的路了…

299
00:26:43,791 --> 00:26:45,526
We can't have the Japanese look down
on us anymore
不要再让日本人看不起我们

300
00:26:45,526 --> 00:26:47,695
We need to show them what we're made of
要让他们知道我们也不是好惹的！

301
00:26:47,695 --> 00:26:49,830
Let's fight them, Chief
头目，和他们拚了吧！

302
00:26:49,830 --> 00:26:52,298
Yeah! Let's fight them
对！跟他们拚了吧…

303
00:26:55,636 --> 00:26:57,471
Young men..
年轻人…

304
00:26:57,471 --> 00:27:03,878
I hate the Japanese no less than you do
我对日本人的仇恨
不会少于你们…

305
00:27:03,878 --> 00:27:07,248
But do you realize that
只是你们知道行动之后…

306
00:27:07,248 --> 00:27:10,615
we're going to die after all this
and all our people will be wiped out?
我们一定会死…甚至灭族吗？

307
00:27:11,452 --> 00:27:14,789
Our ancestors shed their blood
in exchange for our lives
我们的生命是祖先染血换来的

308
00:27:14,789 --> 00:27:18,192
Now we're taking our children along
to the battlefield to shed blood
我们也要带着子孙们一起染红战衣！

309
00:27:18,192 --> 00:27:20,126
We're Seediq Bale, aren't we?
我们是赛德克巴莱呀！

310
00:27:24,131 --> 00:27:25,428
Temu, does your father know you're here?
泰牧…

311
00:27:26,000 --> 00:27:28,127
你父亲知道你过来吗？

312
00:27:28,803 --> 00:27:32,339
My father told me that I should ask Chief Mouna
我父亲告诉我…
请莫那头目帮忙…

313
00:27:32,339 --> 00:27:34,341
to help us youngsters get our faces tattooed
在孩子们的脸上作印记！

314
00:27:34,341 --> 00:27:36,444
so that the ancestors' spirits
guarding the rainbow bridge
让彩虹桥上的祖灵

315
00:27:36,444 --> 00:27:39,971
will recognize us as the true Seediqs
永远认得我们这些真正的赛德克…

316
00:28:03,604 --> 00:28:04,371
Father?
父亲…

317
00:28:04,371 --> 00:28:07,738
If we want revenge,
it'd be the business of Mehebu Clan alone
如果说复仇，那是我马赫坡的事

318
00:28:08,275 --> 00:28:10,511
But if we're offering a blood sacrifice
to our ancestors
但是如果要血祭祖灵的话…

319
00:28:10,511 --> 00:28:15,312
it will be the business of all the 12 clans
in Wushe
雾社十二个部落全部都要参加…

320
00:28:16,717 --> 00:28:19,753
Keep it a secret before action
行动前先守住秘密！

321
00:28:19,753 --> 00:28:21,589
We must tell none of the elders,
children or women in all these clans
所有部落里的老人、小孩、女人

322
00:28:21,589 --> 00:28:23,991
When did you..
-都不能知道…
-这是什么时侯…

323
00:28:23,991 --> 00:28:26,627
I'm speaking here. Are you listening?
我讲话…有没有在听啊？

324
00:28:26,627 --> 00:28:28,496
Keep it a secret before action
行动前先守住秘密…

325
00:28:28,496 --> 00:28:31,065
I knew Chief Mouna had a plan already
我就知道莫那头目早有计划…

326
00:28:31,065 --> 00:28:34,068
What do you know?
It's your idea and your responsibility
你又知道什么？你起的头你负责…

327
00:28:34,068 --> 00:28:36,332
Inform the chiefs of all the 12 clans
联络十二个血盟部落的头目…

328
00:28:41,509 --> 00:28:43,500
Tomorrow morning..
明天上午…

329
00:28:45,379 --> 00:28:47,779
we're going to gather in Wushe
一起在雾社集合

330
00:28:50,317 --> 00:28:53,309
and offer a blood sacrifice
…血祭祖灵！

331
00:29:03,531 --> 00:29:04,665
Our ancestors' spirits..
祖灵们！

332
00:29:04,665 --> 00:29:06,758
We're here for the guns. Sorry to disturb you
我们来取枪，无意打扰你们！

333
00:29:20,581 --> 00:29:23,951
Boss.. -Welcome. This way please
-老板…
-欢迎…里面请…

334
00:29:23,951 --> 00:29:26,720
Fill them up with salt
And give me ten boxes of matches
盐…装满…火柴十盒…

335
00:29:26,720 --> 00:29:28,455
Wow! Lots of things to buy, huh?
买这么多？

336
00:29:28,455 --> 00:29:31,492
Boss, we'll pay for it next time
老板…这个先欠着吧？

337
00:29:31,492 --> 00:29:32,626
On credit again?
又要欠钱？

338
00:29:32,626 --> 00:29:35,151
Yes, we can -How much is it?
-可以的啦…
-老板…这多少钱？

339
00:29:35,696 --> 00:29:37,823
No, you can't!
不行不行！

340
00:29:41,001 --> 00:29:44,872
Wait! You're buying all these on credit?
等一下…你们这些全部都要欠喔？

341
00:29:44,872 --> 00:29:46,674
It's alright
没关系啦…

342
00:29:46,674 --> 00:29:49,040
It's alright? But you never pay me back!
没关系…没关系…你们有还过吗？

343
00:29:59,420 --> 00:30:00,682
Let's give them a hand
到外面帮忙！

344
00:30:08,462 --> 00:30:13,525
That old drunkard Mouna Rudo
really can't take it anymore?
莫那鲁道这老酒鬼真的忍不住了？

345
00:30:40,160 --> 00:30:46,161
I'll ask the young men to get ready
before they all get dead drunk
我去召集年轻人准备了
要不然醉光就麻烦了

346
00:30:48,736 --> 00:30:52,172
Young man, how dare you tell me these
年轻人…
你好大的胆子呀…

347
00:30:52,172 --> 00:30:55,699
in front of the police station!
在驻在所前跟我说这些…

348
00:31:05,753 --> 00:31:07,050
Good morning!
早安啊！

349
00:31:08,922 --> 00:31:10,924
Pihu Sapu?
比荷沙波…

350
00:31:10,924 --> 00:31:13,360
What the hell was he up to?
这小子在干嘛？

351
00:31:13,360 --> 00:31:16,386
That crazy boy spells nothing but trouble
整天疯疯癫癫的只会惹事…

352
00:31:17,064 --> 00:31:21,802
But we'd be bored around here
without him, won't we?
不过…如果山上少了他
应该会很无趣吧！

353
00:31:21,802 --> 00:31:24,100
You call making troubles interesting?
到处惹事叫有趣吗？

354
00:31:33,547 --> 00:31:36,377
Tado, look! Only the gun barrel is left
达多，你看…
都烂成这样了！

355
00:31:39,186 --> 00:31:42,353
No, I won't do it -Won't do it?
我不答应！
不答应？

356
00:31:43,657 --> 00:31:45,192
Chief Dahdo..
塔道头目

357
00:31:45,192 --> 00:31:47,422
the chiefs of the other clans
have all agreed to join us
其他部落头目都答应了

358
00:31:47,761 --> 00:31:49,430
and everything is ready now
我们也都准备计划好了

359
00:31:49,430 --> 00:31:52,399
Fighting the Japanese will lead us to death only
和日本军队拚只有死路一条

360
00:31:53,100 --> 00:31:55,703
We've had three chiefs in our family
that died of fighting the Japanese
我们家族三代头目都为抗日而死

361
00:31:55,703 --> 00:31:56,635
Now we've stooped to bring you kids up
今天…

362
00:31:57,271 --> 00:32:04,411
to carry on the lifeline of our people
not to get killed on the battlefield
我们辛苦忍辱把你们这些孩子养大
是为了要保住族群命脉
不是要你们去求死的！

363
00:32:04,411 --> 00:32:06,547
Chief... -We're not afraid of death
-头目 -我们不怕死！

364
00:32:06,547 --> 00:32:09,183
Even Chief Mouna agreed to do it
人家连莫那头目都答应了！

365
00:32:09,183 --> 00:32:12,553
Chief Dahdo, they'll laugh at us if you don't do it
塔道头目…
你这样人家会笑我们的

366
00:32:12,553 --> 00:32:15,222
They can laugh at me for all I care
笑我怕死也没关系

367
00:32:15,222 --> 00:32:19,093
I'll never allow our Gungu Clan
to join the battle. Period
我就是不准我荷戈社参战！

368
00:32:19,093 --> 00:32:21,362
But Chief.. -Chief!
头目…头目…
头目！

369
00:32:21,362 --> 00:32:25,498
Are you going to be a hunter
forever without guns or hunting grounds?
难道你要永远当一个…
没有枪、没有猎场的猎人吗？

370
00:32:29,770 --> 00:32:33,707
You have no tattoo on your face
Don't forget whom you're talking to
你这个没有图腾的孩子…
不要忘了你的身份！

371
00:32:41,215 --> 00:32:42,580
What do we do now?
现在怎么办呢？

372
00:32:43,851 --> 00:32:45,785
I can't stand that old man
真受不了这个老头子…

373
00:32:47,020 --> 00:32:49,356
No way
不可能！

374
00:32:49,356 --> 00:32:52,326
I won't allow our young clansmen
我不会让我们的年轻人

375
00:32:52,326 --> 00:32:54,595
to sacrifice themselves in vain
with you maniacs
陪着你们这些疯子去白白牺牲…

376
00:32:54,595 --> 00:32:59,066
But.. -I won't let out this secret of yours
可是…
我不会把你们的秘密说出去的…

377
00:32:59,066 --> 00:33:00,590
Go home
你回去吧！

378
00:33:09,977 --> 00:33:13,674
You only show off your bravery
with those animal skulls now?
你现在只靠兽骨炫耀你的勇敢吗？

379
00:33:14,982 --> 00:33:19,486
Chief Walis, you once fought the Japanese
at Hakaw Supeitei
瓦力斯头目…
当年在人止关

380
00:33:19,486 --> 00:33:21,886
Where's your bravery now?
你对抗日本人的英勇哪里去了？

381
00:33:23,657 --> 00:33:27,183
Bravery? I gave it all to you long ago
英勇？
…我全部都已经留给你了！

382
00:33:30,831 --> 00:33:34,323
Bring your women and children here
to our Paran Clan
把女人孩子带过来我们巴兰社吧！

383
00:33:36,103 --> 00:33:38,663
to keep the bloodline of your clan
替你们部落留些人口…

384
00:33:53,320 --> 00:33:58,920
A clan so big...with so many people..
这么大的一个部落
这么多的人…

385
00:34:15,442 --> 00:34:17,644
What are you doing?
你们在干嘛？

386
00:34:17,644 --> 00:34:19,236
Hello, sir!
大人好！

387
00:34:20,948 --> 00:34:23,075
Come closer
靠中间站一点…

388
00:34:24,751 --> 00:34:27,185
Stop fooling around!
Go home and clean your places up
不要嘻皮笑脸，快回去整理环境！

389
00:34:28,255 --> 00:34:29,051
Yes, sir
好

390
00:34:31,625 --> 00:34:33,160
Go on!
快走！

391
00:34:33,160 --> 00:34:34,627
Sorry
对不起…

392
00:34:35,696 --> 00:34:37,931
Stay away, kids
那边的小朋友让开…

393
00:34:37,931 --> 00:34:39,399
Okay, ready
好！那要拍啰！

394
00:34:39,399 --> 00:34:41,697
One, two, three
一、二、三！

395
00:34:49,376 --> 00:34:51,241
I'm not going in
我就送你们到这里了！

396
00:34:52,045 --> 00:34:53,847
Make me proud in tomorrow's games
明天加油喔…

397
00:34:53,847 --> 00:34:56,611
Can you stay with us, Father?
父亲也留下来嘛！

398
00:34:57,384 --> 00:35:02,556
No, I can't. I have to go back before dark
不行…
父亲再不回去，要天黑了…

399
00:35:02,556 --> 00:35:07,327
You're spending the night here
Be a good boy, you hear?
晚上睡别人家里要乖喔…
懂不懂？

400
00:35:07,327 --> 00:35:08,487
See you then
那我走了！

401
00:35:10,898 --> 00:35:12,924
Bye -Take care
再见！
小心慢走…

402
00:35:17,738 --> 00:35:18,932
Let's go!
我们走吧！

403
00:35:58,445 --> 00:35:59,639
Excuse me!
不好意思…

404
00:36:07,287 --> 00:36:12,960
Mouna knows everything about battles
…莫那…
这家伙确实懂得战斗…

405
00:36:12,960 --> 00:36:16,597
But I'm old. I can't go with him
不过我已经老了，不能陪他去了…

406
00:36:16,597 --> 00:36:21,058
But..
-But our Drodux Clan won't be absent in this
可是…
可是我们罗多夫是不会缺席的…

407
00:36:22,669 --> 00:36:25,365
Do I have to say it again in Japanese?
…要我说日本话吗？

408
00:36:26,106 --> 00:36:28,976
Good morning!
早安…早安…

409
00:36:28,976 --> 00:36:31,774
Pihu! What's wrong with you?
比荷！搞什么啊你？

410
00:36:33,347 --> 00:36:34,336
Pihu!
比荷…

411
00:36:34,948 --> 00:36:37,644
Good morning!
早…安…

412
00:37:06,179 --> 00:37:09,706
Why did you get all our hounds
to bark like crazy?
你干嘛惹得我整个部落狗吠…

413
00:37:11,685 --> 00:37:15,177
Chief Mouna, didn't you say
that you wouldn't do it?
莫那头目，你不是说你不会干吗？

414
00:37:17,057 --> 00:37:19,793
Do what? Who says I'm doing anything?
要干什么？…谁跟你说我要干的？

415
00:37:19,793 --> 00:37:22,396
Dakis, you're nothing
but a police dog wearing a collar
达奇斯…
你这只戴着项圈的警犬…

416
00:37:22,396 --> 00:37:24,531
Did your master send you here
as a persuader?
你的主人派你来劝降的吗？

417
00:37:24,531 --> 00:37:25,555
-Tado!
达多！

418
00:37:44,051 --> 00:37:48,954
Dakis, you haven't answered
my question from last time
达奇斯…
你上次还没有回答我

419
00:37:50,791 --> 00:37:53,760
When you die,
are you entering a Japanese shrine
你将来要进日本人的神社

420
00:37:53,760 --> 00:37:56,422
or the heavenly home of our ancestors?
还是我们赛德克祖灵的家？

421
00:37:59,299 --> 00:38:02,936
Are you Dakis? Or Hanaoka Ichiro?
你是达奇斯？还是花冈一郎？

422
00:38:02,936 --> 00:38:05,639
I'm a true Seediq tribesman. I am!
我是真正的赛德克！我是…

423
00:38:05,639 --> 00:38:07,074
But...
-If you are, take off your uniform
-可是…
-是的话就换掉这身衣服

424
00:38:07,074 --> 00:38:09,542
and offer blood sacrifice to our ancestors
with us tomorrow
明天和我们一起血祭祖灵！

425
00:38:12,412 --> 00:38:16,314
You know well
how many soldiers the Japanese have
你又不是不知道日本军队有多少…

426
00:38:16,950 --> 00:38:21,284
You're going to get killed for nothing
这么做只不过是白白牺牲而已…

427
00:38:22,923 --> 00:38:27,227
You told me the other day that there are
more Japanese people than..
你上次不是还说日本人比森林里的…

428
00:38:27,227 --> 00:38:30,664
There are more Japanese people
than the tree leaves in the forest
日本人比森林的树叶还要繁密…

429
00:38:30,664 --> 00:38:33,500
than the pebbles in Jhuoshuei River
比浊水溪里的石头还要多…

430
00:38:33,500 --> 00:38:38,460
But my determination to fight them
is more adamant than Mt. Chilai
但我反抗的决心比奇莱山还要坚定！

431
00:38:41,074 --> 00:38:45,712
If your civilization wants us to cringe
如果你的文明是叫我们卑躬屈膝

432
00:38:45,712 --> 00:38:51,218
I'll show you the pride of savages
那我就带你们看见野蛮的骄傲！

433
00:38:51,218 --> 00:38:53,812
The true Seediq tribesmen
真正的赛德克…

434
00:38:55,722 --> 00:38:57,324
Listen carefully, Dakis
达奇斯…

435
00:38:57,324 --> 00:39:03,563
You being a Seediq descendant
who never tried to understand yourself
你这从来不想了解自己的子孙听好…

436
00:39:03,563 --> 00:39:07,033
A Seediq Bale can lose his body
赛德克巴莱可以输去身体…

437
00:39:07,033 --> 00:39:10,537
but he fights to keep his soul at all cost
但是一定要赢得灵魂！

438
00:39:10,537 --> 00:39:13,840
A Seediq who loses his soul
输去灵魂的赛德克…

439
00:39:13,840 --> 00:39:16,707
will be forsaken by our ancestors' spirits
一定会遭到祖灵遗弃！

440
00:39:17,744 --> 00:39:19,302
Do you understand..
你懂了吗？

441
00:39:20,547 --> 00:39:22,742
..my child?
…孩子啊！

442
00:39:40,400 --> 00:39:45,667
There are over 130 guns
in the Wushe substation
…雾社分室里有一百三十几枝枪

443
00:39:47,641 --> 00:39:50,710
and many boxes of ammunition too
还有好几箱弹药…

444
00:39:50,710 --> 00:39:52,913
On the sports day tomorrow
明天运动会的时侯

445
00:39:52,913 --> 00:39:57,651
Jiro...Dakis Nawi will be on duty
二郎…达奇斯那威值勤

446
00:39:57,651 --> 00:39:59,983
I'll tell him everything beforehand
我会先跟他讲好…

447
00:40:23,810 --> 00:40:26,746
Father, will he betray us?
父亲，他会不会跑去密告啊？

448
00:40:26,746 --> 00:40:28,373
No, he won't
他不会的！

449
00:40:30,283 --> 00:40:33,775
Can't believe all the gunpowder
I spent years collecting will go to waste
害我白白准备了那么多年的火药…

450
00:40:34,955 --> 00:40:38,925
What is it, Pihu? -They're all cowards!
比荷，怎么样了？
都是些胆小鬼啦！

451
00:40:38,925 --> 00:40:41,795
Chief, only six clans are willing to join us
头目…
只有六个社愿意参加

452
00:40:41,795 --> 00:40:44,831
A little more than 300 men in all
-300 men?
人数也才三百多个人而已！
…三百人？

453
00:40:44,831 --> 00:40:46,132
I tried so hard to persuade them
我一直讲一直讲…

454
00:40:46,132 --> 00:40:48,001
I was so incensed that
I nearly drew my machete
讲到我猎刀都快拔出来了

455
00:40:48,001 --> 00:40:50,128
But they... -Take it easy
-可是他们…
-你放轻松…

456
00:40:50,837 --> 00:40:54,941
It's quite enough to have 300. Go home quietly
Chief..
头目…
三百个够了…
全部都安安静静的离开

457
00:40:54,941 --> 00:40:57,637
Don't get caught before action
-Chief..
-别还没行动就被抓了…
-头目…

458
00:41:03,984 --> 00:41:06,817
Get out of here. All of you
出去…全部离开…

459
00:41:08,355 --> 00:41:09,583
Get out!
出去！

460
00:41:17,297 --> 00:41:27,774
(Why do men belittle women so?)
你们男人为何要这样欺负女人…

461
00:41:27,774 --> 00:41:32,545
(Don't forget all the pride you boast of)
别忘了所有你们自夸的骄傲

462
00:41:32,545 --> 00:41:38,251
(comes from us women)
都是来自我们女人

463
00:41:38,251 --> 00:41:44,557
(lt is us who weave your glory)
是我们女人为你们所编织的呀！

464
00:41:44,557 --> 00:41:50,223
(lt is us women behind men's tattoos of bravery)
是女人成就了男人英勇的图腾呀！

465
00:42:22,462 --> 00:42:23,724
The sun..
太阳…

466
00:42:27,367 --> 00:42:30,303
(l'm on my way)
我正在路上

467
00:42:30,303 --> 00:42:34,603
(to the heavenly home of our ancestors)
我要走向祖灵之家了

468
00:42:39,946 --> 00:42:45,819
(We'll be back as brothers)
让我带你回来成为兄弟吧！

469
00:42:45,819 --> 00:42:48,955
(Hark!)
听着吧！

470
00:42:48,955 --> 00:42:52,258
(Behold!)
看着吧！

471
00:42:52,258 --> 00:42:58,031
(My soul fights in the falling leaves)
我的灵魂如松叶纷飞

472
00:42:58,031 --> 00:43:03,731
(l am Mouna Rudo)
我是莫那鲁道

473
00:43:08,775 --> 00:43:14,647
(l bring home the innocent souls)
而如今提领着无邪的魂魄回来了…

474
00:43:14,647 --> 00:43:17,550
(Young warriors)
年轻的勇士啊…

475
00:43:17,550 --> 00:43:20,553
(No one can defeat us)
没人能抵抗我们！

476
00:43:20,553 --> 00:43:23,456
(Oh, our warriors)
我们的勇士啊…

477
00:43:23,456 --> 00:43:28,951
(much like the budding pine leaves)
像松枝嫩芽般的勇士啊…

478
00:44:34,594 --> 00:44:39,857
You don't think I know
what you men are up to, do you?
你以为我看不出来…
你们男人在计划什么？

479
00:44:46,239 --> 00:44:49,008
I'm the chief's daughter
我是头目的女儿…

480
00:44:49,008 --> 00:44:53,874
Wherever you're going
the children and I will follow
不管你将来去哪里
我和孩子一定都要在你身边

481
00:44:56,683 --> 00:44:59,846
Your job is to guard this firepan
and keep the fire burning
你尽管守好火盆，别让火熄了

482
00:45:02,989 --> 00:45:06,925
When it's time to leave
I'll take you along with me
该离开的时侯，我不会丢下你们…

483
00:45:40,927 --> 00:45:42,622
Yamada!
山田…

484
00:45:50,837 --> 00:45:53,101
Sugiura, get out of there!
衫浦…你给我出来…

485
00:45:55,008 --> 00:45:57,944
Come on, coward
-Who is it? What's going on?
-胆小鬼出来…
-是谁？怎么了？

486
00:45:57,944 --> 00:45:59,639
What's going on?
怎么回事？

487
00:46:01,381 --> 00:46:04,083
Stop! Who is it?
你住手…谁啊？

488
00:46:04,083 --> 00:46:06,608
Baso, what the hell?
巴索…你在搞什么？

489
00:46:07,554 --> 00:46:10,590
What the hell are you doing?
Are you out of your mind?
你到底在干什么？你想死啊！

490
00:46:10,590 --> 00:46:12,148
Shut up!
闭嘴！

491
00:46:18,965 --> 00:46:24,737
(Do you know who l am?)
知道我是谁吗？

492
00:46:24,737 --> 00:46:30,210
(l'm Tado Mouna, a true warrior)
我是达多莫那！真正的勇士！

493
00:46:30,210 --> 00:46:43,590
(When you bleed, the animosity)
(between you and me no longer exists)
当你流出血，你我的仇恨从此消失…

494
00:46:43,590 --> 00:46:49,796
(l'm a true warrior)
我就是真正的勇士

495
00:46:49,796 --> 00:46:56,469
(l'm a Seediq Bale, a true warrior)
我是赛德克巴莱，真正的勇士

496
00:46:56,469 --> 00:47:04,344
(Your soul is welcome to dwell with me)
欢迎你的灵魂居住在我这里

497
00:47:04,344 --> 00:47:07,914
(l'll feed you with millet wine and foods)
我会拿酒及食物供养你

498
00:47:07,914 --> 00:47:11,651
(There's no longer hatred between us)
我们之间不再有仇恨

499
00:47:11,651 --> 00:47:26,966
(When you bleed, the animosity)
(between you and me no longer exists)
当你流出血，你我的仇恨从此消失…

500
00:47:26,966 --> 00:47:34,641
(You'll be with our ancestors' spirits)
你也要和我们的祖灵一起

501
00:47:34,641 --> 00:47:49,614
(to watch over my people)
守护我们族人…

502
00:47:51,357 --> 00:47:54,527
Lubi, keep the fire burning
露比，别让火熄了…

503
00:47:54,527 --> 00:47:56,927
I'll be home before dark
我天黑就回来…

504
00:48:46,913 --> 00:48:51,551
Women! Children! Why aren't you singing?
女人呀！孩子呀！
为什么不唱歌呢？

505
00:48:51,551 --> 00:48:52,381
Sing!
唱歌啊…

506
00:48:53,720 --> 00:48:54,812
Sing!
唱歌啊！

507
00:48:58,491 --> 00:48:59,287
Mouna!
莫那…

508
00:49:00,126 --> 00:49:01,728
My old friend!
我的老朋友！

509
00:49:01,728 --> 00:49:04,856
Mouna! Chief Mouna!
莫那…莫那头目…

510
00:49:05,565 --> 00:49:08,466
Shut up!
闭嘴…闭嘴！

511
00:49:10,503 --> 00:49:11,936
Not you
我不是在说你…

512
00:49:13,973 --> 00:49:17,335
Tanah, split your men into two teams
达那哈…
把你们的人分成两队

513
00:49:18,411 --> 00:49:24,150
You lead one team along Bkasan River
to annihilate all the police stations
你带一队沿着布砍散溪
消灭所有沿线的驻在所

514
00:49:24,150 --> 00:49:27,854
and cut off the communication
of the Japanese to the east
切断日本人东边的联络线

515
00:49:27,854 --> 00:49:32,281
The other team follows me to Gungu Clan
to meet up with other clans
另一队跟我一起到荷戈社…
和其他部落会合！

516
00:49:33,993 --> 00:49:37,588
What do we do
after those police stations are annihilated?
那我们消灭了那些驻在所之后呢？

517
00:49:39,799 --> 00:49:44,133
After that? Come to Mehebu Clan for a drink
之后？…到我马赫坡来喝酒！

518
00:49:48,841 --> 00:49:50,138
Chief Mouna!
莫那头目！

519
00:49:51,177 --> 00:49:53,679
Where are they? Aren't they here yet?
人呢？都到吗？

520
00:49:53,679 --> 00:49:54,881
They're all here
都到了…

521
00:49:54,881 --> 00:49:59,051
but Chief Dahdo doesn't allow
our Gungu Clan to join in the battle
但是塔道头目不准我们荷戈社参战

522
00:49:59,051 --> 00:50:01,954
Everyone's trying to convince him
大家都在劝塔道头目！

523
00:50:01,954 --> 00:50:04,390
Have all the police stations been annihilated?
驻在所打下来没有？

524
00:50:04,390 --> 00:50:05,792
We've burned down every one of them
都烧光了！

525
00:50:05,792 --> 00:50:08,094
Then why waste our time persuading him?
那还跟他啰嗦什么！

526
00:50:08,094 --> 00:50:09,495
I said no
不行就是不行…

527
00:50:09,495 --> 00:50:12,565
Our clan is big. We must join in
我们这么大的部落怎么可以不参战

528
00:50:12,565 --> 00:50:13,666
Chief Dahdo..
塔道头目…

529
00:50:13,666 --> 00:50:16,335
even a boar fights back when driven to bay
Why don't you understand?
山猪都懂得反击，为什么你不懂？

530
00:50:16,335 --> 00:50:19,639
I'd rather be punished by the Japanese
than have our whole clan wiped out
我宁可被日本人处罚，也不能灭族

531
00:50:19,639 --> 00:50:24,644
My children, don't you remember
how your fathers died?
你们这些孩子…
忘了你们父亲是怎么死去的吗？

532
00:50:24,644 --> 00:50:26,546
No one from our Gungu Clan is allowed to go
我荷戈社任何一个人都不准参加！

533
00:50:26,546 --> 00:50:29,649
Are you frightened to death by the Japanese?
Or are you spoiled by them?
你到底是被日本人吓坏了？
还是被日本人给惯坏了？

534
00:50:29,649 --> 00:50:31,173
Chief! Chief Mouna!
头目…莫那头目…

535
00:50:32,652 --> 00:50:35,288
You know well
that we're bound to lose this battle
你明明知道这一战一定会输

536
00:50:35,288 --> 00:50:37,190
Why do you insist on fighting it?
为什么还要打？

537
00:50:37,190 --> 00:50:38,657
Because of our ancestral spirit
that's soon to be forgotten
为了快被遗忘的图腾！

538
00:50:39,692 --> 00:50:40,927
Look at these young men
你看这些年轻人

539
00:50:40,927 --> 00:50:44,964
Their faces are clean without the Seediq tattoos
白白净净的脸…
没有赛德克该有的图腾

540
00:50:44,964 --> 00:50:48,568
Do you want to see their souls
forsaken by our ancestors' spirits?
你忍心看着他们死去的灵魂
被祖灵遗弃？

541
00:50:48,568 --> 00:50:50,403
Or don't you think they're qualified
还是你觉得他们不够资格

542
00:50:50,403 --> 00:50:52,735
to be Seediq Bale
with hands stained with blood?
成为一个双手染血的赛德克巴莱？

543
00:50:57,810 --> 00:50:59,078
Ancestral spirit?
图腾？

544
00:50:59,078 --> 00:51:00,340
Ancestral spirit!
图腾！

545
00:51:02,582 --> 00:51:05,718
You want to sacrifice their lives
in exchange for these tattoos
拿生命来换图腾印记…

546
00:51:05,718 --> 00:51:07,652
but what does it take to get
these young lives back?
那拿什么来换回这些年轻的生命？

547
00:51:09,222 --> 00:51:11,383
Pride!
骄傲！

548
00:51:23,603 --> 00:51:24,934
Let's go!
出发！

549
00:51:36,949 --> 00:51:39,474
Let's go!
出发！

550
00:52:05,278 --> 00:52:10,079
Mr. Inspector, look! Here comes the mist!
督学先生…
你看，起雾了！

551
00:52:15,788 --> 00:52:17,585
What a beautiful sight!
好美呀！

552
00:52:22,361 --> 00:52:25,296
Here comes your brother. Good luck!
哥哥来了…加油…

553
00:52:26,132 --> 00:52:27,827
Good luck!
加油！加油！

554
00:52:30,169 --> 00:52:33,039
What a thick mist!
好浓的雾啊！

555
00:52:33,039 --> 00:52:35,908
Yeah, it's often misty around here
是啊！这里的天气一向如此

556
00:52:35,908 --> 00:52:41,180
But with a mist so thick
how will they judge the games?
可是这么浓的雾…
待会怎么判定比赛成绩啊？

557
00:52:41,180 --> 00:52:45,151
Those games are just for kids
Having fun is all that matters
小孩子的游戏好玩就好了…

558
00:52:45,151 --> 00:52:47,954
Come on, have more hot tea. It's chilly
来…再来杯热茶，天气冷…

559
00:52:47,954 --> 00:52:49,355
Thank you
谢谢…

560
00:52:49,355 --> 00:52:52,722
We still have time for a rest
还有点时间的…可以再休息一下！

561
00:52:54,493 --> 00:52:57,395
Be careful! -I'm sorry
小心！
对不起…

562
00:52:58,864 --> 00:53:01,457
Are you alright? -Yeah, thank you
没事吧？
嗯…谢谢！

563
00:53:21,487 --> 00:53:24,854
Let's do it. There's no turning back
行动吧！已经脱不了身了！

564
00:53:28,694 --> 00:53:30,863
My children..
孩子们…

565
00:53:30,863 --> 00:53:33,599
at the other end of the rainbow
in the heavenly home of our ancestors
在通往祖灵之家的彩虹彼端

566
00:53:33,599 --> 00:53:36,500
lies a fertile hunting ground
还有一座肥美的猎场

567
00:53:37,637 --> 00:53:39,832
Our ancestors are all there
我们的祖先可都在那儿哪！

568
00:53:40,706 --> 00:53:44,276
Only brave souls are allowed to enter
那片只有英勇灵魂才能进入的猎场

569
00:53:44,276 --> 00:53:46,512
It's the one hunting ground
we cannot afford to lose
绝对不能失去…

570
00:53:46,512 --> 00:53:48,207
Fellow tribesmen!
族人啊…

571
00:53:49,582 --> 00:53:54,286
My fellow tribesmen!
Let's hunt the heads of our enemies
我的族人啊！
猎取敌人的首级吧！

572
00:53:54,286 --> 00:53:58,424
We can no longer keep the hunting ground
in the Wushe mountains
雾社高山的猎场我们是守不住了…

573
00:53:58,424 --> 00:54:01,761
Let's wash our souls clean with blood
用鲜血洗净灵魂！

574
00:54:01,761 --> 00:54:05,595
Stride over the rainbow
to our eternal hunting ground
走进彩虹！永远的猎场！

575
00:54:21,380 --> 00:54:24,406
We're offering a blood sacrifice to our ancestors
这是在血祭祖灵…

576
00:54:26,285 --> 00:54:27,946
Young men, let our ancestors' spirits
be possessed in your blades
年轻人…

577
00:54:28,721 --> 00:54:31,815
让祖灵寄居在你们的刀锋中

578
00:54:33,325 --> 00:54:36,954
Entrust your hatred to the clouds and mists
把你们的仇恨寄存在云雾间

579
00:54:42,802 --> 00:54:45,498
Let's do it
行动吧！

580
00:54:46,005 --> 00:54:48,873
Be still! How many times do I have to tell you?
排个队动来动去
要讲几次才会明白啊！

581
00:54:50,876 --> 00:54:52,309
Go to the back of the line!
排到最后去！

582
00:55:30,950 --> 00:55:33,719
No, it's not what you think
…其实不是这样的…

583
00:55:33,719 --> 00:55:35,020
Hello?
喂…

584
00:55:35,020 --> 00:55:36,388
Really?
真的吗？

585
00:55:36,388 --> 00:55:39,822
How fair-spoken you are!
-No, you're too kind
你真是会说话啊！
没有…没什么啦！

586
00:55:40,626 --> 00:55:42,027
Hatsuko!
初子…

587
00:55:42,027 --> 00:55:45,053
What the hell! Lower you voice
干什么啊？那么大声…

588
00:55:46,866 --> 00:55:47,967
Hanaoka?
花冈…

589
00:55:47,967 --> 00:55:50,401
It's your shift at the ammunition storage
弹药库叫你去换班了！

590
00:55:54,707 --> 00:55:55,639
Hello
你好！

591
00:55:58,677 --> 00:56:00,146
Your candies
这是你的糖…

592
00:56:00,146 --> 00:56:01,814
Thank you
谢谢啰…

593
00:56:01,814 --> 00:56:03,645
Thank you
谢谢你喔！

594
00:56:04,884 --> 00:56:06,552
Hanako!
花子！

595
00:56:06,552 --> 00:56:08,220
Hello -Hello
-你好！
-你好！

596
00:56:08,220 --> 00:56:09,847
Wow! You bought candies
你买糖果啦？

597
00:56:10,790 --> 00:56:12,849
So cute
好可爱喔…

598
00:56:16,762 --> 00:56:19,799
Come on, let's go. Bye!
我们也走吧…再见！

599
00:56:19,799 --> 00:56:21,289
Bye!
慢走！

600
00:56:47,092 --> 00:56:48,582
It's Ichiro!
一郎耶！

601
00:56:52,631 --> 00:56:56,135
Welcome! You've come a long way
欢迎你来！辛苦你了！

602
00:56:56,135 --> 00:56:58,729
This way please -Thank you
-请走这边…
-谢谢！

603
00:57:06,779 --> 00:57:09,381
It's spectacular
好盛大的运动会啊…

604
00:57:09,381 --> 00:57:10,871
All rise!
起立！

605
00:57:16,388 --> 00:57:18,083
Be quiet!
安静！

606
00:57:20,159 --> 00:57:22,457
Sing the national anthem
唱国歌！

607
00:57:30,636 --> 00:57:32,627
Sing the national anthem
唱国歌！

608
00:57:46,418 --> 00:57:56,729
(Our Mikado rules the world)
吾皇御世…

609
00:57:56,729 --> 00:58:05,404
(For generations to come)
千秋万代永存…

610
00:58:05,404 --> 00:58:10,205
(Like sands accumulating to rocks)
犹如小石成岩…

611
00:58:20,552 --> 00:58:21,541
Get him!
抓住他！

612
00:58:22,521 --> 00:58:23,385
Stop!
不要跑！

613
00:58:24,390 --> 00:58:25,724
Stop!
不要逃！

614
00:58:25,724 --> 00:58:27,851
What's going on?
发生什么事啊？

615
00:58:28,127 --> 00:58:30,329
Keep playing! Come on!
继续弹…继续啊…

616
00:58:30,329 --> 00:58:31,819
Sing! Keep singing!
唱歌…继续唱歌…

617
00:58:32,431 --> 00:58:33,728
Keep singing!
继续唱歌啊…

618
00:58:34,900 --> 00:58:36,390
Play it!
快点弹…

619
00:58:37,069 --> 00:58:38,661
Keep singing!
继续唱歌…

620
00:58:38,771 --> 00:58:42,502
(Like sands accumulating to rocks)
犹如小石成岩…

621
00:58:43,809 --> 00:58:45,367
Get him!
抓住他！

622
00:59:22,848 --> 00:59:24,416
Here comes the blood sacrifice!
血祭祖灵了！

623
00:59:24,416 --> 00:59:26,407
Come on!
走…

624
00:59:44,903 --> 00:59:46,871
Run! Come on!
快逃！快逃呀！

625
01:00:25,411 --> 01:00:27,675
Hatsuko! Hatsuko!
初子…初子…

626
01:00:41,927 --> 01:00:43,485
Hatsuko!
初子…

627
01:01:06,051 --> 01:01:09,043
Come on! Unlock the storage
The savages are hunting heads
快！打开枪库，蕃人出草…

628
01:01:10,456 --> 01:01:12,048
Hanaoka!
花冈…

629
01:01:14,960 --> 01:01:17,827
Unlock that one too!
快把那间也打开！

630
01:01:18,363 --> 01:01:23,001
Chief Mouna, my wife Obing
is still dressed in kimono
莫那头目…
我妻子欧嫔还穿着和服…

631
01:01:23,001 --> 01:01:25,299
Shut up! Open the door!
闭嘴！去开门…

632
01:01:28,941 --> 01:01:30,738
Run for your lives!
你们快逃！

633
01:01:32,277 --> 01:01:34,177
I'm a descendant from a samurai as well
我也是武士的后裔呀…

634
01:01:36,448 --> 01:01:37,583
Mr. Satsuka! -Mr. Commissioner!
-佐冢先生…
-郡守…

635
01:01:37,583 --> 01:01:39,084
Mr. Satsuka! -Come on!
-佐冢先生…
-快一点啊…

636
01:01:39,084 --> 01:01:40,381
Mr. Satsuka!
佐冢先生…

637
01:01:48,260 --> 01:01:49,528
Hide in there! Be quiet!
快进去…安静点…

638
01:01:49,528 --> 01:01:51,996
Hush! Be quiet!
小声一点不要出声…

639
01:01:54,500 --> 01:01:58,264
Aren't you a savage too?
Why are you hiding with us?
你不也是蕃人吗？
干嘛也跟我们一起躲？

640
01:02:36,074 --> 01:02:39,009
We're offering blood sacrifice
What are you daydreaming for?
血祭祖灵了…发什么呆呀！

641
01:02:46,084 --> 01:02:47,352
Follow me!
跟我走！

642
01:02:47,352 --> 01:02:50,014
Pawan! Pawan!
巴万…

643
01:03:00,332 --> 01:03:03,165
Come on! Hurry up!
快…快一点…

644
01:03:19,818 --> 01:03:22,048
Missed! Come on!
没中…快！

645
01:03:25,958 --> 01:03:28,460
Damned Japanese! I'll make you weep!
可恶的日本人，看我今天让你哭…

646
01:03:28,460 --> 01:03:30,121
Come with me!
跟我走！

647
01:03:43,542 --> 01:03:52,584
(Oh, my children, l know)
(我的孩子啊，我知道)

648
01:03:52,584 --> 01:04:02,755
(ln those passionate days)
(在那激情奔放的日子里

649
01:04:04,229 --> 01:04:12,371
(You've learned a song)
(你们学会一首歌)

650
01:04:12,371 --> 01:04:25,580
(To sing for the soon-be-forgotten ancestral spirit)
(为即将被遗忘的祖灵唱歌)

651
01:04:26,818 --> 01:04:30,522
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
(每一个音符紧密地拥抱祖灵)

652
01:04:30,522 --> 01:04:33,859
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
My children! What are you doing?
(每一个音符紧密地拥抱祖灵)
孩子啊！你们在做什么？

653
01:04:33,859 --> 01:04:39,398
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
What on earth are you doing, my children?
(每一个音符紧密地拥抱祖灵)
我的孩子啊，你们在做什么？

654
01:04:39,398 --> 01:04:47,272
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
(每一个音符紧密地拥抱祖灵)

655
01:04:47,272 --> 01:05:06,887
(Your dynamic bodies
dance to our ancestors' spirits)
(你们跃动的身躯舞向祖灵灵)

656
01:05:09,561 --> 01:05:11,463
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
Dahdo! Dahdo!
(你们灵魂的尊严像密云中的闪电)
塔道…塔道…

657
01:05:11,463 --> 01:05:13,732
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
Go to the school right now
to save your daughter Obing
(你们灵魂的尊严像密云中的闪电)
快去公学校救你女儿欧嫔…

658
01:05:13,732 --> 01:05:15,701
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
She's dressed in kimono
(你们灵魂的尊严像密云中的闪电)
她穿着和服哪！

659
01:05:15,701 --> 01:05:18,470
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
(你们灵魂的尊严像密云中的闪电)

660
01:05:18,470 --> 01:05:21,440
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
No! No!
(你们灵魂的尊严像密云中的闪电)
不要…不要…

661
01:05:21,440 --> 01:05:23,275
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
(你们灵魂的尊严像密云中的闪电)

662
01:05:23,275 --> 01:05:28,680
(No enemy dares to gaze at it)
(令敌人不敢直视)

663
01:05:28,680 --> 01:05:30,582
Didn't we agree not to kill the Hans?
不是说别杀汉人吗？

664
01:05:30,582 --> 01:05:34,920
(But my children!)
What are you chasing him for?
-We did?
(But my children!)
Didn't we agree not to kill the Hans?
(但是，我的孩子啊？)
不是说别杀汉人吗？
(但是，我的孩子啊？)
你还追什么？…
(但是，我的孩子啊？)
有说过吗？

665
01:05:34,920 --> 01:05:36,521
(But my children!)
You'd better stay sober today!
(但是，我的孩子啊？)
你今天给我清醒一点！

666
01:05:36,521 --> 01:05:40,025
(Your hatred darkens the heaven and the earth)
(But my children!)
(但是，我的孩子啊？)
(你们的恨意让天地暗下来)

667
01:05:40,025 --> 01:05:42,260
(Your hatred darkens the heaven and the earth)
Don't throw anything hard stuff at me again!
(你们的恨意让天地暗下来)
下次别拿那硬硬的丢我…

668
01:05:42,260 --> 01:05:45,364
(Your hatred darkens the heaven and the earth)
Okay, fine
(你们的恨意让天地暗下来)
好好…

669
01:05:45,364 --> 01:05:48,500
(The distant stars are nowhere to be seen)
(Your hatred darkens the heaven and the earth)
(你们的恨意让天地暗下来)
(看不见远方的星辰)

670
01:05:48,500 --> 01:05:49,101
(The distant stars are nowhere to be seen)
Hush! Hush!
(看不见远方的星辰)
安静！安静！

671
01:05:49,101 --> 01:05:50,135
(Oh, see how the stars are dimming)
Hush! Hush!
(啊，那些星辰已渐渐垂灭)
安静！安静！

672
01:05:50,135 --> 01:06:00,340
(Oh, see how the stars are dimming)
(啊，那些星辰已渐渐垂灭)

673
01:06:02,047 --> 01:06:10,956
(My children!)
(我的孩子啊！)

674
01:06:10,956 --> 01:06:17,295
(The chilling light reflected
off the tips of your machetes)
(你们刀尖的寒光)

675
01:06:17,295 --> 01:06:21,900
(Makes the moon seem pale as wax )
(让月亮苍白如蜡

676
01:06:21,900 --> 01:06:25,270
(The bloodstain on the tips of your machetes)
(你们刀尖的血渍)

677
01:06:25,270 --> 01:06:27,973
(The bloodstain on the tips of your machetes)
Come on, Mr. Commissioner!
-I can't run anymore
(你们刀尖的血渍)
郡守，快点…
(你们刀尖的血渍)
我跑不动了…

678
01:06:27,973 --> 01:06:31,109
(Keeps the night fire burning bright)
What are you talking about? Come on!
(让夜晚不停燃烧)
你在说什么…
(让夜晚不停燃烧)
快点…

679
01:06:31,109 --> 01:06:32,844
(Keeps the night fire burning bright)
(让夜晚不停燃烧)

680
01:06:32,844 --> 01:06:33,879
(Keeps the night fire burning bright)
Get up!
(让夜晚不停燃烧)
起来…

681
01:06:33,879 --> 01:06:34,504
(Keeps the night fire burning bright)
(让夜晚不停燃烧)

682
01:06:34,880 --> 01:06:36,148
Someone's here!
有人追过来了…

683
01:06:36,148 --> 01:06:36,381
(Listen, children!)
Someone's here!
(听啊，孩子们)
有人追过来了…

684
01:06:36,381 --> 01:06:38,450
(Listen, children!)
I'm exhausted -This way!
(Listen, children!)
Someone's here!
(听啊，孩子们)
(听啊，孩子们)
-我不行了…
-往这边…这边下去！

685
01:06:38,450 --> 01:06:39,651
(Listen, children!)
I really can't run anymore!
(听啊，孩子们)
我真的不行了…

686
01:06:39,651 --> 01:06:40,685
(Listen, children!)
(听啊，孩子们)

687
01:06:40,685 --> 01:06:42,254
(Listen, children!)
Mr. Kikukawa!
(听啊，孩子们)
菊川先生…

688
01:06:42,254 --> 01:06:44,656
(Listen, children!)
(听啊，孩子们)

689
01:06:44,656 --> 01:06:46,024
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
(从森林里飘落下来的声音)

690
01:06:46,024 --> 01:06:48,026
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
I don't want to die here!
(从森林里飘落下来的声音)
我不要死在这里呀…

691
01:06:48,026 --> 01:06:49,561
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
Tado, don't shoot!
(从森林里飘落下来的声音)
达多，别开枪！

692
01:06:49,561 --> 01:06:55,233
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
(从森林里飘落下来的声音)

693
01:06:55,233 --> 01:06:55,801
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
Temu,
you'd do anything to become a hero, huh?
(从森林里飘落下来的声音)
泰牧，你想当英雄想疯了…

694
01:06:55,801 --> 01:06:56,802
Temu,
you'd do anything to become a hero, huh?
泰牧，你想当英雄想疯了…

695
01:06:56,802 --> 01:07:00,138
(ls it the sigh of our ancestors' spirits?)
Temu,
you'd do anything to become a hero, huh?
(是祖灵的叹息)
泰牧，你想当英雄想疯了…

696
01:07:00,138 --> 01:07:03,008
(ls it the sigh of our ancestors' spirits?)
(是祖灵的叹息)

697
01:07:03,008 --> 01:07:04,876
(ls it the sigh of our ancestors' spirits?)
Look, I killed a high-ranking official
(是祖灵的叹息)
你看，我杀的可是大官哪！

698
01:07:04,876 --> 01:07:06,211
(Or is it the sigh of the wind?)
Look, I killed a high-ranking official
(还是风的叹息)
你看，我杀的可是大官哪！

699
01:07:06,211 --> 01:07:09,815
(Or is it the sigh of the wind?)
(还是风的叹息)

700
01:07:09,815 --> 01:07:11,516
(Or is it the sigh of the wind?)
Where's the other one?
(还是风的叹息)
还有一个呢？

701
01:07:11,516 --> 01:07:17,022
(Or is it the sigh of the wind?)
(还是风的叹息)

702
01:07:17,022 --> 01:07:25,397
(Listen, children!)
(听啊，孩子们)

703
01:07:25,397 --> 01:07:29,334
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
(从浊水溪流下来的呜咽)

704
01:07:29,334 --> 01:07:31,703
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
Pihu..
(从浊水溪流下来的呜咽)
比荷…

705
01:07:31,703 --> 01:07:35,674
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
Don't kill me. We're friends
-My friend..
(从浊水溪流下来的呜咽)
不要杀我…我们是朋友…
(从浊水溪流下来的呜咽)
我的朋友…

706
01:07:35,674 --> 01:07:37,642
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
I'm not killing people
I'm offering blood sacrifice to our ancestors
(从浊水溪流下来的呜咽)
我不是在杀人，我是在血祭祖灵…

707
01:07:37,642 --> 01:07:39,644
I'm not killing people
I'm offering blood sacrifice to our ancestors
我不是在杀人，我是在血祭祖灵…

708
01:07:39,644 --> 01:07:40,111
(ls it our ancestors' spirits weeping?)
I'm not killing people
I'm offering blood sacrifice to our ancestors
(是祖灵的哭泣)
我不是在杀人，我是在血祭祖灵…

709
01:07:40,111 --> 01:07:48,620
(ls it our ancestors' spirits weeping?)
(是祖灵的哭泣)

710
01:07:48,620 --> 01:07:54,493
(Or is it the clouds crying?)
(还是云的哭泣)

711
01:07:54,493 --> 01:07:56,094
(Or is it the clouds crying?)
Is that your teacher?
(还是云的哭泣)
你们老师吗？

712
01:07:56,094 --> 01:07:59,655
(Or is it the clouds crying?)
(还是云的哭泣)

713
01:08:01,833 --> 01:08:07,873
(Oh, my children!)
(我的孩子啊！)

714
01:08:07,873 --> 01:08:10,275
(Oh, my children!)
Teacher...My dear teacher..
(我的孩子啊！)
老师…亲爱的老师！

715
01:08:10,275 --> 01:08:12,677
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
You think we're a bunch of cowards?
(你们看，世界在不停地颤抖)
你以为我们很好欺负吗？

716
01:08:12,677 --> 01:08:15,981
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
I'm sorry. I was trying to educate you
(你们看，世界在不停地颤抖)
对不起！我是在教育你们…

717
01:08:15,981 --> 01:08:19,284
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
I'd punish a Japanese kid
when he makes mistakes
(你们看，世界在不停地颤抖)
日本小孩犯错我也有打呀！

718
01:08:19,284 --> 01:08:21,786
(Look! The reddened earth is silent)
But you've been so mean to me!
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
But you've been so mean to me!
(你们看，世界在不停地颤抖)
可是你打我最凶！
(你们看，染红的土地沉默不语)
可是你打我最凶！

719
01:08:21,786 --> 01:08:25,357
(Look! The reddened earth is silent)
(你们看，染红的土地沉默不语)

720
01:08:25,357 --> 01:08:36,165
(Look! The bark of Pusu Qhuni is peeling off)
(你们看，波索康夫尼的树皮一片片剥落)

721
01:08:38,403 --> 01:08:43,642
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
(你们摸摸看，你们染血的双手)

722
01:08:43,642 --> 01:08:45,710
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
You poor Japanese..
(你们摸摸看，你们染血的双手)
可怜的日本人…

723
01:08:45,710 --> 01:08:50,949
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
Come to the heavenly home of our ancestors
and be our friends forever
(你们摸摸看，你们染血的双手)
一起到我们祖灵的天家
(你们摸摸看，你们染血的双手)
当永远的朋友吧！

724
01:08:50,949 --> 01:08:58,082
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
(你们摸摸看，你们染血的双手)

725
01:08:59,724 --> 01:09:19,771
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
(还能捧住猎场的沙土吗？)

726
01:09:21,279 --> 01:09:41,633
(Touch your angry forehead)
(你们摸摸看，你们悲愤的前额)

727
01:09:41,633 --> 01:09:57,743
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
(还能展开一座美丽的彩虹桥吗？)

728
01:09:59,117 --> 01:10:06,891
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴

729
01:10:06,891 --> 01:10:10,095
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
Come here! You go there!
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴
过来这里…你们去那边！

730
01:10:10,095 --> 01:10:13,398
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
Come here!
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴
你过来！

731
01:10:13,398 --> 01:10:15,133
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
Wait!
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴
慢着…

732
01:10:15,133 --> 01:10:17,202
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴

733
01:10:17,202 --> 01:10:18,637
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
Have you seen my daughter Obing?
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴
有没有看到我们家欧嫔？

734
01:10:18,637 --> 01:10:19,904
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
No
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
No
(你们摸摸看，你们疑惑不安的嘴
没有…
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
没有…

735
01:10:19,904 --> 01:10:21,506
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)

736
01:10:21,506 --> 01:10:24,609
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Han...I'm a Han! -Go there!
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
汉人…我是汉人…
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
去那边！

737
01:10:24,609 --> 01:10:26,911
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Have you seen my daughter Obing?
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
有没有看到我们家欧嫔？

738
01:10:26,911 --> 01:10:31,883
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)

739
01:10:31,883 --> 01:10:33,351
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Are you a Seediq from Toda?
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
你是道泽人？

740
01:10:33,351 --> 01:10:34,052
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)

741
01:10:34,052 --> 01:10:35,353
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Get lost!
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
你们走开…

742
01:10:35,353 --> 01:10:36,521
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)

743
01:10:36,521 --> 01:10:38,223
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Tell your chief Temu Walis
(还能在所有的季节说话吗？)
回去告诉铁木瓦力斯

744
01:10:38,223 --> 01:10:38,723
Tell your chief Temu Walis
回去告诉铁木瓦力斯

745
01:10:38,723 --> 01:10:40,091
that we're offering blood sacrifice
to our Seediq ancestors
这是血祭整个赛德克的祖灵

746
01:10:40,091 --> 01:10:42,761
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Wushe has fallen into our hands
we Seediqs from Tgdaya
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
that we're offering blood sacrifice
to our Seediq ancestors
(我的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
这是血祭整个赛德克的祖灵
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
雾社已经被我们攻下来了

747
01:10:42,761 --> 01:10:45,563
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Those of you from Toda and Truku
should join us as well
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
叫你们道泽和托洛库也一起加入！

748
01:10:45,563 --> 01:10:53,004
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)

749
01:10:53,004 --> 01:10:54,739
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Move over!
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
过去！过去…

750
01:10:54,739 --> 01:10:57,609
(All the pinecones have broken in the wind)
Move over!
(森林中的松子已在风中全部碎裂)
过去！过去…

751
01:10:57,609 --> 01:11:01,546
(All the pinecones have broken in the wind)
(森林中的松子已在风中全部碎裂)

752
01:11:01,546 --> 01:11:02,313
(The teary moon stops you
from walking towards death)
(泪光闪闪的月亮横在你们走向死亡的途中)

753
01:11:02,313 --> 01:11:04,015
(The teary moon stops you
from walking towards death)
Chief Mouna?
(泪光闪闪的月亮横在你们走向死亡的途中)
莫那头目

754
01:11:04,015 --> 01:11:09,087
(The teary moon stops you
from walking towards death)
(泪光闪闪的月亮横在你们走向死亡的途中)

755
01:11:09,087 --> 01:11:11,356
(The gloomy clouds cannot shelter the sadness)
Obing!
(The gloomy clouds cannot shelter the sadness)
(暗郁的云朵已遮不住)
(暗郁的云朵已遮不住)
欧嫔…欧嫔…

756
01:11:11,356 --> 01:11:11,656
(The gloomy clouds cannot shelter the sadness)
Obing!
(The gloomy clouds cannot shelter the sadness)
Obing!
(暗郁的云朵已遮不住)
欧嫔…欧嫔…

757
01:11:11,656 --> 01:11:12,257
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
Obing!
(暗郁的云朵已遮不住)
欧嫔…

758
01:11:12,257 --> 01:11:14,793
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
(向着微弱的星光缓缓驶去的悲伤)
欧嫔…
(向着微弱的星光缓缓驶去的悲伤)

759
01:11:14,793 --> 01:11:17,128
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
Obing!
(向着微弱的星光缓缓驶去的悲伤)
欧嫔…

760
01:11:17,128 --> 01:11:18,930
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
Jiro!
(向着微弱的星光缓缓驶去的悲伤)
二郎…

761
01:11:18,930 --> 01:11:21,066
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
Obing! -Jiro!
(向着微弱的星光缓缓驶去的悲伤)
-欧嫔…
-二郎…

762
01:11:21,066 --> 01:11:25,059
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
(向着微弱的星光缓缓驶去的悲伤)

763
01:11:25,203 --> 01:11:28,106
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Obing! -I'm in here!
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
欧嫔…
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
我在这里…

764
01:11:28,106 --> 01:11:30,041
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Obing! -Help me!
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
-欧嫔…
-快点救我…

765
01:11:30,041 --> 01:11:31,743
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Move away!
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
让开！

766
01:11:31,743 --> 01:11:35,480
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)

767
01:11:35,480 --> 01:11:39,417
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Father!
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
父亲…

768
01:11:39,417 --> 01:11:41,319
(Time is light as a flame)
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)
(时间轻如一朵火焰

769
01:11:41,319 --> 01:11:43,588
(Time is light as a flame)
Father!
(时间轻如一朵火焰
父亲…

770
01:11:43,588 --> 01:11:46,424
(Time is light as a flame)
Why must you hunt heads?
(时间轻如一朵火焰
为什么要出草…

771
01:11:46,424 --> 01:11:47,726
(That lights up the stars in your souls)
Why must you hunt heads?
(你们灵魂里的星星已被点燃)
为什么要出草…

772
01:11:47,726 --> 01:11:58,103
(That lights up the stars in your souls)
(你们灵魂里的星星已被点燃)

773
01:11:58,103 --> 01:12:17,888
(Your dreams are vast like a blue ocean)
(你们梦广大如一片蓝色海洋)

774
01:12:20,024 --> 01:12:40,278
(But the joyous tears
in your souls have dried out)
(而你们的灵魂里欢乐的泪水却已干涸)

775
01:12:40,278 --> 01:12:58,897
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们知道吗？)

776
01:12:58,897 --> 01:13:06,471
(How much pain do you swallow to
sing the song of our ancestral spirit?)
(为唱出祖灵的歌需要吞下许多痛苦)

777
01:13:06,471 --> 01:13:12,777
(How much shame do you swallow
to speak what you want to say?)
(为说出自己的话需要吞下许多屈辱)

778
01:13:12,777 --> 01:13:24,289
(How much regret do you swallow
to fulfill your dreams?)
(为实现梦想需要吞下许多遗憾)

779
01:13:24,289 --> 01:13:47,812
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(孩子啊，你们怎么了？)

780
01:13:47,812 --> 01:14:11,728
(Oh, my children!
What exactly is wrong with you?)
(我的的孩子啊，你们到底怎么了？)
