1
00:00:01,749 --> 00:00:01,942
-

2
00:00:01,942 --> 00:00:02,135
-=

3
00:00:02,135 --> 00:00:02,328
-= L

4
00:00:02,328 --> 00:00:02,521
-= LU

5
00:00:02,521 --> 00:00:02,714
-= LUO

6
00:00:02,714 --> 00:00:02,907
-= LUO M

7
00:00:02,907 --> 00:00:03,100
-= LUO MA

8
00:00:03,100 --> 00:00:03,293
-= LUO MAD

9
00:00:03,293 --> 00:00:03,486
-= LUO MADE

10
00:00:03,486 --> 00:00:03,679
-= LUO MADE D

11
00:00:03,679 --> 00:00:03,872
-= LUO MADE DV

12
00:00:03,872 --> 00:00:04,065
-= LUO MADE DVD

13
00:00:04,065 --> 00:00:04,258
-= LUO MADE DVD =

14
00:00:04,258 --> 00:00:04,451
-= LUO MADE DVD =-

15
00:00:04,451 --> 00:00:11,644
-= LUO MADE DVD =-

2
00:00:11,908 --> 00:00:14,710
Mouna! Take it easy!
莫那！别急…

3
00:00:14,710 --> 00:00:19,613
A good hunter waits patiently
好猎人要懂得等待时机…

4
00:00:21,384 --> 00:00:22,817
Out of the way! Let me do it!
走开！让我来！

5
00:01:02,291 --> 00:01:03,849
Move!
让开！

6
00:01:07,029 --> 00:01:09,224
Mouna! Mouna!
莫那…莫那…

7
00:01:10,866 --> 00:01:14,734
Mouna, be careful!
莫那…小心…

8
00:01:40,997 --> 00:01:43,065
Mouna!
莫那…

9
00:01:43,065 --> 00:01:45,601
Mouna,
here come the Bununs from Kntabang Clan!
莫那，干卓万人来了…

10
00:01:45,601 --> 00:01:48,637
Let's go! Come on!
快跑啊！快点！

11
00:01:48,637 --> 00:01:49,905
Come on, let's go! Leave the boar!
快跑，山猪不要了！

12
00:01:49,905 --> 00:01:52,465
There he is!
人在那边！

13
00:01:55,578 --> 00:01:57,102
Kill him!
快打死他…

14
00:02:18,334 --> 00:02:20,029
Mouna, get down!
莫那，躲下去！

15
00:02:43,959 --> 00:02:44,618
Over there!
在那边…

16
00:02:45,661 --> 00:02:47,993
Mouna is over there! -Shoot him!
-莫那跑出来了…
-开枪！

17
00:02:53,436 --> 00:02:54,733
Come on! Hurry!
走！快点！

18
00:03:01,844 --> 00:03:05,181
Listen to me! My name is Mouna Rudo!
听好了，我叫莫那鲁道！

19
00:03:05,181 --> 00:03:08,241
Be alert when you hear this name again!
以后听到这个名字要小心了！

20
00:04:04,039 --> 00:04:05,407
Who?
是谁？

21
00:04:05,407 --> 00:04:06,775
Who becomes the hero?
是谁当英雄了吗？

22
00:04:06,775 --> 00:04:08,911
Who is it?
到底是谁呀？

23
00:04:08,911 --> 00:04:10,310
Your Mouna is back!
你们家莫那回来了…

24
00:04:11,313 --> 00:04:15,682
It's your Mouna! He's back!
是你们家莫那…是你们家莫那…

25
00:04:16,519 --> 00:04:19,121
It's Mouna!
是莫那呀！

26
00:04:19,121 --> 00:04:22,113
Mouna is a true man now
莫那是真正的男人了…

27
00:04:25,361 --> 00:04:26,729
Mouna is back!
莫那回来了…

28
00:04:26,729 --> 00:04:28,531
Well done, Mouna!
好一个莫那呀！

29
00:04:28,531 --> 00:04:30,522
A true man is back!
真正的男人回来了！

30
00:04:32,067 --> 00:04:35,059
The hero is back!
英雄回家了…

31
00:04:49,351 --> 00:04:50,619
Mouna..
莫那！

32
00:04:50,619 --> 00:04:53,789
you've offered blood sacrifice
to our ancestors' spirits
你已经血祭了祖灵

33
00:04:53,789 --> 00:04:58,021
I hereby tattoo the marks of manhood
on your face
我在你脸上刺上男人的记号

34
00:04:58,627 --> 00:05:00,796
From now on..
从今以后…

35
00:05:00,796 --> 00:05:04,333
you shall abide by our ancestral spirit
遵守祖律的约束

36
00:05:04,333 --> 00:05:06,435
to guard our clan and our hunting grounds
守护部落

37
00:05:06,435 --> 00:05:09,071
to guard our clan and our hunting grounds
守护猎场

38
00:05:09,071 --> 00:05:11,807
On the rainbow bridge
在彩虹桥上…

39
00:05:11,807 --> 00:05:14,071
our ancestors' spirits await the reunion
with your valiant soul
祖灵将等侯你英勇的灵魂

40
00:05:20,548 --> 00:05:26,317
Warriors of The Rainbow I : Sun Flag

41
00:05:29,288 --> 00:05:31,547
(In 1895)

42
00:05:31,588 --> 00:05:33,927
(the island of Taiwan was ceded to Japan)

43
00:05:33,958 --> 00:05:36,947
(under the Treaty of Shimonoseki
between Japan and China)

44
00:06:21,343 --> 00:06:26,548
The island of Taiwan
is the new territory of our empire
台湾岛是帝国的新版图

45
00:06:26,548 --> 00:06:31,987
yet to receive our Mikado's grace
未浴皇恩之地

46
00:06:31,987 --> 00:06:35,858
The islanders are warlike innately
虽然岛上的人民好逞凶斗狠

47
00:06:35,858 --> 00:06:41,297
It's said that they're armed to fight us
据闻已经武装要抵抗我军接收

48
00:06:41,297 --> 00:06:46,168
but they're a scattered bunch,
nothing to be afraid of
但尽是散兵游勇，无需畏惧！

49
00:06:46,168 --> 00:06:49,305
Once disembarked at Keelung Port
基隆港登陆之后…

50
00:06:49,305 --> 00:06:54,868
we must sweep the entire island with force
由北至南全面扫荡

51
00:07:01,417 --> 00:07:06,548
We must prevent any disrespect
from the people
必须使岛民不再有狎侮之心

52
00:07:07,656 --> 00:07:14,721
so as to gain their wholehearted allegiance
to our empire of the sun
诚心臣服在我太阳帝国之下…

53
00:07:16,932 --> 00:07:23,303
Especially the heartland of Taiwan
occupied by the tribal savages
特别是由蕃族割据的心脏地带

54
00:07:26,775 --> 00:07:33,382
There are ample resources
of lumber and mines in the mountains
这里的高山，林产、矿产…

55
00:07:33,382 --> 00:07:36,783
Endless treasures..
无限的宝藏呀…

56
00:07:46,428 --> 00:07:53,232
Father, last night I dreamt of a deer
with white spots around its eyes..
父亲…昨晚我梦到一只鹿…
一只眼睛有白色斑纹的鹿唷…

57
00:08:01,977 --> 00:08:04,847
Sisin babblers are singing an auspicious song
祖灵鸟唱吉利的歌了！

58
00:08:04,847 --> 00:08:08,339
Go ahead and hunt the deer in your dream
去追猎你梦中的鹿吧！

59
00:08:09,618 --> 00:08:12,746
...for your own wedding
来一场丰盛的婚礼吧！

60
00:08:21,897 --> 00:08:24,457
Wait! Hold on!
等一下…等一下喔…

61
00:08:30,806 --> 00:08:31,830
Hold on!
等一下喔…

62
00:08:33,976 --> 00:08:34,777
Charge!
冲啊！

63
00:08:34,777 --> 00:08:35,709
Hold on!
等一下等一下…

64
00:08:38,580 --> 00:08:39,979
Charge!
攻击！

65
00:08:42,518 --> 00:08:43,780
Let's kill them!
…跟他拚啦！

66
00:10:29,725 --> 00:10:32,250
That was the deer in my dream
这头是我梦中的鹿！

67
00:11:33,855 --> 00:11:36,058
Listen to me!
大家听我说…

68
00:11:36,058 --> 00:11:39,653
Dance! Let's dance!
跳舞吧！用力跳！

69
00:11:40,662 --> 00:11:42,892
Everyone Dance!
跳到不能动吧！

70
00:11:44,032 --> 00:11:47,869
Come and dance, my in-law!
亲家，起来跳舞呀！

71
00:11:47,869 --> 00:11:52,674
Come on, everyone! Let's dance!
所有人呀…都跳起来！

72
00:11:52,674 --> 00:11:55,043
This is my son Mouna Rudo
这是我的儿子莫那鲁道！

73
00:11:55,043 --> 00:11:58,714
The bravest and strongest warrior
in Mehebu Clan
马赫坡最勇猛剽悍的勇士

74
00:11:58,714 --> 00:12:03,318
He'll be an unparalleled chief
将来一定是部落的大领袖

75
00:12:03,318 --> 00:12:07,656
You're wise to marry your daughter to him
你把女儿嫁给他是非常明智的

76
00:12:07,656 --> 00:12:11,493
Dance! Let's dance!
用力跳！用力呀！

77
00:12:11,493 --> 00:12:14,930
Let's cheer for them!
大家都替他们开心啊！

78
00:12:14,930 --> 00:12:17,990
Be joyful, everyone!
大家都要开心啊！

79
00:12:22,571 --> 00:12:24,106
Out of the way!
靠边点…

80
00:12:24,106 --> 00:12:26,097
Stand clear of the path please
大家配合一下…

81
00:12:29,011 --> 00:12:32,071
Out of the way! Please!
靠边靠边一点！拜托！

82
00:12:33,348 --> 00:12:35,213
Out of the way!
靠边一点啦！

83
00:12:38,253 --> 00:12:42,349
Out of the way! Move!
靠边点…配合一点…靠边…

84
00:12:45,994 --> 00:12:48,258
Out of the way please!
靠边点…拜托一下…

85
00:13:15,023 --> 00:13:16,320
Hey, my old friend!
老朋友！

86
00:13:19,061 --> 00:13:21,825
Oh no! It's him again
糟糕…怎么又是这个家伙…

87
00:13:22,564 --> 00:13:23,496
My old friend!
老朋友！

88
00:13:28,303 --> 00:13:30,601
You from Mehebu Clan! Over here!
马赫坡的…这里…

89
00:13:31,573 --> 00:13:32,335
Over here!
这里…

90
00:13:41,950 --> 00:13:42,974
Hey, boss!
老板！

91
00:13:45,787 --> 00:13:46,776
Come
来啊！

92
00:13:55,030 --> 00:13:58,667
Must you wear such a big head
on that small head of yours?
头小小一个，帽子戴这么大顶…

93
00:13:58,667 --> 00:14:00,328
My old friend!
老朋友！

94
00:14:09,177 --> 00:14:10,109
Mouna?
莫那…

95
00:14:14,683 --> 00:14:16,916
Seediqs from Toda
-You from Tnbarah Clan, over here!
道泽人…
屯巴拉的…这里…

96
00:14:21,323 --> 00:14:24,852
Hey, young man, don't you make trouble here
年轻人…
不要在我这里乱来喔…

97
00:14:28,530 --> 00:14:32,626
The tallest one is Mouna Rudo
of Mehebu Clan from Tgdaya
那最高的就是马赫坡的莫那鲁道…

98
00:15:10,372 --> 00:15:12,007
You've come all the way here
with so little meat for exchange?
走那么远的路

99
00:15:12,007 --> 00:15:17,670
Those of you from Toda are so shameless
就只带这么一点点猎物来交易？
道泽人还真的不怕丢脸…

100
00:15:18,780 --> 00:15:20,839
Why don't you offer your
hunting grounds to us for free?
干脆把猎场送我们吧！

101
00:15:23,585 --> 00:15:28,056
Mouna Rudo, don't be too proud
I'm not afraid of you
莫那鲁道…你别嚣张
我没有在怕你！

102
00:15:28,056 --> 00:15:29,658
Mouna Rudo, I'm Temu Walis
莫那鲁道！我是铁木瓦力斯

103
00:15:29,658 --> 00:15:31,853
I'll cut your head off when I grow up
我长大一定猎下你人头！

104
00:15:46,842 --> 00:15:49,211
Temu Walis?
铁木瓦力斯？

105
00:15:49,211 --> 00:15:51,475
You won't have the chance to grow up
…我不会让你长大的！

106
00:16:04,125 --> 00:16:06,025
Is that Temu Cire?
那个是铁木奇莱吗？

107
00:16:07,095 --> 00:16:09,130
No, it's Temu Walis
是铁木瓦力斯吧！

108
00:16:09,130 --> 00:16:11,733
I mean that grown-up man
我问的是那个男人！

109
00:16:11,733 --> 00:16:13,997
I don't know. Not someone famous, I guess
不知道！应该不太有名吧…

110
00:16:25,580 --> 00:16:28,450
Gather up, young men!
年轻人集合…

111
00:16:28,450 --> 00:16:31,519
Come on! Bring your weapons!
快！年轻人带上武器！

112
00:16:31,519 --> 00:16:34,249
Come with us! Quick!
跟我们来！快点！

113
00:16:36,057 --> 00:16:37,456
Put these away!
收起来！

114
00:16:41,062 --> 00:16:44,395
Quick! All young men come with us!
快点…年轻人都过来…

115
00:17:09,524 --> 00:17:10,548
Run!
快跑！

116
00:17:23,538 --> 00:17:24,800
Temu!
铁木…

117
00:17:39,354 --> 00:17:40,378
Mouna!
莫那…

118
00:17:45,293 --> 00:17:46,225
Mouna!
莫那…

119
00:17:47,862 --> 00:17:50,353
Mouna, he's one of our own
莫那，你打到自己人了…

120
00:18:10,018 --> 00:18:14,381
No one can ever run ahead of me, you hear?
任何人都不准跑在我的前面…
听到没有！

121
00:18:21,129 --> 00:18:22,897
Come on, Labay!
快点…拉拜…

122
00:18:22,897 --> 00:18:24,228
Are you alright?
没事吧！

123
00:18:36,311 --> 00:18:38,404
Laying railway tracks?
铺设铁道？

124
00:18:40,281 --> 00:18:43,444
It's no easy task in the mountains
在山里铺铁道可不容易啊…

125
00:18:44,786 --> 00:18:47,922
In order to harvest the natural resources
in those forests
山地森林产业要开发

126
00:18:47,922 --> 00:18:50,625
we need to have proper transportation
交通不做不行…

127
00:18:50,625 --> 00:18:51,592
Yeah
是啊…

128
00:18:52,660 --> 00:18:56,097
It's a shame to leave
those resources undeveloped
虽说山区丰富的资源不开发可惜…

129
00:18:56,097 --> 00:18:59,134
but those savages up there..
不过山上的生蕃…

130
00:18:59,134 --> 00:19:00,802
Sir?
长官…

131
00:19:00,802 --> 00:19:02,537
Here she is, sir
长官，人来了！

132
00:19:02,537 --> 00:19:07,942
She dares not lead you past Hakaw Supeitei,
Captain
大尉，他只敢带你们到人止关

133
00:19:07,942 --> 00:19:10,979
She'll spend the night in her father's house
in Meisi
然后她在她的眉溪老家过夜

134
00:19:10,979 --> 00:19:15,382
She won't accompany you to
the hunting grounds of other clans
不敢再和你们进去其他部落的猎场

135
00:19:20,822 --> 00:19:22,380
Much obliged
麻烦你了！

136
00:19:29,264 --> 00:19:30,196
Let's go!
出发了！

137
00:19:44,813 --> 00:19:46,548
Captain?
大尉…

138
00:19:46,548 --> 00:19:49,017
Those savages in the mountains
are rather ferocious
山上的生蕃很凶…

139
00:19:49,017 --> 00:19:51,485
Please be careful!
你们要小心啊！

140
00:20:01,062 --> 00:20:03,164
Hey!
喂…

141
00:20:03,164 --> 00:20:05,496
Hey, it's your turn now
喂，该你了…

142
00:21:08,763 --> 00:21:11,527
Wow! How beautiful!
哇…好漂亮啊…

143
00:21:13,902 --> 00:21:15,369
Yes, indeed
是啊…

144
00:21:17,172 --> 00:21:18,640
It was so dark last night
昨晚夜黑…

145
00:21:18,640 --> 00:21:22,303
that we didn't notice we're surrounded
by cherry blossom trees
竟然不知道睡在这美丽的樱花林

146
00:21:22,677 --> 00:21:23,609
Cherry blossoms?
樱花？

147
00:21:26,447 --> 00:21:27,573
They really are cherry blossoms
真的是樱花！

148
00:21:34,255 --> 00:21:35,415
It's so red
好红…

149
00:21:39,394 --> 00:21:41,259
Red as blood
像血一样的红樱花…

150
00:22:02,083 --> 00:22:03,846
Blockade the entire Wushe region
封锁雾社！

151
00:22:05,420 --> 00:22:08,122
Ban all trading between the Hans
and the Wushe savages
禁止汉人与雾社蕃的一切交易！

152
00:22:08,122 --> 00:22:09,248
Yes, sir
是…

153
00:22:34,983 --> 00:22:36,451
Back off!
后退！后退！

154
00:22:36,451 --> 00:22:39,614
Put down your weapons! Go up there!
把枪放下！过去那边！

155
00:22:42,090 --> 00:22:44,081
Hurry up!
动作快一点！

156
00:22:53,268 --> 00:22:55,065
Come on!
走快一点！

157
00:23:36,077 --> 00:23:37,544
It's an ambush! Watch out!
有突击…小心…

158
00:23:43,251 --> 00:23:45,053
Hide there! Quick!
先躲起来…快！

159
00:23:45,053 --> 00:23:46,145
They're up there!
在那边…

160
00:23:49,223 --> 00:23:50,224
Uwe! Uwe!
巫黑…巫黑…

161
00:23:50,224 --> 00:23:52,419
Retreat!
退…撤退！

162
00:24:04,772 --> 00:24:07,104
There's no way out!
不行啊！退不出去啊…

163
00:24:15,550 --> 00:24:17,418
These intruders are out of their minds
这些异族人真是不要命了…

164
00:24:17,418 --> 00:24:19,620
How dare they show up at my doorstep
胆敢进到我部落门口…

165
00:24:19,620 --> 00:24:21,087
Throw them down!
全部推下去！

166
00:24:36,571 --> 00:24:39,631
Get out of here! Quick!
快逃…快逃…

167
00:24:50,918 --> 00:24:52,613
Hurry up!
快一点！

168
00:24:53,654 --> 00:24:55,281
Follow me!
跟我走！

169
00:25:43,371 --> 00:25:44,736
I see. I see
知道了…知道了…

170
00:25:47,875 --> 00:25:49,240
I see
知道了…

171
00:25:50,008 --> 00:25:51,837
(A Short Account of Taiwan)

172
00:26:18,072 --> 00:26:21,439
Give me their biggest enemy
他们最大的敌人是谁？

173
00:26:28,850 --> 00:26:29,908
There they are!
他们在那边！

174
00:26:48,402 --> 00:26:49,237
Hello
你好啊！

175
00:26:49,237 --> 00:26:50,568
Hello
你好！

176
00:26:54,509 --> 00:26:55,635
Here
给你…

177
00:26:57,345 --> 00:27:01,249
The intruders don't allow
the Hans to deal with us
异族人不让汉人和我们交易

178
00:27:01,249 --> 00:27:05,753
But we can deal with you, can't we?
难道我们就不会和你们交易吗？

179
00:27:05,753 --> 00:27:07,050
Idiots!
笨蛋…

180
00:27:11,592 --> 00:27:12,684
Bring me the wine!
拿酒来！

181
00:27:18,332 --> 00:27:20,425
Bring the wine!
拿酒…拿酒呀…

182
00:27:21,335 --> 00:27:22,029
Drink!
喝！

183
00:27:26,207 --> 00:27:27,141
Look! I'm Mouna Rudo
你看！

184
00:27:27,141 --> 00:27:32,404
I killed at Hakaw Supeitei a chief
of the intruders
我莫那鲁道在人止关杀的…
可是异族头目哪！

185
00:27:33,281 --> 00:27:35,082
Mouna Rudo?
莫那鲁道…

186
00:27:35,082 --> 00:27:37,318
You're Mouna Rudo?
你就是莫那鲁道…

187
00:27:37,318 --> 00:27:39,912
Yes, I am
我！莫那鲁道！

188
00:27:41,289 --> 00:27:43,723
Mouna Rudo!
莫那.鲁道！

189
00:28:04,312 --> 00:28:07,645
Chief? Chief?
头目…头目…

190
00:28:15,690 --> 00:28:18,284
Where is Mouna Rudo?
莫那鲁道在哪里？

191
00:28:24,799 --> 00:28:27,734
I couldn't get him drunk
…这个家伙一直灌不醉！

192
00:29:30,531 --> 00:29:32,433
Wake up!
醒来…快醒来！

193
00:29:32,433 --> 00:29:35,403
Those Bununs from Kntabang Clan
are hunting heads
干卓万人出草了！

194
00:29:35,403 --> 00:29:36,734
Get up! Let's go!
起来！快逃啊！

195
00:29:41,142 --> 00:29:43,736
Let's get out of here! Hurry!
快逃…快呀！

196
00:29:53,721 --> 00:29:57,625
All the human beings on this land
活在这大地的人呀…

197
00:29:57,625 --> 00:30:01,862
The gods bestow upon us a mortal life
神灵为我们编织了有限的生命…

198
00:30:01,862 --> 00:30:06,000
But we are true men indeed
可是我们是真正的男人人唷！

199
00:30:06,000 --> 00:30:11,672
A true man dies in the battlefield
真正的男人死在战场上…

200
00:30:11,672 --> 00:30:16,711
and he strides to the heavenly home
of our ancestors
他们走向祖灵之家…

201
00:30:16,711 --> 00:30:24,785
There lies a fertile hunting ground
祖灵之家有一座肥美的场唷！

202
00:30:24,785 --> 00:30:32,087
that can only be guarded by a qualified true man
只有真正的男人
才有资格守护那个猎

203
00:30:33,794 --> 00:30:37,865
When he arrives at the heavenly home
of our ancestors
当他们走向祖灵之家的时侯

204
00:30:37,865 --> 00:30:42,369
he'll come across a beautiful rainbow bridge
会经过一座美丽的虹桥唷！

205
00:30:42,369 --> 00:30:47,508
The ancestors' spirits guarding it say.
守桥的祖灵说：

206
00:30:47,508 --> 00:30:50,711
''Let's take a look at your hands''
‘来看看你的手吧！’

207
00:30:50,711 --> 00:30:53,647
When the man opens his hands
男人摊开手…

208
00:30:53,647 --> 00:31:01,555
we see bloodstains that can never be wiped clean
手上是怎么也揉擦不去的血痕

209
00:31:01,555 --> 00:31:05,252
''Now you're a true man indeed!''
says our ancestors' spirits
‘果然是真正的男人呀！’

210
00:31:10,631 --> 00:31:13,667
Come out, guys!
男人都出来…

211
00:31:13,667 --> 00:31:16,737
Bring your weapons!
带上武器了！

212
00:31:16,737 --> 00:31:18,671
Come on!
快点…

213
00:31:19,974 --> 00:31:25,479
''Go! Go ahead! My hero!''
‘去吧！去吧！我的英雄！’

214
00:31:25,479 --> 00:31:29,750
''Your soul may now enter
the heavenly home of our ancestors
‘你的灵魂可以进入祖灵之家！’

215
00:31:29,750 --> 00:31:36,485
''to guard the hunting ground of honor''
‘去去守护那永远的荣誉猎场吧！’

216
00:31:38,325 --> 00:31:40,919
Stop it! It'll never be ignited
别吵了，点不着的…

217
00:31:41,962 --> 00:31:44,431
And a true woman must be good
at weaving red coat of arms for her man
而真正的女人…

218
00:31:44,431 --> 00:31:51,839
When she reaches the rainbow bridge
she opens her hands
是必须要善于编织红色战衣唷…
当她到达彩虹桥的时侯

219
00:31:51,839 --> 00:31:59,547
showing her calluses that can never be removed
她摊开她的手…
手上是怎么也揉擦不去的茧

220
00:31:59,547 --> 00:32:04,849
''Go! Go ahead! You're a true woman''
‘去吧！去吧！你是真正的女人！’

221
00:32:05,953 --> 00:32:10,858
say the ancestors' spirits
guarding the rainbow bridge
守桥的祖灵这么说：

222
00:32:10,858 --> 00:32:14,829
''Your soul may now enter
the heavenly home of our ancestors
‘你的的灵魂可以到达祖灵之家！’

223
00:32:14,829 --> 00:32:21,997
''No go weave a rainbow-like dress for yourself!''
‘为自己织一件如彩虹般的衣裳吧！’

224
00:32:23,037 --> 00:32:25,062
Be careful! -Over there!
-小心…
-那边…

225
00:33:04,511 --> 00:33:07,139
Stop!
不要跑…

226
00:33:30,137 --> 00:33:33,841
A man who's never decapitated an enemy
or a woman who's not good at weaving
没有出草取过敌人首级的男人

227
00:33:33,841 --> 00:33:41,782
is not qualified to have their faces tattooed
和不善于编织技艺的女人
是没有资格在脸上纹上图腾的

228
00:33:41,782 --> 00:33:45,853
Some day, when they're gone
有一天，他们的灵魂走了

229
00:33:45,853 --> 00:33:50,291
and their souls arrive at the rainbow bridge
到达彩虹桥接受验证的时侯

230
00:33:50,291 --> 00:33:52,426
the ancestors' spirits guarding it
would see their clean faces and ask.
守桥的祖灵看着他们…

231
00:33:52,426 --> 00:33:57,295
How dare you bring a machete! Bastard!
干净没有图腾的脸
还敢带刀…混蛋！

232
00:34:00,634 --> 00:34:03,037
''Are these my children?''
‘这是我的孩子吗？’

233
00:34:03,037 --> 00:34:07,007
''Are you my children?''
‘你们是我的孩子吗？…’

234
00:34:07,007 --> 00:34:11,779
''Go back! Go back now!''
‘回去！回去！回去吧！’

235
00:34:11,779 --> 00:34:15,950
''You're not true Seediqs''
‘你们不是真正的赛德克！’

236
00:34:15,950 --> 00:34:21,980
''You're not qualified to enter
the heavenly home of our ancestors
‘你们不够资格进入祖灵之家！’

237
00:34:56,824 --> 00:34:59,059
Run! Come on!
逃！快逃！

238
00:34:59,059 --> 00:35:00,856
Let's get out of here!
快点逃…

239
00:35:10,871 --> 00:35:13,407
Run, Mouna!
莫那快逃啊…

240
00:35:13,407 --> 00:35:14,931
Just go!
别看了…

241
00:35:17,778 --> 00:35:19,746
Rudo, are you alright?
鲁道，还好吗？

242
00:35:24,218 --> 00:35:25,480
Father!
父亲…

243
00:35:25,719 --> 00:35:29,556
Suddenly, the tribesmen find themselves blowsy
他们霎时蓬首垢面

244
00:35:29,556 --> 00:35:33,227
their eyes blank
魂魄茫然无神…

245
00:35:33,227 --> 00:35:39,166
They turn around in shame
and walk though the rugged valleys
他们羞愧地绕过颠簸难行的溪谷

246
00:35:39,166 --> 00:35:43,470
They become wailing ghosts
suffering unbearable pain
他们哀哭的鬼魂

247
00:35:43,470 --> 00:35:49,843
from all the cuts
by the poisonous crabs along the creek
被守在溪谷的毒蟹剪得伤痛难忍…

248
00:35:49,843 --> 00:35:51,612
Mouna..
莫那…

249
00:35:51,612 --> 00:35:59,280
you must keep the intruders away from our clan
千万不能让异族人进到部落…

250
00:36:41,462 --> 00:36:46,233
Mouna, do you understand?
莫那…我这样说你懂了吗？

251
00:36:46,233 --> 00:36:48,735
Abide by our ancestral dictations
遵守祖律的规范

252
00:36:48,735 --> 00:36:54,298
and be a Seediq Bale (a true man)
当一个真正的人

253
00:37:21,068 --> 00:37:23,003
Excuse me, sir
长官…打扰一下…

254
00:37:23,003 --> 00:37:24,771
Let's see..
跟您报告…

255
00:37:24,771 --> 00:37:29,265
The first one from the left is Mouna Rudo
the chief of Mehebu Clan
最左边的是马赫坡头目莫那鲁道…

256
00:37:32,112 --> 00:37:38,517
Those behind him are Ubus and Mouna Sine
然后…后面是乌布斯和摩那希尼

257
00:37:40,387 --> 00:37:42,890
Mouna, stop glaring
莫那，不要看了

258
00:37:42,890 --> 00:37:44,323
Look down
把头低下来…

259
00:37:47,661 --> 00:37:49,891
Mouna, stop glaring
莫那…别看了…

260
00:37:58,372 --> 00:38:00,240
Ubus..
乌布斯…

261
00:38:00,240 --> 00:38:02,800
our ancestors never lost
any of our hunting grounds in the past
我们祖先再怎样也没失去过猎场…

262
00:38:04,545 --> 00:38:08,072
I can't believe these intruders
are taking them away from us now
而我们竟然让异族人在这里称王！

263
00:38:09,716 --> 00:38:12,048
I'll never submit to them
我不甘心…

264
00:38:13,554 --> 00:38:15,715
I will never
我不甘心…

265
00:38:22,296 --> 00:38:24,787
These are all yours?
这些都是你杀的？

266
00:38:29,937 --> 00:38:31,598
I will never!
我不甘心！

267
00:38:35,442 --> 00:38:36,466
Mouna!
莫那…

268
00:38:46,753 --> 00:38:47,777
Stop it!
不要动…

269
00:38:54,695 --> 00:38:55,957
Mouna!
莫那…

270
00:38:56,430 --> 00:38:57,362
Mouna!
莫那…

271
00:39:33,767 --> 00:39:36,668
Hurry up! It's going to rain
快点，要下雨了！

272
00:39:42,342 --> 00:39:43,741
Awi!
阿威…

273
00:39:44,878 --> 00:39:46,243
Awi!
阿威…

274
00:39:48,181 --> 00:39:49,449
What's wrong?
怎么了？

275
00:39:49,449 --> 00:39:51,110
Are you alright?
…还好吗？

276
00:39:53,220 --> 00:39:55,122
What's wrong?
怎么了？

277
00:39:55,122 --> 00:39:56,350
Are you alright?
…还好吗？

278
00:39:56,358 --> 00:40:00,987
(Wushe, 1930)

279
00:40:04,498 --> 00:40:07,434
Schools, clinics, grocery stores
教育所、医疗所、杂货店…

280
00:40:07,434 --> 00:40:10,871
post offices, hotels, boardinghouses..
邮局、旅馆、宿舍…

281
00:40:10,871 --> 00:40:12,739
We've managed to civilize
整个雾社地区的蕃族

282
00:40:12,739 --> 00:40:16,376
all the Wushe savages
都已经被我们给文明化了

283
00:40:16,376 --> 00:40:19,279
It's not an easy task
真是不容易啊！

284
00:40:19,279 --> 00:40:25,373
Hard to imagine that this was once
the most uncivilized heartland here
很难想像这里曾经是…
这岛上最黑暗的心脏地带呀！

285
00:40:26,520 --> 00:40:29,690
Carrying logs..
他们扛着木头

286
00:40:29,690 --> 00:40:32,292
and walking from the lumberyard uphill to here
takes them a whole day, doesn't it?
从山上的制材场走到这里…

287
00:40:32,292 --> 00:40:34,628
Don't worry. These savages are strong
不就已经一整天吗？

288
00:40:34,628 --> 00:40:44,465
And they're more than happy
to earn some money for millet wine
没关系…这些生蕃身强体壮
给他们几个钱买酒就很高兴了

289
00:40:46,006 --> 00:40:47,633
Come on. This way please
来，请往这边走…

290
00:40:50,510 --> 00:40:51,812
Mr. Satsuka,
佐冢先生…

291
00:40:51,812 --> 00:40:55,115
how long have you been in Wushe?
你到雾社这个地方多久了？

292
00:40:55,115 --> 00:40:56,950
Over a decade
…都十几年了…

293
00:40:56,950 --> 00:41:00,387
So you know this region very well?
所以你对这里非常了解啰？

294
00:41:00,387 --> 00:41:04,224
Of course. My wife is a savage woman
当然…连我妻子都是蕃人了

295
00:41:04,224 --> 00:41:06,827
I know this region like the back of my hand
-It's this bone right here
-我能不了解吗？
-就这块骨头

296
00:41:06,827 --> 00:41:08,762
It hurts so much when you press it
这样压就好痛…

297
00:41:08,762 --> 00:41:10,097
Right here?
是这里吗？

298
00:41:10,097 --> 00:41:11,798
Ah! Easy!
啊…你小力一点…

299
00:41:11,798 --> 00:41:13,629
Here! Have a drink!
来！来…喝酒！喝酒！

300
00:41:14,801 --> 00:41:18,872
No more wine for us please. We can't afford it
老板，别再拿酒了
我们付不起钱呀！

301
00:41:18,872 --> 00:41:20,974
It's alright
没关系…没关系…

302
00:41:20,974 --> 00:41:24,711
This one's on me
下一碗再付钱啦！

303
00:41:24,711 --> 00:41:29,648
You're indeed a beautiful serpent
老板呀，你真是一只美丽的蛇唷！

304
00:41:32,652 --> 00:41:35,255
Every day I carry those damn logs
without getting paid properly
每天扛这种领不到钱的木头

305
00:41:35,255 --> 00:41:37,587
Now I'm so broke that even my hounds
look down on me
穷到连我的猎犬都瞧不起我了…

306
00:41:38,859 --> 00:41:41,061
We're losing our hunting grounds
猎场都快没了

307
00:41:41,061 --> 00:41:44,398
and you still keep the hounds
to look down on you?
还留着猎犬来瞧不起人？

308
00:41:44,398 --> 00:41:47,534
Those are the trees
that used to watch over our ancestors
Look!
你看！
那些看过我们祖先的树…

309
00:41:47,534 --> 00:41:49,502
This is how they end up
都变成这样的木头了…

310
00:41:50,871 --> 00:41:54,975
Strange thing is, why so many constructions?
奇怪…怎么有那么多的工程啊？

311
00:41:54,975 --> 00:42:00,375
What? Not only do you befriend us with wine
but you speak our language fluently
咦！你这个酒料蕃通
蕃话讲得很标准嘛！

312
00:42:02,249 --> 00:42:03,683
Hey! It's going to rain
喂！快下雨了

313
00:42:03,683 --> 00:42:07,387
Stop drinking and go home!
-Good morning, sir!
-不回去还在这喝酒！
-大人好！

314
00:42:07,387 --> 00:42:09,287
Good morning, Mr. Policeman
警察大人好…

315
00:42:11,291 --> 00:42:13,760
You've worked all day long
for such a mean wage
辛辛苦苦扛了一天的木头

316
00:42:13,760 --> 00:42:17,864
and you waste it on wine?
才赚那么点钱…还买酒！

317
00:42:17,864 --> 00:42:21,635
What else can we do with so little money?
这些钱除了买酒还能做什么？

318
00:42:21,635 --> 00:42:24,704
Yeah, right! We're savages, aren't we?
对啦！我们是蕃人

319
00:42:24,704 --> 00:42:27,641
We aren't supposed to know
anything about saving money
怎么会懂得存钱呢？

320
00:42:27,641 --> 00:42:31,478
Yeah, Mr. Policeman. You're Japanese, sir
对啦！警察大人
你是日本人呀！

321
00:42:31,478 --> 00:42:34,214
You don't know how hard our lives are
你不了解我们蕃人的痛苦啊！

322
00:42:34,214 --> 00:42:37,818
Only Mr. Wu here understands us
但是这个汉人老板了解我们

323
00:42:37,818 --> 00:42:40,387
He's a beautiful serpent
他是一只美丽的蛇！

324
00:42:40,387 --> 00:42:42,981
He's a viper!
…有毒的蛇唷！

325
00:42:45,492 --> 00:42:47,027
Excuse me -Hello
-打扰了…
-你好！

326
00:42:47,027 --> 00:42:49,257
I'd like some salt, please -No problem
-我要买盐…
-好！好！

327
00:42:52,899 --> 00:42:57,938
Oh no! It's raining! Hurry up and go home, sir
下雨了…
大人，你快走吧！

328
00:42:57,938 --> 00:43:00,873
Or your glorious uniform will be soaking wet
别让你这身荣耀的制服给淋湿了…

329
00:43:01,875 --> 00:43:03,210
Go ahead!
走吧！走吧！

330
00:43:03,210 --> 00:43:04,643
Go on!
走开啦！

331
00:43:10,750 --> 00:43:12,219
Run, sir!
用跑的呀，大人！

332
00:43:12,219 --> 00:43:15,245
Your Japanese fur is too precious to spoil
你那身日本毛皮可珍贵的哪…

333
00:43:26,266 --> 00:43:27,934
It's raining
下雨了呀！

334
00:43:27,934 --> 00:43:31,238
Go collect the laundry hanging outside
快先去把外面的衣服收进来…

335
00:43:31,238 --> 00:43:35,442
Can't you tell what needs to be done first?
什么事该先做也不知道…真难教…

336
00:43:35,442 --> 00:43:38,879
Hey, come back!
Are you taking the baby out in the rain?
回来！
你要把孩子背出去淋雨啊？

337
00:43:38,879 --> 00:43:40,369
I'm sorry
对不起…

338
00:43:48,054 --> 00:43:51,424
What an imbecile!
怎么会笨成这样啊…

339
00:43:51,424 --> 00:43:53,483
Who'd marry such an idiot like you?
还想要结婚？

340
00:43:54,461 --> 00:43:55,929
When it rains, it pours
这雨下得还真大呀！

341
00:43:55,929 --> 00:43:57,294
Good morning
早安！

342
00:43:58,098 --> 00:44:00,133
This is our policeman Hanaoka Jiro
这位是警手花冈二郎

343
00:44:00,133 --> 00:44:02,966
This is our new police minister Ekawa Hakudo
这是新任警察课长江川博道先生

344
00:44:10,176 --> 00:44:12,576
Jiro is a savage too
二郎也是一个蕃人！

345
00:44:36,836 --> 00:44:38,138
Older brother
哥哥…

346
00:44:38,138 --> 00:44:40,140
Older sister -Older sister
-姊姊…-姊姊…

347
00:44:40,140 --> 00:44:42,309
Younger brother -Younger brother
-弟弟…-弟弟…

348
00:44:42,309 --> 00:44:43,977
Younger sister -Younger sister
-妹妹…-妹妹…

349
00:44:43,977 --> 00:44:46,741
Okay, one more time
好…再来一次！

350
00:44:48,348 --> 00:44:50,483
Father -Father
-父亲…-父亲…

351
00:44:50,483 --> 00:44:52,786
Mother -Mother
-母亲…-母亲…

352
00:44:52,786 --> 00:44:55,055
Older brother -Older brother
-哥哥…-哥哥…

353
00:44:55,055 --> 00:44:56,215
Older sister..
姊姊…

354
00:45:05,799 --> 00:45:07,858
Hurry! She's in labor!
快快快…要生了…

355
00:45:09,869 --> 00:45:13,202
Two savages
can never give birth to a Japanese child
就不信两个蕃人能生出个日本孩子

356
00:45:17,243 --> 00:45:18,478
Are you alright, Hanako?
花子，你还好吗？

357
00:45:18,478 --> 00:45:19,713
This job is for women only. What are you doing?
这是女人的工作，你干嘛？…

358
00:45:19,713 --> 00:45:22,243
Dakis, get out of here! Get out!
达奇斯，你出去…
快点出去！

359
00:45:38,865 --> 00:45:41,425
Oh, what an extraordinary sight!
好特别的景象呀！

360
00:45:48,108 --> 00:45:49,632
Timber!
树倒了！

361
00:45:58,418 --> 00:46:01,254
(Hark, people)
听着吧！人们！

362
00:46:01,254 --> 00:46:04,155
(Behold, people)
看着吧！人们！

363
00:46:10,497 --> 00:46:15,301
(Oh, our warriors)
我们的勇士们！

364
00:46:15,301 --> 00:46:20,140
(The youngsters
much like the budding pine leaves)
像松树嫩芽的青年

365
00:46:20,140 --> 00:46:24,711
(They show true bravery)
是真正的勇士啊！

366
00:46:24,711 --> 00:46:27,013
(Fought in the falling leaves)
决死如纷飞的落叶

367
00:46:27,013 --> 00:46:29,277
(Fought under the withered pine tree)
决死如干枯的松枝

368
00:46:33,420 --> 00:46:37,557
(Now they're back with heads hunted)
而今带着首级归来了…

369
00:46:37,557 --> 00:46:42,119
(Our warriors fought with all their might)
像松叶决死般的勇士呀！

370
00:47:02,048 --> 00:47:05,347
(Mahebu Police Station)
(马赫坡驻在所)

371
00:47:41,087 --> 00:47:42,213
Chief!
头目…

372
00:47:43,923 --> 00:47:47,894
Pawan, why aren't you in school?
巴万…
今天怎么没有去上学！

373
00:47:47,894 --> 00:47:49,195
I'm sick
我生病了！

374
00:47:49,195 --> 00:47:52,491
Sick? But you don't look like sick
生病？
你怎么可能会生病…

375
00:47:55,702 --> 00:47:57,431
Did your teacher beat you?
老师打你吗？

376
00:48:03,143 --> 00:48:06,601
I raced a Japanese kid and I won
我跑步赢了一个日本小孩

377
00:48:07,480 --> 00:48:10,176
And the kid was crying
结果那个日本小孩哭了

378
00:48:11,184 --> 00:48:16,554
The teacher blamed me for bullying him,
so he beat me
老师说我欺负他，就打我…

379
00:48:19,058 --> 00:48:21,219
Can I have another one please?
我可以再喝一杯吗？

380
00:48:25,465 --> 00:48:28,868
I'll win the race on the sports day
运动会那天，看我拿第一名

381
00:48:28,868 --> 00:48:34,932
Those Japanese kids can cry their balls out
when they watch me getting awarded
让那些日本孩子哭着看我领奖…

382
00:48:43,850 --> 00:48:46,783
Chief, I hate the Japanese
头目…
我讨厌日本人…

383
00:49:28,261 --> 00:49:29,762
Chief Mouna?
莫那头目…

384
00:49:29,762 --> 00:49:34,722
My grandpa said you were a hero
when you were younger
我祖父说你年轻时侯是个英雄…

385
00:49:37,604 --> 00:49:40,630
Your grandpa said
I was a hero when I was younger?
你祖父说我年轻时侯是个英雄？

386
00:49:41,608 --> 00:49:44,771
I'm still a hero. Does he know that?
那我现在还是个英雄，他知道吗？

387
00:50:08,635 --> 00:50:13,566
Chief Mouna, will you take me along
next time you go hunting?
莫那头目…
这次打猎你可以带我一起去吗？

388
00:50:18,478 --> 00:50:22,608
Pawan, where is your hunting ground?
巴万，你的猎场在哪里？

389
00:50:27,253 --> 00:50:28,345
Chief Mouna!
莫那头目…

390
00:50:56,783 --> 00:51:01,015
I'm alright. Just a little bit tipsy, that's all
…没事的！我只有一点点醉而已！

391
00:51:02,889 --> 00:51:05,119
What the hell?
怎么了呀？

392
00:51:21,874 --> 00:51:22,772
Hanako!
花子…

393
00:51:32,352 --> 00:51:33,753
Look what you have done!
你们是怎么搬的木头啊？…

394
00:51:33,753 --> 00:51:38,190
How many times do I have to tell you
that you cannot drag these logs along?
叫你们不可以用拖的听不懂吗？

395
00:51:38,925 --> 00:51:43,763
You destroyed the logs
-Only the bark is scratched
好好的木头弄成这样！
不过就皮坏掉而已…

396
00:51:43,763 --> 00:51:45,230
The inside is still intact
里面都还是好的呀！

397
00:51:46,099 --> 00:51:48,496
How many times do I have to tell you?
You savages!
你们这些生蕃…
到底要讲几遍才懂啊？

398
00:51:53,906 --> 00:51:56,876
What? You wanna fight?
怎样？不服气吗？

399
00:51:56,876 --> 00:51:58,478
The paths are slippery because of rain
下雨路那么滑…

400
00:51:58,478 --> 00:52:04,110
He nearly lost his life slipping down a slope
刚刚他差点摔死你知不知道！

401
00:52:05,618 --> 00:52:07,848
Where is your log?
…你的木头呢？

402
00:52:09,455 --> 00:52:12,189
Slipped into the ravine -Slipped?
…滑掉了！
滑掉了？

403
00:52:14,961 --> 00:52:18,897
Do you know how expensive it is?
你知道那一根木头多贵吗？

404
00:52:20,533 --> 00:52:21,761
Pihu!
比荷！

405
00:52:25,638 --> 00:52:26,764
Yoshimura!
吉村！

406
00:52:31,511 --> 00:52:32,739
Chief Mouna..
莫那头目…

407
00:52:38,618 --> 00:52:40,279
Sir Yoshimura?
吉村大人

408
00:52:41,120 --> 00:52:43,322
You're looking at me
at such a disrespectful angle
你用这么没礼貌的角度看我…

409
00:52:43,322 --> 00:52:46,314
Aren't you afraid of being stabbed blind?
不怕我刺瞎你吗？

410
00:52:51,697 --> 00:52:54,257
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁啊？

411
00:52:56,202 --> 00:53:00,662
You're not the boss here in Mehebu
马赫坡的老大不是你…

412
00:53:01,941 --> 00:53:03,272
I am!
是我…

413
00:53:15,655 --> 00:53:17,282
You will not get paid today
今天别想领钱了！

414
00:53:20,660 --> 00:53:24,391
The precious logs are destroyed
好好的木头拖成这样…

415
00:53:26,099 --> 00:53:29,034
Do it again and you'll have to pay for the loss
下次再这样，我还要你们赔！

416
00:53:29,735 --> 00:53:32,038
Keep working! -With what?
-继续工作啊！-赔什么？

417
00:53:32,038 --> 00:53:35,775
We get nothing from working for you
替你们工作又领不到钱

418
00:53:35,775 --> 00:53:38,010
What do you want us to pay with? -Pihu!
还要赔你什么？
比荷！

419
00:53:38,010 --> 00:53:41,147
Chief Mouna, he... -I saw it
-莫那头目，是他…
-我看见了！

420
00:53:41,147 --> 00:53:42,512
Go home!
回去！

421
00:53:43,549 --> 00:53:44,573
Go home!
…回去！

422
00:53:55,695 --> 00:53:59,499
Yoshimura, stop picking on them
吉村，你不要老是找他们麻烦…

423
00:53:59,499 --> 00:54:01,433
You don't know nothing
你这菜鸟懂什么？

424
00:54:03,336 --> 00:54:05,361
I was educating them
我这是在教育呀！

425
00:54:29,929 --> 00:54:31,954
These damn savages!
这些可恶的生蕃…

426
00:54:40,940 --> 00:54:42,635
I'll have you pay for this some day
有一天要你们好看！

427
00:55:02,595 --> 00:55:03,496
Good morning
早安…

428
00:55:03,496 --> 00:55:04,622
Good morning
早安！

429
00:55:07,099 --> 00:55:09,335
Good morning
早安！

430
00:55:09,335 --> 00:55:11,771
What? Checking out guns?
怎么？来借枪啊？

431
00:55:11,771 --> 00:55:15,298
Watan Robo is getting married
We've got some preparations to do
瓦旦要结婚了，得帮他准备呀！

432
00:55:16,542 --> 00:55:18,377
Tado? Baso?
达多…巴索…

433
00:55:18,377 --> 00:55:20,780
I heard your father Mouna Rudo
听说你们父亲莫那鲁道

434
00:55:20,780 --> 00:55:24,477
has mobilized lots of men for this hunt?
为了这次打猎出动了不少人？

435
00:55:26,452 --> 00:55:30,489
Yeah, but what can we hunt
in those disappearing forests?
对啊！只是消失的森林哪来的猎物？

436
00:55:30,489 --> 00:55:33,151
You've about hacked down all the trees
on our hunting grounds
猎场的树已经快被你们砍光了

437
00:55:33,993 --> 00:55:36,086
If we don't go hunting now
不趁现在去多打点猎物

438
00:55:37,496 --> 00:55:40,333
we'll have nothing left
once the trees are all gone
将来树没了…
就什么都没了！

439
00:55:40,333 --> 00:55:41,732
Tado Mouna!
达多莫那！

440
00:55:43,302 --> 00:55:44,963
You'd better watch your mouth!
你讲话给我小心一点！

441
00:55:54,614 --> 00:55:56,605
Savages will always be savages
生蕃就是生蕃…

442
00:55:58,818 --> 00:56:00,183
They have no manners at all
一点礼貌都没有！

443
00:56:15,868 --> 00:56:16,732
Wait!
等一下！

444
00:56:18,571 --> 00:56:19,367
Pawan?
巴万？

445
00:56:20,139 --> 00:56:21,538
What is the kid doing there?
这小子在那边干嘛？

446
00:56:28,180 --> 00:56:29,306
Pawan!
巴万…

447
00:56:57,343 --> 00:57:01,074
Chief Mouna! My hunting ground is right here!
莫那头目
我的猎场在这里呀！

448
00:57:21,467 --> 00:57:22,957
Temu Walis?
铁木瓦力斯…

449
00:57:30,076 --> 00:57:31,911
You red-foot pheasant!
你这只红脚鸠…

450
00:57:31,911 --> 00:57:34,436
Don't you know
this is the Mehebu hunting ground?
不知道这是我马赫坡的猎场吗？

451
00:57:35,047 --> 00:57:36,708
Mouna! It's just a misunderstanding
莫那！莫那…

452
00:57:37,316 --> 00:57:41,721
This is the first time my eldest son goes hunting
别误会…
我大儿子第一次打猎

453
00:57:41,721 --> 00:57:44,087
I asked Temu to bring me here
是我要铁木带我来的！

454
00:57:45,257 --> 00:57:48,661
Mouna, I asked Temu to teach him
莫那，是我请铁木来教他打猎的

455
00:57:48,661 --> 00:57:51,425
Even so, you cannot trespass
into our Mehebu hunting ground
那也不应该跑进我马赫坡的猎场！

456
00:57:52,431 --> 00:57:54,296
This used to be our Toda hunting ground
在我叔父的时侯…

457
00:57:55,234 --> 00:57:58,635
when my uncle was alive
这里本来就是我们道泽的猎场

458
00:57:59,572 --> 00:58:01,107
You Mehebu clansmen robbed it from us
是你们马赫坡强占去的！

459
00:58:01,107 --> 00:58:04,607
Rob it back if you can -Enough!
你有本事就再抢回去啊！
够了！

460
00:58:13,152 --> 00:58:16,349
Mouna, can you do me this favor?
莫那…给我个面子可以吗？

461
00:58:17,490 --> 00:58:19,151
Favor?
面子？

462
00:58:19,725 --> 00:58:20,783
Kojima..
小岛…

463
00:58:21,827 --> 00:58:25,323
if you lived in Mehebu now, I'd do you this favor
如果你现在在我马赫坡…
我一定给足你面子！

464
00:58:26,332 --> 00:58:28,401
But you live in Tnbarah Clan
但是你现在在屯巴拉

465
00:58:28,401 --> 00:58:31,359
Take these red-foot pheasants
and get out of my hunting ground
就给我带着这群红脚鸠…
滚离我的猎场！

466
00:58:37,576 --> 00:58:40,246
I don't care if it's your hunting ground or theirs
什么你的猎场，我的猎场？

467
00:58:40,246 --> 00:58:42,942
because everything here
belongs to us Japanese now
全部都是我们日本人的！

468
00:59:16,415 --> 00:59:19,518
Temu, you just wait and see
铁木…
你等着瞧…

469
00:59:19,518 --> 00:59:21,418
Some day I'll destroy your Tnbarah Clan
有一天我杀进你们屯巴拉…

470
00:59:26,425 --> 00:59:29,053
Go on and do it if you dare
带种的话走进来一步看看！

471
00:59:30,062 --> 00:59:33,259
Let's see who's killed first
看谁先干掉谁！

472
00:59:43,409 --> 00:59:46,037
I don't care if you're Mouna Rudo
莫那鲁道又怎样…

473
01:00:15,641 --> 01:00:17,409
Wow, well done
好厉害喔…

474
01:00:17,409 --> 01:00:20,572
Can a girl carry such a heavy load?
女孩子背那么重没问题吗？

475
01:00:21,747 --> 01:00:23,282
Go! Go!
加油！加油…

476
01:00:23,282 --> 01:00:25,885
Good girl!
好乖唷…

477
01:00:25,885 --> 01:00:29,622
The men in your clan
are all out hunting, aren't they?
部落男人都出去打猎了是吧？

478
01:00:29,622 --> 01:00:31,557
Wanna make some extra bucks?
要不要赚点外快？

479
01:00:31,557 --> 01:00:33,425
Come with me to my boardinghouse! -No!
-陪我到宿舍喝酒吧！
-不要！

480
01:00:33,425 --> 01:00:35,154
I'll give you two dollars -No!
-我会给你两块钱…-不要…

481
01:00:36,529 --> 01:00:38,087
What the hell? Bastard!
…干什么？哪个浑蛋？

482
01:00:42,301 --> 01:00:45,104
Sir Sugiura, how dare you!
衫浦大人…你胆子还真大！

483
01:00:45,104 --> 01:00:48,471
Harassing a Mehebu woman?
敢欺负我马赫坡的女人？

484
01:00:49,341 --> 01:00:52,378
I was offering her a chance to earn
some extra money in our substation
…我只是让她来驻在所赚外快…

485
01:00:52,378 --> 01:00:54,113
It's no big deal
没什么大不了的嘛！

486
01:00:54,113 --> 01:00:59,518
I know you Japanese policemen too well
你以为我不懂你们这些山地警察？

487
01:00:59,518 --> 01:01:03,188
Take that blind prey of yours and scram
带着那些瞎眼的猎物滚吧！

488
01:01:03,188 --> 01:01:04,990
It's true, and she accepted it too
真的，她也答应了…

489
01:01:04,990 --> 01:01:08,527
Another word from you
and I'll have the hounds feast on you
再讲，我就放狗咬你！

490
01:01:08,527 --> 01:01:10,757
Phooey! Fine, fine
哎呀…知道…知道了…

491
01:01:12,031 --> 01:01:14,864
It's hard to reason with you savages
跟你们这群蕃人讲不通啦！

492
01:01:23,042 --> 01:01:24,805
You deserve it! Chicken!
活该…胆小鬼！

493
01:01:26,211 --> 01:01:27,678
活该！

494
01:01:42,595 --> 01:01:44,563
You're back, Sapu
萨布，你回来啦！

495
01:02:00,045 --> 01:02:02,775
Chief, the matches you wanted
头目，你要的火柴…

496
01:02:03,449 --> 01:02:05,351
Sapu?
萨布…

497
01:02:05,351 --> 01:02:09,253
Let the kids eat more meat. They're too skinny
让孩子多吃点肉，都太瘦了…
