-
-=
-= L
-= LU
-= LUO
-= LUO M
-= LUO MA
-= LUO MAD
-= LUO MADE
-= LUO MADE D
-= LUO MADE DV
-= LUO MADE DVD
-= LUO MADE DVD =
-= LUO MADE DVD =-
Mouna! Take it easy!
A good hunter waits patiently
Out of the way! Let me do it!
Move!
Mouna! Mouna!
Mouna, be careful!
Mouna!
Mouna,
here come the Bununs from Kntabang Clan!
Let's go! Come on!
Come on, let's go! Leave the boar!
There he is!
Kill him!
Mouna, get down!
Over there!
Mouna is over there! -Shoot him!
Come on! Hurry!
Listen to me! My name is Mouna Rudo!
Be alert when you hear this name again!
Who?
Who becomes the hero?
Who is it?
Your Mouna is back!
It's your Mouna! He's back!
It's Mouna!
Mouna is a true man now
Mouna is back!
Well done, Mouna!
A true man is back!
The hero is back!
Mouna..
you've offered blood sacrifice
to our ancestors' spirits
I hereby tattoo the marks of manhood
on your face
From now on..
you shall abide by our ancestral spirit
to guard our clan and our hunting grounds
On the rainbow bridge
our ancestors' spirits await the reunion
with your valiant soul
Warriors of The Rainbow I : Sun Flag
(In 1895)
(the island of Taiwan was ceded to Japan)
(under the Treaty of Shimonoseki
between Japan and China)
The island of Taiwan
is the new territory of our empire
yet to receive our Mikado's grace
The islanders are warlike innately
It's said that they're armed to fight us
but they're a scattered bunch,
nothing to be afraid of
Once disembarked at Keelung Port
we must sweep the entire island with force
We must prevent any disrespect
from the people
so as to gain their wholehearted allegiance
to our empire of the sun
Especially the heartland of Taiwan
occupied by the tribal savages
There are ample resources
of lumber and mines in the mountains
Endless treasures..
Father, last night I dreamt of a deer
with white spots around its eyes..
Sisin babblers are singing an auspicious song
Go ahead and hunt the deer in your dream
...for your own wedding
Wait! Hold on!
Hold on!
Charge!
Let's kill them!
That was the deer in my dream
Listen to me!
Dance! Let's dance!
Everyone Dance!
Come and dance, my in-law!
Come on, everyone! Let's dance!
This is my son Mouna Rudo
The bravest and strongest warrior
in Mehebu Clan
He'll be an unparalleled chief
You're wise to marry your daughter to him
Dance! Let's dance!
Let's cheer for them!
Be joyful, everyone!
Out of the way!
Stand clear of the path please
Out of the way! Please!
Out of the way!
Out of the way! Move!
Out of the way please!
Hey, my old friend!
Oh no! It's him again
My old friend!
You from Mehebu Clan! Over here!
Over here!
Hey, boss!
Come
Must you wear such a big head
on that small head of yours?
My old friend!
Mouna?
Seediqs from Toda
-You from Tnbarah Clan, over here!
Hey, young man, don't you make trouble here
The tallest one is Mouna Rudo
of Mehebu Clan from Tgdaya
You've come all the way here
with so little meat for exchange?
Those of you from Toda are so shameless
Why don't you offer your
hunting grounds to us for free?
Mouna Rudo, don't be too proud
I'm not afraid of you
Mouna Rudo, I'm Temu Walis
I'll cut your head off when I grow up
Temu Walis?
You won't have the chance to grow up
Is that Temu Cire?
No, it's Temu Walis
I mean that grown-up man
I don't know. Not someone famous, I guess
Gather up, young men!
Come on! Bring your weapons!
Come with us! Quick!
Put these away!
Quick! All young men come with us!
Run!
Temu!
Mouna!
Mouna, he's one of our own
No one can ever run ahead of me, you hear?
Come on, Labay!
Are you alright?
Laying railway tracks?
It's no easy task in the mountains
In order to harvest the natural resources
in those forests
we need to have proper transportation
Yeah
It's a shame to leave
those resources undeveloped
but those savages up there..
Sir?
Here she is, sir
She dares not lead you past Hakaw Supeitei,
Captain
She'll spend the night in her father's house
in Meisi
She won't accompany you to
the hunting grounds of other clans
Much obliged
Let's go!
Captain?
Those savages in the mountains
are rather ferocious
Please be careful!
Hey!
Hey, it's your turn now
Wow! How beautiful!
Yes, indeed
It was so dark last night
that we didn't notice we're surrounded
by cherry blossom trees
Cherry blossoms?
They really are cherry blossoms
It's so red
Red as blood
Blockade the entire Wushe region
Ban all trading between the Hans
and the Wushe savages
Yes, sir
Back off!
Put down your weapons! Go up there!
Hurry up!
Come on!
It's an ambush! Watch out!
Hide there! Quick!
They're up there!
Uwe! Uwe!
Retreat!
There's no way out!
These intruders are out of their minds
How dare they show up at my doorstep
Throw them down!
Get out of here! Quick!
Hurry up!
Follow me!
I see. I see
I see
(A Short Account of Taiwan)
Give me their biggest enemy
There they are!
Hello
Here
The intruders don't allow
the Hans to deal with us
But we can deal with you, can't we?
Idiots!
Bring me the wine!
Bring the wine!
Drink!
Look! I'm Mouna Rudo
I killed at Hakaw Supeitei a chief
of the intruders
Mouna Rudo?
You're Mouna Rudo?
Yes, I am
Mouna Rudo!
Chief? Chief?
Where is Mouna Rudo?
I couldn't get him drunk
Wake up!
Those Bununs from Kntabang Clan
are hunting heads
Get up! Let's go!
Let's get out of here! Hurry!
All the human beings on this land
The gods bestow upon us a mortal life
But we are true men indeed
A true man dies in the battlefield
and he strides to the heavenly home
of our ancestors
There lies a fertile hunting ground
that can only be guarded by a qualified true man
When he arrives at the heavenly home
of our ancestors
he'll come across a beautiful rainbow bridge
The ancestors' spirits guarding it say.
''Let's take a look at your hands''
When the man opens his hands
we see bloodstains that can never be wiped clean
''Now you're a true man indeed!''
says our ancestors' spirits
Come out, guys!
Bring your weapons!
Come on!
''Go! Go ahead! My hero!''
''Your soul may now enter
the heavenly home of our ancestors
''to guard the hunting ground of honor''
Stop it! It'll never be ignited
And a true woman must be good
at weaving red coat of arms for her man
When she reaches the rainbow bridge
she opens her hands
showing her calluses that can never be removed
''Go! Go ahead! You're a true woman''
say the ancestors' spirits
guarding the rainbow bridge
''Your soul may now enter
the heavenly home of our ancestors
''No go weave a rainbow-like dress for yourself!''
Be careful! -Over there!
Stop!
A man who's never decapitated an enemy
or a woman who's not good at weaving
is not qualified to have their faces tattooed
Some day, when they're gone
and their souls arrive at the rainbow bridge
the ancestors' spirits guarding it
would see their clean faces and ask.
How dare you bring a machete! Bastard!
''Are these my children?''
''Are you my children?''
''Go back! Go back now!''
''You're not true Seediqs''
''You're not qualified to enter
the heavenly home of our ancestors
Run! Come on!
Let's get out of here!
Run, Mouna!
Just go!
Rudo, are you alright?
Father!
Suddenly, the tribesmen find themselves blowsy
their eyes blank
They turn around in shame
and walk though the rugged valleys
They become wailing ghosts
suffering unbearable pain
from all the cuts
by the poisonous crabs along the creek
Mouna..
you must keep the intruders away from our clan
Mouna, do you understand?
Abide by our ancestral dictations
and be a Seediq Bale (a true man)
Excuse me, sir
Let's see..
The first one from the left is Mouna Rudo
the chief of Mehebu Clan
Those behind him are Ubus and Mouna Sine
Mouna, stop glaring
Look down
Ubus..
our ancestors never lost
any of our hunting grounds in the past
I can't believe these intruders
are taking them away from us now
I'll never submit to them
I will never
These are all yours?
I will never!
Mouna!
Stop it!
Hurry up! It's going to rain
Awi!
What's wrong?
Are you alright?
(Wushe, 1930)
Schools, clinics, grocery stores
post offices, hotels, boardinghouses..
We've managed to civilize
all the Wushe savages
It's not an easy task
Hard to imagine that this was once
the most uncivilized heartland here
Carrying logs..
and walking from the lumberyard uphill to here
takes them a whole day, doesn't it?
Don't worry. These savages are strong
And they're more than happy
to earn some money for millet wine
Come on. This way please
Mr. Satsuka,
how long have you been in Wushe?
Over a decade
So you know this region very well?
Of course. My wife is a savage woman
I know this region like the back of my hand
-It's this bone right here
It hurts so much when you press it
Right here?
Ah! Easy!
Here! Have a drink!
No more wine for us please. We can't afford it
It's alright
This one's on me
You're indeed a beautiful serpent
Every day I carry those damn logs
without getting paid properly
Now I'm so broke that even my hounds
look down on me
We're losing our hunting grounds
and you still keep the hounds
to look down on you?
Look!
Those are the trees
that used to watch over our ancestors
This is how they end up
Strange thing is, why so many constructions?
What? Not only do you befriend us with wine
but you speak our language fluently
Hey! It's going to rain
Stop drinking and go home!
-Good morning, sir!
Good morning, Mr. Policeman
You've worked all day long
for such a mean wage
and you waste it on wine?
What else can we do with so little money?
Yeah, right! We're savages, aren't we?
We aren't supposed to know
anything about saving money
Yeah, Mr. Policeman. You're Japanese, sir
You don't know how hard our lives are
Only Mr. Wu here understands us
He's a beautiful serpent
He's a viper!
Excuse me -Hello
I'd like some salt, please -No problem
Oh no! It's raining! Hurry up and go home, sir
Or your glorious uniform will be soaking wet
Go ahead!
Go on!
Run, sir!
Your Japanese fur is too precious to spoil
It's raining
Go collect the laundry hanging outside
Can't you tell what needs to be done first?
Hey, come back!
Are you taking the baby out in the rain?
I'm sorry
What an imbecile!
Who'd marry such an idiot like you?
When it rains, it pours
Good morning
This is our policeman Hanaoka Jiro
This is our new police minister Ekawa Hakudo
Jiro is a savage too
Older brother
Older sister -Older sister
Younger brother -Younger brother
Younger sister -Younger sister
Okay, one more time
Father -Father
Mother -Mother
Older brother -Older brother
Older sister..
Hurry! She's in labor!
Two savages
can never give birth to a Japanese child
Are you alright, Hanako?
This job is for women only. What are you doing?
Dakis, get out of here! Get out!
Oh, what an extraordinary sight!
Timber!
(Hark, people)
(Behold, people)
(Oh, our warriors)
(The youngsters
much like the budding pine leaves)
(They show true bravery)
(Fought in the falling leaves)
(Fought under the withered pine tree)
(Now they're back with heads hunted)
(Our warriors fought with all their might)
(Mahebu Police Station)
Chief!
Pawan, why aren't you in school?
I'm sick
Sick? But you don't look like sick
Did your teacher beat you?
I raced a Japanese kid and I won
And the kid was crying
The teacher blamed me for bullying him,
so he beat me
Can I have another one please?
I'll win the race on the sports day
Those Japanese kids can cry their balls out
when they watch me getting awarded
Chief, I hate the Japanese
Chief Mouna?
My grandpa said you were a hero
when you were younger
Your grandpa said
I was a hero when I was younger?
I'm still a hero. Does he know that?
Chief Mouna, will you take me along
next time you go hunting?
Pawan, where is your hunting ground?
Chief Mouna!
I'm alright. Just a little bit tipsy, that's all
What the hell?
Hanako!
Look what you have done!
How many times do I have to tell you
that you cannot drag these logs along?
You destroyed the logs
-Only the bark is scratched
The inside is still intact
You savages!
How many times do I have to tell you?
What? You wanna fight?
The paths are slippery because of rain
He nearly lost his life slipping down a slope
Where is your log?
Slipped into the ravine -Slipped?
Do you know how expensive it is?
Pihu!
Yoshimura!
Chief Mouna..
Sir Yoshimura?
You're looking at me
at such a disrespectful angle
Aren't you afraid of being stabbed blind?
Who do you think you are?
You're not the boss here in Mehebu
I am!
You will not get paid today
The precious logs are destroyed
Do it again and you'll have to pay for the loss
Keep working! -With what?
We get nothing from working for you
What do you want us to pay with? -Pihu!
Chief Mouna, he... -I saw it
Go home!
Yoshimura, stop picking on them
You don't know nothing
I was educating them
These damn savages!
I'll have you pay for this some day
Good morning
What? Checking out guns?
Watan Robo is getting married
We've got some preparations to do
Tado? Baso?
I heard your father Mouna Rudo
has mobilized lots of men for this hunt?
Yeah, but what can we hunt
in those disappearing forests?
You've about hacked down all the trees
on our hunting grounds
If we don't go hunting now
we'll have nothing left
once the trees are all gone
Tado Mouna!
You'd better watch your mouth!
Savages will always be savages
They have no manners at all
Wait!
Pawan?
What is the kid doing there?
Pawan!
Chief Mouna! My hunting ground is right here!
Temu Walis?
You red-foot pheasant!
Don't you know
this is the Mehebu hunting ground?
Mouna! It's just a misunderstanding
This is the first time my eldest son goes hunting
I asked Temu to bring me here
Mouna, I asked Temu to teach him
Even so, you cannot trespass
into our Mehebu hunting ground
This used to be our Toda hunting ground
when my uncle was alive
You Mehebu clansmen robbed it from us
Rob it back if you can -Enough!
Mouna, can you do me this favor?
Favor?
Kojima..
if you lived in Mehebu now, I'd do you this favor
But you live in Tnbarah Clan
Take these red-foot pheasants
and get out of my hunting ground
I don't care if it's your hunting ground or theirs
because everything here
belongs to us Japanese now
Temu, you just wait and see
Some day I'll destroy your Tnbarah Clan
Go on and do it if you dare
Let's see who's killed first
I don't care if you're Mouna Rudo
Wow, well done
Can a girl carry such a heavy load?
Go! Go!
Good girl!
The men in your clan
are all out hunting, aren't they?
Wanna make some extra bucks?
Come with me to my boardinghouse! -No!
I'll give you two dollars -No!
What the hell? Bastard!
Sir Sugiura, how dare you!
Harassing a Mehebu woman?
I was offering her a chance to earn
some extra money in our substation
It's no big deal
I know you Japanese policemen too well
Take that blind prey of yours and scram
It's true, and she accepted it too
Another word from you
and I'll have the hounds feast on you
Phooey! Fine, fine
It's hard to reason with you savages
You deserve it! Chicken!
You're back, Sapu
Chief, the matches you wanted
Sapu?
Let the kids eat more meat. They're too skinny