Mouna! Mouna!
Bakan,
why does Mouna need so many matches?
Who knows?
Had any meat, my boy?
Have a drink!
Father! Father!
Father, can we slaughter a cow?
Not enough to eat?
It's enough, but we haven't had beef
for such a long time
Do it then
Let's slaughter a cow!
Hooray! Let's slaughter a cow!
Baso, grab it!
Grab its legs!
Come on!
I've cut off the head
of the Japanese Governor-general
Wow! What a party!
Sir Yoshimura
Whose wedding day is it?
It's Watan and Lubi's
Come! Have a drink with us, sir
No
No -Come on, have a drink
No way
I don't drink the wine with your nasty saliva in it
Come on, have a drink
-I told you that I don't want to
Your hand is all dirty with blood
I invited you with good will
-You son-of-a-bitch!
You've soiled me with blood!
I offered you a drink and you hit me?
I'll beat you into senses!
Stop!
-I don't need to reason with a savage
What is it? Let's go look!
Hurry up!
I know what you said just now
with a boar's head in your hand
Out of my way!
Say it again in Japanese if you dare
Say it again!
Get out of my way! -I dare you!
Come on, guys!
Faster!
Tado!
Baso, kill him!
I'm holding down his feet! Beat him up!
I'm holding down his feet again!
Stop! All of you!
What is it? What the hell?
Let me cut off this pig head of yours!
Stop! Stop! Yoshi..
Yoshimura
You're in big trouble
You have the nerve to beat me up
-Let's kill him!
Shut your mouth!
Excuse us! Let us through!
I'll kill all you Mehebu clansmen
I'll kill you all
Let's do it, Father,
before the Japanese kill us all
Why the hell did you provoke him
when you knew he'd kill us all?
You're nothing but a bunch of hounds
that can only chase and hunt
and know nothing of self-restraint
How much longer do I have to put up with you?
Out of my way!
Now you're here to bribe me with wine?
It's too late
I've filed the report on the case
of you beating up a police officer
Tell you something..
This time I'll destroy your clan
Yoshimura..
I, Mouna Rudo, come here to
apologize to you personally
Stop being so arrogant
Who do you think you are?
You think you're still a chief?
You can't even control your own sons
I don't think you're qualified
to be a chief anymore
Get out!
Who the hell let you in?
Get the hell out!
I don't want to see your faces again
Go home and rot!
Hey! Why did you do that to him?
-Shut up!
I couldn't sleep last night because of a mosquito
Really? I'll see to it
Mr. Hanaoka!
Yes?
May I know which clan you grew up in?
Gungu Clan
And your original name?
Dakis Nawi
We have another savage policeman
named Hanoka Ichiro
He is the highest educated policemen here
What are you doing this afternoon?
I'm going home for some private matter
I was to ask you
to patrol all the savage clans with us
and tell me the relationships among them all
Come with us! -No, it's alright
It's alright
Do whatever you need to do
Kabasawa will go with us -Yes
He knows the savages well too
Yoshimura has reported
Tado's case to the substation
I can't believe this Yoshimura
Chief Mouna apologized to him personally
Why did he insist on filing the case?
Yoshimura and Sugiura are not the same
as Kojima after all
They will never try to understand our people
If Kojima were living in Mehebu
there wouldn't be so much trouble
Since I was very little
I've always been scared of Chief Mouna
It looks as if underneath his mantle
he's always gripping his machete
ready to draw it to kill anytime
He's no ordinary man
He's impossible to be tamed
It must be difficult for him to torn between
the expectations of his fellow tribesmen
and the intimidation of the Japanese
Aren't we living like that as well?
We don't want to be savages
but however hard
we try to dress up like the Japanese
we'll always be seen as uncivilized people
We've lived like this for 20 years
Another 20 years won't be impossible
By the time our children grow up
maybe we will have changed forever
the savage image of ours
Do we still have the chance?
Mehebu Clan may be wiped out soon
Father, let's fight the Japanese
Ouch! It hurts! -You dumb ass!
Father, don't be mad!
Father! -You never learn!
Enough! -You moron!
Oh no! How come..
It's the temporary bamboo bridge
that the savages used in the past
It's ugly and insecure,
but they keep walking over it
I'll tear it down sooner or later
But it saves them lots of time
if they walk over it to fetch water or to the field
Look! This wire bridge is strong and firm
Tado?
This young man is Tado Mouna
the eldest son of the Mehebu chief Mouna Rudo
But he saw us without saying anything
Is there anything wrong with him?
No, it's a habit of the savages
-It's not a very good habit
Oh well, they're savages after all
Can you stop talking about them like that?
Sugiura! -Welcome, sirs
This is Officer Sugiura
This way please
You should've informed me
before you came here, sir
I could've asked those savages
to welcome you with dances
No need for that
We're only showing our hospitality
Chief Mouna!
What?
Chief Mouna,
can you tell me something about Japan?
I know you've been there before
They have armies, cannons, machineguns
airplanes and large steamers in Japan
There are more Japanese people
than the tree leaves in the forest
than the pebbles in Jhuoshuei River
I know why you're asking me this
You don't really want to know Japan
All you want is to remind me
how powerful the Japanese are
Don't worry. I'll never forget
Humph! You Japanese policemen
took us on the ship for days to Japan
but all they showed us
were airplanes and cannons
However, the policemen in Japan
were much nicer and kinder
than those of you here
They feared we'd revolt against them
so they tried their best to befriend us
But those of you here in the mountains
always provoke us so much
that I want to hunt your heads
Chief Mouna, I'm still a Seediq
Although I'm now a Japanese policeman
I never forget
that the same blood runs in our veins
Dakis, when you die
are you entering a Japanese shrine?
Or the heavenly home of our ancestors?
I heard that..
in the school for savage children
you beat up our kids like the Japanese do
I beat them up because I don't want
the Japanese to look down on them
You graduated from Normal School
You're more highly-educated
than any other Japanese policemen
But how come you get the lowest salary?
Don't the Japanese look down on you already?
Beating up your own people makes them
look down on you even more
During our stay in Japan
the Japanese knew all of us chiefs
from different clans hated one another
but they made us sit together
at the dining table deliberately
We were glaring at one another
all the time while we were eating
intending to draw our machetes and kill
Humph! The Japanese are good at these things
Chief, is it so bad to be ruled by the Japanese?
At least we're leading a civilized life
We have schools and post offices
and we don't have to survive
by hunting savagely anymore
Is it so bad to be ruled by the Japanese?
Is it so good to be ruled by them?
Our men are forced to bend over
to carry logs on our backs
and our women have to kneel down
to serve and pour wine
And all the money ends up
in the pockets of the Japanese policemen
I'm a chief
but all I can do is get drunk
and pretend I see nothing and hear nothing
What else can I do?
Post offices? Stores? Schools?
Do any of those things
make our lives easier and better?
Instead,
we're made to see how impoverished we are
Chief, can't we bear it for another 20 years?
In 20 years, there will be no Seediq
and there will be no hunting ground
All our children will have turned Japanese
Chief Mouna,
have you made up your mind to do it?
Chief Mouna?
About Yoshimura... -I'm old
Don't worry
The Japanese are far too powerful
I won't go against them
Go home
This is the hunting ground
that belongs to me only
Get lost
Chief... -Get lost!
Dakis, have a drink
Go home and get yourself dead-drunk
We can't drink anymore
We already... -Drink!
The millet wine that we make
can set our people free
making them sing and dance,
cry and laugh freely
You'll see once you're drunk
Go home now
Mouna!
Father?
Mouna, the tattoos on your face
are still so dark and clear
You're indeed a Seediq Bale
You're a true hero
Mouna? Look at the lines on that rock
It split into half
when struck by the lightening, didn't it?
In the dim light at dusk
the lightening splits a rock into half
What a beautiful sight!
Father?
I can't keep the intruders away
(Ah, it's for real)
(Here l am)
(l used to guard these mountains
and forests bravely)
(Oh yes, it's for real)
Mouna, let's sing
We haven't sung together for long
(Reminisce the people from the past)
(Here l am)
(l used to guard these mountains
and forests bravely)
(These are our mountains)
(These are our creeks)
(We're the true Seediq Bale)
(We go hunting in the mountains)
(We share food in our clan)
(We fetch water from the creeks)
(l'm willing to give my life for these)
(Oh, creek! Be quiet)
(Sisin babblers are singing)
(Sing us a beautiful song please)
(Sing for our people)
(a song of our ancestral spirit)
(l'm willing to give my life too)
(When the lightening rifts the rock)
(a rainbow appears)
(and a proud man emerges)
(Who is this man so proud?)
(lt's your offspring)
(A Seediq Bale)
What?
Tado Mouna became a hero before I did
Those Japanese are outrageous
I can't believe they beat up someone
who offers them a drink
A while ago..
three girls from Boarung Clan
were asked to serve them drinks
and they were raped
Why couldn't Tado be a real hero
and kill Yoshimura right on the spot?
Kill him?
Don't you remember how my family died?
My father killed only one Japanese man
and they burned my whole family alive
I was hiding in the woods watching
without even blinking my eyes
So..
that's why we can't kill only one Japanese man
We have to kill all of them to make a difference
Are you kidding me?
We wouldn't still be sitting here
if we could kill them all
Now the Mehebu chief Mouna Rudo
is driven to bay
by that policeman from the lumberyard
and the day after tomorrow on October 27th
is the big sports day
By then, all the Japanese in Wushe
are going to gather in one place
Is it time already?
Father, there won't be a better chance
And we have no other choice
We can't have the Japanese look down
on us anymore
We need to show them what we're made of
Let's fight them, Chief
Yeah! Let's fight them
Young men..
I hate the Japanese no less than you do
But do you realize that
we're going to die after all this
and all our people will be wiped out?
Our ancestors shed their blood
in exchange for our lives
Now we're taking our children along
to the battlefield to shed blood
We're Seediq Bale, aren't we?
Temu, does your father know you're here?
My father told me that I should ask Chief Mouna
to help us youngsters get our faces tattooed
so that the ancestors' spirits
guarding the rainbow bridge
will recognize us as the true Seediqs
Father?
If we want revenge,
it'd be the business of Mehebu Clan alone
But if we're offering a blood sacrifice
to our ancestors
it will be the business of all the 12 clans
in Wushe
Keep it a secret before action
We must tell none of the elders,
children or women in all these clans
When did you..
I'm speaking here. Are you listening?
Keep it a secret before action
I knew Chief Mouna had a plan already
What do you know?
It's your idea and your responsibility
Inform the chiefs of all the 12 clans
Tomorrow morning..
we're going to gather in Wushe
and offer a blood sacrifice
Our ancestors' spirits..
We're here for the guns. Sorry to disturb you
Boss.. -Welcome. This way please
Fill them up with salt
And give me ten boxes of matches
Wow! Lots of things to buy, huh?
Boss, we'll pay for it next time
On credit again?
Yes, we can -How much is it?
No, you can't!
Wait! You're buying all these on credit?
It's alright
It's alright? But you never pay me back!
Let's give them a hand
That old drunkard Mouna Rudo
really can't take it anymore?
I'll ask the young men to get ready
before they all get dead drunk
Young man, how dare you tell me these
in front of the police station!
Good morning!
Pihu Sapu?
What the hell was he up to?
That crazy boy spells nothing but trouble
But we'd be bored around here
without him, won't we?
You call making troubles interesting?
Tado, look! Only the gun barrel is left
No, I won't do it -Won't do it?
Chief Dahdo..
the chiefs of the other clans
have all agreed to join us
and everything is ready now
Fighting the Japanese will lead us to death only
We've had three chiefs in our family
that died of fighting the Japanese
Now we've stooped to bring you kids up
to carry on the lifeline of our people
not to get killed on the battlefield
Chief... -We're not afraid of death
Even Chief Mouna agreed to do it
Chief Dahdo, they'll laugh at us if you don't do it
They can laugh at me for all I care
I'll never allow our Gungu Clan
to join the battle. Period
But Chief.. -Chief!
Are you going to be a hunter
forever without guns or hunting grounds?
You have no tattoo on your face
Don't forget whom you're talking to
What do we do now?
I can't stand that old man
No way
I won't allow our young clansmen
to sacrifice themselves in vain
with you maniacs
But.. -I won't let out this secret of yours
Go home
You only show off your bravery
with those animal skulls now?
Chief Walis, you once fought the Japanese
at Hakaw Supeitei
Where's your bravery now?
Bravery? I gave it all to you long ago
Bring your women and children here
to our Paran Clan
to keep the bloodline of your clan
A clan so big...with so many people..
What are you doing?
Hello, sir!
Come closer
Stop fooling around!
Go home and clean your places up
Yes, sir
Go on!
Sorry
Stay away, kids
Okay, ready
One, two, three
I'm not going in
Make me proud in tomorrow's games
Can you stay with us, Father?
No, I can't. I have to go back before dark
You're spending the night here
Be a good boy, you hear?
See you then
Bye -Take care
Let's go!
Excuse me!
Mouna knows everything about battles
But I'm old. I can't go with him
But..
-But our Drodux Clan won't be absent in this
Do I have to say it again in Japanese?
Good morning!
Pihu! What's wrong with you?
Pihu!
Good morning!
Why did you get all our hounds
to bark like crazy?
Chief Mouna, didn't you say
that you wouldn't do it?
Do what? Who says I'm doing anything?
Dakis, you're nothing
but a police dog wearing a collar
Did your master send you here
as a persuader?
-Tado!
Dakis, you haven't answered
my question from last time
When you die,
are you entering a Japanese shrine
or the heavenly home of our ancestors?
Are you Dakis? Or Hanaoka Ichiro?
I'm a true Seediq tribesman. I am!
But...
-If you are, take off your uniform
and offer blood sacrifice to our ancestors
with us tomorrow
You know well
how many soldiers the Japanese have
You're going to get killed for nothing
You told me the other day that there are
more Japanese people than..
There are more Japanese people
than the tree leaves in the forest
than the pebbles in Jhuoshuei River
But my determination to fight them
is more adamant than Mt. Chilai
If your civilization wants us to cringe
I'll show you the pride of savages
The true Seediq tribesmen
Listen carefully, Dakis
You being a Seediq descendant
who never tried to understand yourself
A Seediq Bale can lose his body
but he fights to keep his soul at all cost
A Seediq who loses his soul
will be forsaken by our ancestors' spirits
Do you understand..
..my child?
There are over 130 guns
in the Wushe substation
and many boxes of ammunition too
On the sports day tomorrow
Jiro...Dakis Nawi will be on duty
I'll tell him everything beforehand
Father, will he betray us?
No, he won't
Can't believe all the gunpowder
I spent years collecting will go to waste
What is it, Pihu? -They're all cowards!
Chief, only six clans are willing to join us
A little more than 300 men in all
-300 men?
I tried so hard to persuade them
I was so incensed that
I nearly drew my machete
But they... -Take it easy
Chief..
It's quite enough to have 300. Go home quietly
Don't get caught before action
-Chief..
Get out of here. All of you
Get out!
(Why do men belittle women so?)
(Don't forget all the pride you boast of)
(comes from us women)
(lt is us who weave your glory)
(lt is us women behind men's tattoos of bravery)
The sun..
(l'm on my way)
(to the heavenly home of our ancestors)
(We'll be back as brothers)
(Hark!)
(Behold!)
(My soul fights in the falling leaves)
(l am Mouna Rudo)
(l bring home the innocent souls)
(Young warriors)
(No one can defeat us)
(Oh, our warriors)
(much like the budding pine leaves)
You don't think I know
what you men are up to, do you?
I'm the chief's daughter
Wherever you're going
the children and I will follow
Your job is to guard this firepan
and keep the fire burning
When it's time to leave
I'll take you along with me
Yamada!
Sugiura, get out of there!
Come on, coward
-Who is it? What's going on?
What's going on?
Stop! Who is it?
Baso, what the hell?
What the hell are you doing?
Are you out of your mind?
Shut up!
(Do you know who l am?)
(l'm Tado Mouna, a true warrior)
(When you bleed, the animosity)
(between you and me no longer exists)
(l'm a true warrior)
(l'm a Seediq Bale, a true warrior)
(Your soul is welcome to dwell with me)
(l'll feed you with millet wine and foods)
(There's no longer hatred between us)
(When you bleed, the animosity)
(between you and me no longer exists)
(You'll be with our ancestors' spirits)
(to watch over my people)
Lubi, keep the fire burning
I'll be home before dark
Women! Children! Why aren't you singing?
Sing!
Mouna!
My old friend!
Mouna! Chief Mouna!
Shut up!
Not you
Tanah, split your men into two teams
You lead one team along Bkasan River
to annihilate all the police stations
and cut off the communication
of the Japanese to the east
The other team follows me to Gungu Clan
to meet up with other clans
What do we do
after those police stations are annihilated?
After that? Come to Mehebu Clan for a drink
Chief Mouna!
Where are they? Aren't they here yet?
They're all here
but Chief Dahdo doesn't allow
our Gungu Clan to join in the battle
Everyone's trying to convince him
Have all the police stations been annihilated?
We've burned down every one of them
Then why waste our time persuading him?
I said no
Our clan is big. We must join in
Chief Dahdo..
even a boar fights back when driven to bay
Why don't you understand?
I'd rather be punished by the Japanese
than have our whole clan wiped out
My children, don't you remember
how your fathers died?
No one from our Gungu Clan is allowed to go
Are you frightened to death by the Japanese?
Or are you spoiled by them?
Chief! Chief Mouna!
You know well
that we're bound to lose this battle
Why do you insist on fighting it?
Because of our ancestral spirit
that's soon to be forgotten
Look at these young men
Their faces are clean without the Seediq tattoos
Do you want to see their souls
forsaken by our ancestors' spirits?
Or don't you think they're qualified
to be Seediq Bale
with hands stained with blood?
Ancestral spirit?
Ancestral spirit!
You want to sacrifice their lives
in exchange for these tattoos
but what does it take to get
these young lives back?
Pride!
Let's go!
Mr. Inspector, look! Here comes the mist!
What a beautiful sight!
Here comes your brother. Good luck!
Good luck!
What a thick mist!
Yeah, it's often misty around here
But with a mist so thick
how will they judge the games?
Those games are just for kids
Having fun is all that matters
Come on, have more hot tea. It's chilly
Thank you
We still have time for a rest
Be careful! -I'm sorry
Are you alright? -Yeah, thank you
Let's do it. There's no turning back
My children..
at the other end of the rainbow
in the heavenly home of our ancestors
lies a fertile hunting ground
Our ancestors are all there
Only brave souls are allowed to enter
It's the one hunting ground
we cannot afford to lose
Fellow tribesmen!
My fellow tribesmen!
Let's hunt the heads of our enemies
We can no longer keep the hunting ground
in the Wushe mountains
Let's wash our souls clean with blood
Stride over the rainbow
to our eternal hunting ground
We're offering a blood sacrifice to our ancestors
Young men, let our ancestors' spirits
be possessed in your blades
Entrust your hatred to the clouds and mists
Let's do it
Be still! How many times do I have to tell you?
Go to the back of the line!
No, it's not what you think
Hello?
Really?
How fair-spoken you are!
-No, you're too kind
Hatsuko!
What the hell! Lower you voice
Hanaoka?
It's your shift at the ammunition storage
Hello
Your candies
Thank you
Hanako!
Hello -Hello
Wow! You bought candies
So cute
Come on, let's go. Bye!
Bye!
It's Ichiro!
Welcome! You've come a long way
This way please -Thank you
It's spectacular
All rise!
Be quiet!
Sing the national anthem
(Our Mikado rules the world)
(For generations to come)
(Like sands accumulating to rocks)
Get him!
Stop!
What's going on?
Keep playing! Come on!
Sing! Keep singing!
Keep singing!
Play it!
(Like sands accumulating to rocks)
Get him!
Here comes the blood sacrifice!
Come on!
Run! Come on!
Hatsuko! Hatsuko!
Hatsuko!
Come on! Unlock the storage
The savages are hunting heads
Hanaoka!
Unlock that one too!
Chief Mouna, my wife Obing
is still dressed in kimono
Shut up! Open the door!
Run for your lives!
I'm a descendant from a samurai as well
Mr. Satsuka! -Mr. Commissioner!
Mr. Satsuka! -Come on!
Mr. Satsuka!
Hide in there! Be quiet!
Hush! Be quiet!
Aren't you a savage too?
Why are you hiding with us?
We're offering blood sacrifice
What are you daydreaming for?
Follow me!
Pawan! Pawan!
Come on! Hurry up!
Missed! Come on!
Damned Japanese! I'll make you weep!
Come with me!
(Oh, my children, l know)
(ln those passionate days)
(You've learned a song)
(To sing for the soon-be-forgotten ancestral spirit)
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
My children! What are you doing?
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
What on earth are you doing, my children?
(Every note tightly embraces
our ancestors' spirits)
(Your dynamic bodies
dance to our ancestors' spirits)
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
Dahdo! Dahdo!
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
Go to the school right now
to save your daughter Obing
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
She's dressed in kimono
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
No! No!
(The pride of your souls
is like lightning in the clouds)
(No enemy dares to gaze at it)
Didn't we agree not to kill the Hans?
(But my children!)
What are you chasing him for?
-We did?
(But my children!)
You'd better stay sober today!
(Your hatred darkens the heaven and the earth)
Don't throw anything hard stuff at me again!
Okay, fine
(Your hatred darkens the heaven and the earth)
(The distant stars are nowhere to be seen)
Hush! Hush!
(Oh, see how the stars are dimming)
(My children!)
(The chilling light reflected
off the tips of your machetes)
(Makes the moon seem pale as wax )
(The bloodstain on the tips of your machetes)
Come on, Mr. Commissioner!
-I can't run anymore
(Keeps the night fire burning bright)
What are you talking about? Come on!
Get up!
(Keeps the night fire burning bright)
Someone's here!
(Listen, children!)
I'm exhausted -This way!
I really can't run anymore!
(Listen, children!)
Mr. Kikukawa!
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
I don't want to die here!
Tado, don't shoot!
(The sound drifting down from the forest)
Temu,
you'd do anything to become a hero, huh?
(ls it the sigh of our ancestors' spirits?)
Temu,
you'd do anything to become a hero, huh?
(ls it the sigh of our ancestors' spirits?)
Look, I killed a high-ranking official
(Or is it the sigh of the wind?)
Where's the other one?
(Listen, children!)
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
Pihu..
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
Don't kill me. We're friends
-My friend..
(That sobbing flowing down
the Jhuoshuei River)
I'm not killing people
I'm offering blood sacrifice to our ancestors
(ls it our ancestors' spirits weeping?)
I'm not killing people
I'm offering blood sacrifice to our ancestors
(ls it our ancestors' spirits weeping?)
(Or is it the clouds crying?)
Is that your teacher?
(Oh, my children!)
Teacher...My dear teacher..
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
You think we're a bunch of cowards?
I'm sorry. I was trying to educate you
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
I'd punish a Japanese kid
when he makes mistakes
(Look! The world keeps shivering)
But you've been so mean to me!
(Look! The reddened earth is silent)
(Look! The bark of Pusu Qhuni is peeling off)
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
You poor Japanese..
Come to the heavenly home of our ancestors
and be our friends forever
(Touch your bloodstained hands)
(Can they still hold the sand
from our hunting grounds?)
(Touch your angry forehead)
(Can a beautiful rainbow bridge
still be spread out over it?)
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
Come here! You go there!
Come here!
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
Wait!
Have you seen my daughter Obing?
(Touch your uneasy mouth)
No
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Han...I'm a Han! -Go there!
Have you seen my daughter Obing?
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Are you a Seediq from Toda?
Get lost!
(Can it still speak in all four seasons?)
Tell your chief Temu Walis
that we're offering blood sacrifice
to our Seediq ancestors
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
that we're offering blood sacrifice
to our Seediq ancestors
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Wushe has fallen into our hands
we Seediqs from Tgdaya
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Those of you from Toda and Truku
should join us as well
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Move over!
(All the pinecones have broken in the wind)
(The teary moon stops you
from walking towards death)
Chief Mouna?
(The teary moon stops you
from walking towards death)
(The gloomy clouds cannot shelter the sadness)
Obing!
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
Jiro!
Obing! -Jiro!
(that's sailing towards the dim starlight)
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Obing! -I'm in here!
Obing! -Help me!
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
Move away!
Father!
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(Time is light as a flame)
Father!
Why must you hunt heads?
(That lights up the stars in your souls)
(Your dreams are vast like a blue ocean)
(But the joyous tears
in your souls have dried out)
(Oh, my children! Do you know?)
(How much pain do you swallow to
sing the song of our ancestral spirit?)
(How much shame do you swallow
to speak what you want to say?)
(How much regret do you swallow
to fulfill your dreams?)
(Oh, children! What's wrong with you?)
(Oh, my children!
What exactly is wrong with you?)